<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<OAI-PMH xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" 
         xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance"
         xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/OAI-PMH.xsd">
    <responseDate>2026-07-13T06:27:50Z</responseDate>
                <request verb="GetRecord" identifier="oai:arXiv.org:2510.11679" metadataPrefix="arXiv">http://oaipmh.arxiv.org/oai</request>


    <GetRecord>
                <record>
                <header>
        <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:2510.11679</identifier>
        <datestamp>2025-10-14</datestamp>
            <setSpec>physics:quant-ph</setSpec>
            <setSpec>physics:cond-mat:quant-gas</setSpec>
            <setSpec>physics:hep-lat</setSpec>
            <setSpec>physics:hep-ph</setSpec>
    </header>

            <metadata>
                        <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ https://oaipmh.arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
        <id>2510.11679</id>
        <created>2025-10-13</created>
            <updated>2025-10-14</updated>
        <authors>
                <author>
                    <keyname>Mark</keyname>
                        <forenames>Daniel K.</forenames>
                </author>
                <author>
                    <keyname>Surace</keyname>
                        <forenames>Federica M.</forenames>
                </author>
                <author>
                    <keyname>Schuster</keyname>
                        <forenames>Thomas</forenames>
                </author>
                <author>
                    <keyname>Shaw</keyname>
                        <forenames>Adam L.</forenames>
                </author>
                <author>
                    <keyname>Gong</keyname>
                        <forenames>Wenjie</forenames>
                </author>
                <author>
                    <keyname>Choi</keyname>
                        <forenames>Soonwon</forenames>
                </author>
                <author>
                    <keyname>Endres</keyname>
                        <forenames>Manuel</forenames>
                </author>
        </authors>
        <title>Observation of ballistic plasma and memory in high-energy gauge theory dynamics</title>
            <categories>quant-ph cond-mat.quant-gas hep-lat hep-ph</categories>
            <report-no>MIT-CTP/5931</report-no>
            <license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license>
            <abstract>Gauge theories describe the fundamental forces of nature. However, high-energy dynamics, such as the formation of quark-gluon plasmas, is notoriously difficult to model with classical methods. Quantum simulation offers a promising alternative in this regime, yet experiments have mainly probed low energies. Here, we observe the formation of a ballistic plasma and long-time memory effects in high-energy gauge theory dynamics on a high-precision quantum simulator. Both observations are unexpected, as the initial state - fully filled with particle-antiparticle pairs - was thought to rapidly thermalize. Instead, we find correlations spreading ballistically to long distances and a memory of charge clusters. Our observations cannot be explained by many-body scars, but are captured by a new theory of plasma oscillations between electric field and current operators, persisting all the way to the continuum limit of the (1+1)D Schwinger model, of which we simulate a lattice version. Adapting techniques from quantum optics, we visualize plasma oscillations as rotations of Wigner distributions, leading to a novel set of predictions which we test in experiment and numerics. The new framework encompasses both our scenario and scars, which show up as coherent states of the plasma. The experimental surprises we observe in the high-energy dynamics of a simple gauge theory point to the potential of high-precision quantum simulations of gauge theories for general scientific discovery.</abstract>
    </arXiv>

            </metadata>
        </record>

    </GetRecord>
</OAI-PMH>