<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<OAI-PMH xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" 
         xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance"
         xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/OAI-PMH.xsd">
    <responseDate>2026-07-13T06:23:04Z</responseDate>
                <request verb="GetRecord" identifier="oai:arXiv.org:2510.00082" metadataPrefix="arXiv">http://oaipmh.arxiv.org/oai</request>


    <GetRecord>
                <record>
                <header>
        <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:2510.00082</identifier>
        <datestamp>2025-10-02</datestamp>
            <setSpec>physics:astro-ph:IM</setSpec>
            <setSpec>physics:astro-ph:EP</setSpec>
    </header>

            <metadata>
                        <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ https://oaipmh.arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
        <id>2510.00082</id>
        <created>2025-09-30</created>
            <updated>2025-10-02</updated>
        <authors>
                <author>
                    <keyname>Ellery</keyname>
                        <forenames>Alex</forenames>
                </author>
        </authors>
        <title>Technosignatures of Self-Replicating Probes in the Solar System</title>
            <categories>astro-ph.IM astro-ph.EP</categories>
            <comments>31 pages</comments>
            <license>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0/</license>
            <abstract>We explore a much-neglected area of SETI: solar system techno-signatures. As our cursory solar system exploration consolidates into commercial industrialisation, it is crucial that we determine what to look for and where. We first consider the rationale for interstellar self-replicating probes and their implications for the Fermi paradox. Whether for defensive or exploratory reasons, self-replicating probes are a rational strategy for Galactic investigation. We determine that self-replicating probes will systematically explore the Galaxy by tracking resources of sufficient metallicity. We focus on the resource requirements of a self-replicating interstellar probe that may have visited our solar system. After considering asteroid resources, we suggest that evidence of asteroidal processing will be difficult to discern from natural processes given the constraints imposed by self-replication. We further determine that the Moon is an ideal base of manufacturing operations. We suggest that nuclear reactors, such as the Magnox reactor model, can feasibly be constructed from lunar resources which will have left isotopic ratio signatures of Th-232/Nd-144 and/or Th-232/Ba-137. We further suggest that in anticipatory economic trade for resources, a self-replicating probe may have left artefacts buried with asteroidal resources on the Moon. Such gifts would be detectable and accessible only once a threshold of technological sophistication has been achieved. An obvious gift in trade for the resources utilised would be a universal constructor.</abstract>
    </arXiv>

            </metadata>
        </record>

    </GetRecord>
</OAI-PMH>