<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<OAI-PMH xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" 
         xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance"
         xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/OAI-PMH.xsd">
    <responseDate>2026-07-12T15:32:57Z</responseDate>
                <request verb="GetRecord" identifier="oai:arXiv.org:2506.01131v1" metadataPrefix="arXiv">http://oaipmh.arxiv.org/oai</request>


    <GetRecord>
                <record>
                <header>
        <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:2506.01131</identifier>
        <datestamp>2025-12-12</datestamp>
            <setSpec>physics:cond-mat:str-el</setSpec>
            <setSpec>physics:cond-mat:stat-mech</setSpec>
            <setSpec>physics:hep-th</setSpec>
            <setSpec>physics:quant-ph</setSpec>
    </header>

            <metadata>
                        <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ https://oaipmh.arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
        <id>2506.01131</id>
        <created>2025-06-01</created>
            <updated>2025-12-12</updated>
        <authors>
                <author>
                    <keyname>Chen</keyname>
                        <forenames>Yu-Hsueh</forenames>
                </author>
                <author>
                    <keyname>Grover</keyname>
                        <forenames>Tarun</forenames>
                </author>
        </authors>
        <title>Analogs of deconfined quantum criticality for non-invertible symmetry breaking in 1d</title>
            <categories>cond-mat.str-el cond-mat.stat-mech hep-th quant-ph</categories>
            <comments>16 pages, 4 figures, 1 table; main results are summarized in the Introduction</comments>
            <journal-ref>Phys. Rev. B 112, 195129 (2025)</journal-ref>
            <doi>10.1103/8tsg-q9j6</doi>
            <license>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0/</license>
            <abstract>The spontaneous breaking of non-invertible symmetries can lead to exotic phenomena such as coexistence of order and disorder. Here we explore second-order phase transitions in 1d spin chains between two phases that correspond to distinct patterns of non-invertible symmetry breaking. The critical point shares several features with well-understood examples of deconfined quantum critical points, such as enlarged symmetry and identical exponents for the two order parameters participating in the transition. Interestingly, such deconfined transitions involving non-invertible symmetries allow one to construct a whole family of similar critical points by gauging spin-flip symmetries. By employing gauging and bosonization, we characterize the phase diagram of our model in the vicinity of the critical point. We also explore proximate phases and phase transitions in related models, including a deconfined quantum critical point between invertible order parameters that is enforced by a non-invertible symmetry.</abstract>
    </arXiv>

            </metadata>
        </record>

    </GetRecord>
</OAI-PMH>