<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<OAI-PMH xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" 
         xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance"
         xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/OAI-PMH.xsd">
    <responseDate>2026-07-13T21:13:24Z</responseDate>
                <request verb="GetRecord" identifier="oai:arXiv.org:2602.15080" metadataPrefix="arXiv">http://oaipmh.arxiv.org/oai</request>


    <GetRecord>
                <record>
                <header>
        <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:2602.15080</identifier>
        <datestamp>2026-07-13</datestamp>
            <setSpec>physics:quant-ph</setSpec>
    </header>

            <metadata>
                        <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ https://oaipmh.arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
        <id>2602.15080</id>
        <created>2026-04-13</created>
            <updated>2026-07-13</updated>
        <authors>
                <author>
                    <keyname>AlMasri</keyname>
                        <forenames>M. W.</forenames>
                </author>
        </authors>
        <title>Geometry of Quantum Logic Gates</title>
            <categories>quant-ph</categories>
            <comments>9 pages, matches accepted version</comments>
            <journal-ref>Mod. Phys. Lett. A 41 (25), 2650141 (2026)</journal-ref>
            <doi>10.1142/S0217732326501415</doi>
            <license>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-sa/4.0/</license>
            <abstract>In this work, we investigate the geometry of quantum logic gates within the holomorphic representation of quantum mechanics. We begin by embedding the physical qubit subspace into the space of holomorphic functions that are homogeneous of degree one in each Schwinger boson pair $(z_{a_j}, z_{b_j})$. Within this framework, we derive explicit closed-form differential operator representations for a universal set of quantum gates, including the Pauli operators, Hadamard, CNOT, CZ, and SWAP, and demonstrate that they preserve the physical subspace exactly. Restricting to unit-magnitude variables ($|z| = 1$) reveals a toroidal space $\mathbb{T}^{2N}$, on which quantum gates act as canonical transformations: Pauli operators generate Hamiltonian flows, the Hadamard gate induces a nonlinear automorphism, and entangling gates produce correlated diffeomorphisms that couple distinct toroidal factors. Beyond the torus, the full Segal--Bargmann space carries a natural Kähler geometry that governs amplitude dynamics. Entanglement is geometrically characterized via the Segre embedding into complex projective space, while topological protection arises from the $U(1)^N$ fiber bundle structure associated with the Jordan--Schwinger constraint.</abstract>
    </arXiv>

            </metadata>
        </record>

    </GetRecord>
</OAI-PMH>