<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<OAI-PMH xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" 
         xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance"
         xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/OAI-PMH.xsd">
    <responseDate>2026-07-12T21:40:00Z</responseDate>
                <request verb="GetRecord" identifier="oai:arXiv.org:2605.04631v1" metadataPrefix="arXiv">http://oaipmh.arxiv.org/oai</request>


    <GetRecord>
                <record>
                <header>
        <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:2605.04631</identifier>
        <datestamp>2026-05-08</datestamp>
            <setSpec>physics:astro-ph:HE</setSpec>
            <setSpec>physics:gr-qc</setSpec>
            <setSpec>physics:hep-th</setSpec>
    </header>

            <metadata>
                        <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ https://oaipmh.arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
        <id>2605.04631</id>
        <created>2026-05-06</created>
            <updated>2026-05-08</updated>
        <authors>
                <author>
                    <keyname>Xia</keyname>
                        <forenames>Jing-ze</forenames>
                </author>
                <author>
                    <keyname>Jiang</keyname>
                        <forenames>Hong-xuan</forenames>
                </author>
                <author>
                    <keyname>Liu</keyname>
                        <forenames>Cheng</forenames>
                </author>
                <author>
                    <keyname>Mizuno</keyname>
                        <forenames>Yosuke</forenames>
                </author>
        </authors>
        <title>Dynamics and Radiative Signatures of Accretion Flows onto a Kerr-like Wormhole</title>
            <categories>astro-ph.HE gr-qc hep-th</categories>
            <comments>15pages, 13 figures; Accepted by Apj, comments wellcome</comments>
            <license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license>
            <abstract>Wormholes are a hypothetical object that connects disparate points in spacetime. It is a theoretically well-motivated black hole alternative and offers a potential observationally testable arena for probing strong-field gravity with horizon-scale images. We perform general relativistic magnetohydrodynamic (GRMHD) simulations and general relativistic radiative transfer (GRRT) calculations of accretion flows onto a Kerr-like wormhole. Adopting a Kerr black-bounce metric with a fixed throat parameter $\ell = 2.5\,\rm M$, we explore the effects of spin using both two- and three-dimensional simulations. The accretion flow is initialized as a magnetized geometrically thick torus near one mouth of the wormhole, while the opposite mouth is initially gas-free. We find that the spin parameter influences the dynamical properties on both sides of the wormhole through the frame-dragging effects. Based on the GRMHD results, we compute ray-traced images at $230\,\mathrm{GHz}$ using \texttt{RAPTOR}, and analyze the horizon-scale image structure through higher-order photon trajectories. Our GRRT calculations show that emissions originating from the immediate vicinity of the throat can dominate, in contrast to the case of a Kerr black hole. It provides the variable component of the signal and imprints a clear quasi-periodic modulation in the light curves. These properties would be useful to either confirm or rule out such exotic compact objects through horizon-scale observations.</abstract>
    </arXiv>

            </metadata>
        </record>

    </GetRecord>
</OAI-PMH>