<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<OAI-PMH xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" 
         xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance"
         xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/OAI-PMH.xsd">
    <responseDate>2026-07-12T20:55:57Z</responseDate>
                <request verb="GetRecord" identifier="oai:arXiv.org:2605.03038v1" metadataPrefix="arXiv">http://oaipmh.arxiv.org/oai</request>


    <GetRecord>
                <record>
                <header>
        <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:2605.03038</identifier>
        <datestamp>2026-05-06</datestamp>
            <setSpec>physics:hep-th</setSpec>
            <setSpec>physics:gr-qc</setSpec>
            <setSpec>physics:hep-ph</setSpec>
            <setSpec>physics:nucl-th</setSpec>
    </header>

            <metadata>
                        <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ https://oaipmh.arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
        <id>2605.03038</id>
        <created>2026-05-04</created>
            <updated>2026-05-06</updated>
        <authors>
                <author>
                    <keyname>Staśto</keyname>
                        <forenames>Anna M.</forenames>
                </author>
                <author>
                    <keyname>Raj</keyname>
                        <forenames>Himanshu</forenames>
                </author>
                <author>
                    <keyname>Venugopalan</keyname>
                        <forenames>Raju</forenames>
                </author>
        </authors>
        <title>Squeezed-state radiation in shockwave scattering: QCD-Gravity double copy</title>
            <categories>hep-th gr-qc hep-ph nucl-th</categories>
            <comments>33 pages, To appear in proceedings of the 66th Cracow School of Theoretical Physics, dedicated to Prof. Andrzej Białas on the occasion of his 90th birthday</comments>
            <license>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0/</license>
            <abstract>Gluon and graviton radiation in strong field shockwave scattering are described by effective Lipatov vertices, with the graviton Lipatov vertex proportional to the bilinear of its QCD counterpart. We show here that the n-particle gluon radiation spectrum can be described as a generalized Susskind-Glogower (gSG) squeezed coherent state and discuss the properties of such squeezed states. The double copy structure of the radiative frameworks suggests that multi-graviton radiation can be similarly described as a gSG state. We examine the physical parameter space and show that very large squeezing parameters $\sim \ln({\bar n})$ (where ${\bar n}$ is the mean graviton occupancy) are feasible for nearly minimal uncertainty configurations of the gSG state. Quantum noise in the corresponding gravitational wave spectrum is enhanced above the sensitivity of current and future gravitational wave detectors. Our results point to the importance of a comprehensive study of the strong field Lipatov regime of gravitational radiation.</abstract>
    </arXiv>

            </metadata>
        </record>

    </GetRecord>
</OAI-PMH>