<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<OAI-PMH xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" 
         xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance"
         xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/OAI-PMH.xsd">
    <responseDate>2026-07-13T06:20:55Z</responseDate>
                <request verb="GetRecord" identifier="oai:arXiv.org:2508.10500" metadataPrefix="arXiv">http://oaipmh.arxiv.org/oai</request>


    <GetRecord>
                <record>
                <header>
        <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:2508.10500</identifier>
        <datestamp>2026-01-26</datestamp>
            <setSpec>physics:quant-ph</setSpec>
    </header>

            <metadata>
                        <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ https://oaipmh.arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
        <id>2508.10500</id>
        <created>2026-01-23</created>
            <updated>2026-01-26</updated>
        <authors>
                <author>
                    <keyname>Naseem</keyname>
                        <forenames>M. Tahir</forenames>
                </author>
        </authors>
        <title>Reservoir-Engineered Mechanical Cat States with a Driven Qubit</title>
            <categories>quant-ph</categories>
            <journal-ref>Phys. Rev. A 013732 (113) 2026</journal-ref>
            <doi>10.1103/dxzd-nqrv</doi>
            <license>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0/</license>
            <abstract>Macroscopic quantum superpositions, such as mechanical Schrödinger cat states, are central to emerging quantum technologies in sensing and bosonic error-correcting codes. We propose a scheme to generate such states by coupling a nanomechanical resonator to a coherently driven two-level system via both transverse and longitudinal interactions. Driving the qubit at twice the oscillator frequency activates resonant two-phonon exchange processes, enabling coherent conversion of drive energy into phonon pairs and their dissipative stabilization. Starting from the full time-dependent Hamiltonian, we derive an effective master equation for the mechanical mode by perturbative elimination of the lossy qubit. The reduced dynamics feature engineered two-phonon loss and a coherent squeezing term, which together drive the resonator into a deterministic Schrödinger-cat state. Our approach requires only a single driven qubit and no auxiliary cavity, offering a scalable and experimentally accessible route to macroscopic quantum superpositions in circuit-QED and related platforms.</abstract>
    </arXiv>

            </metadata>
        </record>

    </GetRecord>
</OAI-PMH>