<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<OAI-PMH xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" 
         xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance"
         xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/OAI-PMH.xsd">
    <responseDate>2026-07-11T08:20:56Z</responseDate>
                <request verb="GetRecord" identifier="oai:arXiv.org:2606.04052v1" metadataPrefix="arXiv">http://oaipmh.arxiv.org/oai</request>


    <GetRecord>
                <record>
                <header>
        <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:2606.04052</identifier>
        <datestamp>2026-06-04</datestamp>
            <setSpec>physics:astro-ph:IM</setSpec>
    </header>

            <metadata>
                        <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ https://oaipmh.arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
        <id>2606.04052</id>
        <created>2026-06-02</created>
            <updated>2026-06-04</updated>
        <authors>
                <author>
                    <keyname>Shen</keyname>
                        <forenames>Chao</forenames>
                </author>
                <author>
                    <keyname>Li</keyname>
                        <forenames>Jiaze</forenames>
                </author>
        </authors>
        <title>Relativistic Lightsail Propulsion Dynamics</title>
            <categories>astro-ph.IM</categories>
            <comments>9 pages, 4 figures</comments>
            <license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license>
            <abstract>Lightsail technology currently stands as one of the most promising means for interstellar travel, having entered the application phase following multiple successful on-orbit validations. This paper systematically investigates the propulsion effects of incident light, specularly reflected light, and diffusely scattered light on high-speed relativistic lightsails based on radiation dynamics for the first time. The results indicate that, due to the Doppler effect, the thrust from all three components decreases as velocity increases, with incident light providing the strongest thrust, followed by specular reflection, and diffuse scattering being the weakest. Furthermore, the study reveals the existence of a critical velocity for thrust from diffuse scattering: beyond this point, it transforms into drag, although the net radiative force continues to accelerate the spacecraft. By establishing and numerically solving the equations of motion for the lightsail, it is shown that velocity increase is concentrated primarily in the initial acceleration phase, with efficiency declining as speed rises. This research provides a rigorous and in-depth theoretical foundation for lightsail dynamics</abstract>
    </arXiv>

            </metadata>
        </record>

    </GetRecord>
</OAI-PMH>