<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<OAI-PMH xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" 
         xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance"
         xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/OAI-PMH.xsd">
    <responseDate>2026-07-13T06:24:34Z</responseDate>
                <request verb="GetRecord" identifier="oai:arXiv.org:2604.19418" metadataPrefix="arXiv">http://oaipmh.arxiv.org/oai</request>


    <GetRecord>
                <record>
                <header>
        <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:2604.19418</identifier>
        <datestamp>2026-04-22</datestamp>
            <setSpec>physics:gr-qc</setSpec>
    </header>

            <metadata>
                        <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ https://oaipmh.arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
        <id>2604.19418</id>
        <created>2026-04-21</created>
            <updated>2026-04-22</updated>
        <authors>
                <author>
                    <keyname>Hübsch</keyname>
                        <forenames>Tristan</forenames>
                </author>
                <author>
                    <keyname>Minic</keyname>
                        <forenames>Djordje</forenames>
                </author>
        </authors>
        <title>Quantum Spacetime, Quantum Gravity and Gravitized Quantum Theory</title>
            <categories>gr-qc</categories>
            <comments>32 pages, presented at the International Conference &#34;Nonlinearity, Nonlocality and Ultrametricity&#34;</comments>
            <license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license>
            <abstract>General relativity is a background-independent theory of a dynamical classical spacetime geometry. Quantum theory is formulated in a classical spacetime, as an intrinsically probabilistic, contextual theory of non-classical, interfering probabilities, with a fixed Born rule for computing those probabilities. We argue that the quantum nature of spacetime, which includes a non-commutative dual companion to the (observed) classical spacetime, is the reason behind an intrinsically probabilistic and contextual nature of quantum theory, with the fixed Born rule. In quantum gravity, we claim, quantum theory is gravitized into a background-independent structure with dynamical and contextual quantum probabilities. This proposal implies intrinsic triple and higher-order interference in the context of massive quantum probes, which sheds light on string theory and the observed vacuum energy as well as the masses of elementary particles.</abstract>
    </arXiv>

            </metadata>
        </record>

    </GetRecord>
</OAI-PMH>