<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<OAI-PMH xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" 
         xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance"
         xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/OAI-PMH.xsd">
    <responseDate>2026-07-13T06:26:00Z</responseDate>
                <request verb="GetRecord" identifier="oai:arXiv.org:2601.05046" metadataPrefix="arXiv">http://oaipmh.arxiv.org/oai</request>


    <GetRecord>
                <record>
                <header>
        <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:2601.05046</identifier>
        <datestamp>2026-01-09</datestamp>
            <setSpec>physics:quant-ph</setSpec>
    </header>

            <metadata>
                        <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ https://oaipmh.arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
        <id>2601.05046</id>
        <created>2026-01-08</created>
            <updated>2026-01-09</updated>
        <authors>
                <author>
                    <keyname>Chattopadhyay</keyname>
                        <forenames>Pritam</forenames>
                </author>
                <author>
                    <keyname>Santos</keyname>
                        <forenames>Jonas F. G.</forenames>
                </author>
                <author>
                    <keyname>Misra</keyname>
                        <forenames>Avijit</forenames>
                </author>
        </authors>
        <title>Anomaly to Resource: The Mpemba Effect in Quantum Thermometry</title>
            <categories>quant-ph</categories>
            <license>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0/</license>
            <abstract>Quantum thermometry provides a key capability for nanoscale devices and quantum technologies, but most existing strategies rely on probes initialized near equilibrium. This equilibrium paradigm imposes intrinsic limitations: sensitivity is tied to long-time thermalization and often cannot be improved in fast, noisy, or nonstationary settings. In contrast, the \textit{Mpemba effect}, the counterintuitive phenomenon where hotter states relax faster than colder ones, has mostly been viewed as a thermodynamic anomaly. Here, we bridge this gap by proving that Mpemba-type inversions generically yield a finite-time enhancement of the quantum Fisher information (QFI) for temperature estimation, thereby converting an anomalous relaxation effect into a concrete metrological resource. Through explicit analyses of two-level and $Λ$-level probes coupled to bosonic baths, we show that nonequilibrium initializations can transiently outperform both equilibrium strategies and colder states, realizing a \emph{metrological Mpemba effect}. Our results establish anomalous relaxation as a general design principle for nonequilibrium quantum thermometry, enabling ultrafast and nanoscale sensing protocols that exploit, rather than avoid, transient dynamics.</abstract>
    </arXiv>

            </metadata>
        </record>

    </GetRecord>
</OAI-PMH>