<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<OAI-PMH xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" 
         xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance"
         xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/OAI-PMH.xsd">
    <responseDate>2026-07-13T06:28:22Z</responseDate>
                <request verb="GetRecord" identifier="oai:arXiv.org:2605.04801" metadataPrefix="arXiv">http://oaipmh.arxiv.org/oai</request>


    <GetRecord>
                <record>
                <header>
        <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:2605.04801</identifier>
        <datestamp>2026-05-07</datestamp>
            <setSpec>physics:astro-ph:GA</setSpec>
    </header>

            <metadata>
                        <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ https://oaipmh.arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
        <id>2605.04801</id>
        <created>2026-05-06</created>
            <updated>2026-05-07</updated>
        <authors>
                <author>
                    <keyname>Horns</keyname>
                        <forenames>Dieter</forenames>
                </author>
                <author>
                    <keyname>Knop</keyname>
                        <forenames>Niklas</forenames>
                </author>
                <author>
                    <keyname>Mohammadidoust</keyname>
                        <forenames>Mohammad</forenames>
                </author>
        </authors>
        <title>Contribution of interstellar objects to local dark matter density</title>
            <categories>astro-ph.GA</categories>
            <license>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0/</license>
            <abstract>The recent discovery of three interstellar comets in the solar system indicates the presence of so-far unaccounted baryonic matter in the Galaxy as a population of inter-stellar objects (ISO). The contribution of ISOs to the overall mass budget of the Galaxy affects the estimates on mass of the non-baryonic dark matter halo. We are attempting to estimate the mass density of non-baryonic Dark Matter after including a Galactic ISO contribution to the Galactic rotation curve. The object 3I/ATLAS is a surprisingly massive object with estimates of the nuclear radius reaching up to few kilo-metres. The observed incidence rate of interstellar objects (ISO) passing through the inner solar system in combination with estimates on the mass density and size provides an estimate of the local mass density if ISOs in the interstellar medium. The resulting estimate carries large uncertainties which are the consequence of the difficulties to constrain or measure the nuclear radius. The large kinematic age of 3I/ATLAS motivates a model where ISO objects are distributed in a thick (0.8~kpc) disk with a large radial scale length of $\approx 7$~kpc estimated from a fit to rotational velocity measurements from GAIA DR3 data. We find that the ISO contribution to the baryonic mass budget could reach a total mass of $5\times 10^{10}~M_\odot$ which leads to a reduction of the local Dark Matter halo density to $0.24$~GeV/cm$^3$. Even though this scenario requires an overly optimistic fraction of matter to be released in the form of ISO objects, it is plausible that the local Dark Matter halo density is biased towards large values given our ignorance of non-detectable baryonic matter in the Galaxy.</abstract>
    </arXiv>

            </metadata>
        </record>

    </GetRecord>
</OAI-PMH>