<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<OAI-PMH xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" 
         xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance"
         xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/OAI-PMH.xsd">
    <responseDate>2026-07-13T06:20:53Z</responseDate>
                <request verb="GetRecord" identifier="oai:arXiv.org:2508.02351" metadataPrefix="arXiv">http://oaipmh.arxiv.org/oai</request>


    <GetRecord>
                <record>
                <header>
        <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:2508.02351</identifier>
        <datestamp>2025-08-05</datestamp>
            <setSpec>physics:quant-ph</setSpec>
    </header>

            <metadata>
                        <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ https://oaipmh.arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
        <id>2508.02351</id>
        <created>2025-08-04</created>
            <updated>2025-08-05</updated>
        <authors>
                <author>
                    <keyname>Zhou</keyname>
                        <forenames>Yue-Hui</forenames>
                </author>
                <author>
                    <keyname>Liao</keyname>
                        <forenames>Jie-Qiao</forenames>
                </author>
        </authors>
        <title>Microscopic Theory of Heat Transfer across a Vacuum</title>
            <categories>quant-ph</categories>
            <comments>45 pages,5 figures</comments>
            <license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license>
            <abstract>Heat transfer is a fundamental concept in physics, and how to characterize the microscopical physical mechanism of heat transfer is a significant topic. Recently, a new mechanism for heat transfer, phonon heat transfer across a vacuum through quantum fluctuations, has been experimentally demonstrated in a two-vibrating-membrane system. However, a microscopic quantum electrodynamics theory behind this phenomenon remains unexplored. Here, we establish the nonrelativistic microscopic theory of phonon heat transfer across a vacuum confined by two movable end mirrors of a one-dimensional optomechanical cavity. Under the multimode-cavity-field framework, we obtain a second-order effective Hamiltonian governing the heat transfer effect. This Hamiltonian describes a phonon-exchange interaction between the two mirrors with a strength proportional to a multimode factor and $l_{0}^{-3}$, where $l_{0}$ is the rest cavity length. We also confirm the dependence of the mode temperatures and heat flux on the rest cavity length, corresponding to the thermal steady state of the mirrors. This work initiates the microscopic investigation of thermodynamics based on the optomechanical cavity platform, and will have profound implications for both thermal management in nanoscale devices and cavity optomechanics.</abstract>
    </arXiv>

            </metadata>
        </record>

    </GetRecord>
</OAI-PMH>