<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<OAI-PMH xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" 
         xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance"
         xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/OAI-PMH.xsd">
    <responseDate>2026-07-13T06:29:02Z</responseDate>
                <request verb="GetRecord" identifier="oai:arXiv.org:2509.14320" metadataPrefix="arXiv">http://oaipmh.arxiv.org/oai</request>


    <GetRecord>
                <record>
                <header>
        <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:2509.14320</identifier>
        <datestamp>2026-06-29</datestamp>
            <setSpec>physics:hep-ph</setSpec>
            <setSpec>physics:astro-ph:CO</setSpec>
            <setSpec>physics:cond-mat:mes-hall</setSpec>
            <setSpec>physics:physics:ins-det</setSpec>
            <setSpec>physics:quant-ph</setSpec>
    </header>

            <metadata>
                        <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ https://oaipmh.arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
        <id>2509.14320</id>
        <created>2026-06-26</created>
            <updated>2026-06-29</updated>
        <authors>
                <author>
                    <keyname>Mehrani</keyname>
                        <forenames>Jaanita</forenames>
                </author>
                <author>
                    <keyname>Xu</keyname>
                        <forenames>Tao</forenames>
                </author>
                <author>
                    <keyname>Baydin</keyname>
                        <forenames>Andrey</forenames>
                </author>
                <author>
                    <keyname>Manfra</keyname>
                        <forenames>Michael J.</forenames>
                </author>
                <author>
                    <keyname>Everitt</keyname>
                        <forenames>Henry O.</forenames>
                </author>
                <author>
                    <keyname>Long</keyname>
                        <forenames>Andrew J.</forenames>
                </author>
                <author>
                    <keyname>Sinha</keyname>
                        <forenames>Kuver</forenames>
                </author>
                <author>
                    <keyname>Kono</keyname>
                        <forenames>Junichiro</forenames>
                </author>
                <author>
                    <keyname>Huang</keyname>
                        <forenames>Shengxi</forenames>
                </author>
        </authors>
        <title>Quantum Semiconductor Heterostructures for meV Axion Dark Matter Detection</title>
            <categories>hep-ph astro-ph.CO cond-mat.mes-hall physics.ins-det quant-ph</categories>
            <comments>Matches version published in PRL. 9+18 pages, 6+12 figures</comments>
            <journal-ref>Phys. Rev. Lett. 136, 241001 (2026)</journal-ref>
            <doi>10.1103/y7jl-gj2k</doi>
            <license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license>
            <abstract>We propose a novel strategy and a new class of detectors for the direct detection of axion dark matter in the meV mass range, based on resonantly enhanced axion-photon conversion through the inverse Primakoff effect in engineered radiometers composed of quantum semiconductor heterostructures. Semiconductor-Quantum-Well Axion Radiometer Experiments (SQWAREs) are multiple quantum well structures forming magnetoplasmonic cavities, containing high-mobility two-dimensional electron gases, realizing tunable epsilon-near-zero resonances in the terahertz frequency range. By controlling the orientation of the cavity within a strong external magnetic field, both the resonance frequency and the axion-induced current are optimized $\it{in\,situ}$, enabling efficient scanning across a broad mass range without the need for complex mechanical adjustments. The axion-induced electromagnetic signal radiatively emitted from the cavity is then detected by a photodetector. We present the theoretical basis for resonant enhancement, detail the experimental design and benchmarks through extensive simulations, project the sensitivity of an example SQWARE for several realistic configurations, and demonstrate the modularity and flexibility of the design to fit reasonably with any lab&#39;s existing capabilities and target unique axion mass ranges. Our results demonstrate that the SQWAREs can probe the well-motivated quantum chromodynamics axion parameter space and close a critical gap in direct searches at meV masses.</abstract>
    </arXiv>

            </metadata>
        </record>

    </GetRecord>
</OAI-PMH>