<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<OAI-PMH xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" 
         xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance"
         xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/OAI-PMH.xsd">
    <responseDate>2026-07-13T06:28:28Z</responseDate>
                <request verb="GetRecord" identifier="oai:arXiv.org:2605.21942" metadataPrefix="arXiv">http://oaipmh.arxiv.org/oai</request>


    <GetRecord>
                <record>
                <header>
        <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:2605.21942</identifier>
        <datestamp>2026-05-29</datestamp>
            <setSpec>physics:quant-ph</setSpec>
    </header>

            <metadata>
                        <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ https://oaipmh.arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
        <id>2605.21942</id>
        <created>2026-05-28</created>
            <updated>2026-05-29</updated>
        <authors>
                <author>
                    <keyname>Zhao</keyname>
                        <forenames>Sheng</forenames>
                </author>
                <author>
                    <keyname>Li</keyname>
                        <forenames>Peng-Bo</forenames>
                </author>
        </authors>
        <title>Photon blockade via three-body interactions: toward high-purity and bright single-photon sources</title>
            <categories>quant-ph</categories>
            <comments>7+14 pages, 3+5 figures</comments>
            <license>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0/</license>
            <abstract>Photon blockade is vital for single-photon generation, but current schemes with conventional and unconventional photon blockade face critical limitations like the purity-brightness trade-off, hindering the generation of high-performance single-photons. To overcome these limitations, we introduce a fundamentally new photon blockade mechanism by utilizing three-body interactions between a single photonic mode and two qubits. This kind of interaction intrinsically cuts off the excitation path to the two-photon state, resulting in a perfect photon blockade effect. The mechanism operates across a broad parameter range, free from the constraints of strong coupling or weak driving. Remarkably, it breaks the purity-brightness trade-off, enabling the simultaneous achievement of extreme purity and high brightness, both significantly outperforming previous mechanisms. Furthermore, this approach demonstrates robustness against thermal noise and avoids unwanted oscillations in the time-delayed correlation function. This work provides a path for generating high-purity, high-brightness, and robust single-photon sources, a key resource for quantum technologies.</abstract>
    </arXiv>

            </metadata>
        </record>

    </GetRecord>
</OAI-PMH>