<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<OAI-PMH xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" 
         xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance"
         xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/OAI-PMH.xsd">
    <responseDate>2026-07-13T06:28:30Z</responseDate>
                <request verb="GetRecord" identifier="oai:arXiv.org:2606.03671" metadataPrefix="arXiv">http://oaipmh.arxiv.org/oai</request>


    <GetRecord>
                <record>
                <header>
        <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:2606.03671</identifier>
        <datestamp>2026-06-03</datestamp>
            <setSpec>physics:gr-qc</setSpec>
            <setSpec>physics:hep-th</setSpec>
            <setSpec>physics:quant-ph</setSpec>
    </header>

            <metadata>
                        <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ https://oaipmh.arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
        <id>2606.03671</id>
        <created>2026-06-02</created>
            <updated>2026-06-03</updated>
        <authors>
                <author>
                    <keyname>Fujita</keyname>
                        <forenames>Tomohiro</forenames>
                </author>
                <author>
                    <keyname>Sasaki</keyname>
                        <forenames>Misao</forenames>
                </author>
        </authors>
        <title>Quantum Matter Makes Lightcones Quantum</title>
            <categories>gr-qc hep-th quant-ph</categories>
            <comments>16 pages, 4 figures</comments>
            <report-no>YITP-26-57</report-no>
            <license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license>
            <abstract>In gravitational physics, matter does not merely move within spacetime; it also determines the light cones that define causal relations. What happens when the matter that determines these light cones is itself in a quantum state? We address this question in a controlled low-energy setting: a massless scalar field propagating in the spacetime with the Newtonian gravitational potential sourced by a non-relativistic quantum particle. We show that the light cones are affected by an operator-valued Shapiro delay, with the three consequences: (i) causal-boundary shifts are promoted to noncommuting observables, giving the causal structure an irreducible quantum uncertainty; (ii) the causal relation between two fixed spacetime points can become a superposition of timelike and spacelike configurations; and (iii) tracing out the source smears the Wightman light-cone singularity, producing an effective UV cutoff. Thus, quantum matter does not merely fluctuate within spacetime; it makes the causal structure itself quantum, even without quantized gravitons.</abstract>
    </arXiv>

            </metadata>
        </record>

    </GetRecord>
</OAI-PMH>