<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<OAI-PMH xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" 
         xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance"
         xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/OAI-PMH.xsd">
    <responseDate>2026-07-13T06:21:39Z</responseDate>
                <request verb="GetRecord" identifier="oai:arXiv.org:2511.13768" metadataPrefix="arXiv">http://oaipmh.arxiv.org/oai</request>


    <GetRecord>
                <record>
                <header>
        <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:2511.13768</identifier>
        <datestamp>2025-11-19</datestamp>
            <setSpec>physics:physics:bio-ph</setSpec>
            <setSpec>physics:physics:chem-ph</setSpec>
            <setSpec>physics:quant-ph</setSpec>
    </header>

            <metadata>
                        <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ https://oaipmh.arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
        <id>2511.13768</id>
        <created>2025-11-14</created>
            <updated>2025-11-19</updated>
        <authors>
                <author>
                    <keyname>Filho</keyname>
                        <forenames>Elso Drigo</forenames>
                </author>
                <author>
                    <keyname>Ricotta</keyname>
                        <forenames>Regina Maria</forenames>
                </author>
        </authors>
        <title>Study of Quantum Confinement inside a Viral Capsid</title>
            <categories>physics.bio-ph physics.chem-ph quant-ph</categories>
            <comments>11 pages</comments>
            <license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license>
            <abstract>Classical computational methods, such as molecular dynamics and Monte Carlo simulations, have long been the standard for modeling viral structure and function. However, these approaches may overlook crucial quantum phenomena that operate at the nanoscale, particularly within the highly-compacted genetic material of the viral capsid. The confined, high-density environment of genetic material within the capsid strongly suggests that quantum confinement effects play a significant, yet unexplored, role in viral processes. This study introduces a novel quantum approach using Supersymmetric Quantum Mechanics (SQM) to investigate the quantum confinement effects on viruses. In this paper, the viral capsid environment is modeled using the Pariacoto virus, a model system well-suited for this analysis due to its specific structural properties. The findings reveal that quantum effects are not merely marginal but essential for understanding key processes inside the capsid, providing new insights beyond the scope of classical physics.</abstract>
    </arXiv>

            </metadata>
        </record>

    </GetRecord>
</OAI-PMH>