<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<OAI-PMH xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" 
         xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance"
         xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/OAI-PMH.xsd">
    <responseDate>2026-07-13T06:25:24Z</responseDate>
                <request verb="GetRecord" identifier="oai:arXiv.org:2510.07378" metadataPrefix="arXiv">http://oaipmh.arxiv.org/oai</request>


    <GetRecord>
                <record>
                <header>
        <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:2510.07378</identifier>
        <datestamp>2025-10-10</datestamp>
            <setSpec>physics:astro-ph:EP</setSpec>
    </header>

            <metadata>
                        <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ https://oaipmh.arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
        <id>2510.07378</id>
        <created>2025-10-08</created>
            <updated>2025-10-10</updated>
        <authors>
                <author>
                    <keyname>Arora</keyname>
                        <forenames>R.</forenames>
                </author>
                <author>
                    <keyname>Ranjan</keyname>
                        <forenames>S.</forenames>
                </author>
                <author>
                    <keyname>Moitra</keyname>
                        <forenames>P.</forenames>
                </author>
                <author>
                    <keyname>Mallik</keyname>
                        <forenames>A.</forenames>
                </author>
        </authors>
        <title>Thin H$_2$-dominated Atmospheres as Signposts of Magmatic Outgassing on Tidally-Heated Terrestrial Exoplanets</title>
            <categories>astro-ph.EP</categories>
            <license>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0/</license>
            <abstract>H$_2$-dominated terrestrial exoplanets are highly accessible to atmospheric characterization via transmission spectroscopy, but such atmospheres are generally thought to be unstable to escape. Here, we propose that close-in, eccentric terrestrial exoplanets can sustain H$_2$-dominated atmospheres due to intense tidally-driven volcanic degassing. We develop an interior-atmosphere framework to assess whether volcanic outgassing can sustain \ch{H2}-dominated atmospheres over geologic timescales ($\geq$1 Gyr). We incorporate interior redox state, tidal heating, volatile inventory, and planetary parameters to compute outgassing fluxes and confront them with energy-limited hydrodynamic escape. We demonstrate that to sustain an H$_2$-dominated atmosphere, a terrestrial exoplanet must have a water-rich basal magma ocean and reduced melts, in addition to high eccentricity. We additionally demonstrate that detection of a specifically thin H$_2$-dominated atmosphere is a sign of current magmatic outgassing. We delineate an &#34;outgassing zone&#34; (OZ) most favorable to the existence of such planets, and identify the most observationally compelling targets. We propose combining precise mass-radius-eccentricity measurements with JWST constraints on atmospheric mean molecular mass $μ$ to search for thin H$_2$-dominated atmospheres. Inversely, we argue that robust atmospheric non-detections on OZ exoplanets can constrain the planetary interior, including melt redox state, mantle melt fraction and volatile inventory, and tidal heat flux.</abstract>
    </arXiv>

            </metadata>
        </record>

    </GetRecord>
</OAI-PMH>