<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<OAI-PMH xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" 
         xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance"
         xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/OAI-PMH.xsd">
    <responseDate>2026-07-13T06:24:12Z</responseDate>
                <request verb="GetRecord" identifier="oai:arXiv.org:2603.23473" metadataPrefix="arXiv">http://oaipmh.arxiv.org/oai</request>


    <GetRecord>
                <record>
                <header>
        <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:2603.23473</identifier>
        <datestamp>2026-03-25</datestamp>
            <setSpec>physics:astro-ph:CO</setSpec>
            <setSpec>physics:gr-qc</setSpec>
    </header>

            <metadata>
                        <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ https://oaipmh.arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
        <id>2603.23473</id>
        <created>2026-03-24</created>
            <updated>2026-03-25</updated>
        <authors>
                <author>
                    <keyname>Contaldi</keyname>
                        <forenames>Carlo R.</forenames>
                </author>
                <author>
                    <keyname>Pieroni</keyname>
                        <forenames>Mauro</forenames>
                </author>
        </authors>
        <title>Solving the Cosmic Coincidence Problem: The Locally Pumped Dark Energy Model</title>
            <categories>astro-ph.CO gr-qc</categories>
            <comments>18 pages, 6 figures, 3 appendices</comments>
            <report-no>Imperial/TP/2026/CC/1</report-no>
            <license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license>
            <abstract>We propose the Locally Pumped Dark Energy (LPDE) mechanism in which cosmic acceleration is triggered by the emergence of non-linear dark matter structure. In an effective-field-theory description, coarse-graining over the density contrast profile, whose short-wavelength modes grow during halo formation, induces a shift in the local equilibrium point of a second, sufficiently heavy scalar field $χ$. At early times, the pump mechanism is negligible and $χ$ remains fixed at the origin, contributing no DE. As structures form, the equilibrium value of $χ$ is locally displaced within halos, generating a vacuum energy whose global contribution, in a mean-field picture, is controlled by the halo volume filling factor. If the $χ$ field is sufficiently heavy, with a Compton wavelength limited by halo scales, its response is localised, and spatial gradients are exponentially suppressed on large scales. After volume-averaging over the halo population, the resulting contribution on large scales behaves as a homogeneous DE component. Using the halo mass function of a fiducial $Λ$CDM cosmology, we show that vacuum-energy domination generically emerges at $z\sim\mathcal{O}(1)$, naturally correlating cosmic acceleration with structure formation. For reference, we present an explicit realisation of such a mechanism and show that, by naturally featuring a transient acceleration epoch, it can be in excellent agreement with the most recent cosmological data, including the Dark Energy Spectroscopic Instrument (DESI).</abstract>
    </arXiv>

            </metadata>
        </record>

    </GetRecord>
</OAI-PMH>