<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<OAI-PMH xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" 
         xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance"
         xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/OAI-PMH.xsd">
    <responseDate>2026-07-13T10:04:52Z</responseDate>
                <request verb="GetRecord" identifier="oai:arXiv.org:2605.28932" metadataPrefix="arXiv">http://oaipmh.arxiv.org/oai</request>


    <GetRecord>
                <record>
                <header>
        <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:2605.28932</identifier>
        <datestamp>2026-06-16</datestamp>
            <setSpec>physics:gr-qc</setSpec>
            <setSpec>physics:math-ph</setSpec>
            <setSpec>math:math:MP</setSpec>
    </header>

            <metadata>
                        <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ https://oaipmh.arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
        <id>2605.28932</id>
        <created>2026-06-15</created>
            <updated>2026-06-16</updated>
        <authors>
                <author>
                    <keyname>Natário</keyname>
                        <forenames>José</forenames>
                </author>
                <author>
                    <keyname>Nazaré</keyname>
                        <forenames>Filipe</forenames>
                </author>
        </authors>
        <title>Relativistic Elastic Response to Gravitational Waves: Explicit Solutions for a Rectangular Plate</title>
            <categories>gr-qc math-ph math.MP</categories>
            <comments>17 pages, 2 figures; v2: minor corrections to section 6, main results unchanged</comments>
            <msc-class>35L05, 74K20, 83C35, 83C55</msc-class>
            <license>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0/</license>
            <abstract>We study the interaction between gravitational waves and elastic bodies within the framework of relativistic elasticity. Starting from the Lagrangian formulation of relativistic elasticity, we derive the linearized equations governing the response of a homogeneous and isotropic solid to a weak gravitational wave by expanding the action to quadratic order in the elastic field derivatives and to linear order in the metric perturbation. In this way, Dyson&#39;s interaction term from the effective potential approach emerges naturally from the relativistic theory.
  We then apply the formalism to a thin rectangular elastic plate aligned with the direction of propagation and polarization of a plus-polarized gravitational wave. For a material with vanishing Poisson ratio, the equations decouple and admit simple explicit solutions. We obtain closed-form expressions for the induced displacements and for the energy deposited on the plate by both short gravitational wave bursts and continuous harmonic waves. Finally, we compute the gravitational wave emission generated by the oscillating plate itself under continuous harmonic excitation. These results provide a fully relativistic derivation of the elastic response to gravitational waves together with explicit solvable examples relevant to resonant gravitational wave detectors.</abstract>
    </arXiv>

            </metadata>
        </record>

    </GetRecord>
</OAI-PMH>