<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<OAI-PMH xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" 
         xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance"
         xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/OAI-PMH.xsd">
    <responseDate>2026-07-13T06:22:29Z</responseDate>
                <request verb="GetRecord" identifier="oai:arXiv.org:2607.03552" metadataPrefix="arXiv">http://oaipmh.arxiv.org/oai</request>


    <GetRecord>
                <record>
                <header>
        <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:2607.03552</identifier>
        <datestamp>2026-07-07</datestamp>
            <setSpec>physics:quant-ph</setSpec>
    </header>

            <metadata>
                        <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ https://oaipmh.arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
        <id>2607.03552</id>
        <created>2026-07-03</created>
            <updated>2026-07-07</updated>
        <authors>
                <author>
                    <keyname>Ramos-Silva</keyname>
                        <forenames>Javier Noé</forenames>
                </author>
                <author>
                    <keyname>Noh</keyname>
                        <forenames>Sangjun</forenames>
                </author>
                <author>
                    <keyname>Jiang</keyname>
                        <forenames>Minghao</forenames>
                </author>
                <author>
                    <keyname>Aghaei</keyname>
                        <forenames>Parisa</forenames>
                </author>
                <author>
                    <keyname>Hazrathosseini</keyname>
                        <forenames>Ayla</forenames>
                </author>
                <author>
                    <keyname>Leon</keyname>
                        <forenames>Jocelyn</forenames>
                </author>
                <author>
                    <keyname>Hemmer</keyname>
                        <forenames>Philip</forenames>
                </author>
                <author>
                    <keyname>Burke</keyname>
                        <forenames>Peter J.</forenames>
                </author>
        </authors>
        <title>A Pulsed Live-Cell Quantum Microscope for Entangled Solid State and Biological Qubits</title>
            <categories>quant-ph</categories>
            <comments>27 pages, 17 figures in main text</comments>
            <license>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0/</license>
            <abstract>Two revolutions in quantum sensing are converging on the same microscope stage. Biological qubits have emerged as genetically encoded, optically addressable quantum systems inside live cells. Solid state spin based qubits have been entangled and used as nanoscale correlator magnetometers, delivering sensitivity and spatial-resolution gains that single-spin probes cannot reach. Here we report a pulsed quantum microscope that enables simultaneous quantum state manipulation of both qubit technologies in live cells. The platform combines nanosecond-gated optical excitation at 450 nm and 520 nm, three-dimensional diffraction-limited addressing by galvo beam scanning and piezo objective focus, rapidly switched static and radio-frequency magnetic fields, single-photon timing with picosecond resolution, and microwave control for frequencies from DC to 5 GHz, including the 2.87 GHz resonance of solid state spins, the 500 MHz to 800 MHz resonance of radical pairs in biological qubits, and any future qubit resonance in the GHz range. Live cell imaging with simultaneous biological and solid state nanoparticle qubits in the same cell demonstrates the power of this technique for multiplexed quantum sensing. We anticipate this approach will open new opportunities for researchers to explore quantum sensing in live cells, and, ultimately, entanglement between a solid-state qubit and a protein-hosted spin qubit.</abstract>
    </arXiv>

            </metadata>
        </record>

    </GetRecord>
</OAI-PMH>