<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<OAI-PMH xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" 
         xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance"
         xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/OAI-PMH.xsd">
    <responseDate>2026-07-13T06:21:06Z</responseDate>
                <request verb="GetRecord" identifier="oai:arXiv.org:2508.19217" metadataPrefix="arXiv">http://oaipmh.arxiv.org/oai</request>


    <GetRecord>
                <record>
                <header>
        <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:2508.19217</identifier>
        <datestamp>2026-05-26</datestamp>
            <setSpec>physics:astro-ph:CO</setSpec>
            <setSpec>physics:hep-ph</setSpec>
    </header>

            <metadata>
                        <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ https://oaipmh.arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
        <id>2508.19217</id>
        <created>2026-05-25</created>
            <updated>2026-05-26</updated>
        <authors>
                <author>
                    <keyname>Maiti</keyname>
                        <forenames>Subhasis</forenames>
                </author>
                <author>
                    <keyname>Maity</keyname>
                        <forenames>Debaprasad</forenames>
                </author>
        </authors>
        <title>The Magnetic Origin of Primordial Black Holes: A Viable Dark Matter Scenario</title>
            <categories>astro-ph.CO hep-ph</categories>
            <comments>Citations added; updated to match the journal version</comments>
            <journal-ref>JCAP 04 (2026) 020</journal-ref>
            <license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license>
            <abstract>Primordial Black Holes (PBHs) are compelling candidates for explaining the present-day relic abundance of cold dark matter (CDM), yet their formation typically requires finely tuned early-universe dynamics. In this work, we propose a novel PBH formation mechanism within a well-established magnetogenesis framework. This scenario simultaneously accounts for the large-scale magnetic fields observed today and generates an enhanced curvature power spectrum at intermediate scales, leading to PBH formation with masses that can survive until the present epoch. We identify a narrow reheating temperature range, $10^5\,\mathrm{GeV} \leq T_{re} \leq 3\times 10^5\,\mathrm{GeV}$, within which the resulting PBHs can constitute the entirety of the observed CDM abundance. Furthermore, our model predicts a stochastic gravitational wave (GW) background as a byproduct of the PBH formation process. Remarkably, the predicted GW signal lies within the sensitivity reach of upcoming space-based interferometers, such as the LISA, DECIGO, or SKA mission, offering a direct observational probe of this PBH generation mechanism.</abstract>
    </arXiv>

            </metadata>
        </record>

    </GetRecord>
</OAI-PMH>