<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<OAI-PMH xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" 
         xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance"
         xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/OAI-PMH.xsd">
    <responseDate>2026-07-13T06:25:56Z</responseDate>
                <request verb="GetRecord" identifier="oai:arXiv.org:2512.24878" metadataPrefix="arXiv">http://oaipmh.arxiv.org/oai</request>


    <GetRecord>
                <record>
                <header>
        <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:2512.24878</identifier>
        <datestamp>2026-01-01</datestamp>
            <setSpec>physics:quant-ph</setSpec>
            <setSpec>physics:physics:ins-det</setSpec>
            <setSpec>physics:physics:optics</setSpec>
    </header>

            <metadata>
                        <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ https://oaipmh.arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
        <id>2512.24878</id>
        <created>2025-12-31</created>
            <updated>2026-01-01</updated>
        <authors>
                <author>
                    <keyname>McFadden</keyname>
                        <forenames>David</forenames>
                </author>
                <author>
                    <keyname>Heintzmann</keyname>
                        <forenames>Rainer</forenames>
                </author>
        </authors>
        <title>Image-Plane Detection of Spatially Entangled Photon Pairs with a CMOS Camera</title>
            <categories>quant-ph physics.ins-det physics.optics</categories>
            <comments>10 pages, 3 figures</comments>
            <license>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0/</license>
            <abstract>Spatially entangled photon pairs (biphotons) generated by spontaneous parametric down-conversion offer unique opportunities for quantum imaging, but image-plane biphoton correlations are difficult to observe with camera-based detectors. Previous camera-based biphoton imaging experiments have relied on photon-counting detection, which necessitates operation deep in the photon-sparse regime and requires extremely low dark rates.
  Here, we demonstrate the detection of spatial biphoton joint probability distributions in both the image plane and the pupil plane (also termed &#34;near-field plane&#34; and &#34;far-field plane&#34; respectively) using a conventional scientific CMOS camera operated in linear mode. We work at mesoscopic intensity levels, corresponding to a photon flux approximately four orders of magnitude higher than typical photon-counting approaches. From the measured image- and pupil plane correlations, we observe position and momentum correlations consistent with an EPR-type entanglement witness.
  A tailored correlation analysis suited for image plane imaging suppresses detector artifacts and intensity fluctuations, enabling acquisition with significantly fewer frames. Our results demonstrate that spatially entangled-light imaging can be performed efficiently with standard imaging hardware, extending quantum imaging techniques beyond the photon-counting regime.</abstract>
    </arXiv>

            </metadata>
        </record>

    </GetRecord>
</OAI-PMH>