<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<OAI-PMH xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" 
         xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance"
         xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/OAI-PMH.xsd">
    <responseDate>2026-07-13T21:13:34Z</responseDate>
                <request verb="GetRecord" identifier="oai:arXiv.org:2408.08428" metadataPrefix="arXiv">http://oaipmh.arxiv.org/oai</request>


    <GetRecord>
                <record>
                <header>
        <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:2408.08428</identifier>
        <datestamp>2024-08-19</datestamp>
            <setSpec>physics:physics:app-ph</setSpec>
            <setSpec>cs:cs:LG</setSpec>
    </header>

            <metadata>
                        <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ https://oaipmh.arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
        <id>2408.08428</id>
        <created>2024-08-15</created>
            <updated>2024-08-19</updated>
        <authors>
                <author>
                    <keyname>Bastawrous</keyname>
                        <forenames>Mary V.</forenames>
                </author>
                <author>
                    <keyname>Chen</keyname>
                        <forenames>Zhi</forenames>
                </author>
                <author>
                    <keyname>Ogren</keyname>
                        <forenames>Alexander C.</forenames>
                </author>
                <author>
                    <keyname>Daraio</keyname>
                        <forenames>Chiara</forenames>
                </author>
                <author>
                    <keyname>Rudin</keyname>
                        <forenames>Cynthia</forenames>
                </author>
                <author>
                    <keyname>Brinson</keyname>
                        <forenames>L. Catherine</forenames>
                </author>
        </authors>
        <title>Phononic materials with effectively scale-separated hierarchical features using interpretable machine learning</title>
            <categories>physics.app-ph cs.LG</categories>
            <license>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-sa/4.0/</license>
            <abstract>Manipulating the dispersive characteristics of vibrational waves is beneficial for many applications, e.g., high-precision instruments. architected hierarchical phononic materials have sparked promise tunability of elastodynamic waves and vibrations over multiple frequency ranges. In this article, hierarchical unit-cells are obtained, where features at each length scale result in a band gap within a targeted frequency range. Our novel approach, the ``hierarchical unit-cell template method,&#39;&#39; is an interpretable machine-learning approach that uncovers global unit-cell shape/topology patterns corresponding to predefined band-gap objectives. A scale-separation effect is observed where the coarse-scale band-gap objective is mostly unaffected by the fine-scale features despite the closeness of their length scales, thus enabling an efficient hierarchical algorithm. Moreover, the hierarchical patterns revealed are not predefined or self-similar hierarchies as common in current hierarchical phononic materials. Thus, our approach offers a flexible and efficient method for the exploration of new regions in the hierarchical design space, extracting minimal effective patterns for inverse design in applications targeting multiple frequency ranges.</abstract>
    </arXiv>

            </metadata>
        </record>

    </GetRecord>
</OAI-PMH>