<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<OAI-PMH xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" 
         xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance"
         xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/OAI-PMH.xsd">
    <responseDate>2026-07-13T06:22:01Z</responseDate>
                <request verb="GetRecord" identifier="oai:arXiv.org:2603.22253" metadataPrefix="arXiv">http://oaipmh.arxiv.org/oai</request>


    <GetRecord>
                <record>
                <header>
        <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:2603.22253</identifier>
        <datestamp>2026-03-24</datestamp>
            <setSpec>physics:quant-ph</setSpec>
            <setSpec>physics:physics:app-ph</setSpec>
            <setSpec>physics:physics:ins-det</setSpec>
            <setSpec>physics:physics:optics</setSpec>
    </header>

            <metadata>
                        <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ https://oaipmh.arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
        <id>2603.22253</id>
        <created>2026-03-23</created>
            <updated>2026-03-24</updated>
        <authors>
                <author>
                    <keyname>Sherwani</keyname>
                        <forenames>Atta Ur Rehman</forenames>
                </author>
                <author>
                    <keyname>Pearce</keyname>
                        <forenames>Emma</forenames>
                </author>
                <author>
                    <keyname>Hildenstein</keyname>
                        <forenames>Philipp</forenames>
                </author>
                <author>
                    <keyname>Mauerhoff</keyname>
                        <forenames>Felix</forenames>
                </author>
                <author>
                    <keyname>Sahm</keyname>
                        <forenames>Alexander</forenames>
                </author>
                <author>
                    <keyname>Paschke</keyname>
                        <forenames>Katrin</forenames>
                </author>
                <author>
                    <keyname>Chrzanowski</keyname>
                        <forenames>Helen M.</forenames>
                </author>
                <author>
                    <keyname>Ramelow</keyname>
                        <forenames>Sven</forenames>
                </author>
        </authors>
        <title>Polymer identification via undetected photons using a low footprint nonlinear interferometer</title>
            <categories>quant-ph physics.app-ph physics.ins-det physics.optics</categories>
            <comments>11 pages, 9 figures</comments>
            <license>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0/</license>
            <abstract>Plastic pollution has become a critical global challenge, with microplastics pervading ecosystems and entering human food chains. Effectively monitoring this widespread contamination demands rapid, reliable, and portable material identification techniques that often elude conventional Raman and FTIR spectroscopy. Undetected photon spectroscopy within a nonlinear interferometer (NLI) offers a solution, allowing the retrieval of mid-infrared absorption spectra by detecting only near-infrared signal photons using standard silicon-based technology. Here, we demonstrate a highly compact, micro-integrated, thermally-stabilised NLI with a Michelson-like geometry designed for the rapid spectroscopy of plastics. We benchmarked its room-temperature performance, demonstrating a signal-to-noise ratio of 34 with a measurement rate of 100 Hz and a spectral resolution of 6 cm$^{-1}$. We show that we can accurately and rapidly retrieve the characteristic vibrational absorption spectra of common polymers such as polypropylene, polyethene, and polystyrene, without using mid-infrared technology. These results establish our compact module as a promising field-deployable platform for robust, real-time environmental monitoring systems and other mid-infrared spectroscopy applications.</abstract>
    </arXiv>

            </metadata>
        </record>

    </GetRecord>
</OAI-PMH>