<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<OAI-PMH xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" 
         xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance"
         xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/OAI-PMH.xsd">
    <responseDate>2026-07-13T21:13:18Z</responseDate>
                <request verb="GetRecord" identifier="oai:arXiv.org:2511.18407" metadataPrefix="arXiv">http://oaipmh.arxiv.org/oai</request>


    <GetRecord>
                <record>
                <header>
        <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:2511.18407</identifier>
        <datestamp>2025-11-25</datestamp>
            <setSpec>physics:hep-th</setSpec>
    </header>

            <metadata>
                        <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ https://oaipmh.arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
        <id>2511.18407</id>
        <created>2025-11-23</created>
            <updated>2025-11-25</updated>
        <authors>
                <author>
                    <keyname>Belhaj</keyname>
                        <forenames>Adil</forenames>
                </author>
                <author>
                    <keyname>Jemri</keyname>
                        <forenames>Maryem</forenames>
                </author>
        </authors>
        <title>On Thermodynamics of Charged Black Holes via Extended Space-time Derivatives</title>
            <categories>hep-th</categories>
            <comments>22 pages, 7 figures, Latex. Authors are listed in alphabetical order, Accepted for publication in International Journal of Modern Physics A (2025)</comments>
            <license>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0/</license>
            <abstract>Inspired by non-commutative geometry in string theory, we propose extended derivatives in black hole physics by incorporating a real antisymmetric tensor of rank 2 carrying similarities of certain stringy fields. Using gauge theory formulation of gravity via de Sitter group theory, we first find the associated black hole solutions by solving the Einstein field equations. Then, we study the thermodynamic properties by approaching the stability analysis, the criticality, and the phase transitions. Concretely, we investigate the P-V criticality behavior of the obtained solution. We compute and examine the Gibbs free energy revealing comparable attitudes with the Van der Waals phase transitions. Combining such results, we provide constraints on the deformed parameter B and the charge Q with the help of CUDA numerical methods exploited in machine learning computations. Precisely, we show that there are suitable ranges for such parameters where the obtained black holes behave like the Van der Waals fluid systems.</abstract>
    </arXiv>

            </metadata>
        </record>

    </GetRecord>
</OAI-PMH>