<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<OAI-PMH xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" 
         xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance"
         xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/OAI-PMH.xsd">
    <responseDate>2026-07-13T06:27:28Z</responseDate>
                <request verb="GetRecord" identifier="oai:arXiv.org:2606.23045" metadataPrefix="arXiv">http://oaipmh.arxiv.org/oai</request>


    <GetRecord>
                <record>
                <header>
        <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:2606.23045</identifier>
        <datestamp>2026-06-23</datestamp>
            <setSpec>physics:quant-ph</setSpec>
    </header>

            <metadata>
                        <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ https://oaipmh.arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
        <id>2606.23045</id>
        <created>2026-06-22</created>
            <updated>2026-06-23</updated>
        <authors>
                <author>
                    <keyname>Nowak</keyname>
                        <forenames>Michel</forenames>
                </author>
                <author>
                    <keyname>Marchand</keyname>
                        <forenames>Benjamin</forenames>
                </author>
                <author>
                    <keyname>Naghmouchi</keyname>
                        <forenames>Yassine</forenames>
                </author>
                <author>
                    <keyname>Rainjonneau</keyname>
                        <forenames>Serge</forenames>
                </author>
                <author>
                    <keyname>Coelho</keyname>
                        <forenames>Wesley</forenames>
                </author>
                <author>
                    <keyname>Vignoli</keyname>
                        <forenames>Louis</forenames>
                </author>
                <author>
                    <keyname>Henry</keyname>
                        <forenames>Louis-Paul</forenames>
                </author>
        </authors>
        <title>Satellite Mission Planning with Rydberg Atoms</title>
            <categories>quant-ph</categories>
            <license>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0/</license>
            <abstract>Quantum computers relying on cold atoms are being built and promise a high flexibility in the way information in encoded into the physical system. In particular, the analog mode is spiking interest in the field of optimization as a classically intractable number of configurations can be tackled. In this work, we investigate a problem that requires every-day scheduling of critical tasks involving a large number of actors. Namely, fixing the planning for a Earth Observation satellite fleet composed of several of units exposed to a high density of targets to be scanned. We explore numerical schemes that convert the formulated problem into a cold-atoms friendly setup. We begin by a naive formulation of the Satellite Mission Planning problem without taking account for the agility of the satellites. We then extend the problem to take it into account based on the literature. By formulating the planning problem as a Maximum Independent Set problem, we are able to solve the problem with a QPU based on Rydberg atoms. We explore two ways of solving the MIS problem on the QPU, one relying on the graphs and on the Quadratic Unconstrained Binary Optimization Framework (QUBO). We show that the QUBO methodology is the most relevant and explore it more deeply with numerical experiments. We conclude on the potential utility of using a QPU to solve the Satellite Mission Planning problem in an operational context.</abstract>
    </arXiv>

            </metadata>
        </record>

    </GetRecord>
</OAI-PMH>