<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<OAI-PMH xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" 
         xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance"
         xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/OAI-PMH.xsd">
    <responseDate>2026-07-13T06:26:32Z</responseDate>
                <request verb="GetRecord" identifier="oai:arXiv.org:2603.07639" metadataPrefix="arXiv">http://oaipmh.arxiv.org/oai</request>


    <GetRecord>
                <record>
                <header>
        <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:2603.07639</identifier>
        <datestamp>2026-03-10</datestamp>
            <setSpec>physics:quant-ph</setSpec>
            <setSpec>physics:cond-mat:stat-mech</setSpec>
            <setSpec>physics:hep-th</setSpec>
    </header>

            <metadata>
                        <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ https://oaipmh.arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
        <id>2603.07639</id>
        <created>2026-03-08</created>
            <updated>2026-03-10</updated>
        <authors>
                <author>
                    <keyname>Wang</keyname>
                        <forenames>Zuo</forenames>
                </author>
                <author>
                    <keyname>He</keyname>
                        <forenames>Liang</forenames>
                </author>
        </authors>
        <title>Black-Hole Signatures in the Finite-Temperature Critical Ising Chain</title>
            <categories>quant-ph cond-mat.stat-mech hep-th</categories>
            <comments>4 pages, 3 figures</comments>
            <license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license>
            <abstract>We demonstrate that the finite-temperature critical transverse-field Ising chain exhibits quantitative signatures of black-hole physics in its dual gravitational description within the AdS/CFT correspondence. Its finite-temperature dynamics and thermodynamics are consistently captured by a mixed thermal-AdS/BTZ black hole saddle, leading to three mutually compatible observations. First, antipodal excitation transport collapses onto a universal temperature-dependent curve determined by the relative AdS and BTZ contributions to the gravitational partition function, reflecting horizon absorption. Second, in the high-temperature regime, the retarded response exhibits exponential relaxation governed by the lowest quasi-normal mode of the dual black hole. Third, the temperature derivative of the von Neumann entropy develops a pronounced minimum at a temperature consistent with the Hawking-Page transition. These results identify critical quantum spin chains as minimal and experimentally accessible platforms for probing dynamical and thermodynamic aspects of quantum black holes in controllable many-body systems.</abstract>
    </arXiv>

            </metadata>
        </record>

    </GetRecord>
</OAI-PMH>