<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<OAI-PMH xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" 
         xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance"
         xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/OAI-PMH.xsd">
    <responseDate>2026-07-12T22:39:17Z</responseDate>
                <request verb="GetRecord" identifier="oai:arXiv.org:2605.09426v1" metadataPrefix="arXiv">http://oaipmh.arxiv.org/oai</request>


    <GetRecord>
                <record>
                <header>
        <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:2605.09426</identifier>
        <datestamp>2026-05-12</datestamp>
            <setSpec>physics:gr-qc</setSpec>
    </header>

            <metadata>
                        <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ https://oaipmh.arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
        <id>2605.09426</id>
        <created>2026-05-10</created>
            <updated>2026-05-12</updated>
        <authors>
                <author>
                    <keyname>Karmakar</keyname>
                        <forenames>Rajesh</forenames>
                </author>
                <author>
                    <keyname>Lee</keyname>
                        <forenames>Bum-Hoon</forenames>
                </author>
                <author>
                    <keyname>Lee</keyname>
                        <forenames>Wonwoo</forenames>
                </author>
        </authors>
        <title>Resonant transmission of scalar waves through rotating traversable wormhole</title>
            <categories>gr-qc</categories>
            <comments>11 pages, 8 figures</comments>
            <license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license>
            <abstract>The viability of traversable wormholes as exotic compact objects requires the identification of signatures that distinguish them from other compact objects. Given recent advances in observing rotating black hole signatures, identifying characteristic imprints that reflect the absence of an event horizon and the presence of a throat structure is of considerable significance. Motivated by this, in the present work, we analyze the propagation of a massless scalar field in a rotating traversable wormhole spacetime described by Teo&#39;s class of solutions. We numerically compute the transmission (greybody) factor and the corresponding absorption spectrum across a broad range of frequencies. The spectrum exhibits a series of sharp peaks in the amplitudes, which we identify as Breit-Wigner-type resonances. The emergence of such peaks can be attributed to the scalar modes temporarily trapped within the potential well formed by barriers on either side of the throat. These resonant features, previously identified in static wormhole backgrounds, persist in the rotating case. In particular, for Teo&#39;s class of wormholes, we find that rotation enhances the strength of the resonances. Overall, our results demonstrate the role of rotation in shaping the resonance effect and indicate these features as characteristic signatures of wormhole geometries.</abstract>
    </arXiv>

            </metadata>
        </record>

    </GetRecord>
</OAI-PMH>