<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<OAI-PMH xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" 
         xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance"
         xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/OAI-PMH.xsd">
    <responseDate>2026-07-13T06:24:54Z</responseDate>
                <request verb="GetRecord" identifier="oai:arXiv.org:2606.06653" metadataPrefix="arXiv">http://oaipmh.arxiv.org/oai</request>


    <GetRecord>
                <record>
                <header>
        <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:2606.06653</identifier>
        <datestamp>2026-06-08</datestamp>
            <setSpec>physics:quant-ph</setSpec>
            <setSpec>physics:cond-mat:stat-mech</setSpec>
    </header>

            <metadata>
                        <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ https://oaipmh.arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
        <id>2606.06653</id>
        <created>2026-06-04</created>
            <updated>2026-06-08</updated>
        <authors>
                <author>
                    <keyname>Aditya</keyname>
                        <forenames>Sreemayee</forenames>
                </author>
                <author>
                    <keyname>Murciano</keyname>
                        <forenames>Sara</forenames>
                </author>
                <author>
                    <keyname>Turkeshi</keyname>
                        <forenames>Xhek</forenames>
                </author>
        </authors>
        <title>Higher-order Symmetric Quantum Mpemba Effect in Fragmented Systems</title>
            <categories>quant-ph cond-mat.stat-mech</categories>
            <comments>31 Pages, 12 Figures</comments>
            <license>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0/</license>
            <abstract>A quantum system can restore a broken symmetry faster the more strongly it initially breaks it, an anomaly known as the quantum Mpemba effect. Whether this effect survives once conservation laws fragment the Hilbert space into exponentially many disconnected Krylov sectors has remained open. We address this question for circuits and Hamiltonians with simultaneous charge and dipole conservation, the paradigmatic setting for strong Hilbert-space fragmentation. Combining a replica tensor-network formulation for charge and dipole-conserving gates, which reaches the annealed Rényi-2 entanglement asymmetry up to $L=128$, with Hamiltonian simulations and an exactly solvable dissipative model, we uncover a higher-order symmetric quantum Mpemba effect: the charge and dipole asymmetries each display Mpemba-like crossings on parametrically distinct timescales. Resolving the state into frozen and active Krylov sectors reveals the mechanism: frozen fragments retain a finite asymmetry that obstructs full restoration, while active fragments host the relaxation responsible for the crossings. Fragmentation thus does not preclude the quantum Mpemba effect but reshapes it into frozen memory and active-fragment relaxation, providing a framework for the Mpemba phenomenology of higher-moment symmetries.</abstract>
    </arXiv>

            </metadata>
        </record>

    </GetRecord>
</OAI-PMH>