<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<OAI-PMH xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" 
         xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance"
         xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/OAI-PMH.xsd">
    <responseDate>2026-07-13T06:22:10Z</responseDate>
                <request verb="GetRecord" identifier="oai:arXiv.org:2604.10090" metadataPrefix="arXiv">http://oaipmh.arxiv.org/oai</request>


    <GetRecord>
                <record>
                <header>
        <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:2604.10090</identifier>
        <datestamp>2026-05-26</datestamp>
            <setSpec>physics:hep-th</setSpec>
            <setSpec>physics:quant-ph</setSpec>
    </header>

            <metadata>
                        <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ https://oaipmh.arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
        <id>2604.10090</id>
        <created>2026-05-24</created>
            <updated>2026-05-26</updated>
        <authors>
                <author>
                    <keyname>Byun</keyname>
                        <forenames>Moongul</forenames>
                </author>
                <author>
                    <keyname>Kim</keyname>
                        <forenames>Keun-Young</forenames>
                </author>
                <author>
                    <keyname>Lee</keyname>
                        <forenames>Hyeonsoo</forenames>
                </author>
        </authors>
        <title>Quantum simulation of traversable-wormhole-inspired quantum teleportation in a chaotic binary sparse SYK model</title>
            <categories>hep-th quant-ph</categories>
            <comments>8 pages, 7 figures; 9 pages Supplemental Material, 6 supplemental figures; data updated and typos corrected</comments>
            <license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license>
            <abstract>We report the experimental observation of holographically motivated quantum teleportation on a quantum processor, driven by the highly entangled, chaotic dynamics of a many-body system. Specifically, we implement the traversable-wormhole (TW) protocol utilizing a \textit{chaotic} binary sparse $N = 8$ Sachdev--Ye--Kitaev (SYK) model. This optimized approach dramatically reduces circuit depth for noisy intermediate-scale quantum (NISQ) hardware while rigorously preserving the spectral chaos required for gravitational duality. Diagnosing the teleportation signal via mutual information, we find that while inherent noise in NISQ hardware precludes perfect quantitative agreement with exact numerical simulations, our experimental results clearly demonstrate the essential qualitative signature: a sign-dependent asymmetry. This work establishes a practical, scalable framework for holographic quantum simulations, offering a novel empirical testbed for exploring holographic quantum gravity.</abstract>
    </arXiv>

            </metadata>
        </record>

    </GetRecord>
</OAI-PMH>