<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<OAI-PMH xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" 
         xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance"
         xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/OAI-PMH.xsd">
    <responseDate>2026-07-13T21:14:15Z</responseDate>
                <request verb="GetRecord" identifier="oai:arXiv.org:2501.04739" metadataPrefix="arXiv">http://oaipmh.arxiv.org/oai</request>


    <GetRecord>
                <record>
                <header>
        <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:2501.04739</identifier>
        <datestamp>2025-04-01</datestamp>
            <setSpec>physics:gr-qc</setSpec>
            <setSpec>physics:hep-th</setSpec>
    </header>

            <metadata>
                        <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ https://oaipmh.arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
        <id>2501.04739</id>
        <created>2025-03-15</created>
            <updated>2025-04-01</updated>
        <authors>
                <author>
                    <keyname>Rizwan</keyname>
                        <forenames>Muhammad</forenames>
                </author>
                <author>
                    <keyname>Jamil</keyname>
                        <forenames>Mubasher</forenames>
                </author>
                <author>
                    <keyname>Moughal</keyname>
                        <forenames>M. Z. A.</forenames>
                </author>
        </authors>
        <title>Universal thermodynamic topological classes of black holes in perfect fluid dark matter background</title>
            <categories>gr-qc hep-th</categories>
            <comments>10 pages, 11 figures, minor revision, accepted for publication in Eur. Phys. J. C</comments>
            <journal-ref>Eur. Phys. J. C (2025) 85:359</journal-ref>
            <doi>10.1140/epjc/s10052-025-14070-8</doi>
            <license>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0/</license>
            <abstract>In this paper, we study the universal thermodynamic topological classes of a family of black holes in a perfect fluid dark matter (PFDM) background. Recent research on black hole thermodynamics suggests that all black holes can be classified into four universal thermodynamic classes, denoted by $W^{1-}$, $W^{0+}$, $W^{0-}$, and $W^{1+}$. Our study reveals that the Schwarzschild black hole in PFDM belongs to the $W^{1-}$ class, and independence of black hole size thermodynamically unstable at both low- and high-temperature limits. The Reissner-Nordström, Kerr, and Kerr-Newman black holes in the PFDM background belong to the same universal thermodynamic class, $W^{0+}$, which represents small, stable black holes and large, unstable black holes at low-temperature limits, whereas no black hole state exists at high temperatures. The AdS black holes behave differently compared to their counterparts in PFDM. The Schwarzschild-AdS black hole belongs to the $W^{0-}$ class, indicating no black hole state at low temperatures, but small, unstable and large, stable black hole states at high temperatures. Furthermore, the Kerr-AdS black hole belongs to the $W^{1+}$ class, characterized by small, stable black holes at low temperatures, large, stable black holes at high temperatures, and unstable, intermediate-sized black holes at both low and high temperatures. These findings uncover the universal topological classifications underlying black hole thermodynamics, offering profound insights into the fundamental principles of quantum gravity.</abstract>
    </arXiv>

            </metadata>
        </record>

    </GetRecord>
</OAI-PMH>