<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<OAI-PMH xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" 
         xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance"
         xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/OAI-PMH.xsd">
    <responseDate>2026-07-11T21:46:07Z</responseDate>
                <request verb="GetRecord" identifier="oai:arXiv.org:2601.05935v2" metadataPrefix="arXiv">http://oaipmh.arxiv.org/oai</request>


    <GetRecord>
                <record>
                <header>
        <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:2601.05935</identifier>
        <datestamp>2026-03-19</datestamp>
            <setSpec>physics:hep-ph</setSpec>
            <setSpec>physics:astro-ph:CO</setSpec>
            <setSpec>physics:astro-ph:HE</setSpec>
            <setSpec>physics:nucl-th</setSpec>
    </header>

            <metadata>
                        <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ https://oaipmh.arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
        <id>2601.05935</id>
        <created>2026-02-20</created>
            <updated>2026-03-19</updated>
        <authors>
                <author>
                    <keyname>Klipfel</keyname>
                        <forenames>Alexandra P.</forenames>
                </author>
                <author>
                    <keyname>Kaiser</keyname>
                        <forenames>David I.</forenames>
                </author>
        </authors>
        <title>Gravitational Ionization by Schwarzschild Primordial Black Holes</title>
            <categories>hep-ph astro-ph.CO astro-ph.HE nucl-th</categories>
            <comments>20 pp. 10 figures. References added to match published version in Physical Review D</comments>
            <report-no>MIT-CTP Preprint 5976</report-no>
            <journal-ref>Physical Review D 113 (2026): 063031</journal-ref>
            <doi>10.1103/4p67-rxhp</doi>
            <license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license>
            <abstract>Primordial black holes (PBHs) are theorized to form from the collapse of overdensities in the very early Universe. PBHs in the asteroid-mass range $10^{17} \, {\rm g}\lesssim M \lesssim 10^{23} \, {\rm g}$ could serve as all or most of the dark matter today, but are particularly difficult to detect due to their modest rates of Hawking emission and sub-micron Schwarzschild radii. We consider whether the steep gradients of a PBH&#39;s gravitational field could generate tidal forces strong enough to disrupt atoms and nuclei. Such phenomena may yield new observables that could uniquely distinguish a PBH from a macroscopic object of the same mass. We first consider the gravitational ionization of ambient neutral hydrogen and evaluate prospects for detecting photon radiation from the recombination of ionized atoms. During the present epoch, this effect would be swamped by Hawking radiation -- which would itself be difficult to detect for PBHs at the upper end of the asteroid-mass window. We then consider the gravitational ionization and heating of neutral hydrogen immediately following recombination at $z\simeq1090$, and identify a broad class of PBH distributions with typical mass $5\times10^{21}\,{\rm g}\lesssim M \lesssim 10^{23}\, {\rm g}$ within which gravitational interactions would have been the dominant form of energy deposition to the medium. We also identify conditions under which tidal forces from a transiting PBH could overcome the strong nuclear force, either by dissociating deuterons, which would be relevant during big bang nucleosynthesis (BBN), or by inducing fission of heavy nuclei. We find that gravitational dissociation of deuterons dominates photodissociation rates due to Hawking radiation for PBHs with masses $10^{14}\,{\rm g}\lesssim M \lesssim 10^{16}\,{\rm g}$. We additionally identify the phenomenon of gravitationally induced fission of heavy nuclei via tidal deformation.</abstract>
    </arXiv>

            </metadata>
        </record>

    </GetRecord>
</OAI-PMH>