<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<OAI-PMH xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" 
         xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance"
         xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/OAI-PMH.xsd">
    <responseDate>2026-07-11T22:35:31Z</responseDate>
                <request verb="GetRecord" identifier="oai:arXiv.org:2601.08923v1" metadataPrefix="arXiv">http://oaipmh.arxiv.org/oai</request>


    <GetRecord>
                <record>
                <header>
        <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:2601.08923</identifier>
        <datestamp>2026-01-15</datestamp>
            <setSpec>physics:astro-ph:EP</setSpec>
    </header>

            <metadata>
                        <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ https://oaipmh.arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
        <id>2601.08923</id>
        <created>2026-01-13</created>
            <updated>2026-01-15</updated>
        <authors>
                <author>
                    <keyname>Fenucci</keyname>
                        <forenames>M.</forenames>
                </author>
                <author>
                    <keyname>Novaković</keyname>
                        <forenames>B.</forenames>
                </author>
                <author>
                    <keyname>Granvik</keyname>
                        <forenames>M.</forenames>
                </author>
                <author>
                    <keyname>Zhang</keyname>
                        <forenames>P.</forenames>
                </author>
        </authors>
        <title>Origin of asteroid (469219) Kamo`oalewa: the main asteroid belt or the Giordano Bruno crater on the Moon?</title>
            <categories>astro-ph.EP</categories>
            <comments>Accepted for publication on A&amp;A</comments>
            <license>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0/</license>
            <abstract>Asteroid Kamo`oalewa is the target of the Tianwen-2 sample-return mission by CNSA. Because of its orbit and its spectral properties, it was proposed that Kamo`oalewa originated from the Moon as impact ejecta, possibly from the Giordano Bruno crater. We aim at estimating the relative contribution of Kamo`oalewa-like objects originating from the general near-Earth asteroid (NEA) population which originated in the main asteroid belt, and compare it with the relative contribution of Giordano Bruno ejecta. We first estimate the average fraction of quasi-satellite orbits at any given time. By using recently developed NEA population models, we extract the expected number of Earth co-orbitals of the same size of Kamo`oalewa, and then get an estimate of the average number of Kamo`oalewa-like objects using the fraction computed before. Similarly, we obtain an estimate for the number of Kamo`oalewa-like objects that may originate as ejecta from the Giordano Bruno impact. We also performed survey simulations to estimate their efficiency in the detection of Kamo`oalewa-like objects. We found that the main belt accounts for 1.23 \pm 0.13 Kamo`oalewa-like objects on average. The expected number of Kamo`oalewa-like objects originated as Giordano Bruno ejecta is 0.042, which is more than order of magnitude smaller. We found a discovery efficiency of Earth quasi-satellites between 95% and 70% for absolute magnitude between 22 and 25 for the Pan-STARRS survey, and population models show that this is in agreement with the known population. The Vera Rubin Observatory should reach an efficiency of 92% down to absolute magnitude 25. These estimates show that population models of NEAs are capable to account for Kamo`oalewa-like objects, thus supporting the hypothesis that that Kamo&#39;oalewa originated from the main belt. This will be further investigated by the in-situ exploration of the Tianwen-2 mission.</abstract>
    </arXiv>

            </metadata>
        </record>

    </GetRecord>
</OAI-PMH>