<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<OAI-PMH xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" 
         xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance"
         xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/OAI-PMH.xsd">
    <responseDate>2026-07-13T06:24:01Z</responseDate>
                <request verb="GetRecord" identifier="oai:arXiv.org:2603.13137" metadataPrefix="arXiv">http://oaipmh.arxiv.org/oai</request>


    <GetRecord>
                <record>
                <header>
        <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:2603.13137</identifier>
        <datestamp>2026-03-16</datestamp>
            <setSpec>physics:astro-ph:CO</setSpec>
    </header>

            <metadata>
                        <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ https://oaipmh.arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
        <id>2603.13137</id>
        <created>2026-03-13</created>
            <updated>2026-03-16</updated>
        <authors>
                <author>
                    <keyname>Najafi</keyname>
                        <forenames>Mahdi</forenames>
                </author>
                <author>
                    <keyname>Habibollahi</keyname>
                        <forenames>Mahdi</forenames>
                </author>
                <author>
                    <keyname>Reyhani</keyname>
                        <forenames>Masoume</forenames>
                </author>
                <author>
                    <keyname>Di Valentino</keyname>
                        <forenames>Eleonora</forenames>
                </author>
                <author>
                    <keyname>Pan</keyname>
                        <forenames>Supriya</forenames>
                </author>
                <author>
                    <keyname>Firouzjaee</keyname>
                        <forenames>Javad T.</forenames>
                </author>
                <author>
                    <keyname>Yang</keyname>
                        <forenames>Weiqiang</forenames>
                </author>
        </authors>
        <title>When Dark Energy Turns On: Constraints on a Critical Emergence Model</title>
            <categories>astro-ph.CO</categories>
            <license>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0/</license>
            <abstract>We investigate a specific emergent dark energy scenario, known as critically emergent dark energy (CEDE), in which dark energy is effectively absent in the early Universe and becomes dynamically relevant only after a critical cosmic epoch through a phase transition. We constrain this model using recent cosmological observations, including cosmic microwave background (CMB) data from \emph{Planck} 2018, baryon acoustic oscillation (BAO) measurements from SDSS and DESI DR2, and two independent Type Ia supernova compilations, PantheonPlus and Union3. Our results show that within the CEDE framework a dark energy phase transition is not ruled out. In particular, CMB-only, CMB+SDSS, and CMB+DESI datasets provide evidence for a nonzero transition scale factor and, according to standard statistical indicators such as $Δχ^2$ and Bayesian evidence, can favor CEDE over the $Λ$CDM model. At the same time, we find that CEDE does not fully resolve the Hubble constant tension. Overall, our analysis indicates that dark energy models featuring a phase transition remain a viable and phenomenologically interesting extension of the standard cosmological framework. Upcoming high-precision cosmological surveys will be essential to further assess whether such emergent dark energy scenarios represent a genuine departure from $Λ$CDM or an effective description of current data.</abstract>
    </arXiv>

            </metadata>
        </record>

    </GetRecord>
</OAI-PMH>