<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<OAI-PMH xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" 
         xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance"
         xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/OAI-PMH.xsd">
    <responseDate>2026-07-13T06:21:22Z</responseDate>
                <request verb="GetRecord" identifier="oai:arXiv.org:2510.13121" metadataPrefix="arXiv">http://oaipmh.arxiv.org/oai</request>


    <GetRecord>
                <record>
                <header>
        <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:2510.13121</identifier>
        <datestamp>2025-10-16</datestamp>
            <setSpec>physics:astro-ph:CO</setSpec>
    </header>

            <metadata>
                        <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ https://oaipmh.arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
        <id>2510.13121</id>
        <created>2025-10-15</created>
            <updated>2025-10-16</updated>
        <authors>
                <author>
                    <keyname>Son</keyname>
                        <forenames>Junhyuk</forenames>
                </author>
                <author>
                    <keyname>Lee</keyname>
                        <forenames>Young-Wook</forenames>
                </author>
                <author>
                    <keyname>Chung</keyname>
                        <forenames>Chul</forenames>
                </author>
                <author>
                    <keyname>Park</keyname>
                        <forenames>Seunghyun</forenames>
                </author>
                <author>
                    <keyname>Cho</keyname>
                        <forenames>Hyejeon</forenames>
                </author>
        </authors>
        <title>Strong Progenitor Age-bias in Supernova Cosmology. II. Alignment with DESI BAO and Signs of a Non-Accelerating Universe</title>
            <categories>astro-ph.CO</categories>
            <comments>Published in MNRAS, 10 figures, 2 tables,</comments>
            <license>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0/</license>
            <abstract>Supernova (SN) cosmology is based on the key assumption that the luminosity standardization process of Type Ia SNe remains invariant with progenitor age. However, direct and extensive age measurements of SN host galaxies reveal a significant (5.5σ) correlation between standardized SN magnitude and progenitor age, which is expected to introduce a serious systematic bias with redshift in SN cosmology. This systematic bias is largely uncorrected by the commonly used mass-step correction, as progenitor age and host galaxy mass evolve very differently with redshift. After correcting for this age-bias as a function of redshift, the SN dataset aligns more closely with the w0waCDM model recently suggested by the DESI BAO project from a combined analysis using only BAO and CMB data. This result is further supported by an evolution-free test that uses only SNe from young, coeval host galaxies across the full redshift range. When the three cosmological probes (SNe, BAO, CMB) are combined, we find a significantly stronger (&gt; 9σ) tension with the ΛCDM model than that reported in the DESI papers, suggesting a time-varying dark energy equation of state in a currently non-accelerating universe.</abstract>
    </arXiv>

            </metadata>
        </record>

    </GetRecord>
</OAI-PMH>