<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<OAI-PMH xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" 
         xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance"
         xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/OAI-PMH.xsd">
    <responseDate>2026-07-13T06:21:50Z</responseDate>
                <request verb="GetRecord" identifier="oai:arXiv.org:2602.11276" metadataPrefix="arXiv">http://oaipmh.arxiv.org/oai</request>


    <GetRecord>
                <record>
                <header>
        <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:2602.11276</identifier>
        <datestamp>2026-02-13</datestamp>
            <setSpec>physics:quant-ph</setSpec>
            <setSpec>physics:physics:optics</setSpec>
    </header>

            <metadata>
                        <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ https://oaipmh.arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
        <id>2602.11276</id>
        <created>2026-02-11</created>
            <updated>2026-02-13</updated>
        <authors>
                <author>
                    <keyname>Anguita</keyname>
                        <forenames>Malaquias Correa</forenames>
                </author>
                <author>
                    <keyname>Marzban</keyname>
                        <forenames>Sara</forenames>
                </author>
                <author>
                    <keyname>Braasch</keyname>
                        <forenames>William F.</forenames>
                        <suffix>Jr.</suffix>
                </author>
                <author>
                    <keyname>Upadhyaya</keyname>
                        <forenames>Twesh</forenames>
                </author>
                <author>
                    <keyname>Landi</keyname>
                        <forenames>Gabriel</forenames>
                </author>
                <author>
                    <keyname>Halpern</keyname>
                        <forenames>Nicole Yunger</forenames>
                </author>
                <author>
                    <keyname>Renema</keyname>
                        <forenames>Jelmer J.</forenames>
                </author>
        </authors>
        <title>Bosonic statistics enhance Maxwell&#39;s demon in photonic experiment</title>
            <categories>quant-ph physics.optics</categories>
            <comments>4.5 pages (3 figures) + appendices (10.5 pages / 3 figures / 2 tables)</comments>
            <license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license>
            <abstract>Maxwell&#39;s demon elucidates the value of information in thermodynamics, using measurement and feedback: he evolves an equilibrated gas into a nonequilibrium state, from which one might extract work. The demon can evolve the system farther from equilibrium, on average, if the particles obey Bose-Einstein statistics than if they are distinguishable. We experimentally support this decade-and-a-half-old prediction by comparing indistinguishable with distinguishable photons. We use a fully programmable linear-optics platform, whose local photon statistics were shown recently to behave thermally. Our demon nondestructively measures the number of photons in a subset of the modes. Guided by the outcome, he conditionally interchanges the measured and unmeasured modes. This interchange creates a positive temperature difference between a mode in a particular subset and a mode in the other. The temperature difference is greater, on average, if the photons are indistinguishable. This result bolsters a long-standing prediction about the interplay among thermodynamics, information, and quantum particle statistics. Additionally, this work suggests a thermodynamic means of weakly validating boson-sampling platforms.</abstract>
    </arXiv>

            </metadata>
        </record>

    </GetRecord>
</OAI-PMH>