<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<OAI-PMH xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" 
         xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance"
         xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/OAI-PMH.xsd">
    <responseDate>2026-07-11T08:54:26Z</responseDate>
                <request verb="GetRecord" identifier="oai:arXiv.org:2606.05299v1" metadataPrefix="arXiv">http://oaipmh.arxiv.org/oai</request>


    <GetRecord>
                <record>
                <header>
        <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:2606.05299</identifier>
        <datestamp>2026-06-05</datestamp>
            <setSpec>physics:hep-ph</setSpec>
            <setSpec>physics:astro-ph:CO</setSpec>
            <setSpec>physics:astro-ph:GA</setSpec>
            <setSpec>physics:hep-ex</setSpec>
    </header>

            <metadata>
                        <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ https://oaipmh.arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
        <id>2606.05299</id>
        <created>2026-06-03</created>
            <updated>2026-06-05</updated>
        <authors>
                <author>
                    <keyname>Graham</keyname>
                        <forenames>Peter W.</forenames>
                </author>
                <author>
                    <keyname>Ramani</keyname>
                        <forenames>Harikrishnan</forenames>
                </author>
                <author>
                    <keyname>Wong</keyname>
                        <forenames>Samuel S. Y.</forenames>
                </author>
        </authors>
        <title>Heavy-element paleodetectors for Higgsino dark matter</title>
            <categories>hep-ph astro-ph.CO astro-ph.GA hep-ex</categories>
            <comments>19 pages, 9 figures</comments>
            <license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license>
            <abstract>Paleodetectors have been proposed as a new approach to direct detection of weakly interacting massive particles (WIMPs), through the search for damage tracks in ancient minerals induced by WIMP-nucleon scattering. However, for inelastic dark matter such as the Higgsino, existing paleodetector targets lack sufficiently heavy nuclei to overcome the kinematic threshold for scattering. We propose heavy-element paleodetectors as a new probe of inelastic dark matter, using ancient, radiopure minerals containing heavy elements such as lead. We identify brine precipitates from deep geothermal aquifers as a possible geological source of such minerals. Additionally, paleodetectors are uniquely sensitive to the history of the dark matter high-velocity tail, including a possible fast population induced by the Large Magellanic Cloud&#39;s close approach 50 Myr ago. Such a scenario would favor younger minerals than usually assumed in the paleodetector literature. This method can probe Higgsino mass splittings up to $δ\simeq 920$ keV. Due to the large Higgsino-nucleon cross section, we find that even suboptimal mineral samples with ordinary radioactivity from depths of only 2 km can probe new parameter space, thus partially relaxing the stringent requirements on radiopurity and depth that constitute two significant challenges for the paleodetector program.</abstract>
    </arXiv>

            </metadata>
        </record>

    </GetRecord>
</OAI-PMH>