<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<OAI-PMH xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" 
         xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance"
         xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/OAI-PMH.xsd">
    <responseDate>2026-07-13T06:26:29Z</responseDate>
                <request verb="GetRecord" identifier="oai:arXiv.org:2602.23641" metadataPrefix="arXiv">http://oaipmh.arxiv.org/oai</request>


    <GetRecord>
                <record>
                <header>
        <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:2602.23641</identifier>
        <datestamp>2026-03-02</datestamp>
            <setSpec>physics:astro-ph:SR</setSpec>
    </header>

            <metadata>
                        <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ https://oaipmh.arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
        <id>2602.23641</id>
        <created>2026-02-27</created>
            <updated>2026-03-02</updated>
        <authors>
                <author>
                    <keyname>Chen</keyname>
                        <forenames>Weiqi</forenames>
                </author>
                <author>
                    <keyname>Li</keyname>
                        <forenames>Kejun</forenames>
                </author>
                <author>
                    <keyname>Xu</keyname>
                        <forenames>Jingchen</forenames>
                </author>
        </authors>
        <title>The Split Janus-faced Sun: Magnetic Rhythm and Duality in the Solar Cycle</title>
            <categories>astro-ph.SR</categories>
            <license>http://creativecommons.org/publicdomain/zero/1.0/</license>
            <abstract>The solar cycle - most notably characterized by its sunspot activity patterns - serves as a cornerstone of heliospheric physics. This research uncovers a fundamental magnetic dichotomy in the Sun&#39;s full-disk field, identifying two functionally separate populations: the Strong-Field Group (SG) and Weak-Field Group (WG). The solar cycle exhibits a dual nature, much like Janus, with the SG and WG operating in opposing phases regardless of low or high latitudes. The SG-dominated cycle represents one facet of this duality and is visually prominent at the solar surface. It is well-established that this component synchronizes with the sunspot cycle at low latitudes but operates in anti-phase at high latitudes. In contrast, the WG-driven cycle acts as its hidden counterpart, functioning in opposition to the SG at both high and low latitudes -- a behavior that had not been identified until now. Influenced by these magnetic field groups, this dual nature permeates the entire solar atmosphere, revealing that the full-disk solar activity is globally modulated by the Janus cycle.</abstract>
    </arXiv>

            </metadata>
        </record>

    </GetRecord>
</OAI-PMH>