<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<OAI-PMH xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" 
         xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance"
         xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/OAI-PMH.xsd">
    <responseDate>2026-07-13T06:21:46Z</responseDate>
                <request verb="GetRecord" identifier="oai:arXiv.org:2601.02490" metadataPrefix="arXiv">http://oaipmh.arxiv.org/oai</request>


    <GetRecord>
                <record>
                <header>
        <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:2601.02490</identifier>
        <datestamp>2026-01-07</datestamp>
            <setSpec>physics:gr-qc</setSpec>
            <setSpec>physics:hep-th</setSpec>
    </header>

            <metadata>
                        <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ https://oaipmh.arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
        <id>2601.02490</id>
        <created>2026-01-05</created>
            <updated>2026-01-07</updated>
        <authors>
                <author>
                    <keyname>Azizi</keyname>
                        <forenames>Arash</forenames>
                </author>
        </authors>
        <title>Saving the Unruh Signal: Coherent Cancellation of Spontaneous Emission with Entangled Detectors</title>
            <categories>gr-qc hep-th</categories>
            <comments>9 pages, 2 figures, PRD version</comments>
            <doi>10.1103/w7tn-wmmz</doi>
            <license>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0/</license>
            <abstract>The Unruh effect is notoriously difficult to detect, as it is exponentially overwhelmed by Wigner--Weisskopf spontaneous emission. We show that this fundamental obstacle can be overcome by harnessing multi-detector quantum interference. By preparing a system of three entangled Unruh--DeWitt detectors in a specific W-state, the spontaneous emission channels can be forced to destructively interfere and vanish, thereby &#34;saving&#34; the Unruh signal by coherently silencing this dominant noise. Our central result is the derivation of the condition for complete and simultaneous cancellation of all right- and left-traveling emission modes. We find this requires preparing the detectors in a unique entangled state whose real-valued coefficients are fixed by an elegant geometric constraint, given by a ratio of sines of the logarithms of the detector accelerations. This work establishes multi-detector entanglement as a precision tool for noise cancellation in relativistic quantum settings, offering a new pathway toward the definitive observation of the Unruh signal.</abstract>
    </arXiv>

            </metadata>
        </record>

    </GetRecord>
</OAI-PMH>