<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<OAI-PMH xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" 
         xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance"
         xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/OAI-PMH.xsd">
    <responseDate>2026-07-13T21:13:44Z</responseDate>
                <request verb="GetRecord" identifier="oai:arXiv.org:2512.07364" metadataPrefix="arXiv">http://oaipmh.arxiv.org/oai</request>


    <GetRecord>
                <record>
                <header>
        <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:2512.07364</identifier>
        <datestamp>2025-12-12</datestamp>
            <setSpec>physics:gr-qc</setSpec>
    </header>

            <metadata>
                        <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ https://oaipmh.arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
        <id>2512.07364</id>
        <created>2025-12-11</created>
            <updated>2025-12-12</updated>
        <authors>
                <author>
                    <keyname>Holme</keyname>
                        <forenames>S. M.</forenames>
                </author>
                <author>
                    <keyname>Ramadhan</keyname>
                        <forenames>H. S.</forenames>
                </author>
                <author>
                    <keyname>Huda</keyname>
                        <forenames>I. Nurul</forenames>
                </author>
                <author>
                    <keyname>Putra</keyname>
                        <forenames>Leonardus B.</forenames>
                </author>
        </authors>
        <title>Orbital dynamics and spin-precession around a circular chiral vorton</title>
            <categories>gr-qc</categories>
            <comments>36 pages, 22 figures</comments>
            <license>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0/</license>
            <abstract>Vortons are of interest in high-energy physics as possible dark matter candidates and as probes of Grand Unified Theories. Using the recently derived weak-field metric for a chiral vorton, we study the dynamics of test particles by analyzing both timelike and null geodesics. We identify several classes of trajectories, including bound precessing orbits, circular orbits, toroidal, and crown-type oscillations, as well as unbound scattering paths. Poincare surfaces of section reveal transitions between regular and chaotic motions that depend sensitively on the vorton tension $Gμ$ and initial conditions. We further compute the Lense-Thirring and general spin-precession frequencies for gyroscopes along Killing trajectories. The resulting precession profiles exhibit several distinct features not present in Kerr black holes but reminiscent of Kerr naked singularities, such as: divergences near the ring core, and multi-minima structures. These dynamical and precessional signatures may offer potential observational pathways for detecting vortons.</abstract>
    </arXiv>

            </metadata>
        </record>

    </GetRecord>
</OAI-PMH>