<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<OAI-PMH xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" 
         xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance"
         xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/OAI-PMH.xsd">
    <responseDate>2026-07-13T06:22:30Z</responseDate>
                <request verb="GetRecord" identifier="oai:arXiv.org:2607.03622" metadataPrefix="arXiv">http://oaipmh.arxiv.org/oai</request>


    <GetRecord>
                <record>
                <header>
        <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:2607.03622</identifier>
        <datestamp>2026-07-07</datestamp>
            <setSpec>physics:quant-ph</setSpec>
            <setSpec>physics:physics:app-ph</setSpec>
    </header>

            <metadata>
                        <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ https://oaipmh.arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
        <id>2607.03622</id>
        <created>2026-07-03</created>
            <updated>2026-07-07</updated>
        <authors>
                <author>
                    <keyname>Cunill-Subiranas</keyname>
                        <forenames>Jaume</forenames>
                </author>
                <author>
                    <keyname>Resare</keyname>
                        <forenames>Fabian</forenames>
                </author>
                <author>
                    <keyname>Zhao</keyname>
                        <forenames>Suocheng</forenames>
                </author>
                <author>
                    <keyname>Qvarfort</keyname>
                        <forenames>Sofia</forenames>
                </author>
                <author>
                    <keyname>Metelmann</keyname>
                        <forenames>A.</forenames>
                </author>
                <author>
                    <keyname>Navau</keyname>
                        <forenames>Carles</forenames>
                </author>
                <author>
                    <keyname>Wieczorek</keyname>
                        <forenames>Witlef</forenames>
                </author>
        </authors>
        <title>Macroscopic Quantum Interference of the Center-of-Mass Motion of Levitated Superconducting Microparticles enabled by Magnetic Higher-Order Traps</title>
            <categories>quant-ph physics.app-ph</categories>
            <comments>30 pages, 9 figures, including appendices</comments>
            <license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license>
            <abstract>We show how magnetostatic higher-order multipole traps can be used to generate macroscopic quantum interference of the motion of levitated superconducting microparticles. An appropriate combination of multipolar magnetic fields offers great versatility in constructing various trap potentials, including anharmonic trap potentials such as Duffing or double-well types. Crucially, the anharmonic trap potentials realize a nonlinearity on the order of hundred times the zero-point motion, i.e., on a length scale below nanometers. These anharmonic potentials allow for the generation of quantum features of the center-of-mass motion of a magnetically levitated superconducting microparticle. Importantly, they can be easily generated with a static arrangement of coils, requiring only that the current running through them is tunable. We propose protocols exploiting the versatility of the magnetic trap landscape to generate non-Gaussian motional states. We solve the dynamics of the center-of-mass motion of the particle in phase space and analyze its parameter dependence. Furthermore, we give a recipe to distinguish classical from quantum behavior in a statistically meaningful way through measurement of the position of the particle. Our results open a path to accessing the quantum regime of the center-of-mass motion of objects with masses larger than picogram, i.e., $10^{13}$ atomic mass units. This will enable fundamental physics experiments for studying the transition between quantum and classical behavior, exploring the intersection between quantum physics and gravity as well as probing of certain types of dark matter.</abstract>
    </arXiv>

            </metadata>
        </record>

    </GetRecord>
</OAI-PMH>