<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<OAI-PMH xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" 
         xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance"
         xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/OAI-PMH.xsd">
    <responseDate>2026-07-11T20:37:33Z</responseDate>
                <request verb="GetRecord" identifier="oai:arXiv.org:2601.01999v2" metadataPrefix="arXiv">http://oaipmh.arxiv.org/oai</request>


    <GetRecord>
                <record>
                <header>
        <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:2601.01999</identifier>
        <datestamp>2026-06-23</datestamp>
            <setSpec>physics:astro-ph:HE</setSpec>
            <setSpec>physics:physics:plasm-ph</setSpec>
    </header>

            <metadata>
                        <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ https://oaipmh.arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
        <id>2601.01999</id>
        <created>2026-06-22</created>
            <updated>2026-06-23</updated>
        <authors>
                <author>
                    <keyname>Ly</keyname>
                        <forenames>Minh Nhat</forenames>
                </author>
                <author>
                    <keyname>Inoue</keyname>
                        <forenames>Yoshiyuki</forenames>
                </author>
                <author>
                    <keyname>Sentoku</keyname>
                        <forenames>Yasuhiko</forenames>
                </author>
                <author>
                    <keyname>Sano</keyname>
                        <forenames>Takayoshi</forenames>
                </author>
        </authors>
        <title>Proton Acceleration by Collisionless Shocks in Supermassive Black Hole Coronae: Implications for High-Energy Neutrinos</title>
            <categories>astro-ph.HE physics.plasm-ph</categories>
            <comments>Accepted for publication in ApJ</comments>
            <journal-ref>The Astrophysical Journal 1004, 27 (2026)</journal-ref>
            <doi>10.3847/1538-4357/ae61ab</doi>
            <license>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0/</license>
            <abstract>Recent observations by the IceCube Neutrino Observatory have revealed a significant excess of high-energy neutrinos from nearby Seyfert galaxies, such as NGC~1068, without a corresponding flux of high-energy gamma-rays. This suggests that neutrinos are produced via hadronic interactions in a region opaque to gamma-rays, likely a hot corona surrounding the central supermassive black hole. However, the mechanism responsible for accelerating the parent protons to the required energies ($\sim 100$ TeV) remains an open question. In this study, we investigate diffusive shock acceleration (DSA) in active galactic nucleus (AGN) coronae using a suite of one-dimensional Particle-in-cell (PIC) simulations spanning a broad range of plasma parameters. We find that DSA is a robust and efficient mechanism for proton acceleration, consistently channeling approximately 10\% of the shock&#39;s kinetic energy into non-thermal ions, even for shocks with sonic Mach number as low as $ M_s \approx 2$. In contrast, the efficiency of electron acceleration is highly variable and less efficient ($&lt;1\%$) in our parameter survey. These findings provide strong, first-principles support for the hadronic models of neutrino production in AGN and offer quantitative constraints that can explain the observed gamma-ray deficit.</abstract>
    </arXiv>

            </metadata>
        </record>

    </GetRecord>
</OAI-PMH>