<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<OAI-PMH xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" 
         xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance"
         xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/OAI-PMH.xsd">
    <responseDate>2026-07-13T06:25:06Z</responseDate>
                <request verb="GetRecord" identifier="oai:arXiv.org:2607.01118" metadataPrefix="arXiv">http://oaipmh.arxiv.org/oai</request>


    <GetRecord>
                <record>
                <header>
        <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:2607.01118</identifier>
        <datestamp>2026-07-02</datestamp>
            <setSpec>physics:gr-qc</setSpec>
    </header>

            <metadata>
                        <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ https://oaipmh.arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
        <id>2607.01118</id>
        <created>2026-07-01</created>
            <updated>2026-07-02</updated>
        <authors>
                <author>
                    <keyname>Procopio</keyname>
                        <forenames>Lorenzo M.</forenames>
                </author>
                <author>
                    <keyname>Aguero-Santacruz</keyname>
                        <forenames>Raul</forenames>
                </author>
                <author>
                    <keyname>Bermudez</keyname>
                        <forenames>David</forenames>
                </author>
                <author>
                    <keyname>Leonhardt</keyname>
                        <forenames>Ulf</forenames>
                </author>
        </authors>
        <title>Backreaction of stimulated Hawking radiation in an optical analogue</title>
            <categories>gr-qc</categories>
            <journal-ref>Nature, published online 1 July 2026</journal-ref>
            <doi>10.1038/s41586-026-10720-3</doi>
            <license>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0/</license>
            <abstract>Hawking radiation - the emission of quantum particles at the event horizon of a black hole - connects gravity with quantum mechanics and thermodynamics; the Bekenstein-Hawking entropy has been the benchmark for potential quantum theories of gravity. But Hawking radiation has never been observed in astronomy, only in laboratory analogues and the chances of ever observing it in space are astronomically small. The energy of Hawking radiation must come from the gravitational field around the black hole, but how field quanta generate Hawking quanta has been unknown. Here we report on experimental and theoretical evidence for the process that generates Hawking radiation in a fibre-optical analogue of the event horizon. There, as in gravity, it has been believed that Hawking radiation comes from a complicated, cascaded process; here we have found a simple, direct process and measured its backreaction on the field. Our findings suggest an equally direct process for other laboratory analogues and perhaps also for gravitational fields, shedding light on how black holes might radiate.</abstract>
    </arXiv>

            </metadata>
        </record>

    </GetRecord>
</OAI-PMH>