<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<OAI-PMH xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" 
         xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance"
         xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/OAI-PMH.xsd">
    <responseDate>2026-07-13T06:24:44Z</responseDate>
                <request verb="GetRecord" identifier="oai:arXiv.org:2605.16148" metadataPrefix="arXiv">http://oaipmh.arxiv.org/oai</request>


    <GetRecord>
                <record>
                <header>
        <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:2605.16148</identifier>
        <datestamp>2026-06-09</datestamp>
            <setSpec>physics:quant-ph</setSpec>
            <setSpec>physics:cond-mat:stat-mech</setSpec>
            <setSpec>physics:hep-th</setSpec>
    </header>

            <metadata>
                        <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ https://oaipmh.arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
        <id>2605.16148</id>
        <created>2026-06-06</created>
            <updated>2026-06-09</updated>
        <authors>
                <author>
                    <keyname>Siringo</keyname>
                        <forenames>Fabio</forenames>
                </author>
        </authors>
        <title>A reason why we do not observe Schrödinger&#39;s cats</title>
            <categories>quant-ph cond-mat.stat-mech hep-th</categories>
            <license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license>
            <abstract>A reason is discussed (may be not the only one) for why we do not see any superposition of macroscopic states in the real world. Under the general assumption that quantum macrostates are statistical ensembles of microstates, it is shown that any superposition of macrostates is reduced in a very short time by the unitary dynamics of the ordinary Schrödinger equation, deducing the Born rule without having to postulate it. In more detail, the macroscopic and microscopic degrees of freedom are decoupled in the Schrödinger equation, yielding an effective stochastic equation for the macroscopic variables, with the ensemble average of the microscopic amplitudes that acts as a self-generated internal white noise. The stochastic equation is shown to be a reducing Itô equation if some general causality conditions are met, predicting a very quick collapse of any macroscopic superposition upon formation, with probabilities which satisfy the Born rule. In the context of the von Neumann measurement scheme, the relevance of the result is discussed as a simple dynamical solution of the measurement problem.</abstract>
    </arXiv>

            </metadata>
        </record>

    </GetRecord>
</OAI-PMH>