<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<OAI-PMH xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" 
         xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance"
         xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/OAI-PMH.xsd">
    <responseDate>2026-07-11T10:24:39Z</responseDate>
                <request verb="GetRecord" identifier="oai:arXiv.org:2606.07751v2" metadataPrefix="arXiv">http://oaipmh.arxiv.org/oai</request>


    <GetRecord>
                <record>
                <header>
        <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:2606.07751</identifier>
        <datestamp>2026-06-19</datestamp>
            <setSpec>physics:astro-ph:GA</setSpec>
            <setSpec>physics:astro-ph:SR</setSpec>
    </header>

            <metadata>
                        <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ https://oaipmh.arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
        <id>2606.07751</id>
        <created>2026-06-09</created>
            <updated>2026-06-19</updated>
        <authors>
                <author>
                    <keyname>Goudfrooij</keyname>
                        <forenames>Paul</forenames>
                </author>
                <author>
                    <keyname>Bellini</keyname>
                        <forenames>Andrea</forenames>
                </author>
                <author>
                    <keyname>Brown</keyname>
                        <forenames>Thomas M.</forenames>
                </author>
                <author>
                    <keyname>Puzia</keyname>
                        <forenames>Thomas H.</forenames>
                </author>
        </authors>
        <title>A Colour-colour Fingerprint Links the UV Upturn in Early-type Galaxies to Second-generation Stars from Dissolved Globular Clusters</title>
            <categories>astro-ph.GA astro-ph.SR</categories>
            <comments>7 pages, 4 figures, accepted for publication as a MNRAS Letter</comments>
            <journal-ref>MNRAS, Vol. 549, 1-7 (2026)</journal-ref>
            <doi>10.1093/mnras/stag1087</doi>
            <license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license>
            <abstract>We address two mass-dependent properties among early-type galaxies (ETGs): (1) abundance ratios [N/Fe] and [Na/Fe], and (2) the centrally concentrated &#34;UV upturn&#34; at far-UV (FUV) wavelengths, which is likely produced by extreme horizontal branch stars with supersolar helium abundances. Using new HST/WFC3 observations of one FUV-weak and one FUV-bright ETG, we probe the &#34;MP scenario&#34; by Goudfrooij who posited that the UV upturn and the mass-dependent abundance variations of N and Na within and among ETGs are physically connected and produced by dissolution of metal-rich globular clusters, which represent the only galactic environment where mass-dependent enrichment of He, N, and Na is known to occur (i.e., second-generation stars of the &#34;multiple stellar populations&#34; (MPs) phenomenon). We show that passbands F275W and F390W are uniquely sensitive to correlated changes in $Y$ and [N/Fe] in integrated-light photometry when combined with archival data in F475W and F850LP. While F475W-F850LP is found to decrease with increasing radius in both galaxies, consistent with known metallicity gradients, F275W-F390W increases with increasing radius, as expected if the UV upturn is caused by second-generation stars with supersolar $Y$ and [N/Fe]. Furthermore, the radial gradient in F275W-F390W and the implied fractions of He- and N-enhanced stars are found to be significantly larger in the FUV-bright ETG than in the FUV-weak one, consistent with the predictions of the MP scenario.</abstract>
    </arXiv>

            </metadata>
        </record>

    </GetRecord>
</OAI-PMH>