<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<OAI-PMH xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" 
         xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance"
         xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/OAI-PMH.xsd">
    <responseDate>2026-07-13T06:22:30Z</responseDate>
                <request verb="GetRecord" identifier="oai:arXiv.org:2607.07592" metadataPrefix="arXiv">http://oaipmh.arxiv.org/oai</request>


    <GetRecord>
                <record>
                <header>
        <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:2607.07592</identifier>
        <datestamp>2026-07-09</datestamp>
            <setSpec>physics:astro-ph:IM</setSpec>
    </header>

            <metadata>
                        <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ https://oaipmh.arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
        <id>2607.07592</id>
        <created>2026-07-08</created>
            <updated>2026-07-09</updated>
        <authors>
                <author>
                    <keyname>Neilson</keyname>
                        <forenames>Hilding R.</forenames>
                </author>
        </authors>
        <title>Decolonizing technosignatures: Reimagining technosignatures through an Indigenist lens</title>
            <categories>astro-ph.IM</categories>
            <comments>5 pages, accepted for publication in the proceedings of IAU Symposium 404: Advancing the Search for Technosignatures</comments>
            <license>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0/</license>
            <abstract>There exist numerous proposals for potential technosignatures that we can search for, but they all tend to be deviations from possible naturally occurring signals. That is, technosignatures tend to be a search for pollution. Following a number of works by Indigenous scholars, pollution is colonization, even if that pollution is lightyears away. In this situations we are searching for colonial societies that are a reflection of colonial societies on Earth. This may help explain the Fermi Paradox. We are searching for systems that are highly polluting and potentially destructive, while we do not search for extraterrestrial societies that are less impactful on their celestial environment. This also suggests that we might consider technosignatures that act to support natural environments and might be more closely related to biosignatures, that is a technology that reflects a supportive relationship with nature.</abstract>
    </arXiv>

            </metadata>
        </record>

    </GetRecord>
</OAI-PMH>