<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<OAI-PMH xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" 
         xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance"
         xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/OAI-PMH.xsd">
    <responseDate>2026-07-13T06:27:50Z</responseDate>
                <request verb="GetRecord" identifier="oai:arXiv.org:2510.14229" metadataPrefix="arXiv">http://oaipmh.arxiv.org/oai</request>


    <GetRecord>
                <record>
                <header>
        <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:2510.14229</identifier>
        <datestamp>2025-10-17</datestamp>
            <setSpec>physics:astro-ph:EP</setSpec>
            <setSpec>physics:astro-ph:IM</setSpec>
    </header>

            <metadata>
                        <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ https://oaipmh.arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
        <id>2510.14229</id>
        <created>2025-10-16</created>
            <updated>2025-10-17</updated>
        <authors>
                <author>
                    <keyname>Yumoto</keyname>
                        <forenames>Koki</forenames>
                </author>
                <author>
                    <keyname>Kouyama</keyname>
                        <forenames>Toru</forenames>
                </author>
                <author>
                    <keyname>Yamada</keyname>
                        <forenames>Manabu</forenames>
                </author>
                <author>
                    <keyname>Mimasu</keyname>
                        <forenames>Yuya</forenames>
                </author>
                <author>
                    <keyname>Morota</keyname>
                        <forenames>Tomokatsu</forenames>
                </author>
                <author>
                    <keyname>Cho</keyname>
                        <forenames>Yuichiro</forenames>
                </author>
                <author>
                    <keyname>Yokota</keyname>
                        <forenames>Yasuhiro</forenames>
                </author>
                <author>
                    <keyname>Hayakawa</keyname>
                        <forenames>Masahiko</forenames>
                </author>
                <author>
                    <keyname>Arfaux</keyname>
                        <forenames>Anthony</forenames>
                </author>
                <author>
                    <keyname>Tatsumi</keyname>
                        <forenames>Eri</forenames>
                </author>
                <author>
                    <keyname>Matsuoka</keyname>
                        <forenames>Moe</forenames>
                </author>
                <author>
                    <keyname>Sakatani</keyname>
                        <forenames>Naoya</forenames>
                </author>
                <author>
                    <keyname>Shimomura</keyname>
                        <forenames>Sumito</forenames>
                </author>
                <author>
                    <keyname>Kameda</keyname>
                        <forenames>Shingo</forenames>
                </author>
                <author>
                    <keyname>Tanaka</keyname>
                        <forenames>Satoshi</forenames>
                </author>
                <author>
                    <keyname>Enya</keyname>
                        <forenames>Keigo</forenames>
                </author>
                <author>
                    <keyname>Sugita</keyname>
                        <forenames>Seiji</forenames>
                </author>
        </authors>
        <title>Demonstrating Exoplanet Transit Photometry from Space with a 15-mm Aperture Optical Navigation Camera on Hayabusa2</title>
            <categories>astro-ph.EP astro-ph.IM</categories>
            <license>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0/</license>
            <abstract>Observations of exoplanet transits by small satellites have gained increasing attention for reducing detection biases. However, no unambiguous detection of an exoplanet has yet been demonstrated using optics with apertures smaller than 60 mm. Here, we investigated the detectability of exoplanet transits using the telescopic Optical Navigation Camera (ONC-T) onboard the Hayabusa2 spacecraft, which has an effective aperture of only 15 mm. We conducted transit observations of the hot Jupiters WASP-189 b and MASCARA-1 b, collecting data for ten and four events, respectively. The transit signal was detected with a signal-to-noise ratio (SNR) of 13 for WASP-189 b and 8 for MASCARA-1 b for each event. Stacking all events improved the SNR to 40 and 16, respectively. The transit mid-times of each event were measured with a precision of 6 minutes and were consistent with Transiting Exoplanet Survey Satellite (TESS) data to within 2 minutes. The planet-to-star radius ratio was determined with an absolute precision of 0.004 (6% relative) and agreed with TESS results to within 0.002 (3% relative). The recent ONC-T and TESS data enabled an update to the planetary ephemerides. We report a 4 sigma discrepancy between the updated orbital period of MASCARA-1 b and previously reported values. ONC-T sets a new record for the smallest-aperture instrument to detect an exoplanet transit from space, advancing the frontier of exoplanet science with miniature instrumentation. Our results suggest that optics as small as ONC-T may be capable of detecting transiting long-period Jupiters: a population that remains underrepresented in current surveys.</abstract>
    </arXiv>

            </metadata>
        </record>

    </GetRecord>
</OAI-PMH>