<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<OAI-PMH xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" 
         xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance"
         xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/OAI-PMH.xsd">
    <responseDate>2026-07-13T05:28:20Z</responseDate>
                <request verb="GetRecord" identifier="oai:arXiv.org:2605.12659" metadataPrefix="arXiv">http://oaipmh.arxiv.org/oai</request>


    <GetRecord>
                <record>
                <header>
        <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:2605.12659</identifier>
        <datestamp>2026-07-07</datestamp>
            <setSpec>physics:astro-ph:HE</setSpec>
            <setSpec>physics:gr-qc</setSpec>
    </header>

            <metadata>
                        <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ https://oaipmh.arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
        <id>2605.12659</id>
        <created>2026-07-02</created>
            <updated>2026-07-07</updated>
        <authors>
                <author>
                    <keyname>Rojas-Paternina</keyname>
                        <forenames>Daniel</forenames>
                </author>
                <author>
                    <keyname>Cárdenas-Avendaño</keyname>
                        <forenames>Alejandro</forenames>
                </author>
        </authors>
        <title>Light Propagation Prescriptions for Black Hole Movies</title>
            <categories>astro-ph.HE gr-qc</categories>
            <comments>18 pages, 20 figures. V2: Minor changes to match the accepted version</comments>
            <doi>10.1103/nsg2-hy9p</doi>
            <license>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0/</license>
            <abstract>The spatiotemporal content of a black-hole movie is set jointly by source variability and by the distribution of light-travel times across the image. In the slow-light prescription, an image evaluated at fixed observer time contains photons emitted at different source times, whereas in fast light all rays sample a single source emission time. In this work we compare these light-propagation prescriptions through the lensing-band structure of Kerr geodesic delays in a controlled semi-analytic setting. For a given emitting geometry, black-hole spin, and observer inclination, we show how the coordinate-time delay distributions of Kerr null geodesics, decomposed by image order across lensing bands, can be compared with the source correlation time to quantify differences between light-propagation prescriptions. We find that when the intrinsic variability timescale is comparable to, or shorter than, the relevant delay spread, the high-inclination mismatch between fast- and slow-light curves can reach several tens of percent. Motivated by this geometric structure, we introduce brisk light, an intermediate prescription that compresses each lensing-band delay map to its dominant temporal interval rather than collapsing the full image to a single source time. The proposed methodology provides both a practical criterion for when slow light matters and an efficient route to black-hole movies that retain the leading temporal imprint of strong lensing, a regime of direct relevance for future space-based VLBI targeting photon-ring observables.</abstract>
    </arXiv>

            </metadata>
        </record>

    </GetRecord>
</OAI-PMH>