<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<OAI-PMH xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" 
         xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance"
         xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/OAI-PMH.xsd">
    <responseDate>2026-07-13T05:48:36Z</responseDate>
                <request verb="GetRecord" identifier="oai:arXiv.org:2605.14977" metadataPrefix="arXiv">http://oaipmh.arxiv.org/oai</request>


    <GetRecord>
                <record>
                <header>
        <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:2605.14977</identifier>
        <datestamp>2026-05-15</datestamp>
            <setSpec>physics:gr-qc</setSpec>
            <setSpec>physics:astro-ph:CO</setSpec>
            <setSpec>physics:hep-th</setSpec>
    </header>

            <metadata>
                        <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ https://oaipmh.arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
        <id>2605.14977</id>
        <created>2026-05-14</created>
            <updated>2026-05-15</updated>
        <authors>
                <author>
                    <keyname>Jusufi</keyname>
                        <forenames>Kimet</forenames>
                </author>
                <author>
                    <keyname>Khodahami</keyname>
                        <forenames>Amir A.</forenames>
                </author>
                <author>
                    <keyname>Sheykhi</keyname>
                        <forenames>Ahmad</forenames>
                </author>
                <author>
                    <keyname>Said</keyname>
                        <forenames>Jackson Levi</forenames>
                </author>
                <author>
                    <keyname>Saridakis</keyname>
                        <forenames>Emmanuel N.</forenames>
                </author>
        </authors>
        <title>Unified dark sector and Hubble-tension alleviation in scalar-vector-tensor gravity</title>
            <categories>gr-qc astro-ph.CO hep-th</categories>
            <comments>10 pages, 2 figures</comments>
            <license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license>
            <abstract>We investigate a scalar-vector-tensor theory in which matter is minimally coupled to a Jordan-frame metric, while a massive vector sector interacts with the baryonic current. We show that the conformal scalar coupling modifies the physical expansion rate measured by matter observers, leading to a late-time enhancement of the effective Hubble constant. By constructing a phenomenological scalar evolution that becomes relevant only at low redshifts, the model provides a purely late-time mechanism for alleviating the Hubble tension without significantly affecting early-universe cosmology. The scalar potential naturally acts as a dynamical dark-energy sector, while the vector contribution behaves effectively as a pressureless component at cosmological scales through a density-dependent vector mass. Hence, the framework connects late-time scalar dynamics, effective dark-energy evolution, and Hubble-tension alleviation within a unified setup. Finally, local gravitational constraints can be suppressed through a chameleon-type screening mechanism, allowing the theory to remain compatible with Solar-System tests while retaining nontrivial cosmological effects.</abstract>
    </arXiv>

            </metadata>
        </record>

    </GetRecord>
</OAI-PMH>