<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<OAI-PMH xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" 
         xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance"
         xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/OAI-PMH.xsd">
    <responseDate>2026-07-13T06:23:31Z</responseDate>
                <request verb="GetRecord" identifier="oai:arXiv.org:2601.08390" metadataPrefix="arXiv">http://oaipmh.arxiv.org/oai</request>


    <GetRecord>
                <record>
                <header>
        <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:2601.08390</identifier>
        <datestamp>2026-01-14</datestamp>
            <setSpec>physics:astro-ph:EP</setSpec>
    </header>

            <metadata>
                        <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ https://oaipmh.arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
        <id>2601.08390</id>
        <created>2026-01-13</created>
            <updated>2026-01-14</updated>
        <authors>
                <author>
                    <keyname>Naver</keyname>
                        <forenames>Estrid Buhl</forenames>
                </author>
                <author>
                    <keyname>Nikolajsen</keyname>
                        <forenames>Katrine Wulff</forenames>
                </author>
                <author>
                    <keyname>Carøe</keyname>
                        <forenames>Martin Sæbye</forenames>
                </author>
                <author>
                    <keyname>Battaglia</keyname>
                        <forenames>Domenico</forenames>
                </author>
                <author>
                    <keyname>Frydenvang</keyname>
                        <forenames>Jens</forenames>
                </author>
                <author>
                    <keyname>Bizzarro</keyname>
                        <forenames>Martin</forenames>
                </author>
                <author>
                    <keyname>Jørgensen</keyname>
                        <forenames>Jakob Sauer</forenames>
                </author>
                <author>
                    <keyname>Lefmann</keyname>
                        <forenames>Kim</forenames>
                </author>
                <author>
                    <keyname>Kaestner</keyname>
                        <forenames>Anders</forenames>
                </author>
                <author>
                    <keyname>Mannes</keyname>
                        <forenames>David Christian</forenames>
                </author>
                <author>
                    <keyname>Cook</keyname>
                        <forenames>Phil</forenames>
                </author>
                <author>
                    <keyname>Birkedal</keyname>
                        <forenames>Henrik</forenames>
                </author>
                <author>
                    <keyname>Christensen</keyname>
                        <forenames>Thorbjørn Erik Køppen</forenames>
                </author>
                <author>
                    <keyname>Kantor</keyname>
                        <forenames>Innokenty</forenames>
                </author>
                <author>
                    <keyname>Poulsen</keyname>
                        <forenames>Henning Friis</forenames>
                </author>
                <author>
                    <keyname>Kuhn</keyname>
                        <forenames>Luise Theil</forenames>
                </author>
        </authors>
        <title>Direct detection of hydrogen reveals a new macroscopic crustal water reservoir on early Mars</title>
            <categories>astro-ph.EP</categories>
            <comments>E.B. Naver and K. W. Nikolajsen have contributed equally</comments>
            <license>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0/</license>
            <abstract>The next great leap in Martian exploration will be the return of samples to Earth. To ensure the maximum scientific return from studying these samples, the development and utilisation of nondestructive analytical techniques are essential to enable early three-dimensional characterisation of their interiors. Neutron computed tomography is a powerful method in this context: it is highly sensitive to hydrogen and complements the more conventional X-ray computed tomography. Because the distribution and nature of hydrous phases are central to understanding the habitability, the climatic and geological evolution, and potential biosignatures of Mars, identifying hydrogenbearing phases in Martian crustal rocks is of particular importance. Using the only Martian crustal material available on Earth, the NWA 7034 meteorite and its pairs, we show that combined neutron and X-ray computed tomography enables non-destructive sample-wide mapping of hydrogen and reveals the distribution and petrographic contexts of hydrous phases. We identify hydrogen-rich iron oxyhydroxides within ancient igneous clasts, forming a macroscopic mineralogical water reservoir within the meteorite. These alteration assemblages closely resemble those observed in samples collected by the Perseverance rover in Jezero crater, where hydrated iron oxyhydroxides are also present. This similarity suggests that such phases may represent a widespread near-surface water reservoir on early Mars.</abstract>
    </arXiv>

            </metadata>
        </record>

    </GetRecord>
</OAI-PMH>