<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<OAI-PMH xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" 
         xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance"
         xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/OAI-PMH.xsd">
    <responseDate>2026-07-13T06:25:50Z</responseDate>
                <request verb="GetRecord" identifier="oai:arXiv.org:2512.14377" metadataPrefix="arXiv">http://oaipmh.arxiv.org/oai</request>


    <GetRecord>
                <record>
                <header>
        <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:2512.14377</identifier>
        <datestamp>2025-12-17</datestamp>
            <setSpec>physics:quant-ph</setSpec>
    </header>

            <metadata>
                        <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ https://oaipmh.arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
        <id>2512.14377</id>
        <created>2025-12-16</created>
            <updated>2025-12-17</updated>
        <authors>
                <author>
                    <keyname>Ma</keyname>
                        <forenames>Xiongfeng</forenames>
                </author>
        </authors>
        <title>Steering Alternative Realities through Local Quantum Memory Operations</title>
            <categories>quant-ph</categories>
            <comments>9 pages, 3 figures</comments>
            <license>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0/</license>
            <abstract>Quantum measurement resolves a superposition into a definite outcome by correlating it with an observer&#39;s memory -- a reality register. While the global quantum state remains coherent, the observer&#39;s local reality becomes singular and definite. This work introduces reality steering, a protocol that allows an observer to probabilistically access a different reality already supported by the initial quantum state, without reversing decoherence on the environment. The mechanism relies on locally erasing the &#39;which-outcome&#39; information stored in the observer&#39;s brain. Here, &#39;local&#39; means operations confined to the observer&#39;s memory, excluding the environment, which may be cosmically large. Reality steering nevertheless faces intrinsic constraints: successful navigation requires coherent participation from the observer&#39;s counterparts across the relevant branches, and any transition is operationally indistinguishable from non-transition. After arriving in a new reality, all memory records are perfectly consistent with that reality, leaving no internal evidence that a switch occurred. This makes conscious confirmation impossible within standard quantum mechanics. We show that nonlinear operations beyond the standard theory could, in principle, enable verifiable and deliberate navigation. Our results shift multi-reality exploration from philosophical speculation toward a concrete -- though fundamentally constrained -- quantum-informational framework.</abstract>
    </arXiv>

            </metadata>
        </record>

    </GetRecord>
</OAI-PMH>