<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<OAI-PMH xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" 
         xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance"
         xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/OAI-PMH.xsd">
    <responseDate>2026-07-09T20:44:55Z</responseDate>
                <request verb="GetRecord" identifier="oai:arXiv.org:2607.04106v1" metadataPrefix="arXiv">http://oaipmh.arxiv.org/oai</request>


    <GetRecord>
                <record>
                <header>
        <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:2607.04106</identifier>
        <datestamp>2026-07-07</datestamp>
            <setSpec>physics:astro-ph:HE</setSpec>
            <setSpec>physics:astro-ph:CO</setSpec>
    </header>

            <metadata>
                        <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ https://oaipmh.arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
        <id>2607.04106</id>
        <created>2026-07-05</created>
            <updated>2026-07-07</updated>
        <authors>
                <author>
                    <keyname>Wang</keyname>
                        <forenames>Bao</forenames>
                </author>
                <author>
                    <keyname>Lu</keyname>
                        <forenames>Zhiyu</forenames>
                </author>
                <author>
                    <keyname>Liu</keyname>
                        <forenames>Yang</forenames>
                </author>
                <author>
                    <keyname>Wei</keyname>
                        <forenames>Jun-Jie</forenames>
                </author>
                <author>
                    <keyname>Wu</keyname>
                        <forenames>Xue-Feng</forenames>
                </author>
        </authors>
        <title>Measuring the Angular Auto-power Spectrum of Fast Radio Burst Dispersion Measures as a Robust Cosmological Probe and Baryon Tracer</title>
            <categories>astro-ph.HE astro-ph.CO</categories>
            <comments>13 pages, 6 figures</comments>
            <license>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0/</license>
            <abstract>Fluctuations in the cosmic electron density are imprinted on the dispersion measures (DMs) of fast radio bursts (FRBs), making DMs a promising probe of cosmology and the spatial distribution of ionized baryons. In this work, we present the first measurement of the angular auto-power spectrum of FRB DMs, using 3455 apparently non-repeating bursts from the CHIME/FRB Catalog 2. We detect an angular correlation signal at $&gt;3σ$ significance, associated with large-scale electron-density fluctuations. By fitting the measured spectrum to theoretical models, we constrain two key parameter combinations: $Ω_{\rm b}h^2$-$H_0$, which probes the cosmic baryon density and expansion rate, and $Ω_{\rm b}h^2$-$f_{\rm d}$, which traces the baryon fraction in cosmic large-scale structure (LSS). We further assess the robustness of the power-spectrum method against systematic uncertainties arising from the assumed FRB redshift distribution and from the DM contributions of host galaxies (${\rm DM}_{\rm host}$), the Galactic halo (${\rm DM}^{\rm MW}_{\rm halo}$), and the Milky Way interstellar medium (${\rm DM}^{\rm MW}_{\rm ISM}$), using mock samples. Our results demonstrate that the angular power spectrum is largely insensitive to uncorrelated DM components such as ${\rm DM}_{\rm host}$, thereby effectively mitigating the impact of poorly constrained host-galaxy systematics. In contrast to the traditional ${\rm DM}_{\rm LSS}$-$z$ relation, this method does not require individual redshift measurements--it relies only on the overall redshift distribution--and it partially breaks the parameter degeneracies in the $Ω_{\rm b}h^2$-$H_0$ and $Ω_{\rm b}h^2$-$f_{\rm d}$ planes. These findings establish the DM angular power spectrum as a robust cosmological probe and a powerful baryon tracer.</abstract>
    </arXiv>

            </metadata>
        </record>

    </GetRecord>
</OAI-PMH>