<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<OAI-PMH xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" 
         xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance"
         xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/OAI-PMH.xsd">
    <responseDate>2026-07-11T10:24:39Z</responseDate>
                <request verb="GetRecord" identifier="oai:arXiv.org:2606.07741v1" metadataPrefix="arXiv">http://oaipmh.arxiv.org/oai</request>


    <GetRecord>
                <record>
                <header>
        <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:2606.07741</identifier>
        <datestamp>2026-06-09</datestamp>
            <setSpec>physics:astro-ph:GA</setSpec>
    </header>

            <metadata>
                        <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ https://oaipmh.arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
        <id>2606.07741</id>
        <created>2026-06-05</created>
            <updated>2026-06-09</updated>
        <authors>
                <author>
                    <keyname>Chen</keyname>
                        <forenames>Zirui</forenames>
                </author>
                <author>
                    <keyname>Oh</keyname>
                        <forenames>S. Peng</forenames>
                </author>
                <author>
                    <keyname>Fielding</keyname>
                        <forenames>Drummond B.</forenames>
                </author>
                <author>
                    <keyname>Lancaster</keyname>
                        <forenames>Lachlan</forenames>
                </author>
                <author>
                    <keyname>Li</keyname>
                        <forenames>Yuan</forenames>
                </author>
                <author>
                    <keyname>Tan</keyname>
                        <forenames>Brent</forenames>
                </author>
        </authors>
        <title>Clumps in a Cocoon: Geometry and Mixing Set the Universal X-ray to H$α$ Surface Brightness Ratio</title>
            <categories>astro-ph.GA</categories>
            <comments>6 pages, 3 figures. Submitted to MNRAS Letters</comments>
            <license>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0/</license>
            <abstract>Recent observations reveal a universal X-ray to H$α$ surface-brightness ratio, ${\rm SB}_{\rm X}/{\rm SB}_{\rm Hα}\sim 3$, in galactic winds, ram-pressure stripped tails, and cluster filaments. This is surprising because H$α$ traces cold ($\sim 10^4$ K) gas while X-rays trace much hotter ($\sim 10^{6}$--$10^{7}$ K) gas. Plane-parallel mixing-layer models do not recover this ratio, and can be off by orders of magnitude. Motivated by recent work showing that geometry controls the temperature PDF of multiphase gas (Chen &amp; Oh 2026), we run 3D wind-tunnel simulations in the high density contrast ($χ\sim 10^3$) regime. In this limit, the cold phase shatters into many small H$α$-emitting clumps, while X-ray-emitting gas forms a volume-filling cocoon around them. After smoothing on the tail-width scale, the measured surface-brightness ratio converges to the observed value, which can be understood theoretically. The H$α$ luminosity fraction is set by atomic physics, whereas the X-ray luminosity fraction is set by the residence time of gas in the X-ray-emitting band. This residence time is much shorter than the cooling time at X-ray temperatures, but scales roughly inversely with pressure, suggesting that it is tied to the cooling time at a lower-temperature outlet of the mixing cascade. This framework naturally explains why the observed ratio is order unity, and robust to changes in gas pressure.</abstract>
    </arXiv>

            </metadata>
        </record>

    </GetRecord>
</OAI-PMH>