<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<OAI-PMH xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" 
         xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance"
         xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/OAI-PMH.xsd">
    <responseDate>2026-07-13T06:25:38Z</responseDate>
                <request verb="GetRecord" identifier="oai:arXiv.org:2511.22671" metadataPrefix="arXiv">http://oaipmh.arxiv.org/oai</request>


    <GetRecord>
                <record>
                <header>
        <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:2511.22671</identifier>
        <datestamp>2025-12-01</datestamp>
            <setSpec>physics:gr-qc</setSpec>
            <setSpec>physics:hep-th</setSpec>
    </header>

            <metadata>
                        <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ https://oaipmh.arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
        <id>2511.22671</id>
        <created>2025-11-27</created>
            <updated>2025-12-01</updated>
        <authors>
                <author>
                    <keyname>Mondal</keyname>
                        <forenames>Rajdeep</forenames>
                </author>
                <author>
                    <keyname>Sadhukhan</keyname>
                        <forenames>Abhishake</forenames>
                </author>
        </authors>
        <title>Echoes of Traversable Wormhole</title>
            <categories>gr-qc hep-th</categories>
            <comments>21 pages, 5 figures</comments>
            <license>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0/</license>
            <abstract>We study linear scalar perturbations of the four-dimensional, traversable wormhole solution of Maldacena, Milekhin, and Popov(arXiv:1807.04726). The geometry is constructed by matching an asymptotically flat, near-extremal Reissner--Nordström region to a throat described by $AdS_2 \times S^2$, supported by charged massless fermions. We derive the effective scalar potential governing wave dynamics, which when viewed in the tortoise coordinate, exhibits two extremely sharp and widely separated barriers. These barriers form a resonant cavity and are a direct consequence of the near-horizon geometry of the wormhole mouths. Using time-domain integration, we analyze the wormhole&#39;s response to an initial scalar wave packet inside the throat. We find that the late-time signal contains a distinct train of echoes whose amplitude depends on the angular momentum number $l$. We show that higher $l$ modes produce significantly stronger echoes, as the corresponding potential barriers are taller and more reflective, which results in more efficient trapping of the wave within the wormhole throat.</abstract>
    </arXiv>

            </metadata>
        </record>

    </GetRecord>
</OAI-PMH>