<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<OAI-PMH xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" 
         xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance"
         xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/OAI-PMH.xsd">
    <responseDate>2026-07-04T19:17:55Z</responseDate>
                <request verb="GetRecord" identifier="oai:arXiv.org:2606.02932v1" metadataPrefix="arXiv">http://oaipmh.arxiv.org/oai</request>


    <GetRecord>
                <record>
                <header>
        <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:2606.02932</identifier>
        <datestamp>2026-06-03</datestamp>
            <setSpec>physics:astro-ph:HE</setSpec>
    </header>

            <metadata>
                        <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ https://oaipmh.arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
        <id>2606.02932</id>
        <created>2026-06-01</created>
            <updated>2026-06-03</updated>
        <authors>
                <author>
                    <keyname>Nava-Callejas</keyname>
                        <forenames>Martin</forenames>
                </author>
                <author>
                    <keyname>Cavecchi</keyname>
                        <forenames>Yuri</forenames>
                </author>
                <author>
                    <keyname>Page</keyname>
                        <forenames>Dany</forenames>
                </author>
        </authors>
        <title>On a re-examination of neutron star cooling in transient sources -- No shallow heating required?</title>
            <categories>astro-ph.HE</categories>
            <comments>7 pages, 3 figures</comments>
            <license>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0/</license>
            <abstract>Context: For the typical modeling of neutron stars cooling after an accretion episode in Low-Mass X-ray Binaries, an extra heating source of unknown physical origin, \textit{the shallow heating}, is invoked in order to account for the inferred high effective temperatures of the star up to hundreds of days after the end of accretion. The amount of the shallow heating generated in the crust is usually taken to be proportional to the accretion rate, although the proportionality constant may change from source to source. Aims: In this paper, we intend to model the effective temperature data of eight outburst episodes from seven different sources (\mxb, \xte, \exo, \igr, \swift, \rxs\ and \ks) without {\it ad hoc} shallow heating but accounting for the presence of thermonuclear heating due to the burning of the accreted H/He. Methods: We employ the fully relativistic code \texttt{nscool}, which simulates both the crust and core of a neutron star, equipped with a new boundary condition at the envelope/crust transition which considers thermonuclear heating leakage from the envelope into the crust and depends on the mass accretion rate. Results: We find that the neutron star cooling for seven out of eight of these outbursts can be well explained with this new boundary condition and without the requirement of {\it ad hoc} shallow heating. While the qualitative features of \exo\ cooling curve can be explained, a good fitting still requires additional physics.</abstract>
    </arXiv>

            </metadata>
        </record>

    </GetRecord>
</OAI-PMH>