<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<OAI-PMH xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" 
         xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance"
         xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/OAI-PMH.xsd">
    <responseDate>2026-07-13T06:27:28Z</responseDate>
                <request verb="GetRecord" identifier="oai:arXiv.org:2606.20942" metadataPrefix="arXiv">http://oaipmh.arxiv.org/oai</request>


    <GetRecord>
                <record>
                <header>
        <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:2606.20942</identifier>
        <datestamp>2026-06-23</datestamp>
            <setSpec>physics:hep-th</setSpec>
            <setSpec>physics:astro-ph:CO</setSpec>
            <setSpec>physics:gr-qc</setSpec>
    </header>

            <metadata>
                        <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ https://oaipmh.arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
        <id>2606.20942</id>
        <created>2026-06-18</created>
            <updated>2026-06-23</updated>
        <authors>
                <author>
                    <keyname>Danielsson</keyname>
                        <forenames>Ulf</forenames>
                </author>
                <author>
                    <keyname>Giri</keyname>
                        <forenames>Suvendu</forenames>
                </author>
        </authors>
        <title>Dark bubbles, dark dimensions and fat gravitons</title>
            <categories>hep-th astro-ph.CO gr-qc</categories>
            <comments>9 pages + references</comments>
            <report-no>UUITP-14/26</report-no>
            <license>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0/</license>
            <abstract>The dark bubble model explains the existence of a positive cosmological constant by making explicit use of the instabilities underlying the de Sitter swampland conjectures to make the accelerated expansion of the universe inevitable. A distinctive consequence of the construction is a unique hierarchy connecting cosmological, gravitational, string, and higher-dimensional scales. In particular, the model naturally predicts the existence of a dark dimension of micron size, an idea that has been argued for on independent grounds in the literature. The same framework also predicts a weakening of gravity at distances of order the dark-dimension scale, leading to a fading of the gravitational force at micron distances. We argue that the dark bubble therefore provides a concrete realization of both the dark dimension proposal and Sundrum&#39;s fat graviton scenario, in which gravity effectively ceases to probe shorter distances. Additional predictions include a string scale of order tens of TeV and a measurable positive spatial curvature of the universe. We review these key aspects of the model, discuss their implications for gravity and cosmology, and highlight its key predictions.</abstract>
    </arXiv>

            </metadata>
        </record>

    </GetRecord>
</OAI-PMH>