<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<OAI-PMH xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" 
         xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance"
         xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/OAI-PMH.xsd">
    <responseDate>2026-07-11T20:54:44Z</responseDate>
                <request verb="GetRecord" identifier="oai:arXiv.org:2601.02812v2" metadataPrefix="arXiv">http://oaipmh.arxiv.org/oai</request>


    <GetRecord>
                <record>
                <header>
        <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:2601.02812</identifier>
        <datestamp>2026-06-19</datestamp>
            <setSpec>physics:astro-ph:GA</setSpec>
            <setSpec>physics:astro-ph:IM</setSpec>
    </header>

            <metadata>
                        <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ https://oaipmh.arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
        <id>2601.02812</id>
        <created>2026-06-18</created>
            <updated>2026-06-19</updated>
        <authors>
                <author>
                    <keyname>Zhao</keyname>
                        <forenames>Shan-Shan</forenames>
                </author>
                <author>
                    <keyname>Lu</keyname>
                        <forenames>Ru-Sen</forenames>
                </author>
                <author>
                    <keyname>Liu</keyname>
                        <forenames>Lei</forenames>
                </author>
                <author>
                    <keyname>Shen</keyname>
                        <forenames>Zhiqiang</forenames>
                </author>
                <author>
                    <keyname>Mizuno</keyname>
                        <forenames>Yosuke</forenames>
                </author>
        </authors>
        <title>Beyond Sgr A* and M87*: Sub-Microarcsecond Black Hole Shadow Detection via Lunar-based Extremely Long Baseline Interferometry</title>
            <categories>astro-ph.GA astro-ph.IM</categories>
            <license>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0/</license>
            <abstract>The 1.3 mm ground-based very long baseline interferometry (VLBI) array Event Horizon Telescope (EHT), is limited by Earth&#39;s diameter, restricting its black hole shadow imaging to only M87* and Sgr A*. Extending baselines to the Moon would achieve ~0.7 uas angular resolution at 230 GHz, enabling shadow detection for a much larger sample of supermassive black holes (SMBHs). The concept is motivated by space VLBI missions and lunar exploration, including the ongoing Lunar Orbit VLBI EXperiment (LOVEX) aboard QueQiao-2 (Chang&#39;E-7) and the planned International Lunar Research Station (ILRS). We assess shadow detectability for 31 SMBHs with predicted large angular sizes, exploring different telescope location and antenna size. Assuming a telescope at the lunar antipode, we simulate the Moon-Earth (u,v) coverage and show that sources with direction near the Moon&#39;s orbital plane yield projected baselines spanning from short to long, enabling sampling of the first visibility null - a key shadow signature. Using a geometric ring model, we identify six shadow-detectable candidates for Moon-Earth VLBI. Among these, M104, NGC 5077, and NGC 1052 are detectable with a 5 m lunar-based telescope; PGC 049940 requires 10 m; NGC 524 requires 20 m; and NGC 5252 requires 40 m. Furthermore, if space telescopes fill the baseline coverage gaps between Moon and Earth, the n=2 photon ring region is detectable for Sgr A*, M87* with a 10 m lunar-based telescope, and 12 candidates are detectable for the n=1 photon ring region using a lunar-based telescope of up to 40 m. These results provide a clear scientific and technical motivation for lunar-based telescopes in future black hole shadow studies.</abstract>
    </arXiv>

            </metadata>
        </record>

    </GetRecord>
</OAI-PMH>