<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<OAI-PMH xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" 
         xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance"
         xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/OAI-PMH.xsd">
    <responseDate>2026-07-11T21:37:19Z</responseDate>
                <request verb="GetRecord" identifier="oai:arXiv.org:2601.04576v1" metadataPrefix="arXiv">http://oaipmh.arxiv.org/oai</request>


    <GetRecord>
                <record>
                <header>
        <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:2601.04576</identifier>
        <datestamp>2026-01-09</datestamp>
            <setSpec>physics:hep-ph</setSpec>
            <setSpec>physics:astro-ph:CO</setSpec>
            <setSpec>physics:hep-ex</setSpec>
    </header>

            <metadata>
                        <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ https://oaipmh.arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
        <id>2601.04576</id>
        <created>2026-01-08</created>
            <updated>2026-01-09</updated>
        <authors>
                <author>
                    <keyname>Li</keyname>
                        <forenames>Chunlong</forenames>
                </author>
                <author>
                    <keyname>Huang</keyname>
                        <forenames>Yiwei</forenames>
                </author>
                <author>
                    <keyname>Yang</keyname>
                        <forenames>Shien</forenames>
                </author>
                <author>
                    <keyname>Ren</keyname>
                        <forenames>Yichong</forenames>
                </author>
                <author>
                    <keyname>Zhang</keyname>
                        <forenames>Yu</forenames>
                </author>
                <author>
                    <keyname>Yin</keyname>
                        <forenames>Peiran</forenames>
                </author>
                <author>
                    <keyname>Huang</keyname>
                        <forenames>Pu</forenames>
                </author>
                <author>
                    <keyname>Xue</keyname>
                        <forenames>Fei</forenames>
                </author>
        </authors>
        <title>Search for Ultralight Axion Dark Matter with a Levitated Ferromagnetic Torsional Oscillator</title>
            <categories>hep-ph astro-ph.CO hep-ex</categories>
            <comments>15 pages, 8 figures</comments>
            <license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license>
            <abstract>We present a search for ultralight axion dark matter coupled to electron spins using a levitated ferromagnetic torsional oscillator (FMTO). This platform directly measures axion-induced torques on a macroscopic spin-polarized body, combining large spin density with strong mechanical isolation to probe magnetic fluctuations below 10 Hz while suppressing gradient-field noise. In a first implementation, the experiment yielded 18000 s of analyzable data at room temperature under high vacuum with optical readout and triple-layer magnetic shielding. A likelihood-based statistical framework, incorporating stochastic fluctuations in the axion-field amplitude, was used to evaluate the data. No excess consistent with an axion-induced pseudo-magnetic field was observed near 2e-14 eV. To account for possible shielding-induced signal attenuation, we quantify its effect and report both the uncorrected (g_aee &lt; 1e-7) and attenuation-corrected (g_aee &lt; 6e-5) 90% CL limits on the axion-electron coupling. Looking ahead, improvements guided by both noise-budget analysis and shielding-attenuation considerations, including optimized levitation geometry, cryogenic operation, and superconducting shielding, are expected to boost sensitivity by multiple orders of magnitude.</abstract>
    </arXiv>

            </metadata>
        </record>

    </GetRecord>
</OAI-PMH>