<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<OAI-PMH xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" 
         xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance"
         xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/OAI-PMH.xsd">
    <responseDate>2026-07-13T06:28:57Z</responseDate>
                <request verb="GetRecord" identifier="oai:arXiv.org:2605.20076" metadataPrefix="arXiv">http://oaipmh.arxiv.org/oai</request>


    <GetRecord>
                <record>
                <header>
        <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:2605.20076</identifier>
        <datestamp>2026-05-20</datestamp>
            <setSpec>physics:gr-qc</setSpec>
            <setSpec>physics:astro-ph:CO</setSpec>
            <setSpec>physics:hep-th</setSpec>
            <setSpec>physics:physics:space-ph</setSpec>
    </header>

            <metadata>
                        <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ https://oaipmh.arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
        <id>2605.20076</id>
        <created>2026-05-19</created>
            <updated>2026-05-20</updated>
        <authors>
                <author>
                    <keyname>Montes</keyname>
                        <forenames>M.</forenames>
                </author>
                <author>
                    <keyname>Aguilar</keyname>
                        <forenames>José Edgar Madriz</forenames>
                </author>
                <author>
                    <keyname>Bernal</keyname>
                        <forenames>A.</forenames>
                </author>
                <author>
                    <keyname>Reyna</keyname>
                        <forenames>Diego Allan</forenames>
                </author>
        </authors>
        <title>A novel pre-inflationary model in view of the lack of angular correlation of CMB</title>
            <categories>gr-qc astro-ph.CO hep-th physics.space-ph</categories>
            <comments>22 pages, no figures</comments>
            <license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license>
            <abstract>In this paper we propose a novel unified cosmological model that connects a pre-inflationary epoch, starting at the Planckian time, with the onset of inflation within a single scalar-field framework. The pre-inflationary phase is characterized by a decelerated expansion with an increasing comoving Hubble horizon, followed by a gradually transition to an accelerated inflationary regime. This early dynamics leads to a modified causal structure that naturally accounts for the suppression of large-angle $(θ\gtrsim 60^\circ)$ correlations in the cosmic microwave background (CMB) reported by the satellite PLANCK. We study the quantum fluctuations of the scalar field using the Mukhanov-Sasaki formalism and a canonical quantization procedure based on energy minimization. We find that the vacuum state is well-defined only for sub-horizon modes at the onset of inflation, which induces a natural cutoff in the primordial power spectrum. The resulting spectrum exhibits a suppression at large scales while remaining nearly scale-invariant at small scales. In the appropriate limit, the model recovers the standard de Sitter result, in agreement with current observational constraints. These results highlight the relevance of pre-inflationary dynamics for addressing large-scale anomalies within a consistent inflationary framework.</abstract>
    </arXiv>

            </metadata>
        </record>

    </GetRecord>
</OAI-PMH>