<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<OAI-PMH xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" 
         xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance"
         xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/OAI-PMH.xsd">
    <responseDate>2026-07-13T06:28:15Z</responseDate>
                <request verb="GetRecord" identifier="oai:arXiv.org:2602.22386" metadataPrefix="arXiv">http://oaipmh.arxiv.org/oai</request>


    <GetRecord>
                <record>
                <header>
        <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:2602.22386</identifier>
        <datestamp>2026-02-27</datestamp>
            <setSpec>physics:astro-ph:GA</setSpec>
            <setSpec>physics:astro-ph:HE</setSpec>
    </header>

            <metadata>
                        <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ https://oaipmh.arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
        <id>2602.22386</id>
        <created>2026-02-25</created>
            <updated>2026-02-27</updated>
        <authors>
                <author>
                    <keyname>Madau</keyname>
                        <forenames>Piero</forenames>
                </author>
                <author>
                    <keyname>Maiolino</keyname>
                        <forenames>Roberto</forenames>
                </author>
        </authors>
        <title>Little Red Dots as Obscured Little Blue Dots: A Super-Eddington Unification Model</title>
            <categories>astro-ph.GA astro-ph.HE</categories>
            <comments>13 pages, 8 figures, submitted</comments>
            <license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license>
            <abstract>We test whether &#34;Little Red Dots&#34; (LRDs) are dust-reddened, high-inclination counterparts of compact, blue broad-line AGNs (&#34;Little Blue Dots&#34;, LBDs) powered by super-Eddington accretion. We model the central engine as a geometrically thick, radiation-pressure supported accretion flow whose funnel yields strongly anisotropic, intrinsically blue ionizing continua, coupled to an equatorially concentrated BLR and a dusty screen with modest covering factor. Using inclination-dependent SEDs as input to Cloudy, we show that the extreme broad Halpha equivalent widths (EWs) of JWST LRDs are reproduced with global BLR covering factors of only 15%, consistent with standard Type 1 AGNs. Large Balmer EWs arise because self-shadowing suppresses the high-inclination optical continuum while the BLR is illuminated by an EUV-rich SED. Weak high-ionization lines follow from orientation-dependent suppression of the XUV/soft X-ray continuum toward equatorial directions, without requiring a fully enclosing gaseous &#34;cocoon&#34;. With a gray attenuation law of AV = 2.8 along LRD-selected sightlines, the fiducial model matches the V-shaped UV-optical continua and large Balmer decrements; strong Balmer breaks occur only for the most obscured views. A compact equatorial dust component tied to the BLR and normalized by energy conservation intercepts and reradiates only a small fraction of Lbol, producing a modest hot-dust bump and far-IR/sub-mm emission consistent with current limits and implying small dust masses. The model unifies LRD and LBD observables via orientation, predicting correlated trends in Halpha EW, Balmer decrement, Balmer break, high-ionization line strengths, and IR emission.</abstract>
    </arXiv>

            </metadata>
        </record>

    </GetRecord>
</OAI-PMH>