<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<OAI-PMH xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" 
         xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance"
         xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/OAI-PMH.xsd">
    <responseDate>2026-07-13T06:21:16Z</responseDate>
                <request verb="GetRecord" identifier="oai:arXiv.org:2509.08411" metadataPrefix="arXiv">http://oaipmh.arxiv.org/oai</request>


    <GetRecord>
                <record>
                <header>
        <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:2509.08411</identifier>
        <datestamp>2025-09-11</datestamp>
            <setSpec>physics:quant-ph</setSpec>
            <setSpec>physics:physics:atom-ph</setSpec>
            <setSpec>physics:physics:optics</setSpec>
    </header>

            <metadata>
                        <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ https://oaipmh.arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
        <id>2509.08411</id>
        <created>2025-09-10</created>
            <updated>2025-09-11</updated>
        <authors>
                <author>
                    <keyname>Wang</keyname>
                        <forenames>Jiefei</forenames>
                </author>
                <author>
                    <keyname>Dai</keyname>
                        <forenames>Jianhao</forenames>
                </author>
                <author>
                    <keyname>Mao</keyname>
                        <forenames>Ruosong</forenames>
                </author>
                <author>
                    <keyname>Lu</keyname>
                        <forenames>Yunzhou</forenames>
                </author>
                <author>
                    <keyname>Liu</keyname>
                        <forenames>Xiao</forenames>
                </author>
                <author>
                    <keyname>Hu</keyname>
                        <forenames>Huizhu</forenames>
                </author>
                <author>
                    <keyname>Zhu</keyname>
                        <forenames>Shi-Yao</forenames>
                </author>
                <author>
                    <keyname>Xu</keyname>
                        <forenames>Xingqi</forenames>
                </author>
                <author>
                    <keyname>Cai</keyname>
                        <forenames>Han</forenames>
                </author>
                <author>
                    <keyname>Wang</keyname>
                        <forenames>Da-Wei</forenames>
                </author>
        </authors>
        <title>Realizing the Haldane Model in Thermal Atoms</title>
            <categories>quant-ph physics.atom-ph physics.optics</categories>
            <comments>9 pages, 4 figures</comments>
            <license>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0/</license>
            <abstract>Topological materials hold great promise for developing next-generation devices with transport properties that remain resilient in the presence of local imperfections. However, their susceptibility to thermal noise has posed a major challenge. In particular, the Haldane model, a cornerstone in topological physics, generally requires cryogenic temperatures for experimental realization, limiting both the investigation of topologically robust quantum phenomena and their practical applications. In this work, we demonstrate a room-temperature realization of the Haldane model using atomic ensembles in momentum-space superradiance lattices, a platform intrinsically resistant to thermal noise. The topological phase transition is revealed through the superradiant emission contrast between two timed Dicke states in the lattice. Crucially, the thermal resilience of this platform allows us to access a deep modulation regime, where topological transitions to high Chern number phases emerge -- going beyond the traditional Haldane model. Our results not only deepen the understanding of exotic topological phases, but also offer a robust, reconfigurable, and room-temperature-compatible platform that connects quantum simulation to real-world quantum technologies.</abstract>
    </arXiv>

            </metadata>
        </record>

    </GetRecord>
</OAI-PMH>