<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<OAI-PMH xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" 
         xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance"
         xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/OAI-PMH.xsd">
    <responseDate>2026-07-13T05:48:32Z</responseDate>
                <request verb="GetRecord" identifier="oai:arXiv.org:2605.15429" metadataPrefix="arXiv">http://oaipmh.arxiv.org/oai</request>


    <GetRecord>
                <record>
                <header>
        <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:2605.15429</identifier>
        <datestamp>2026-05-26</datestamp>
            <setSpec>physics:gr-qc</setSpec>
            <setSpec>physics:astro-ph:HE</setSpec>
            <setSpec>physics:hep-th</setSpec>
    </header>

            <metadata>
                        <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ https://oaipmh.arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
        <id>2605.15429</id>
        <created>2026-05-14</created>
            <updated>2026-05-26</updated>
        <authors>
                <author>
                    <keyname>Hadj</keyname>
                        <forenames>Mohamed Ould El</forenames>
                </author>
                <author>
                    <keyname>Dolan</keyname>
                        <forenames>Sam R.</forenames>
                </author>
        </authors>
        <title>Ringdown and echoes from compact objects: Debye series and Debye quasinormal modes</title>
            <categories>gr-qc astro-ph.HE hep-th</categories>
            <comments>29 pages, 19 figures, 5 tables</comments>
            <license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license>
            <abstract>We introduce a new series decomposition of the waveform constructed in the spirit of Debye expansions in scattering theory, and we use this to analyse the time-domain response of compact, horizonless bodies to scalar-field perturbations on curved spacetimes. The Debye decomposition separates out direct exterior propagation, surface reflection, and successive transmissions through the interior of a compact body, and it provides an intuitive interpretation of the waveform in terms of geodesic trajectories. By analysing the quasinormal-mode (QNM) content of individual Debye terms, we set out a Debye-QNM description that is complementary to the standard QNM description. With this framework, we examine a scalar field propagating on two illustrative `Schwarzschild star&#39; compact-body spacetimes: a neutron-star-like model \(R&gt;3M\) and an ultracompact object \(R&lt;3M\). We show that the Debye reconstruction matches well with the exact waveform, and that (unlike the standard QNM reconstruction) it converges even at early times, giving an accurate description of all waveform features including the prompt response. In the neutron-star case, the low-order Debye terms mainly describe the ringdown and a non-modal component associated with the sub-threshold branch cut. In the ultracompact case, the Debye series organizes the waveform into a prompt/ringdown contribution followed by a succession of individually resolved echo-like wavepackets. The new Debye-QNM expansion and the standard QNM expansion have complementary spectral interpretations: the former identifies modes in individual propagation channels, whereas the latter describes collective resonances that are resummations of the former. This distinction clarifies how echo-like structures emerge from repeated interior propagation, and how pole and branch-cut contributions enter the time-domain signal.</abstract>
    </arXiv>

            </metadata>
        </record>

    </GetRecord>
</OAI-PMH>