<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<OAI-PMH xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" 
         xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance"
         xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/OAI-PMH.xsd">
    <responseDate>2026-07-11T10:52:05Z</responseDate>
                <request verb="GetRecord" identifier="oai:arXiv.org:2606.17067v1" metadataPrefix="arXiv">http://oaipmh.arxiv.org/oai</request>


    <GetRecord>
                <record>
                <header>
        <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:2606.17067</identifier>
        <datestamp>2026-06-17</datestamp>
            <setSpec>physics:astro-ph:HE</setSpec>
            <setSpec>physics:astro-ph:SR</setSpec>
            <setSpec>physics:hep-ph</setSpec>
    </header>

            <metadata>
                        <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ https://oaipmh.arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
        <id>2606.17067</id>
        <created>2026-06-05</created>
            <updated>2026-06-17</updated>
        <authors>
                <author>
                    <keyname>Gao</keyname>
                        <forenames>Sinuo</forenames>
                </author>
                <author>
                    <keyname>Wang</keyname>
                        <forenames>Chen</forenames>
                </author>
                <author>
                    <keyname>Liu</keyname>
                        <forenames>Maoyuan</forenames>
                </author>
        </authors>
        <title>Searching for axion dark matter conversion spectral lines in neutron star magnetospheres with FAST</title>
            <categories>astro-ph.HE astro-ph.SR hep-ph</categories>
            <license>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0/</license>
            <abstract>The axion is a well-motivated dark matter candidate, which can convert into narrow radio spectral lines via the Primakoff effect in the strongly magnetized magnetospheres of neutron stars. This provides a novel astrophysical probe for axion searches that is complementary to laboratory experiments. Using FAST, the world&#39;s most sensitive single-dish radio telescope, we observed two X-ray dim isolated neutron stars (RXJ1605.3+3249 and RXJ1308.6+2127) within its sky coverage, which are predicted to yield the strongest axion-conversion spectral lines (ACL). Although no significant signal was detected at the 5 sigma confidence level, we establish new upper limits on the axion-photon coupling constant g_{a gamma gamma} less than or similar to 5 x 10^{-12} GeV^{-1} for axion masses ranging from 4.14 to 6.20 micro-eV corresponding to the 1.0-1.5 GHz observational band. This result constitutes the tightest constraint in this axion mass range among all existing studies employing the same ACL-based method.</abstract>
    </arXiv>

            </metadata>
        </record>

    </GetRecord>
</OAI-PMH>