<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<OAI-PMH xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" 
         xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance"
         xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/OAI-PMH.xsd">
    <responseDate>2026-07-13T06:21:34Z</responseDate>
                <request verb="GetRecord" identifier="oai:arXiv.org:2511.03843" metadataPrefix="arXiv">http://oaipmh.arxiv.org/oai</request>


    <GetRecord>
                <record>
                <header>
        <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:2511.03843</identifier>
        <datestamp>2026-04-13</datestamp>
            <setSpec>physics:cond-mat:stat-mech</setSpec>
            <setSpec>physics:nlin:CD</setSpec>
            <setSpec>physics:physics:hist-ph</setSpec>
            <setSpec>physics:quant-ph</setSpec>
    </header>

            <metadata>
                        <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ https://oaipmh.arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
        <id>2511.03843</id>
        <created>2026-04-10</created>
            <updated>2026-04-13</updated>
        <authors>
                <author>
                    <keyname>Wolfson</keyname>
                        <forenames>Ira</forenames>
                </author>
        </authors>
        <title>Quantum Inaccessibility</title>
            <categories>cond-mat.stat-mech nlin.CD physics.hist-ph quant-ph</categories>
            <comments>20 pages, 2 figures. SI- 4 pages</comments>
            <license>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0/</license>
            <abstract>Loschmidt&#39;s paradox asks why macroscopic irreversibility is universal despite the time-reversal symmetry of microscopic dynamics. We argue that irreversibility is not a property of the dynamics but of accessibility: chaotic evolution drives phase-space structure below the quantum resolution scale $\ell_\hbar$, at a critical time $t_c = λ^{-1}\ln(δ_0/\ell_\hbar)$, after which the time-reversed microstate exists as a valid solution of Hamilton&#39;s equations but cannot be selected by any physically admissible operation. The mechanism operates entirely within the semiclassical regime $t_c \leq t_E$, where classical geometry is exact. This provides a dynamical resolution of the Loschmidt paradox.
  The quantum foundation is established using a Krylov-complexity framework: we prove that for any $H(t)=H(-t)$, the quantum Lyapunov exponent satisfies $λ_L^{\rm forward} = λ_L^{\rm backward}$. The arrow of time is not in the dynamics. The mechanism predicts sigmoid fidelity decay, logarithmic scaling of $t_c$ with $λ^{-1}$, and ensemble-size independence of the inaccessibility threshold -- all consistent with three decades of Loschmidt echo experiments and confirmed in a stadium-billiard simulation reported here. Underlying everything: quantum mechanics conserves information exactly. Entropy, defined as the logarithm of the multiplicity $Ω$ -- the number of possibilities consistent with the available information -- can only increase when information becomes operationally inaccessible. The second law reflects not a breakdown of microscopic reversibility, but the dynamical inaccessibility of the information required to reverse it.</abstract>
    </arXiv>

            </metadata>
        </record>

    </GetRecord>
</OAI-PMH>