<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<OAI-PMH xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" 
         xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance"
         xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/OAI-PMH.xsd">
    <responseDate>2026-07-12T23:24:47Z</responseDate>
                <request verb="GetRecord" identifier="oai:arXiv.org:2605.14050v1" metadataPrefix="arXiv">http://oaipmh.arxiv.org/oai</request>


    <GetRecord>
                <record>
                <header>
        <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:2605.14050</identifier>
        <datestamp>2026-05-15</datestamp>
            <setSpec>physics:gr-qc</setSpec>
            <setSpec>physics:hep-th</setSpec>
    </header>

            <metadata>
                        <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ https://oaipmh.arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
        <id>2605.14050</id>
        <created>2026-05-13</created>
            <updated>2026-05-15</updated>
        <authors>
                <author>
                    <keyname>Forget</keyname>
                        <forenames>Thomas</forenames>
                </author>
                <author>
                    <keyname>Paranjape</keyname>
                        <forenames>M. B.</forenames>
                </author>
                <author>
                    <keyname>Yajnik</keyname>
                        <forenames>Urjit</forenames>
                </author>
        </authors>
        <title>Reflecting Gravitons: The Graviton Laser and the Gertsenshtein effect</title>
            <categories>gr-qc hep-th</categories>
            <comments>Honourable Mention 2026 Gravity Research Foundation Essay Competition</comments>
            <report-no>UdeM-GPP-TH-26-308</report-no>
            <license>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0/</license>
            <abstract>Graviton lasers have been considered in the past, \cite{gl}, but practical terrestrial implementations appear infeasible. The absence of any known mechanism to reflect gravitons means that it remains unclear how a graviton beam could be directed repeatedly through a putative lasing medium. Astrophysical graviton lasing is still a possibilty as circular graviton orbits around blackholes afford the possibility of an arbitrarily long path length through the lasing medium of ultra-light dark matter \cite{bhgl,nhaxs}. In this essay, we consider the possibility of a graviton laser that could be constructed in a laboratory setting. The graviton lasing medium could be one of many possible gravitating systems, of which we give three possible examples. We calculate the possibility of reflecting the gravitons by using the conversion of gravitons into photons in an external magnetic field, the Gertsenshtein effect, \cite{Gertsenshtein1962}. We may convert the gravitons to photons, then reflect the photons, then reconvert the photons into gravitons via the same effect, and then pass them through the graviton lasing medium. With an identical apparatus on the other side, we can essentially extend the path length of the gravitons through the lasing medium as arbitrarily long as desired.</abstract>
    </arXiv>

            </metadata>
        </record>

    </GetRecord>
</OAI-PMH>