<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<OAI-PMH xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" 
         xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance"
         xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/OAI-PMH.xsd">
    <responseDate>2026-07-13T06:22:15Z</responseDate>
                <request verb="GetRecord" identifier="oai:arXiv.org:2604.18928" metadataPrefix="arXiv">http://oaipmh.arxiv.org/oai</request>


    <GetRecord>
                <record>
                <header>
        <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:2604.18928</identifier>
        <datestamp>2026-04-22</datestamp>
            <setSpec>physics:nucl-th</setSpec>
            <setSpec>physics:physics:plasm-ph</setSpec>
    </header>

            <metadata>
                        <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ https://oaipmh.arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
        <id>2604.18928</id>
        <created>2026-04-21</created>
            <updated>2026-04-22</updated>
        <authors>
                <author>
                    <keyname>Wang</keyname>
                        <forenames>Hong-Yi</forenames>
                </author>
                <author>
                    <keyname>Li</keyname>
                        <forenames>Yu-Qi</forenames>
                </author>
                <author>
                    <keyname>Wu</keyname>
                        <forenames>Qian</forenames>
                </author>
                <author>
                    <keyname>Cui</keyname>
                        <forenames>Zhu-Fang</forenames>
                </author>
        </authors>
        <title>A novel approach to proton-boron-11 fusion</title>
            <categories>nucl-th physics.plasm-ph</categories>
            <comments>7 pages, 6 figures, 1 table</comments>
            <license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license>
            <abstract>Proton-boron-11 (p-$^{11}$B) fusion is a highly attractive aneutronic pathway for clean energy production, offering abundant fuel, negligible neutron activation, and the potential for direct energy conversion of charged $α$ particles. However, its practical implementation is severely hindered by the extremely high Coulomb barrier, necessitating ignition temperatures far beyond those of conventional deuterium-tritium reactions. In this work, we propose a novel approach to enhance the low-energy fusion cross-section by introducing a negative muon ($μ$). Instead of relying on the thermal equilibrium formation of a muonic molecule, we investigate a kinetic scenario in which a muonic hydrogen atom (p$μ$) is formed first and subsequently bombarded with a $^{11}$B nucleus. We quantitatively characterize the dynamic screening of the proton&#39;s Coulomb field by the tightly bound $μ$ cloud, the resulting modified Coulomb potential substantially lowers the effective barrier at intermediate separations. We also evaluate the penetrability, reaction cross-section, and reactivity of the p$μ$-$^{11}$B system, the results indicate that the inclusion of $μ$ enhances the tunneling probability by several orders of magnitude at incident energies below 100~keV, thereby significantly reducing the threshold for the nuclear reaction. This mechanism offers a promising alternative perspective for catalyzing p-$^{11}$B fusion, and also suggests a potential ignition pathway.</abstract>
    </arXiv>

            </metadata>
        </record>

    </GetRecord>
</OAI-PMH>