<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<OAI-PMH xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" 
         xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance"
         xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/OAI-PMH.xsd">
    <responseDate>2026-07-13T06:21:42Z</responseDate>
                <request verb="GetRecord" identifier="oai:arXiv.org:2512.06212" metadataPrefix="arXiv">http://oaipmh.arxiv.org/oai</request>


    <GetRecord>
                <record>
                <header>
        <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:2512.06212</identifier>
        <datestamp>2025-12-09</datestamp>
            <setSpec>physics:nucl-ex</setSpec>
            <setSpec>physics:cond-mat:mtrl-sci</setSpec>
    </header>

            <metadata>
                        <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ https://oaipmh.arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
        <id>2512.06212</id>
        <created>2025-12-05</created>
            <updated>2025-12-09</updated>
        <authors>
                <author>
                    <keyname>Karahadian</keyname>
                        <forenames>Micah. E.</forenames>
                </author>
                <author>
                    <keyname>Colborne</keyname>
                        <forenames>Matthew</forenames>
                </author>
                <author>
                    <keyname>Persaud</keyname>
                        <forenames>Arun</forenames>
                </author>
                <author>
                    <keyname>Schenkel</keyname>
                        <forenames>Thomas</forenames>
                </author>
                <author>
                    <keyname>Munday</keyname>
                        <forenames>Jeremy N.</forenames>
                </author>
        </authors>
        <title>Enhanced nuclear fusion in the sub-keV energy regime</title>
            <categories>nucl-ex cond-mat.mtrl-sci</categories>
            <comments>10 pages, 3 figures</comments>
            <license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license>
            <abstract>Nuclear fusion requires overcoming or traversing a repulsive Coulomb barrier of hundreds of kiloelectronvolts, rendering the probability of fusion at sub-keV energies vanishingly small. Yet in condensed matter, the electronic and structural environment of reacting nuclei can profoundly alter fusion rates. Here we demonstrate that deuterium-deuterium fusion within metallic foils exhibits a pronounced enhancement and reaction yield plateau below energies of 2.5 keV- contrary to the expected exponential suppression with decreasing energy. Using a dual-chamber platform that combines electrochemical deuterium loading with ion-beam bombardment, we show that fusion yields in palladium and titanium hydrides are enhanced by over 10^18 compared to theoretical bare-nucleus fusion rates. These results demonstrate that access to low-energy fusion processes can be governed by materials degrees of freedom. This materials-driven fusion regime establishes a reproducible, tunable framework for studying and ultimately engineering nuclear reactions in solids. While the reaction rates reported here are low, these insights into materials-modulated fusion processes offer a potential foundation for understanding how condensed-matter environments could influence future fusion-energy concepts.</abstract>
    </arXiv>

            </metadata>
        </record>

    </GetRecord>
</OAI-PMH>