<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<OAI-PMH xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" 
         xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance"
         xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/OAI-PMH.xsd">
    <responseDate>2026-07-13T06:28:53Z</responseDate>
                <request verb="GetRecord" identifier="oai:arXiv.org:2512.18801" metadataPrefix="arXiv">http://oaipmh.arxiv.org/oai</request>


    <GetRecord>
                <record>
                <header>
        <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:2512.18801</identifier>
        <datestamp>2025-12-23</datestamp>
            <setSpec>physics:quant-ph</setSpec>
    </header>

            <metadata>
                        <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ https://oaipmh.arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
        <id>2512.18801</id>
        <created>2025-12-21</created>
            <updated>2025-12-23</updated>
        <authors>
                <author>
                    <keyname>Gao</keyname>
                        <forenames>Xiaoting</forenames>
                </author>
                <author>
                    <keyname>Zhu</keyname>
                        <forenames>Yan</forenames>
                </author>
                <author>
                    <keyname>Sun</keyname>
                        <forenames>Feng-Xiao</forenames>
                </author>
                <author>
                    <keyname>Wu</keyname>
                        <forenames>Ya-Dong</forenames>
                </author>
                <author>
                    <keyname>He</keyname>
                        <forenames>Qiongyi</forenames>
                </author>
        </authors>
        <title>Foundation Model for Unified Characterization of Optical Quantum States</title>
            <categories>quant-ph</categories>
            <license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license>
            <abstract>Machine learning methods have been used to infer specific properties of limited families of optical quantum states, but a unified model that predicts a broad range of properties for practically relevant-especially multimode non-Gaussian-states without full tomography is still lacking. Here we introduce the first foundation model for the characterization of optical quantum states across a wide range of complexity, defined by three key factors: non-Gaussianity, number of modes, and degree of squeezing. We show that a single model pretrained on low-complexity states can be directly applied to characterize states of higher complexity. With limited fine-tuning, the model adapts to downstream tasks such as predicting quantum fidelity and Wigner negativity over a broad class of experimentally relevant states, including strongly non-Gaussian Schrödinger cat states, multimode systems with up to ten modes, and highly squeezed states with squeezing levels up to 10.4dB. Our results establish a unified framework for characterizing optical quantum states from limited measurement data, enabling efficient certification of quantum states relevant to optical quantum information computation, communication and metrology.</abstract>
    </arXiv>

            </metadata>
        </record>

    </GetRecord>
</OAI-PMH>