<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<OAI-PMH xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" 
         xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance"
         xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/OAI-PMH.xsd">
    <responseDate>2026-07-13T06:25:29Z</responseDate>
                <request verb="GetRecord" identifier="oai:arXiv.org:2510.13247" metadataPrefix="arXiv">http://oaipmh.arxiv.org/oai</request>


    <GetRecord>
                <record>
                <header>
        <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:2510.13247</identifier>
        <datestamp>2025-10-16</datestamp>
            <setSpec>physics:quant-ph</setSpec>
            <setSpec>physics:physics:bio-ph</setSpec>
            <setSpec>physics:physics:hist-ph</setSpec>
    </header>

            <metadata>
                        <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ https://oaipmh.arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
        <id>2510.13247</id>
        <created>2025-10-15</created>
            <updated>2025-10-16</updated>
        <authors>
                <author>
                    <keyname>Adlam</keyname>
                        <forenames>Emily C.</forenames>
                </author>
                <author>
                    <keyname>McQueen</keyname>
                        <forenames>Kelvin J.</forenames>
                </author>
                <author>
                    <keyname>Waegell</keyname>
                        <forenames>Mordecai</forenames>
                </author>
        </authors>
        <title>Agency cannot be a purely quantum phenomenon</title>
            <categories>quant-ph physics.bio-ph physics.hist-ph</categories>
            <comments>26 pages, 2 figures</comments>
            <license>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0/</license>
            <abstract>What are the physical requirements for agency? We investigate whether a purely quantum system (one evolving unitarily in a coherent regime without decoherence or collapse) can satisfy three minimal conditions for agency: an agent must be able to create a world-model, use it to evaluate the likely consequences of alternative actions, and reliably perform the action that maximizes expected utility. We show that the first two conditions conflict with the no-cloning theorem, which forbids copying unknown quantum states: world-model construction requires copying information from the environment, and deliberation requires copying the world-model to assess multiple actions. Approximate cloning strategies do not permit sufficient fidelity or generality for agency to be viable in purely quantum systems. The third agency condition also fails due to the linearity of quantum dynamics. These results imply four key consequences. First, agency requires significant classical resources, placing clear constraints on its physical basis. Second, they provide insight into how classical agents emerge within a quantum universe. Third, they show that quantum computers cannot straightforwardly simulate agential behavior without significant classical components. Finally, they challenge quantum theories of agency, free will, and consciousness.</abstract>
    </arXiv>

            </metadata>
        </record>

    </GetRecord>
</OAI-PMH>