<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<OAI-PMH xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" 
         xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance"
         xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/OAI-PMH.xsd">
    <responseDate>2026-07-13T06:28:02Z</responseDate>
                <request verb="GetRecord" identifier="oai:arXiv.org:2512.14463" metadataPrefix="arXiv">http://oaipmh.arxiv.org/oai</request>


    <GetRecord>
                <record>
                <header>
        <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:2512.14463</identifier>
        <datestamp>2025-12-17</datestamp>
            <setSpec>physics:quant-ph</setSpec>
    </header>

            <metadata>
                        <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ https://oaipmh.arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
        <id>2512.14463</id>
        <created>2025-12-16</created>
            <updated>2025-12-17</updated>
        <authors>
                <author>
                    <keyname>Wang</keyname>
                        <forenames>Xin</forenames>
                </author>
                <author>
                    <keyname>Liao</keyname>
                        <forenames>Zeyang</forenames>
                </author>
        </authors>
        <title>Super-Heisenberg-limited Sensing via Collective Subradiance in Waveguide QED</title>
            <categories>quant-ph</categories>
            <license>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0/</license>
            <abstract>We explore the quantum-metrological potential of subwavelength-spaced emitter arrays coupled to a one-dimensional nanophotonic waveguide. In this system, strong dipole--dipole interactions profoundly modify the collective optical response, leading to the emergence of ultranarrow subradiant resonances. Through an eigenmode analysis of the effective non-Hermitian Hamiltonian, we derive a universal scaling law for the decay rate of the most subradiant state, which exhibits an $ N^{-3} $ scaling with even-odd oscillatory behavior in the deep-subwavelength regime. This scaling is directly observable in the single-photon scattering spectrum, enabling the detection of minute changes in atomic separation with a figure of merit that scales as $ N^3 $. The quantum Fisher information (QFI) scales as $N^6$ and can be closely approached by measuring spectral shifts near the steepest slope of the most subradiant resonance. These enhancements remain robust under realistic positional disorder, confirming that dipole--dipole-engineered subradiance provides a viable resource for quantum metrology. Our work bridges many-body waveguide quantum electrodynamics and high-precision sensing, opening a route toward scalable quantum sensors on integrated nanophotonic platforms.</abstract>
    </arXiv>

            </metadata>
        </record>

    </GetRecord>
</OAI-PMH>