<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<OAI-PMH xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" 
         xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance"
         xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/OAI-PMH.xsd">
    <responseDate>2026-07-13T21:13:18Z</responseDate>
                <request verb="GetRecord" identifier="oai:arXiv.org:2601.03787" metadataPrefix="arXiv">http://oaipmh.arxiv.org/oai</request>


    <GetRecord>
                <record>
                <header>
        <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:2601.03787</identifier>
        <datestamp>2026-04-10</datestamp>
            <setSpec>physics:physics:comp-ph</setSpec>
            <setSpec>physics:cond-mat:stat-mech</setSpec>
            <setSpec>physics:math-ph</setSpec>
            <setSpec>math:math:MP</setSpec>
    </header>

            <metadata>
                        <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ https://oaipmh.arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
        <id>2601.03787</id>
        <created>2026-04-09</created>
            <updated>2026-04-10</updated>
        <authors>
                <author>
                    <keyname>Najem</keyname>
                        <forenames>Sara</forenames>
                </author>
                <author>
                    <keyname>Mouawad</keyname>
                        <forenames>Amer E.</forenames>
                </author>
        </authors>
        <title>Finding Graph Isomorphisms in Heated Spaces in Almost No Time</title>
            <categories>physics.comp-ph cond-mat.stat-mech math-ph math.MP</categories>
            <license>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0/</license>
            <abstract>Determining whether two graphs are structurally identical is a fundamental problem with applications spanning mathematics, computer science, chemistry, and network science. Despite decades of study, graph isomorphism remains a challenging algorithmic task, particularly for highly regular structures. Here we introduce a new algorithmic approach based on ideas from spectral graph theory and geometry that constructs candidate correspondences between vertices using their curvatures. Any correspondence produced by the algorithm is explicitly verified, ensuring that non-isomorphic graphs are never incorrectly identified as isomorphic. Although the method does not yet guarantee success on all inputs, we find that it correctly resolves every instance tested in deterministic polynomial time, including a broad collection of graphs known to be difficult for classical techniques. These results demonstrate that enriched spectral methods can be far more powerful than previously understood, and suggest a promising direction for the practical resolution of the complexity of the graph isomorphism problem.</abstract>
    </arXiv>

            </metadata>
        </record>

    </GetRecord>
</OAI-PMH>