<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<OAI-PMH xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" 
         xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance"
         xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/OAI-PMH.xsd">
    <responseDate>2026-07-13T06:25:23Z</responseDate>
                <request verb="GetRecord" identifier="oai:arXiv.org:2509.20832" metadataPrefix="arXiv">http://oaipmh.arxiv.org/oai</request>


    <GetRecord>
                <record>
                <header>
        <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:2509.20832</identifier>
        <datestamp>2025-09-26</datestamp>
            <setSpec>physics:astro-ph:GA</setSpec>
            <setSpec>physics:astro-ph:CO</setSpec>
    </header>

            <metadata>
                        <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ https://oaipmh.arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
        <id>2509.20832</id>
        <created>2025-09-25</created>
            <updated>2025-09-26</updated>
        <authors>
                <author>
                    <keyname>Zhao</keyname>
                        <forenames>Mengke</forenames>
                </author>
                <author>
                    <keyname>Li</keyname>
                        <forenames>Guang-Xing</forenames>
                </author>
        </authors>
        <title>Galactic Contrail in NGC 3627 caused by Dwarf Galaxy Candidate or Massive Black Hole Flyby</title>
            <categories>astro-ph.GA astro-ph.CO</categories>
            <license>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-sa/4.0/</license>
            <abstract>We report the discovery of a kpc scale molecular contrail in the spiral galaxy NGC 3627, a narrow structure spanning 8 kpc in length with a width of 200 pc and an extreme aspect ratio of 40, observed in both mid-infrared dust emission (PHANGS-JWST) and CO(2-1) gas (PHANGS-ALMA). This contrail size significantly exceeds the size of any known analogs in the Milky Way and exhibits supersonic turbulence (10 km/s). Its morphology and dynamics are consistent with gravitational focusing by a flyby compact object of mass 1e6 M_sun, likely a massive black hole or a dwarf galaxy nucleus, traversing the disk at &gt;300 km/s. The crossing time of such a contrail, estimated from its width and velocity dispersion, is only $\sim 20$ Myr, implying a recent interaction. This contrail can be caused by a dwarf galaxy, or massive black hole nucleus. This discovery establishes galactic-scale contrails as probes of massive dark objects interacting with medium in and around galactic disks.</abstract>
    </arXiv>

            </metadata>
        </record>

    </GetRecord>
</OAI-PMH>