<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<OAI-PMH xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" 
         xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance"
         xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/OAI-PMH.xsd">
    <responseDate>2026-07-13T10:41:22Z</responseDate>
                <request verb="GetRecord" identifier="oai:arXiv.org:2606.01141" metadataPrefix="arXiv">http://oaipmh.arxiv.org/oai</request>


    <GetRecord>
                <record>
                <header>
        <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:2606.01141</identifier>
        <datestamp>2026-06-02</datestamp>
            <setSpec>physics:gr-qc</setSpec>
            <setSpec>physics:hep-th</setSpec>
    </header>

            <metadata>
                        <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ https://oaipmh.arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
        <id>2606.01141</id>
        <created>2026-05-31</created>
            <updated>2026-06-02</updated>
        <authors>
                <author>
                    <keyname>Nashed</keyname>
                        <forenames>G. G. L.</forenames>
                </author>
                <author>
                    <keyname>Hanafy</keyname>
                        <forenames>Waleed El</forenames>
                </author>
                <author>
                    <keyname>Abebe</keyname>
                        <forenames>Amare</forenames>
                </author>
                <author>
                    <keyname>Bamba</keyname>
                        <forenames>Kazuharu</forenames>
                </author>
                <author>
                    <keyname>Saridakis</keyname>
                        <forenames>Emmanuel N.</forenames>
                </author>
        </authors>
        <title>Rotating traversable wormholes and particle dynamics in $f(R,T)$ gravity</title>
            <categories>gr-qc hep-th</categories>
            <comments>19 pages, 6 figures</comments>
            <license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license>
            <abstract>Traversable wormholes are among the most interesting solutions of gravitational theories, but within General Relativity they generally require exotic matter violating the null energy condition. Modified gravity theories with matter-geometry coupling provide a promising framework in which wormhole geometries may instead be supported by effective gravitational contributions. Motivated by this possibility, we investigate rotating traversable wormholes in $f(R,T)$ gravity, where $R$ is the scalar curvature and $T$ is the trace of the energy-momentum tensor, within the slow-rotation approximation. We construct stationary and axisymmetric wormhole solutions supported by an anisotropic fluid and show that the obtained geometries are regular, asymptotically flat, horizonless, and satisfy the flare-out condition at the throat. A central result is that the matter sector satisfies both the null and strong energy conditions, indicating that traversable rotating wormholes can be supported without exotic matter. We further analyze particle motion, frame dragging, and non-geodesic effects arising from matter-geometry coupling, together with shadow deformation and gravitational lensing signatures induced by rotation. A preliminary stability analysis based on sound-speed conditions indicates the physical viability of the solutions. These results demonstrate that rotating wormholes in $f(R,T)$ gravity constitute physically consistent compact configurations with potentially observable astrophysical signatures.</abstract>
    </arXiv>

            </metadata>
        </record>

    </GetRecord>
</OAI-PMH>