<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<OAI-PMH xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" 
         xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance"
         xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/OAI-PMH.xsd">
    <responseDate>2026-07-13T06:28:36Z</responseDate>
                <request verb="GetRecord" identifier="oai:arXiv.org:2606.30635" metadataPrefix="arXiv">http://oaipmh.arxiv.org/oai</request>


    <GetRecord>
                <record>
                <header>
        <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:2606.30635</identifier>
        <datestamp>2026-06-30</datestamp>
            <setSpec>physics:quant-ph</setSpec>
            <setSpec>physics:cond-mat:dis-nn</setSpec>
            <setSpec>physics:cond-mat:stat-mech</setSpec>
            <setSpec>physics:hep-th</setSpec>
    </header>

            <metadata>
                        <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ https://oaipmh.arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
        <id>2606.30635</id>
        <created>2026-06-29</created>
            <updated>2026-06-30</updated>
        <authors>
                <author>
                    <keyname>Ippoliti</keyname>
                        <forenames>Matteo</forenames>
                </author>
        </authors>
        <title>Provable random-matrix spectral ramp in a static, geometrically local Hamiltonian</title>
            <categories>quant-ph cond-mat.dis-nn cond-mat.stat-mech hep-th</categories>
            <comments>4 + 2 + 2 pages, 3 figures</comments>
            <license>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0/</license>
            <abstract>Quantum chaos is commonly associated with the emergence of random-matrix statistics in the spectra of quantum systems. A useful diagnostic is provided by the spectral form factor (SFF), which for random matrix ensembles displays a universal linear-growth regime (`ramp&#39;). In the last decade, a landmark result by Bertini, Kos and Prosen (BKP) identified for the first time a class of geometrically local quantum dynamics of finite-dimensional particles where the SFF provably exhibits a random-matrix ramp: periodically driven (Floquet) qudit chains whose evolution is described by `dual-unitary&#39; circuits. Here, building on the BKP result and on a recently proposed variant of the Feynman-Kitaev clock construction, we obtain a spectral ramp in a class of static, geometrically local Hamiltonians. Our strategy is to embed the Floquet quasienergy spectrum of a dual-unitary circuit into the energy spectrum of a static local Hamiltonian, and to prove that the latter&#39;s connected SFF inherits the BKP ramp within a symmetry sector. This is to our knowledge the first proof of a spectral ramp in a time-independent, geometrically local many-body system with finite local Hilbert space dimension.</abstract>
    </arXiv>

            </metadata>
        </record>

    </GetRecord>
</OAI-PMH>