<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<OAI-PMH xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" 
         xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance"
         xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/OAI-PMH.xsd">
    <responseDate>2026-07-11T20:28:09Z</responseDate>
                <request verb="GetRecord" identifier="oai:arXiv.org:2601.02533v2" metadataPrefix="arXiv">http://oaipmh.arxiv.org/oai</request>


    <GetRecord>
                <record>
                <header>
        <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:2601.02533</identifier>
        <datestamp>2026-01-22</datestamp>
            <setSpec>physics:astro-ph:EP</setSpec>
            <setSpec>physics:astro-ph:GA</setSpec>
            <setSpec>physics:astro-ph:IM</setSpec>
    </header>

            <metadata>
                        <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ https://oaipmh.arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
        <id>2601.02533</id>
        <created>2026-01-21</created>
            <updated>2026-01-22</updated>
        <authors>
                <author>
                    <keyname>Hibberd</keyname>
                        <forenames>Adam</forenames>
                </author>
                <author>
                    <keyname>Eubanks</keyname>
                        <forenames>T. Marshall</forenames>
                </author>
                <author>
                    <keyname>Hein</keyname>
                        <forenames>Andreas</forenames>
                </author>
        </authors>
        <title>Catching 3I/ATLAS Using a Solar Oberth</title>
            <categories>astro-ph.EP astro-ph.GA astro-ph.IM</categories>
            <comments>Submitted to JBIS</comments>
            <license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license>
            <abstract>The third interstellar object to be discovered, 3I/ATLAS, has a unique and continually unfolding story to tell about its nature and origin as it is monitored by telescopes on Earth, orbiting Earth and around the Solar System. Previous research into missions using chemical propulsion have only really addressed the direct case, where the opportunity to launch already expired before 3I/ATLAS&#39;s discovery. In contrast, investigations herein exploit &#39;Optimum Interplanetary Trajectory Software&#39; to simulate an alternative indirect option for chemical propulsion, namely the Solar Oberth Manoeuvre (SOM). For a SOM, a low perihelion burn provides maximum benefit from the Oberth Effect, and accelerates the spacecraft rapidly towards the receding 3I/ATLAS. Though in principle feasible, results indicate this option presents significant challenges. For possible launch years between 2031 and 2037 inclusive, a 2035 launch permits the most efficient transfer to 3I/ATLAS. The reference mission requires a SOM at 3.2 Solar Radii from the Sun&#39;s centre, with an intercept after 35-50 years. It is found the SOM can leverage spacecraft masses up to $\sim{500}$ kg. Two or three solid propellant boosters could deliver the required SOM $Δ$V, and furthermore a refuelled Starship Block 3 in LEO has sufficient performance for such a mission. As inevitable with a SOM, some of the payload mass would be needed for a heat shield to protect against the high solar flux at low perihelion.</abstract>
    </arXiv>

            </metadata>
        </record>

    </GetRecord>
</OAI-PMH>