<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<OAI-PMH xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" 
         xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance"
         xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/OAI-PMH.xsd">
    <responseDate>2026-07-12T13:07:49Z</responseDate>
                <request verb="GetRecord" identifier="oai:arXiv.org:2505.00872v4" metadataPrefix="arXiv">http://oaipmh.arxiv.org/oai</request>


    <GetRecord>
                <record>
                <header>
        <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:2505.00872</identifier>
        <datestamp>2025-12-01</datestamp>
            <setSpec>physics:quant-ph</setSpec>
    </header>

            <metadata>
                        <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ https://oaipmh.arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
        <id>2505.00872</id>
        <created>2025-11-26</created>
            <updated>2025-12-01</updated>
        <authors>
                <author>
                    <keyname>Forbes</keyname>
                        <forenames>Richard G.</forenames>
                </author>
        </authors>
        <title>Field emission tunnelling as a window onto fundamental issues in quantum mechanics</title>
            <categories>quant-ph</categories>
            <comments>16 pages, 4 figures. This is accepted version of a book chapter, but this version (v4) notes publisher change of book title</comments>
            <license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license>
            <abstract>Field electron emission (FE) and electrostatic field ionization (ESFI) are quantum-mechanical tunnelling processes that provide basic theory for important technologies. However, the basic theories of FE and ESF1 are not yet completely understood. This paper attempts to identify related fundamental quantum mechanical issues, problems and relevances. The following topics have been identified as deserving closer investigation or discussion. (a) The implication that if a &#34;real electron&#34; cannot have negative kinetic energy, then this necessarily implies that a &#34;real electron&#34; is a distributed object rather than a point object. (b) The implication that the language we use to discuss quantum mechanics needs to be changed in order to avoid referring to the &#34;position of a (point) electron&#34;. (c) The idea that &#34;quantum mathematics&#34; (i.e., the mathematics of quantum mechanics) has different utilisations, namely the &#34;matter distribution&#34; and &#34;pathway choice&#34; utilisations, with &#34;measurement&#34; being observed pathway choice. (d) Difficulties with the present formulations of the uncertainty principle and wave-particle duality. (e) Fundamental difficulties in the exact calculation of exchange-and-correlation effects in both FE and ESFI theory. (f) Conceptual problems associated with &#34;seeing electrons&#34; in the field electron (emission) microscope. (g) Field emission tunnelling and the arrow of time. (h) The choice between tunnelling-integral and overlap-integral formulations of tunnelling theory, and the apparent incompleteness of both types of formulation.</abstract>
    </arXiv>

            </metadata>
        </record>

    </GetRecord>
</OAI-PMH>