<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<OAI-PMH xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" 
         xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance"
         xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/OAI-PMH.xsd">
    <responseDate>2026-07-11T07:45:00Z</responseDate>
                <request verb="GetRecord" identifier="oai:arXiv.org:2606.02097v1" metadataPrefix="arXiv">http://oaipmh.arxiv.org/oai</request>


    <GetRecord>
                <record>
                <header>
        <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:2606.02097</identifier>
        <datestamp>2026-06-02</datestamp>
            <setSpec>physics:astro-ph:CO</setSpec>
    </header>

            <metadata>
                        <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ https://oaipmh.arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
        <id>2606.02097</id>
        <created>2026-06-01</created>
            <updated>2026-06-02</updated>
        <authors>
                <author>
                    <keyname>Lee</keyname>
                        <forenames>Tae-Kyoung</forenames>
                </author>
        </authors>
        <title>Redshift Duality with Pantheon+SH0ES in a Planck-anchored Flat $Λ$CDM Framework: Implications for Hubble Tension and Observational Inference</title>
            <categories>astro-ph.CO</categories>
            <comments>Author version comprising 31 pages and 5 figures. Compiled in the MNRAS LaTeX style. Compared with the Advance Access version, this version includes accessibility-related updates to figure captions, updated affiliation and acknowledgements, revised citation labels, and corrected mathematical notation</comments>
            <journal-ref>Monthly Notices of the Royal Astronomical Society, Volume 549, Issue 1, June 2026, stag726</journal-ref>
            <doi>10.1093/mnras/stag726</doi>
            <license>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0/</license>
            <abstract>We test an operationally defined redshift duality in which the observed redshift comprises the standard metric-expansion component together with an additional line-of-sight quantum contribution arising from the cumulative conversion of photon energy into effective mass as a function of path length and frequency. Fitting this hybrid model to the Pantheon+SH0ES compilation, we find that the metric-expansion Hubble constant, $H_Λ$, is recovered to a value consistent with the Planck baseline of $67.4~\mathrm{km\,s^{-1}\,Mpc^{-1}}$ within $\lesssim 0.33σ$. Redshift-binned analyses show that while the flat Lambda cold dark matter ($Λ$CDM) model produces an apparent drift in the inferred Hubble parameter across the Hubble flow, the hybrid model restores the constancy of $H_Λ$ across redshift bins. The correctional trends of cosmological physical quantities re-inferred under this framework further indicate the potential to alleviate anomalies associated with high-redshift galaxies. These results suggest that redshift duality warrants further consideration in observational processing and inference, while preserving consistency with a Planck-anchored flat $Λ$CDM baseline.</abstract>
    </arXiv>

            </metadata>
        </record>

    </GetRecord>
</OAI-PMH>