<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<OAI-PMH xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" 
         xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance"
         xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/OAI-PMH.xsd">
    <responseDate>2026-07-11T07:44:28Z</responseDate>
                <request verb="GetRecord" identifier="oai:arXiv.org:2606.02514v1" metadataPrefix="arXiv">http://oaipmh.arxiv.org/oai</request>


    <GetRecord>
                <record>
                <header>
        <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:2606.02514</identifier>
        <datestamp>2026-06-03</datestamp>
            <setSpec>physics:gr-qc</setSpec>
            <setSpec>physics:astro-ph:CO</setSpec>
    </header>

            <metadata>
                        <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ https://oaipmh.arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
        <id>2606.02514</id>
        <created>2026-06-01</created>
            <updated>2026-06-03</updated>
        <authors>
                <author>
                    <keyname>Davies</keyname>
                        <forenames>Paul C. W.</forenames>
                </author>
                <author>
                    <keyname>Magueijo</keyname>
                        <forenames>João</forenames>
                </author>
        </authors>
        <title>Teleocosmology and quantum post-selection</title>
            <categories>gr-qc astro-ph.CO</categories>
            <license>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0/</license>
            <abstract>Although cosmic acceleration is well established, its physical origin remains contentious. Most explanations invoke either a non-zero vacuum energy, i.e. a cosmological constant, or new fields. We propose instead a mechanism arising purely from quantum mechanics, without additional constants or local sources. The key point is that quantum theory permits both initial and final boundary conditions on a state, here the wave function of the universe. Pre- and post-selected systems are familiar in laboratory quantum mechanics; we extend the idea to minisuperspace quantum cosmology. As a warm-up, we show that a free non-relativistic particle, initially in a semiclassical wave packet and conditioned on a final quantum state, can have an intermediate peak which accelerates even though the Hamiltonian is free. A semiclassical observer would infer a contrived classical force. We then implement the analogous construction in quantum cosmology using connection variables and unimodular time. A forward semiclassical packet, taken for simplicity to describe pure radiation, is post-selected by a normalizable Chern-Simons soliton. The resulting two-boundary amplitude has a peak which leaves the radiation trajectory and enters an accelerating regime, while the forward Hamiltonian has $Λ=0$. A classical model can mimic this trajectory only by introducing a contrived effective component: near the transition it resembles $w\simeq -1$, but when extrapolated it evolves towards strongly phantom behaviour, $w&lt;-1$. The acceleration is therefore more naturally interpreted as a quantum boundary-condition effect than as a local classical source. We also discuss why the Chern-Simons soliton is a clean final state, the small overlap between initial and final states, and possible tell-tale signatures.</abstract>
    </arXiv>

            </metadata>
        </record>

    </GetRecord>
</OAI-PMH>