<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<OAI-PMH xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" 
         xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance"
         xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/OAI-PMH.xsd">
    <responseDate>2026-07-13T06:24:08Z</responseDate>
                <request verb="GetRecord" identifier="oai:arXiv.org:2603.22419" metadataPrefix="arXiv">http://oaipmh.arxiv.org/oai</request>


    <GetRecord>
                <record>
                <header>
        <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:2603.22419</identifier>
        <datestamp>2026-03-25</datestamp>
            <setSpec>physics:astro-ph:HE</setSpec>
            <setSpec>physics:gr-qc</setSpec>
    </header>

            <metadata>
                        <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ https://oaipmh.arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
        <id>2603.22419</id>
        <created>2026-03-23</created>
            <updated>2026-03-25</updated>
        <authors>
                <author>
                    <keyname>Rodríguez</keyname>
                        <forenames>Cecilia Romero</forenames>
                </author>
                <author>
                    <keyname>Seoane</keyname>
                        <forenames>Pau Amaro</forenames>
                </author>
        </authors>
        <title>The Crimson Kiss of Two Giants: Helium Detonation and High-Energy Neutrino Production</title>
            <categories>astro-ph.HE gr-qc</categories>
            <comments>Submitted</comments>
            <license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license>
            <abstract>The coalescence of degenerate helium cores during red giant collisions - a process we term erythrohenosis - introduces a novel class of transient astrophysical sources of high-energy neutrinos. Using stellar models generated with MESA and SPH simulations of the final inspiral phase, we develop a semi-analytical model to estimate the amount of hydrogen mixed into the cores, the energy release ($\approx 4.28 \times 10^{49}$ erg) that heats the remnant to $T_f \approx 5.3 \times 10^8$ K, the magnetic field amplification ($B \approx 1.77 \times 10^{10}$ G), and the resulting neutrino flux. We find that the predicted TeV--PeV neutrino signal can account for the diffuse neutrino flux observed by IceCube and demonstrate that a single merger event within $\sim 2$ Mpc would be detectable in this energy regime. Furthermore, we discuss the probability of a magnetized helium flash and assess the subsequent activation of the CNO cycle in the remnant core due to hydrogen mixing. In particular, neutrinos from the decay of $^{18}$F offer a direct observational test of the detonation. The simultaneous emission of high-energy hadronic neutrinos, gravitational waves, and -- if the optical depth permits -- an electromagnetic signal would constitute a unique multimessenger signature of red giant core collisions, positioning erythrohenosis events as exotic yet potentially observable phenomena in dense stellar systems.</abstract>
    </arXiv>

            </metadata>
        </record>

    </GetRecord>
</OAI-PMH>