<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<OAI-PMH xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" 
         xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance"
         xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/OAI-PMH.xsd">
    <responseDate>2026-07-13T06:21:45Z</responseDate>
                <request verb="GetRecord" identifier="oai:arXiv.org:2601.00044" metadataPrefix="arXiv">http://oaipmh.arxiv.org/oai</request>


    <GetRecord>
                <record>
                <header>
        <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:2601.00044</identifier>
        <datestamp>2026-05-29</datestamp>
            <setSpec>physics:astro-ph:GA</setSpec>
    </header>

            <metadata>
                        <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ https://oaipmh.arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
        <id>2601.00044</id>
        <created>2026-05-28</created>
            <updated>2026-05-29</updated>
        <authors>
                <author>
                    <keyname>Woo</keyname>
                        <forenames>Tak-Pong</forenames>
                </author>
        </authors>
        <title>Born in the Dark: The Catastrophic Collapse of Fuzzy Dark Matter Solitons as the Origin of Little Red Dots</title>
            <categories>astro-ph.GA</categories>
            <comments>Accepted for publication in ApJ. 6 pages, 4 figures</comments>
            <journal-ref>Astrophys. J. 1002, 41 (2026)</journal-ref>
            <doi>10.3847/1538-4357/ae5230</doi>
            <license>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0/</license>
            <abstract>JWST surveys have uncovered a population of compact, red sources (&#34;Little Red Dots,&#34; LRDs) at $z \ge 5$ that exhibit broad Balmer emission yet remain X-ray faint, implying heavy obscuration with $N_H \ge 10^{24}$ cm$^{-2}$. We propose that LRDs may trace a short-lived, obscured phase associated with rapid baryonic inflow inside the deep solitonic cores of fuzzy dark matter (FDM) halos. Combining the soliton size scaling with (i) the observed compact radii ($r_e \sim 30-100$ pc) and (ii) the requirement that Compton-thick columns be achievable within a region of order the core radius, we find that particle masses $m$ few $\times 10^{-22}$ eV are plausible for soliton masses $M_s \sim 10^8 - 10^9 M_\odot$; we adopt $m_{22}=2$ as a fiducial choice. A conservative mass-budget estimate for the obscuring column, together with isothermal hydrostatic stratification, indicates that configurations reaching $N_H \ge 10^{24} - 10^{25}$ cm$^{-2}$ require densities for which radiative losses (cooling and/or diffusion) occur faster than the dynamical time, suggesting that a long-lived static hot atmosphere is unlikely (an &#34;Opacity Crisis&#34;) and that rapid inflow or radiation-pressure-driven evolution is favored. Using $512^3$ pseudo-spectral Schrödinger-Poisson simulations of idealized soliton mergers, we illustrate that compact, high-density soliton cores can form via violent relaxation under representative scalings. We discuss observational implications and tests, and outline the need for future radiation-hydrodynamic modeling to predict demographics and detailed spectra.</abstract>
    </arXiv>

            </metadata>
        </record>

    </GetRecord>
</OAI-PMH>