<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<OAI-PMH xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" 
         xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance"
         xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/OAI-PMH.xsd">
    <responseDate>2026-07-13T06:27:43Z</responseDate>
                <request verb="GetRecord" identifier="oai:arXiv.org:2509.19501" metadataPrefix="arXiv">http://oaipmh.arxiv.org/oai</request>


    <GetRecord>
                <record>
                <header>
        <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:2509.19501</identifier>
        <datestamp>2025-09-25</datestamp>
            <setSpec>physics:quant-ph</setSpec>
            <setSpec>physics:gr-qc</setSpec>
            <setSpec>physics:physics:atom-ph</setSpec>
    </header>

            <metadata>
                        <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ https://oaipmh.arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
        <id>2509.19501</id>
        <created>2025-09-23</created>
            <updated>2025-09-25</updated>
        <authors>
                <author>
                    <keyname>Fromonteil</keyname>
                        <forenames>Charles</forenames>
                </author>
                <author>
                    <keyname>Vasilyev</keyname>
                        <forenames>Denis V.</forenames>
                </author>
                <author>
                    <keyname>Zache</keyname>
                        <forenames>Torsten V.</forenames>
                </author>
                <author>
                    <keyname>Hammerer</keyname>
                        <forenames>Klemens</forenames>
                </author>
                <author>
                    <keyname>Rey</keyname>
                        <forenames>Ana Maria</forenames>
                </author>
                <author>
                    <keyname>Ye</keyname>
                        <forenames>Jun</forenames>
                </author>
                <author>
                    <keyname>Pichler</keyname>
                        <forenames>Hannes</forenames>
                </author>
                <author>
                    <keyname>Zoller</keyname>
                        <forenames>Peter</forenames>
                </author>
        </authors>
        <title>Non-local mass superpositions and optical clock interferometry in atomic ensemble quantum networks</title>
            <categories>quant-ph gr-qc physics.atom-ph</categories>
            <license>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0/</license>
            <abstract>Quantum networks are emerging as powerful platforms for sensing, communication, and fundamental tests of physics. We propose a programmable quantum sensing network based on entangled atomic ensembles, where optical clock qubits emulate mass superpositions in atom and atom-clock interferometry. Our approach uniquely combines scalability to large atom numbers with minimal control requirements, relying only on collective addressing of internal atomic states. This enables the creation of both non-local and local superpositions with spatial separations beyond those achievable in conventional interferometry. Starting from Bell-type seed states distributed via photonic channels, collective operations within atomic ensembles coherently build many-body mass superpositions sensitive to gravitational redshift. The resulting architecture realizes a non-local Ramsey interferometer, with gravitationally induced phase shifts observable in network-based interference patterns. Beyond extending the spatial reach of mass superpositions, our scheme establishes a scalable, programmable platform to probe the interface of quantum mechanics and gravity, and offers a new experimental pathway to test atom and atom-clock interferometer proposals in a network-based quantum laboratory.</abstract>
    </arXiv>

            </metadata>
        </record>

    </GetRecord>
</OAI-PMH>