<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<OAI-PMH xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" 
         xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance"
         xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/OAI-PMH.xsd">
    <responseDate>2026-07-13T06:24:57Z</responseDate>
                <request verb="GetRecord" identifier="oai:arXiv.org:2606.15759" metadataPrefix="arXiv">http://oaipmh.arxiv.org/oai</request>


    <GetRecord>
                <record>
                <header>
        <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:2606.15759</identifier>
        <datestamp>2026-06-16</datestamp>
            <setSpec>physics:astro-ph:HE</setSpec>
    </header>

            <metadata>
                        <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ https://oaipmh.arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
        <id>2606.15759</id>
        <created>2026-06-14</created>
            <updated>2026-06-16</updated>
        <authors>
                <author>
                    <keyname>Uhm</keyname>
                        <forenames>Z. Lucas</forenames>
                </author>
                <author>
                    <keyname>Lee</keyname>
                        <forenames>Sang-Sung</forenames>
                </author>
                <author>
                    <keyname>Zhang</keyname>
                        <forenames>Bing</forenames>
                </author>
                <author>
                    <keyname>Racusin</keyname>
                        <forenames>Judith</forenames>
                </author>
                <author>
                    <keyname>Rani</keyname>
                        <forenames>Bindu</forenames>
                </author>
                <author>
                    <keyname>Im</keyname>
                        <forenames>Myungshin</forenames>
                </author>
                <author>
                    <keyname>Chung</keyname>
                        <forenames>Aeree</forenames>
                </author>
                <author>
                    <keyname>Lee</keyname>
                        <forenames>Hyung Mok</forenames>
                </author>
        </authors>
        <title>A Universal Physics Defining the Radiation Spectra of Blazars and Gamma-Ray Bursts</title>
            <categories>astro-ph.HE</categories>
            <comments>ApJ published, 9 pages, 4 figures, 1 table</comments>
            <license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license>
            <abstract>Blazars and gamma-ray bursts (GRBs) are both cosmic beacons of extreme energy release powered by relativistic jets. However, they originate from tremendously different environments. Blazars are the sustained powerhouses driven by supermassive black holes at galactic centers, whereas GRBs are the transient death signals of massive stars or merging compact objects. Here we show that, despite the enormous differences, a universal physics defines the radiation spectra of blazars and GRBs. The blazar spectrum is well described by a &#34;log-parabola&#34; function. Employing a simple toy model with a single optically-thin region of a decreasing magnetic field, we produce the log-parabola spectrum very naturally for blazars. We find that the blazar spectrum is shaped by the &#34;cooling physics&#34; of relativistic electrons in the fast-cooling regime, which we identify as the universal physics since we previously showed that the fast-cooling physics of electrons with a decreasing magnetic field also explains the mysterious low-energy spectral index of the gamma-ray spectrum for a majority of GRBs. This fast-cooling physics of electrons likely nails down the physical origin underlying the universal scaling of the jet energetics between blazars and GRBs, which was observationally suggested more than a decade ago. We highlight that the spectrum shaper in both blazars and GRBs is the cooling physics, not the acceleration mechanism. This finding is conventional-belief-defying and may open up new avenues in a wide range of astrophysics.</abstract>
    </arXiv>

            </metadata>
        </record>

    </GetRecord>
</OAI-PMH>