<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<OAI-PMH xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" 
         xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance"
         xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/OAI-PMH.xsd">
    <responseDate>2026-07-13T06:24:46Z</responseDate>
                <request verb="GetRecord" identifier="oai:arXiv.org:2605.19653" metadataPrefix="arXiv">http://oaipmh.arxiv.org/oai</request>


    <GetRecord>
                <record>
                <header>
        <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:2605.19653</identifier>
        <datestamp>2026-05-20</datestamp>
            <setSpec>physics:astro-ph:HE</setSpec>
            <setSpec>physics:astro-ph:CO</setSpec>
            <setSpec>physics:gr-qc</setSpec>
    </header>

            <metadata>
                        <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ https://oaipmh.arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
        <id>2605.19653</id>
        <created>2026-05-19</created>
            <updated>2026-05-20</updated>
        <authors>
                <author>
                    <keyname>Zhou</keyname>
                        <forenames>Huan</forenames>
                </author>
                <author>
                    <keyname>Li</keyname>
                        <forenames>Zhengxiang</forenames>
                </author>
                <author>
                    <keyname>Shao</keyname>
                        <forenames>Cheng-Gang</forenames>
                </author>
                <author>
                    <keyname>Wang</keyname>
                        <forenames>Xi-Jing</forenames>
                </author>
                <author>
                    <keyname>Liao</keyname>
                        <forenames>Kai</forenames>
                </author>
                <author>
                    <keyname>Gao</keyname>
                        <forenames>He</forenames>
                </author>
                <author>
                    <keyname>Zhu</keyname>
                        <forenames>Zong-Hong</forenames>
                </author>
        </authors>
        <title>Evidence for Intermediate-Mass Black Holes From Microlensing Signatures in CHIME/FRB catalog 2</title>
            <categories>astro-ph.HE astro-ph.CO gr-qc</categories>
            <comments>11 pages, 5 figures, 1 table</comments>
            <license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license>
            <abstract>Intermediate-mass black holes (IMBHs) are the missing link in the cosmic hierarchy of black holes, bridging the gap between stellar-mass black holes and supermassive ones. They also serve as unique laboratories for testing strong-field gravity and are prime targets for future multi-messenger observations. However, IMBHs are a population that has remained notoriously difficult to detect. The microlensing effect of fast radio bursts (FRBs) can serve as a clean and powerful method to probe IMBHs. In this work, we develop a pipeline to search for microlensed FRBs based on their dynamic spectra and apply it to the CHIME/FRB Catalog 2. Two microlensing signatures have been identified in two separate sources, i.e. FRB~20190131D and FRB~20211115A. The inferred lens masses for these two signatures are $\sim[539-609]~M_{\odot}$ and $\sim[1544-2571]~M_{\odot}$, respectively. Here we interpret them as evidence for IMBHs. If there are no intervening structures-such as galaxies or clusters-along the line of sights for these two sources, the two identified IMBHs might be isolated and of primordial origins. In that case, we obtain primordial black holes (PBHs) within these two mass ranges would constitute $\sim4\%$ of dark matter. Moreover, if these two candidates are not genuine lensing signatures, the abundance of intermediate-mass PBHs with masses $&gt;300,M_{\odot}$ is constrained to be $\sim13\%$ at $95\%$ confidence level. Therefore, more comprehensive observational information for FRBs, together with a deeper understanding of whether the intrinsic emission mechanisms of FRBs can produce lensing-like signals, will be crucial for establishing this effect as a powerful tool for probing (primordial) IMBHs.</abstract>
    </arXiv>

            </metadata>
        </record>

    </GetRecord>
</OAI-PMH>