<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<OAI-PMH xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" 
         xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance"
         xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/OAI-PMH.xsd">
    <responseDate>2026-07-04T19:17:55Z</responseDate>
                <request verb="GetRecord" identifier="oai:arXiv.org:2606.02897v1" metadataPrefix="arXiv">http://oaipmh.arxiv.org/oai</request>


    <GetRecord>
                <record>
                <header>
        <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:2606.02897</identifier>
        <datestamp>2026-06-03</datestamp>
            <setSpec>physics:astro-ph:CO</setSpec>
    </header>

            <metadata>
                        <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ https://oaipmh.arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
        <id>2606.02897</id>
        <created>2026-06-01</created>
            <updated>2026-06-03</updated>
        <authors>
                <author>
                    <keyname>Remazeilles</keyname>
                        <forenames>Mathieu</forenames>
                </author>
        </authors>
        <title>Field-level constraints on cosmic birefringence with a hybrid $E$-$B$ internal linear combination</title>
            <categories>astro-ph.CO</categories>
            <comments>4 pages, 2 figures, contribution to the 2026 Cosmology session of the 60th Rencontres de Moriond</comments>
            <license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license>
            <abstract>Cosmic birefringence, a signature of parity-violating physics, rotates the cosmic microwave background (CMB) polarization plane, generating correlations between CMB $E$- and $B$-mode anisotropies. Measuring this effect remains challenging due to degeneracies with spurious rotations from instrumental polarization angle miscalibration and limited knowledge of Galactic foreground $EB$ correlations. We present a blind, map-based approach based on a multi-Stokes hybrid internal linear combination (ILC) that breaks this degeneracy and disentangles correlated and uncorrelated CMB polarization components. By jointly combining $E$- and $B$-mode frequency maps, the method preserves achromatic birefringence-induced CMB anisotropies while downweighting foregrounds and chromatic CMB anisotropies resulting from instrumental miscalibration. This enables a direct spatial linear-regression estimator of the birefringence angle. Applied to LiteBIRD simulations, the method yields competitive constraints on birefringence. Applied to Planck PR4 data, we measure a birefringence angle $β\simeq 0.32^\circ \pm 0.12^\circ$, consistent with previous independent analyses and stable across sky fractions.</abstract>
    </arXiv>

            </metadata>
        </record>

    </GetRecord>
</OAI-PMH>