<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<OAI-PMH xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" 
         xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance"
         xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/OAI-PMH.xsd">
    <responseDate>2026-07-13T06:21:07Z</responseDate>
                <request verb="GetRecord" identifier="oai:arXiv.org:2508.19301" metadataPrefix="arXiv">http://oaipmh.arxiv.org/oai</request>


    <GetRecord>
                <record>
                <header>
        <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:2508.19301</identifier>
        <datestamp>2025-12-02</datestamp>
            <setSpec>physics:quant-ph</setSpec>
    </header>

            <metadata>
                        <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ https://oaipmh.arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
        <id>2508.19301</id>
        <created>2025-12-01</created>
            <updated>2025-12-02</updated>
        <authors>
                <author>
                    <keyname>Frank</keyname>
                        <forenames>Alejandro</forenames>
                </author>
        </authors>
        <title>Time Symmetry, Retrocausality and the Emergent: Arrow of Time the Quantum Time-Symmetric Interpretation (QTSI)</title>
            <categories>quant-ph</categories>
            <license>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-sa/4.0/</license>
            <abstract>Microscopic quantum laws are time-symmetric: nothing in the Schr횄쨋dinger equation or its relativistic extensions distinguishes future from past. Yet measurements produce irreversible records, an apparently one-way causal flow, and the familiar notion that causes precede effects. Within the Quantum Time-Symmetric Interpretation (QTSI), this asymmetry is not fundamental but emergent. Isolated quantum systems are described by a two-component temporal state containing forward- and backward-propagating amplitudes. Their mixing, governed by a parameter $횓혬(횕혮)$, defines a retrocausal coherence time $횕혙_{RC}(횕혮)$ beyond which advanced components are suppressed. As the system couples to amplifying environments characterized by a macroscopic parameter $횕혮$, $횓혬(횕혮)$ decreases and the backward component is dynamically eliminated, giving rise to classical causality and effective collapse. QTSI aligns naturally with time-symmetric approaches from Wheeler--Feynman, Aharonov, and Price, agrees with all weak-measurement and quantum eraser results in their operational regimes, and predicts specific signatures in temporal echoes and chaotic cavities. Detailed formal and experimental developments appear in the Supplementary Addenda.</abstract>
    </arXiv>

            </metadata>
        </record>

    </GetRecord>
</OAI-PMH>