<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<OAI-PMH xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" 
         xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance"
         xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/OAI-PMH.xsd">
    <responseDate>2026-07-11T21:17:00Z</responseDate>
                <request verb="GetRecord" identifier="oai:arXiv.org:2601.03659v2" metadataPrefix="arXiv">http://oaipmh.arxiv.org/oai</request>


    <GetRecord>
                <record>
                <header>
        <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:2601.03659</identifier>
        <datestamp>2026-03-03</datestamp>
            <setSpec>physics:astro-ph:EP</setSpec>
            <setSpec>physics:cond-mat:mtrl-sci</setSpec>
    </header>

            <metadata>
                        <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ https://oaipmh.arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
        <id>2601.03659</id>
        <created>2026-03-02</created>
            <updated>2026-03-03</updated>
        <authors>
                <author>
                    <keyname>Liu</keyname>
                        <forenames>Daohong</forenames>
                </author>
                <author>
                    <keyname>Zhang</keyname>
                        <forenames>Wei</forenames>
                </author>
                <author>
                    <keyname>He</keyname>
                        <forenames>Yu</forenames>
                </author>
                <author>
                    <keyname>Guo</keyname>
                        <forenames>Xinzhuan</forenames>
                </author>
                <author>
                    <keyname>Zhang</keyname>
                        <forenames>Chuanyu</forenames>
                </author>
                <author>
                    <keyname>Sun</keyname>
                        <forenames>Yang</forenames>
                </author>
        </authors>
        <title>Protonic thermoelectric effect of Superionic H2O and magnetic field generation in Uranus and Neptune</title>
            <categories>astro-ph.EP cond-mat.mtrl-sci</categories>
            <license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license>
            <abstract>Uranus and Neptune are characterized by anomalously tilted and multi-dipole magnetic fields, which poses substantial challenges for elucidating the internal mechanisms generating magnetic fields. Recent investigations confirmed that superionic H2O is thermodynamically stable and constitutes the dominant H2O phase within their icy mantles. In this study, we demonstrate that the superionic H2O ice exhibits a pronounced protonic thermoelectric effect, in which the maximum Seebeck coefficient within the interior of Uranus can reach approximately 620 uV/K, whereas that of Neptune is lower, within the range of 570-585 uV/K. Consequently, temperature gradients in the icy mantles can induce proton convection, which in turn drives magnetic field generation. Based on this novel mechanism, the disparities in magnetic field strength between Uranus and Neptune can be accounted for exclusively by their differing internal temperature gradients, and the predicted values are in agreement with observations.</abstract>
    </arXiv>

            </metadata>
        </record>

    </GetRecord>
</OAI-PMH>