<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<OAI-PMH xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" 
         xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance"
         xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/OAI-PMH.xsd">
    <responseDate>2026-07-13T06:24:36Z</responseDate>
                <request verb="GetRecord" identifier="oai:arXiv.org:2604.19922" metadataPrefix="arXiv">http://oaipmh.arxiv.org/oai</request>


    <GetRecord>
                <record>
                <header>
        <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:2604.19922</identifier>
        <datestamp>2026-04-23</datestamp>
            <setSpec>physics:astro-ph:CO</setSpec>
    </header>

            <metadata>
                        <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ https://oaipmh.arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
        <id>2604.19922</id>
        <created>2026-04-21</created>
            <updated>2026-04-23</updated>
        <authors>
                <author>
                    <keyname>Zhang</keyname>
                        <forenames>Wangzheng</forenames>
                </author>
                <author>
                    <keyname>Chu</keyname>
                        <forenames>Ming-chung</forenames>
                </author>
                <author>
                    <keyname>Liao</keyname>
                        <forenames>Shihong</forenames>
                </author>
        </authors>
        <title>Measuring neutrino mass and asymmetry through galaxy pairwise peculiar velocity</title>
            <categories>astro-ph.CO</categories>
            <comments>9 pages, 3 figures</comments>
            <license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license>
            <abstract>Cosmic neutrinos are among the most abundant fermions in the Universe, yet the values of their masses and chemical potentials remain uncertain. In this Letter, we present the first constraints on the total neutrino mass $M_ν$ and the neutrino asymmetry parameter $η^2$ derived from the mean galaxy pairwise peculiar velocity in the quasi-linear and nonlinear regimes. We develop a simulation-based analysis pipeline that connects neutrino properties to predictions of galaxy pairwise velocity, and apply it to galaxy data from the Cosmicflows-4 grouped catalog. Our analysis is performed within two independent cosmological frameworks, based on cosmological parameters derived from Cosmic microwave background (CMB) and local distance ladder measurements, respectively. By performing fits to the galaxy pairwise velocity, we obtain consistent constraints from both frameworks. Quoting posterior means with 68% CL, we find $M_ν= 0.24^{+0.34}_{-0.18}\ \mathrm{eV}$ and $η^2 = 2.14^{+0.30}_{-0.32}$ in the CMB framework, and $M_ν= 0.37^{+0.34}_{-0.26}\ \mathrm{eV}$ and $η^2 = 2.4^{+2.1}_{-1.6}$ in the local framework. In particular, we find a 7$σ$ measurement of a non-zero neutrino asymmetry in the CMB framework. These neutrino parameters are consistent with those, in our previous work, obtained from the Planck CMB temperature power spectrum. These results demonstrate that galaxy pairwise velocities provide an independent and sensitive probe of neutrino properties, opening a new avenue for testing neutrino physics with large-scale structure observations.</abstract>
    </arXiv>

            </metadata>
        </record>

    </GetRecord>
</OAI-PMH>