<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<OAI-PMH xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" 
         xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance"
         xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/OAI-PMH.xsd">
    <responseDate>2026-07-13T06:27:26Z</responseDate>
                <request verb="GetRecord" identifier="oai:arXiv.org:2606.12901" metadataPrefix="arXiv">http://oaipmh.arxiv.org/oai</request>


    <GetRecord>
                <record>
                <header>
        <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:2606.12901</identifier>
        <datestamp>2026-06-12</datestamp>
            <setSpec>physics:hep-th</setSpec>
            <setSpec>physics:gr-qc</setSpec>
    </header>

            <metadata>
                        <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ https://oaipmh.arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
        <id>2606.12901</id>
        <created>2026-06-11</created>
            <updated>2026-06-12</updated>
        <authors>
                <author>
                    <keyname>Trenggana</keyname>
                        <forenames>Anom</forenames>
                </author>
                <author>
                    <keyname>Zen</keyname>
                        <forenames>Freddy P.</forenames>
                </author>
        </authors>
        <title>Quantum Gravity Induced Entanglement from Propagating Gravitons</title>
            <categories>hep-th gr-qc</categories>
            <comments>20 pages, 1 figure</comments>
            <license>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0/</license>
            <abstract>In this work, we show how the interaction between propagating modes of the quantized gravitational field and two massive particles trapped in a harmonic oscillator potential can cause the two particles to become entangled. To demonstrate this, we employ an operator-based approach within the framework of the Feynman-Vernon influence functional. Through this method, we find that the effect of the gravitational field on the generated entanglement is encoded in the commutation relations of the gravitational field. This result indicates that, within the framework of the model considered, entanglement arises through the quantum contributions of the gravitational field. Furthermore, this work also shows that entanglement is not formed instantaneously after the two particles interact with the gravitational field. Instead, there exists a time delay, proportional to the distance between the particles, before entanglement is established. This result reflects the causal propagation nature of gravitational interactions. In general, the entanglement generated through this mechanism is extremely small. Nevertheless, if the initial quantum states of the two massive particles are chosen to be squeezed states, the amount of generated entanglement can be enhanced, although the resulting effect remains very small.</abstract>
    </arXiv>

            </metadata>
        </record>

    </GetRecord>
</OAI-PMH>