<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<OAI-PMH xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" 
         xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance"
         xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/OAI-PMH.xsd">
    <responseDate>2026-07-13T06:20:50Z</responseDate>
                <request verb="GetRecord" identifier="oai:arXiv.org:2606.24028" metadataPrefix="arXiv">http://oaipmh.arxiv.org/oai</request>


    <GetRecord>
                <record>
                <header>
        <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:2606.24028</identifier>
        <datestamp>2026-07-02</datestamp>
            <setSpec>physics:astro-ph:EP</setSpec>
    </header>

            <metadata>
                        <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ https://oaipmh.arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
        <id>2606.24028</id>
        <created>2026-07-01</created>
            <updated>2026-07-02</updated>
        <authors>
                <author>
                    <keyname>Pinault</keyname>
                        <forenames>Lewis J.</forenames>
                </author>
                <author>
                    <keyname>Lacki</keyname>
                        <forenames>Brian C.</forenames>
                </author>
                <author>
                    <keyname>Crawford</keyname>
                        <forenames>Ian A.</forenames>
                </author>
                <author>
                    <keyname>Siemion</keyname>
                        <forenames>Andrew P. V.</forenames>
                </author>
        </authors>
        <title>Micron-Scale Technosignatures: How a Cubic Metre of Lunar Regolith May Begin to Constrain the Number of Past Technological Civilisations in the Galaxy</title>
            <categories>astro-ph.EP</categories>
            <comments>Submitted to the International Journal of Astrobiology on 10 March 2026; currently under review. v3 further reconciles used/unused references, and provides additional and correctly matched doi insertions</comments>
            <license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license>
            <abstract>Building on Arkhipov&#39;s proposal that technogenic artefacts may survive natural interstellar transport and accumulate on airless Solar System bodies, we examine the prospects for identifying micron-scale engineered particulate material within the lunar regolith. We analyse the transport of micron and submicron grains through the interstellar medium, including gas drag, sputtering, and ISM phase-dependent survival, and show that refractory particles with characteristic radii of order 0.3 microns may traverse kiloparsec scales over residence times of 0.1-1 Gyr. Solar radiation pressure and heliospheric filtering define a dynamically constrained slow-arrival channel in which a small fraction of grains reach the Earth-Moon system at relative velocities compatible with survival upon impact. Combining these properties with regolith-mixing constraints yields quantitative upper limits on the cumulative undirected technomaterial output of large-scale spacefaring civilisations: a null detection in a cubic metre of regolith excludes scenarios in which Solar-type stars typically disperse more than approximately 0.09 Earth mass equivalents of long-lived artificial particulate debris over Galactic history. Deliberate targeting of the inner Solar System with artificial particulate matter defines a complementary regime characterised by the visitation frequency and deposited mass of such releases, for which the probabilities of detection may be orders of magnitude higher. We outline a multi-modal detection strategy integrating machine-vision triage with laboratory forensic techniques to identify anomalous grains within a well-characterised natural background. Particulate technosignatures thus establish an experimentally accessible form of exo-archaeology, capable of placing meaningful constraints -- and, in favourable cases, yielding direct material evidence -- of the Galaxy&#39;s technological history.</abstract>
    </arXiv>

            </metadata>
        </record>

    </GetRecord>
</OAI-PMH>