<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<OAI-PMH xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" 
         xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance"
         xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/OAI-PMH.xsd">
    <responseDate>2026-07-12T14:18:00Z</responseDate>
                <request verb="GetRecord" identifier="oai:arXiv.org:2505.00336v2" metadataPrefix="arXiv">http://oaipmh.arxiv.org/oai</request>


    <GetRecord>
                <record>
                <header>
        <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:2505.00336</identifier>
        <datestamp>2026-03-31</datestamp>
            <setSpec>physics:quant-ph</setSpec>
    </header>

            <metadata>
                        <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ https://oaipmh.arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
        <id>2505.00336</id>
        <created>2026-02-27</created>
            <updated>2026-03-31</updated>
        <authors>
                <author>
                    <keyname>Fukuda</keyname>
                        <forenames>Ryuya</forenames>
                </author>
                <author>
                    <keyname>Iinuma</keyname>
                        <forenames>Masataka</forenames>
                </author>
                <author>
                    <keyname>Matsumoto</keyname>
                        <forenames>Yuto</forenames>
                </author>
                <author>
                    <keyname>Hofmann</keyname>
                        <forenames>Holger F.</forenames>
                </author>
        </authors>
        <title>Experimental evidence for the physical delocalization of individual photons in an interferometer</title>
            <categories>quant-ph</categories>
            <comments>22 pages, 7 figures</comments>
            <journal-ref>New J. Phys. 28, 034515 (2026)</journal-ref>
            <doi>10.1088/1367-2630/ae51b7</doi>
            <license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license>
            <abstract>It is generally assumed that the detection of a single photon as part of an interference pattern erases all possible which-path information. However, recent insights suggest that weak interactions can provide non-trivial experimental evidence for the physical delocalization of a single particle passing through an interferometer. Here, we present an experimental setup that can quantify the delocalization of individual photons using the rate of polarization flips induced by small rotations of polarization. The results show that photons detected in equal superpositions of the two paths are delocalized when detected in a high probability output port, and &#34;super-localized&#34; when detected in a low probability output port. We can thus confirm that delocalization depends on the detection of photons in the output of the interferometer, providing direct experimental evidence for the dependence of physical reality on the context established by a future measurement.</abstract>
    </arXiv>

            </metadata>
        </record>

    </GetRecord>
</OAI-PMH>