<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<OAI-PMH xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" 
         xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance"
         xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/OAI-PMH.xsd">
    <responseDate>2026-07-13T06:21:22Z</responseDate>
                <request verb="GetRecord" identifier="oai:arXiv.org:2510.16012" metadataPrefix="arXiv">http://oaipmh.arxiv.org/oai</request>


    <GetRecord>
                <record>
                <header>
        <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:2510.16012</identifier>
        <datestamp>2025-10-21</datestamp>
            <setSpec>physics:physics:soc-ph</setSpec>
            <setSpec>physics:quant-ph</setSpec>
    </header>

            <metadata>
                        <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ https://oaipmh.arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
        <id>2510.16012</id>
        <created>2025-10-15</created>
            <updated>2025-10-21</updated>
        <authors>
                <author>
                    <keyname>Khrennikov</keyname>
                        <forenames>Andrei</forenames>
                </author>
        </authors>
        <title>Social Laser Theory as a Natural Extension of Quantum-Like Modeling</title>
            <categories>physics.soc-ph quant-ph</categories>
            <license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license>
            <abstract>This paper presents a comprehensive review of the Social Laser Theory (SLT) as a natural extension of the broader framework of Quantum-Like Modeling (QLM). While QLM applies the mathematical formalism of quantum theory . such as Hilbert space representations, interference, and non-commutative observables - to model context-dependent and non-classical phenomena in cognition, decision-making, and social behavior, SLT advances this approach by integrating concepts from quantum field theory. The theory conceptualizes social systems as ensembles of social atoms capable of absorbing and emitting quantized units of social energy. Under conditions analogous to population inversion in physical lasers, external informational stimuli (e.g., media signals or mobilizing rhetoric) can trigger coherence across the population, resulting in large-scale, synchronized collective actions such as protests or ideological shifts. SLT thus provides a formal framework for understanding the amplification and coherence of social energy leading to abrupt phase-like transitions in collective behavior. Beyond its metaphorical appeal, the theory proposes measurable quantities and predictive parameters that may support empirical diagnostics of sociopolitical dynamics. By bridging micro-level psychological processes with macro-level sociological phenomena, SLT extends QLM into the domain of complex social systems, offering a mathematically grounded paradigm for interpreting rapid transformations in contemporary societies.</abstract>
    </arXiv>

            </metadata>
        </record>

    </GetRecord>
</OAI-PMH>