<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<OAI-PMH xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" 
         xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance"
         xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/OAI-PMH.xsd">
    <responseDate>2026-07-13T06:23:21Z</responseDate>
                <request verb="GetRecord" identifier="oai:arXiv.org:2512.04166" metadataPrefix="arXiv">http://oaipmh.arxiv.org/oai</request>


    <GetRecord>
                <record>
                <header>
        <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:2512.04166</identifier>
        <datestamp>2026-01-26</datestamp>
            <setSpec>physics:astro-ph:GA</setSpec>
            <setSpec>physics:astro-ph:CO</setSpec>
            <setSpec>physics:astro-ph:HE</setSpec>
    </header>

            <metadata>
                        <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ https://oaipmh.arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
        <id>2512.04166</id>
        <created>2026-01-23</created>
            <updated>2026-01-26</updated>
        <authors>
                <author>
                    <keyname>van Dokkum</keyname>
                        <forenames>Pieter</forenames>
                </author>
                <author>
                    <keyname>Jennings</keyname>
                        <forenames>Connor</forenames>
                </author>
                <author>
                    <keyname>Pasha</keyname>
                        <forenames>Imad</forenames>
                </author>
                <author>
                    <keyname>Conroy</keyname>
                        <forenames>Charlie</forenames>
                </author>
                <author>
                    <keyname>Kaul</keyname>
                        <forenames>Ish</forenames>
                </author>
                <author>
                    <keyname>Abraham</keyname>
                        <forenames>Roberto</forenames>
                </author>
                <author>
                    <keyname>Danieli</keyname>
                        <forenames>Shany</forenames>
                </author>
                <author>
                    <keyname>Romanowsky</keyname>
                        <forenames>Aaron J.</forenames>
                </author>
                <author>
                    <keyname>Tremblay</keyname>
                        <forenames>Grant</forenames>
                </author>
        </authors>
        <title>JWST Confirmation of a Runaway Supermassive Black Hole via its Supersonic Bow Shock</title>
            <categories>astro-ph.GA astro-ph.CO astro-ph.HE</categories>
            <comments>ApJ Letters, in press. The single most important new observation is the 600 km/s gradient in the position-velocity diagram, shown in Fig. 7. The discovery paper (van Dokkum et al. 2023) was right about the key interpretation but had quite a few of the details wrong. This is reviewed in section 6.5</comments>
            <license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license>
            <abstract>We present JWST/NIRSpec IFU observations of a candidate runaway supermassive black hole at the tip of a 62 kpc-long linear feature at z=0.96. The JWST data show a sharp kinematic discontinuity at the tip, with a radial velocity change of $\approx 600$ km/s across 0.1&#39;&#39; (1 kpc). The velocity gradient, together with the projected post-shock flow velocity of $\approx 300$ km/s, is well described by a simple shock-compression model of a supersonic object, with a velocity of $v_{BH} = 954^{+110}_{-126}$ km/s and an inclination $i=29^{+6}_{-3}$ deg. The previously puzzling kinematics along the linear feature, with the observed radial velocity decreasing from $\approx 300$ km/s near the tip to $\approx 100$ km/s closer to the former host galaxy, are naturally explained as gradual downstream mixing of shocked gas with the circumgalactic medium through turbulent entrainment. The bow shock interpretation is further supported by the morphology of the gas at the tip of the wake and an analysis of the [OIII]/H$α$, [NII]/H$α$, [SII]/H$α$, and [SIII]/[SII] line ratios. The line ratios are consistent with fast radiative shocks and rapid cooling, with best-fit shock velocities that are in agreement with expectations from the black hole velocity and the shock geometry. Energy conservation over the lifetime of the wake suggests a SMBH mass of $M_{BH} \gtrsim 10^7$ M$_{\odot}$. These results confirm that the wake is powered by a supersonic runaway supermassive black hole, a long-predicted consequence of gravitational-wave recoil or multi-body ejection from galactic nuclei.</abstract>
    </arXiv>

            </metadata>
        </record>

    </GetRecord>
</OAI-PMH>