<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<OAI-PMH xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" 
         xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance"
         xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/OAI-PMH.xsd">
    <responseDate>2026-07-11T09:04:58Z</responseDate>
                <request verb="GetRecord" identifier="oai:arXiv.org:2606.05082v1" metadataPrefix="arXiv">http://oaipmh.arxiv.org/oai</request>


    <GetRecord>
                <record>
                <header>
        <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:2606.05082</identifier>
        <datestamp>2026-06-04</datestamp>
            <setSpec>physics:astro-ph:CO</setSpec>
            <setSpec>physics:astro-ph:SR</setSpec>
            <setSpec>physics:gr-qc</setSpec>
    </header>

            <metadata>
                        <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ https://oaipmh.arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
        <id>2606.05082</id>
        <created>2026-06-03</created>
            <updated>2026-06-04</updated>
        <authors>
                <author>
                    <keyname>Mahapatra</keyname>
                        <forenames>Premachand</forenames>
                </author>
                <author>
                    <keyname>Miller</keyname>
                        <forenames>Andrew L.</forenames>
                </author>
                <author>
                    <keyname>Das</keyname>
                        <forenames>Prasanta Kumar</forenames>
                </author>
        </authors>
        <title>First Constraints on the Ellipticities of Self-Interacting Fermionic Dark Matter Admixed Neutron Stars from Continuous Gravitational-Wave Searches</title>
            <categories>astro-ph.CO astro-ph.SR gr-qc</categories>
            <comments>14 pages, 11 figures</comments>
            <license>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0/</license>
            <abstract>We investigate continuous gravitational-wave (CW) emission from rapidly rotating, non-axisymmetric, isolated neutron stars admixed with self-interacting fermionic dark matter (DM) and hosting DM-induced equatorial deformations (``dark mountains&#39;&#39;). In particular, we develop a formalism that describes how DM accumulation inside the star changes its structure, how dark mountains arise from an anisotropic distribution of DM inside it, and how the star&#39;s moment of inertia and thus the amplitude of its GW emission is increased compared to that of an ordinary neutron star. Moreover, using results from all-sky searches for CWs from non-axisymmetric neutron stars performed with LIGO O3 data, we place the first constraints on the DM-induced ellipticities $\varepsilon$ of DM-admixed neutron stars across the full GW frequency range analyzed by LIGO and for a range of self-interaction strengths. With the same data, we also exclude portions of the DM-mass/self-interaction coupling strength parameter space that would have produced detectable GW signals in LIGO O3 data. We rule out at best (at worst) couplings $g\gtrsim10^{-5.5}$ ($g\gtrsim 10^{-4}$) for DM-admixed neutron stars with ellipticities $\varepsilon=10^{-7}$ ($\varepsilon=10^{-9}$) at distances $d=1$ ($d=10$) kpc away for DM masses of $m_χ\in[0.1,10]$ GeV. Furthermore, we show that even larger regions of this parameter space will become accessible to next-generation detectors, such as Einstein Telescope and Cosmic Explorer, with exclusions as strong as $g\gtrsim10^{-6}$ for neutron stars located $d=10$ kpc away for $\varepsilon=10^{-7}$. Our results demonstrate that searches for CWs naturally provide a direct probe of dark mountains sustained by DM-admixed neutron stars.</abstract>
    </arXiv>

            </metadata>
        </record>

    </GetRecord>
</OAI-PMH>