<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<OAI-PMH xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" 
         xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance"
         xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/OAI-PMH.xsd">
    <responseDate>2026-07-13T21:14:02Z</responseDate>
                <request verb="GetRecord" identifier="oai:arXiv.org:2606.03622" metadataPrefix="arXiv">http://oaipmh.arxiv.org/oai</request>


    <GetRecord>
                <record>
                <header>
        <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:2606.03622</identifier>
        <datestamp>2026-06-03</datestamp>
            <setSpec>physics:physics:ed-ph</setSpec>
    </header>

            <metadata>
                        <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ https://oaipmh.arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
        <id>2606.03622</id>
        <created>2026-06-02</created>
            <updated>2026-06-03</updated>
        <authors>
                <author>
                    <keyname>Pohit</keyname>
                        <forenames>Koushiki</forenames>
                </author>
                <author>
                    <keyname>Hamed</keyname>
                        <forenames>Razan</forenames>
                </author>
                <author>
                    <keyname>Rebello</keyname>
                        <forenames>N. Sanjay</forenames>
                </author>
        </authors>
        <title>Two Paths to Learning Physics: How Games and Simulations Shape Physics Learning Among Physics and Engineering Students</title>
            <categories>physics.ed-ph</categories>
            <comments>6 pages, 5 figures, SITE Conference</comments>
            <license>http://creativecommons.org/publicdomain/zero/1.0/</license>
            <abstract>The use of digital tools like educational video games and interactive simulations is of great importance to physics education. This study investigates the sequencing effects of an educational game, &#39;Photon Jump&#39; and PhET Photoelectric Effect simulation on students&#39; perception of such tools for learning about the photoelectric effect. Using a counterbalanced quasi-experimental crossover design, a total of 55 physics and engineering students from a calculus-based physics course were divided into two groups of comparable sizes and administered the game and the simulation in reverse order followed by 9 open ended reflection questions. The results show a clear preference for the game-based activity over the simulation. Additionally, gaming frequency showed no correlation with willingness to use similar tools, suggesting broad accessibility. Thematic analysis revealed that intuitive and explorative learning through the game was reinforced by the analytical aspect of the simulation.</abstract>
    </arXiv>

            </metadata>
        </record>

    </GetRecord>
</OAI-PMH>