<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<OAI-PMH xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" 
         xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance"
         xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/OAI-PMH.xsd">
    <responseDate>2026-07-13T06:29:08Z</responseDate>
                <request verb="GetRecord" identifier="oai:arXiv.org:2512.16629" metadataPrefix="arXiv">http://oaipmh.arxiv.org/oai</request>


    <GetRecord>
                <record>
                <header>
        <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:2512.16629</identifier>
        <datestamp>2026-06-16</datestamp>
            <setSpec>physics:gr-qc</setSpec>
            <setSpec>physics:hep-ph</setSpec>
            <setSpec>physics:hep-th</setSpec>
            <setSpec>physics:math-ph</setSpec>
            <setSpec>math:math:MP</setSpec>
    </header>

            <metadata>
                        <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ https://oaipmh.arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
        <id>2512.16629</id>
        <created>2026-06-15</created>
            <updated>2026-06-16</updated>
        <authors>
                <author>
                    <keyname>Zhang</keyname>
                        <forenames>Shi-Hao</forenames>
                </author>
                <author>
                    <keyname>Li</keyname>
                        <forenames>Zi-Yuan</forenames>
                </author>
                <author>
                    <keyname>Zhang</keyname>
                        <forenames>Jing-Fei</forenames>
                </author>
                <author>
                    <keyname>Zhang</keyname>
                        <forenames>Xin</forenames>
                </author>
        </authors>
        <title>Universal geometric framework for black hole phase transitions: from multivaluedness to classification</title>
            <categories>gr-qc hep-ph hep-th math-ph math.MP</categories>
            <comments>20 pages, 2 figures</comments>
            <journal-ref>Eur. Phys. J. C 86, 642 (2026)</journal-ref>
            <doi>10.1140/epjc/s10052-026-15851-5</doi>
            <license>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0/</license>
            <abstract>Recent studies have revealed synchronized multivalued behavior in thermodynamic, dynamical, and geometric quantities during the black hole first-order phase transition, which enables a diagnosis from different perspectives, yet its fundamental origin has remained poorly understood. By constructing a unified geometric framework integrating real analysis and covering space theory, we reveal the universal mathematical mechanism behind this phenomenon. We prove that this multivaluedness originates from two non-degenerate critical points in the temperature function $T(r_+)$, where $r_+$ is the horizon radius, which fold the parameter space into a three-sheeted covering structure. As a direct application, we propose that a black hole undergoes a first-order phase transition if and only if its $T(r_+)$ curve has two extrema. Accordingly, we establish a classification scheme, denoted $A1$, $A2$, and $B$ for black holes. This scheme offers a complementary perspective to classifications based on global topological invariants. Our work provides a theoretical foundation for diagnosing phase transitions via multivaluedness and establishes a unified geometric perspective on black hole thermodynamics, chaotic dynamics, and spacetime structure during first-order phase transitions.</abstract>
    </arXiv>

            </metadata>
        </record>

    </GetRecord>
</OAI-PMH>