<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<OAI-PMH xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" 
         xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance"
         xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/OAI-PMH.xsd">
    <responseDate>2026-07-11T10:08:30Z</responseDate>
                <request verb="GetRecord" identifier="oai:arXiv.org:2606.06305v1" metadataPrefix="arXiv">http://oaipmh.arxiv.org/oai</request>


    <GetRecord>
                <record>
                <header>
        <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:2606.06305</identifier>
        <datestamp>2026-06-05</datestamp>
            <setSpec>physics:astro-ph:HE</setSpec>
            <setSpec>physics:astro-ph:SR</setSpec>
    </header>

            <metadata>
                        <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ https://oaipmh.arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
        <id>2606.06305</id>
        <created>2026-06-04</created>
            <updated>2026-06-05</updated>
        <authors>
                <author>
                    <keyname>Oliveira</keyname>
                        <forenames>Alexandre S.</forenames>
                </author>
                <author>
                    <keyname>Souza</keyname>
                        <forenames>D. C.</forenames>
                </author>
                <author>
                    <keyname>Luna</keyname>
                        <forenames>G. J. M.</forenames>
                </author>
                <author>
                    <keyname>Rodrigues</keyname>
                        <forenames>C. V.</forenames>
                </author>
        </authors>
        <title>A micronova burst in the intermediate polar IGR J17014-4306</title>
            <categories>astro-ph.HE astro-ph.SR</categories>
            <comments>7 pages, 4 figures, submitted to MNRAS</comments>
            <license>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0/</license>
            <abstract>We report the detection of a short optical burst in TESS data of IGR J17014-4306, the eclipsing intermediate polar with the longest known orbital period. The burst lasts 1.56 d and shows multiple peaks, reaching $(9.3 \pm 0.2) \times 10^{33}$ erg s$^{-1}$, and releases a total energy of $(3.25 \pm 0.01) \times 10^{38}$ erg. The burst parameters are consistent with those of a micronova eruption, currently understood as a thermonuclear runaway in the magnetically-confined accretion column. From its energy, we infer a burned column mass of $\sim 1.6 \times 10^{-11}$ M$_\odot$, which implies a recurrence time of $\sim 20$ d. Our search for similar events in long-term Gaia, ASAS-SN, and AAVSO light curves reveals 16 possible fast brightenings over $\sim 11$ yr, suggesting that micronova events may be frequent in IGR J17014-4306. Timing analysis of the TESS data shows that the white-dwarf spin period remains stable before and after the burst. During the burst, however, the power spectrum becomes more complex and exhibits multiple peaks. The classification of IGR J17014-4306 as a micronova brings the total number of confirmed systems to eight. Its extreme orbital period and eclipsing nature make it an ideal test-bed for further studies of magnetically confined thermonuclear burning on white dwarfs.</abstract>
    </arXiv>

            </metadata>
        </record>

    </GetRecord>
</OAI-PMH>