<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<OAI-PMH xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" 
         xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance"
         xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/OAI-PMH.xsd">
    <responseDate>2026-07-13T09:49:21Z</responseDate>
                <request verb="GetRecord" identifier="oai:arXiv.org:2605.26696" metadataPrefix="arXiv">http://oaipmh.arxiv.org/oai</request>


    <GetRecord>
                <record>
                <header>
        <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:2605.26696</identifier>
        <datestamp>2026-05-27</datestamp>
            <setSpec>physics:gr-qc</setSpec>
            <setSpec>physics:hep-th</setSpec>
    </header>

            <metadata>
                        <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ https://oaipmh.arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
        <id>2605.26696</id>
        <created>2026-05-26</created>
            <updated>2026-05-27</updated>
        <authors>
                <author>
                    <keyname>Ahmed</keyname>
                        <forenames>Faizuddin</forenames>
                </author>
                <author>
                    <keyname>Al-Badawi</keyname>
                        <forenames>Ahmad</forenames>
                </author>
                <author>
                    <keyname>Sakallı</keyname>
                        <forenames>İzzet</forenames>
                </author>
        </authors>
        <title>Are Petrov type-N and D spacetimes admitting CTCs valid in $f(R,\mathcal{L}_m,Φ,X)$ gravity?</title>
            <categories>gr-qc hep-th</categories>
            <comments>20 pages, 10 Figures, 1 Table (comments are welcome)</comments>
            <license>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0/</license>
            <abstract>We ask whether two classical time-machine geometries, the Ori (2005) compact-vacuum-core metric and the Ahmed (2018) four-dimensional generalisation of Misner space, remain admissible exact solutions when the gravitational sector is enlarged to the recently proposed $f(R,\mathcal{L}_{m},Φ,X)$ class, an extension of $f(R,\mathcal{L}_{m})$ that couples curvature, the matter Lagrangian density, a scalar field $Φ$, and its kinetic invariant $X = g^{μν}\nabla_μΦ\nabla_νΦ$. Working with the explicit model $f = R + \mathcal{L}_{m} + (λ/2)\,X$ and a vanishing scalar potential, we compute the curvature invariants, the modified field equations, and the effective stress-energy components produced by the harmonic scalar profile $Φ(x,y) = a(x^{2}-y^{2})/2$ in both backgrounds. The Ricci scalar vanishes for the Ori metric and obeys $R = e^{f}(f_{,xx}+f_{,yy})$ for the Ahmed metric; the kinetic invariant takes the explicit forms $X = a^{2}(x^{2}+y^{2})$ and $X = a^{2}e^{f}(x^{2}+y^{2})$, respectively. Both metrics solve the field equations of the modified theory with anisotropic matter sources, and the chronology-violating regions $g_{zz}&lt;0$ (Ori) and $g_{ψψ}&lt;0$ (Ahmed) survive the modification. Energy-density profiles measured by a closed-timelike-curve observer match those measured by a static observer outside the chronology horizon, so the additional scalar degree of freedom in $f(R,\mathcal{L}_{m},Φ,X)$ gravity does not enforce a chronology-protection mechanism in either background. The conclusion mirrors the parallel result for the Li time-machine and supplies a consistency test for scalar-extended modified gravity in non-globally-hyperbolic settings.</abstract>
    </arXiv>

            </metadata>
        </record>

    </GetRecord>
</OAI-PMH>