<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<OAI-PMH xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" 
         xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance"
         xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/OAI-PMH.xsd">
    <responseDate>2026-07-13T10:27:22Z</responseDate>
                <request verb="GetRecord" identifier="oai:arXiv.org:2606.00178" metadataPrefix="arXiv">http://oaipmh.arxiv.org/oai</request>


    <GetRecord>
                <record>
                <header>
        <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:2606.00178</identifier>
        <datestamp>2026-06-24</datestamp>
            <setSpec>physics:gr-qc</setSpec>
    </header>

            <metadata>
                        <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ https://oaipmh.arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
        <id>2606.00178</id>
        <created>2026-06-23</created>
            <updated>2026-06-24</updated>
        <authors>
                <author>
                    <keyname>Rebouças</keyname>
                        <forenames>Jonathan A.</forenames>
                </author>
                <author>
                    <keyname>Lustosa</keyname>
                        <forenames>Francisco Bento</forenames>
                </author>
                <author>
                    <keyname>Muniz</keyname>
                        <forenames>Celio R.</forenames>
                </author>
        </authors>
        <title>Traversable Wormholes Supported by Entropy-Inspired Effective Matter Sectors</title>
            <categories>gr-qc</categories>
            <comments>37 pages, 25 figures</comments>
            <license>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0/</license>
            <abstract>The entropic interpretation of gravity suggests that spacetime geometry may encode thermodynamic information associated with microscopic degrees of freedom. In this context, the entropy--geometry correspondence of Refs.[1,2] links modified Bekenstein--Hawking entropies to deformed black-hole geometries and effective anisotropic matter sectors. Motivated by this result, we test whether these entropy-induced density profiles can act as phenomenological sources for traversable wormholes. Here we use the density sector as the thermodynamic input for a Morris--Thorne reconstruction, thereby isolating the role of the entropy-induced radial profile. The radial pressure follows from a barotropic equation of state, $p_r=wρ$, while the remaining variables are determined by the wormhole field equations and anisotropic equilibrium. We analyze five entropy-inspired sectors: Barrow, Tsallis, Kaniadakis, logarithmic, and exponential. Barrow and Tsallis are algebraic negative-density sources; Kaniadakis and exponential profiles are localized; and the logarithmic sector admits negative-density and positive-density phantom-like regimes. In all regular configurations, radial null-energy-condition violation at the throat is tied to the flare-out condition, while the tangential null energy condition and the strong-energy-condition combination diagnose the anisotropic redistribution of exoticity. The TOV balance is sector dependent: in the Barrow and Kaniadakis branches, the gravitational and compensating pressure contributions can reverse their signs together while remaining balanced; the other branches retain a common sign pattern with different degrees of near-throat localization. This framework shows that modified entropy profiles can provide viable effective sources for traversable wormholes, with the supporting mechanism depending sensitively on the underlying entropy deformation.</abstract>
    </arXiv>

            </metadata>
        </record>

    </GetRecord>
</OAI-PMH>