<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<OAI-PMH xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" 
         xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance"
         xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/OAI-PMH.xsd">
    <responseDate>2026-07-11T07:37:14Z</responseDate>
                <request verb="GetRecord" identifier="oai:arXiv.org:2606.02539v1" metadataPrefix="arXiv">http://oaipmh.arxiv.org/oai</request>


    <GetRecord>
                <record>
                <header>
        <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:2606.02539</identifier>
        <datestamp>2026-06-02</datestamp>
            <setSpec>physics:astro-ph:CO</setSpec>
            <setSpec>physics:gr-qc</setSpec>
            <setSpec>physics:hep-ph</setSpec>
    </header>

            <metadata>
                        <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ https://oaipmh.arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
        <id>2606.02539</id>
        <created>2026-06-01</created>
            <updated>2026-06-02</updated>
        <authors>
                <author>
                    <keyname>Ilie</keyname>
                        <forenames>Cosmin</forenames>
                </author>
        </authors>
        <title>JWST&#39;s Little Red Dots as collapsed Supermassive Dark Stars</title>
            <categories>astro-ph.CO gr-qc hep-ph</categories>
            <license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license>
            <abstract>The nature of the ``Little Red Dots&#39;&#39; (LRDs) is one of the most profound mysteries posed by the JWST data. One promising class of models that can reproduce the observed LRDs spectra and morphology are quasi-stars: massive envelopes surrounding accreting black holes formed via the collapse of supermassive stars (SMSs). However, the canonical SMS pathway relies on a highly restricted set of environmental and structural conditions: strong Lyman--Werner (LW) backgrounds to suppress H$_2$ cooling, high and sustained gas inflow rates to enforce entropy stratified envelopes, and assume non-zero rotational support in order to prevent GR instability collapse before $\sim 10^6 M_{\odot}$. Here we show that supermassive dark stars (SMDSs), powered by dark matter (DM) annihilation rather than nuclear burning, naturally satisfy the key structural and energetic requirements for quasi-star (QS) formation while relaxing {\it all} of those restrictive conditions listed above. Moreover, quasi-stars formed through the SMDS pathway are born with prompt BH masses ($\gtrsim 10\%$) of the progenitor mass. They therefore enter directly into a late-stage quasi-star regime; subsequently the envelope expands and cools until its photosphere reaches the zero-metallicity opacity limit $(T_{\rm eff}\sim3000$-$6000\,{\rm K}$). Those cool, optically thick, unresolved photospheres can reproduce key features of many JWST LRDs.</abstract>
    </arXiv>

            </metadata>
        </record>

    </GetRecord>
</OAI-PMH>