<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<OAI-PMH xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" 
         xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance"
         xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/OAI-PMH.xsd">
    <responseDate>2026-07-13T21:14:10Z</responseDate>
                <request verb="GetRecord" identifier="oai:arXiv.org:2505.03258" metadataPrefix="arXiv">http://oaipmh.arxiv.org/oai</request>


    <GetRecord>
                <record>
                <header>
        <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:2505.03258</identifier>
        <datestamp>2026-04-21</datestamp>
            <setSpec>physics:hep-ph</setSpec>
            <setSpec>physics:hep-ex</setSpec>
    </header>

            <metadata>
                        <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ https://oaipmh.arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
        <id>2505.03258</id>
        <created>2026-02-12</created>
            <updated>2026-04-21</updated>
        <authors>
                <author>
                    <keyname>Esmail</keyname>
                        <forenames>W.</forenames>
                </author>
                <author>
                    <keyname>Hammad</keyname>
                        <forenames>A.</forenames>
                </author>
                <author>
                    <keyname>Nojiri</keyname>
                        <forenames>M.</forenames>
                </author>
        </authors>
        <title>IAFormer: Interaction-Aware Transformer network for collider data analysis</title>
            <categories>hep-ph hep-ex</categories>
            <comments>30 pages, 5 figures and 3 tables</comments>
            <journal-ref>SciPost Phys. 20, 108 (2026)</journal-ref>
            <doi>10.21468/SciPostPhys.20.4.108</doi>
            <license>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0/</license>
            <abstract>In this paper, we introduce \texttt{IAFormer}, a novel Transformer-based architecture that efficiently integrates pairwise particle interactions through a dynamic sparse attention mechanism. \texttt{IAFormer} has two new mechanisms within the model. First, the attention matrix depends on predefined boost invariant pairwise quantities, reducing the network parameters significantly from the original particle transformer models. Second, \texttt{IAFormer} incorporates the sparse attention mechanism by utilizing the &#34;differential attention&#34;, so that it can dynamically prioritize relevant particle tokens while reducing computational overhead associated with less informative ones. This approach significantly lowers the model complexity without compromising performance. Despite being computationally efficient by more than an order of magnitude than the Particle Transformer network, \texttt{IAFormer} achieves state-of-the-art performance in classification tasks on the top and quark-gluon datasets. Furthermore, we employ AI interpretability techniques, verifying that the model effectively captures physically meaningful information layer by layer through its sparse attention mechanism, building an efficient network output that is resistant to statistical fluctuations. \texttt{IAFormer} highlights the need for sparse attention in Transformer analysis to reduce the network size while improving its performance.</abstract>
    </arXiv>

            </metadata>
        </record>

    </GetRecord>
</OAI-PMH>