<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<OAI-PMH xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" 
         xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance"
         xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/OAI-PMH.xsd">
    <responseDate>2026-07-13T06:25:41Z</responseDate>
                <request verb="GetRecord" identifier="oai:arXiv.org:2511.23463" metadataPrefix="arXiv">http://oaipmh.arxiv.org/oai</request>


    <GetRecord>
                <record>
                <header>
        <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:2511.23463</identifier>
        <datestamp>2025-12-01</datestamp>
            <setSpec>physics:astro-ph:CO</setSpec>
            <setSpec>physics:hep-ph</setSpec>
    </header>

            <metadata>
                        <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ https://oaipmh.arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
        <id>2511.23463</id>
        <created>2025-11-28</created>
            <updated>2025-12-01</updated>
        <authors>
                <author>
                    <keyname>Toomey</keyname>
                        <forenames>Michael W.</forenames>
                </author>
                <author>
                    <keyname>Hughes</keyname>
                        <forenames>Ellie</forenames>
                </author>
                <author>
                    <keyname>Ivanov</keyname>
                        <forenames>Mikhail M.</forenames>
                </author>
                <author>
                    <keyname>Sullivan</keyname>
                        <forenames>James M.</forenames>
                </author>
        </authors>
        <title>Kinetic Mixing and the Phantom Illusion: Axion-Dilaton Quintessence in Light of DESI DR2</title>
            <categories>astro-ph.CO hep-ph</categories>
            <comments>15 pages, 8 figures, 3 tables</comments>
            <report-no>MIT-CTP/5963</report-no>
            <license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license>
            <abstract>Recent results from DESI BAO analyses suggest that dark energy may not be a cosmological constant and is in fact dynamical. Furthermore, the data suggest that the equation of state may have been in the phantom regime in the distant past, recently undergoing a phantom crossing. In this work, we investigate whether this preference can be realized within a kinetically mixed axion-dilaton (KMIX) quintessence model, a string-motivated system in which an axion-like field couples exponentially to a dilaton-like (moduli) field. Crucially, KMIX can appear phantom in a standard Chevallier-Polarski-Linder (CPL) based analysis. To confront the model with data, we develop a fast pipeline based on normalizing flows that (i) learns a theory-informed prior on $(w_0,w_a)$ from KMIX realizations and (ii) provides an inverse mapping from CPL parameters back to the physical KMIX parameters. By importance-sampling pre-computed CPL chains using this framework, we effectively transform generic phenomenological constraints into direct, computationally efficient constraints on the underlying KMIX theory, avoiding the prohibitive cost of full parameter space exploration. Applied to Planck+DESI DR2 BAO measurements, our framework finds support for KMIX at $2.5σ$ compared to the base CPL fit at $3.1σ$, demonstrating that KMIX may account for the DESI preference without invoking true phantom behavior. When additionally including Type Ia supernovae data, we find that the preference remains above $3σ$ for Union3 and DES Y5, but drops to $2.1σ$ with Pantheon+. The latter, combined with the DESI full-shape power spectrum and bispectrum data, further reduces the preference to $1.7σ$. Ultimately, should the DESI deviation persist with future data, KMIX may offer a theoretically well-motivated explanation for the phantom-like signatures inferred from phenomenological fits.</abstract>
    </arXiv>

            </metadata>
        </record>

    </GetRecord>
</OAI-PMH>