<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<OAI-PMH xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" 
         xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance"
         xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/OAI-PMH.xsd">
    <responseDate>2026-07-13T06:22:11Z</responseDate>
                <request verb="GetRecord" identifier="oai:arXiv.org:2604.13774" metadataPrefix="arXiv">http://oaipmh.arxiv.org/oai</request>


    <GetRecord>
                <record>
                <header>
        <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:2604.13774</identifier>
        <datestamp>2026-04-16</datestamp>
            <setSpec>physics:physics:soc-ph</setSpec>
            <setSpec>physics:astro-ph:IM</setSpec>
            <setSpec>physics:physics:pop-ph</setSpec>
    </header>

            <metadata>
                        <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ https://oaipmh.arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
        <id>2604.13774</id>
        <created>2026-04-15</created>
            <updated>2026-04-16</updated>
        <authors>
                <author>
                    <keyname>Blanco</keyname>
                        <forenames>Celia</forenames>
                </author>
                <author>
                    <keyname>Haqq-Misra</keyname>
                        <forenames>Jacob</forenames>
                </author>
                <author>
                    <keyname>Profitiliotis</keyname>
                        <forenames>George</forenames>
                </author>
        </authors>
        <title>Projections of Earth&#39;s Technosphere: Civilization Collapse-Recovery Dynamics and Detectability</title>
            <categories>physics.soc-ph astro-ph.IM physics.pop-ph</categories>
            <license>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0/</license>
            <abstract>How long a technological civilization remains active, and what determines whether it collapses or persists, is a central question for both projecting humanity&#39;s future and assessing the prevalence of detectable intelligence in the galaxy. We model collapse-recovery dynamics across ten plausible futures for Earth-originating civilization using a hybrid deterministic-stochastic simulation over a 1000-year window. The duty cycle, defined as the fraction of its total lifespan that a civilization is technologically active, ranges from ~0.38 to 1.00, with trajectory outcomes shaped by the interplay of governance structure, resource pressure, and hazard exposure. Several model parameters map onto actionable resilience levers, and modest improvements can qualitatively alter long-term trajectories. Sensitivity analysis reveals that the resource depletion rate and the post-collapse recovery fraction are consistently the most impactful levers across scenarios, suggesting that reducing resource consumption may be at least as important as mitigating existential hazards for avoiding civilizational collapse. We discuss implications for Earth&#39;s civilizational resilience and for the search for extraterrestrial technosignatures. We also derive an effective detectability duration that accounts for intermittent civilizational activity, and show that the apparent absence of extraterrestrial signals may reflect the prevalence of low-duty-cycle civilizations rather than the rarity of intelligent life.</abstract>
    </arXiv>

            </metadata>
        </record>

    </GetRecord>
</OAI-PMH>