<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<OAI-PMH xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" 
         xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance"
         xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/OAI-PMH.xsd">
    <responseDate>2026-07-13T21:13:52Z</responseDate>
                <request verb="GetRecord" identifier="oai:arXiv.org:2512.08739" metadataPrefix="arXiv">http://oaipmh.arxiv.org/oai</request>


    <GetRecord>
                <record>
                <header>
        <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:2512.08739</identifier>
        <datestamp>2025-12-10</datestamp>
            <setSpec>physics:cond-mat:quant-gas</setSpec>
            <setSpec>physics:cond-mat:mes-hall</setSpec>
            <setSpec>physics:quant-ph</setSpec>
    </header>

            <metadata>
                        <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ https://oaipmh.arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
        <id>2512.08739</id>
        <created>2025-12-09</created>
            <updated>2025-12-10</updated>
        <authors>
                <author>
                    <keyname>Coquinot</keyname>
                        <forenames>Baptiste</forenames>
                </author>
                <author>
                    <keyname>Alhyder</keyname>
                        <forenames>Ragheed</forenames>
                </author>
                <author>
                    <keyname>Cappellaro</keyname>
                        <forenames>Alberto</forenames>
                </author>
                <author>
                    <keyname>Lemeshko</keyname>
                        <forenames>Mikhail</forenames>
                </author>
        </authors>
        <title>Fluctuation-Induced Supersolidity at the Superfluid-Solid Interface</title>
            <categories>cond-mat.quant-gas cond-mat.mes-hall quant-ph</categories>
            <license>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0/</license>
            <abstract>Supersolidity, combining superfluid and crystalline orders, has been realized in dipolar Bose-Einstein condensates by tuning interatomic interactions. Here we show that supersolidity can also emerge from mode coupling at a superfluid-solid interface, without modifying bulk interactions and for a broad class of superfluids. Using an analytical and numerical treatment of the coupled superfluid and phonon fields, we derive the criterion for a density-modulation instability driven by interfacial coupling and dependent on dimensionality. In superfluid helium, the instability first appears at the roton mode, while in a Bose-Einstein condensate with contact interactions it occurs at the lowest accessible wave vector set by the system size. Beyond the threshold, the ground state acquires an interfacial density modulation while the bulk remains superfluid, forming a hybrid superfluid-supersolid phase. Our results identify interfacial mode coupling as a promising route to supersolidity, enabling the simultaneous exploitation of interfacial supersolid and bulk superfluid quantum properties.</abstract>
    </arXiv>

            </metadata>
        </record>

    </GetRecord>
</OAI-PMH>