<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<OAI-PMH xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" 
         xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance"
         xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/OAI-PMH.xsd">
    <responseDate>2026-07-13T06:24:45Z</responseDate>
                <request verb="GetRecord" identifier="oai:arXiv.org:2605.18280" metadataPrefix="arXiv">http://oaipmh.arxiv.org/oai</request>


    <GetRecord>
                <record>
                <header>
        <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:2605.18280</identifier>
        <datestamp>2026-05-19</datestamp>
            <setSpec>physics:astro-ph:SR</setSpec>
            <setSpec>physics:astro-ph:EP</setSpec>
    </header>

            <metadata>
                        <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ https://oaipmh.arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
        <id>2605.18280</id>
        <created>2026-05-18</created>
            <updated>2026-05-19</updated>
        <authors>
                <author>
                    <keyname>Guité</keyname>
                        <forenames>L-S.</forenames>
                </author>
                <author>
                    <keyname>Strugarek</keyname>
                        <forenames>A.</forenames>
                </author>
                <author>
                    <keyname>Finley</keyname>
                        <forenames>A. J.</forenames>
                </author>
                <author>
                    <keyname>Parenti</keyname>
                        <forenames>S.</forenames>
                </author>
                <author>
                    <keyname>Réville</keyname>
                        <forenames>V.</forenames>
                </author>
                <author>
                    <keyname>Paul</keyname>
                        <forenames>A.</forenames>
                </author>
                <author>
                    <keyname>Brun</keyname>
                        <forenames>A. S.</forenames>
                </author>
                <author>
                    <keyname>de Carpentier</keyname>
                        <forenames>J.</forenames>
                </author>
        </authors>
        <title>Sungrazer comets as analogs of star-planet magnetic interactions</title>
            <categories>astro-ph.SR astro-ph.EP</categories>
            <comments>Accepted for publication in Astronomy &amp; Astrophysics, 10 pages, 7 figures. The arXiv abstract has been shortened to fall within the character limit</comments>
            <license>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0/</license>
            <abstract>Star-planet magnetic interactions (SPMIs) can transfer energy from an exoplanet to its host star via Alfvén waves when the planet orbits within a sub-Alfvénic stellar wind. Similar conditions were encountered by the sungrazing comet Lovejoy as it passed through the solar corona in December 2011. The possibility that comets could trigger solar activity via magnetic interactions has never been investigated. The aim of this paper is to quantify the energetics of such interaction and to assess if enough energy could be deposited to either form a hotspot or trigger eruptions on the Sun. We used the magnetohydrodynamic WindPredict-AW model to reconstruct the coronal magnetic field and solar wind conditions along the comet&#39;s orbit, and determined the magnetic footpoints that connected the comet to the solar surface. By estimating the travel time of hypothetical Alfvén waves, we identified a brightening event observed by EUVI aboard STEREO-A that is spatially and temporally consistent with comet Lovejoy&#39;s passage. We then computed the SPMI power for all magnetic field lines anchored within 5 degrees of the brightening using SPMI power scaling laws. The resulting power distribution spans approximately 10$^{14}$-10$^{16}$ W. In comparison, the estimated radiative power of the brightening event in the STEREO-A/EUVI 195$Å$ channel is approximately 10$^{17}$ W. We find that comet Lovejoy does not generate sufficient SPMI power to be the energy source of the observed brightening intensity. However, it may still act as a perturbation to existing magnetic structures, and lead to the triggering of solar flares. Confirming this hypothesis would require additional observations that do not exist for this event, which make future passages of sungrazing comets valuable opportunities to study SPMI processes within our solar system.</abstract>
    </arXiv>

            </metadata>
        </record>

    </GetRecord>
</OAI-PMH>