<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<OAI-PMH xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" 
         xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance"
         xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/OAI-PMH.xsd">
    <responseDate>2026-07-13T06:20:53Z</responseDate>
                <request verb="GetRecord" identifier="oai:arXiv.org:2508.03842" metadataPrefix="arXiv">http://oaipmh.arxiv.org/oai</request>


    <GetRecord>
                <record>
                <header>
        <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:2508.03842</identifier>
        <datestamp>2025-10-17</datestamp>
            <setSpec>physics:astro-ph:GA</setSpec>
            <setSpec>physics:astro-ph:CO</setSpec>
    </header>

            <metadata>
                        <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ https://oaipmh.arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
        <id>2508.03842</id>
        <created>2025-10-15</created>
            <updated>2025-10-17</updated>
        <authors>
                <author>
                    <keyname>Visbal</keyname>
                        <forenames>Eli</forenames>
                </author>
                <author>
                    <keyname>Hazlett</keyname>
                        <forenames>Ryan</forenames>
                </author>
                <author>
                    <keyname>Bryan</keyname>
                        <forenames>Greg L.</forenames>
                </author>
        </authors>
        <title>LAP1-B is the First Observed System Consistent with Theoretical Predictions for Population III Stars</title>
            <categories>astro-ph.GA astro-ph.CO</categories>
            <comments>9 pages, 2 figures, replaced with version accepted by ApJL</comments>
            <license>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0/</license>
            <abstract>Recently, Nakajima et al. (2025) presented James Webb Space Telescope observations of the $z=6.6$ Population III (Pop III) candidate LAP1-B, which is gravitationally lensed by galaxy cluster MACS J0416. We argue that this is the first object to agree with three key theoretical predictions for Pop III stars: (1) formation in extremely low-metallicity halos with virial temperatures ranging from $T_{\rm vir}\sim 10^3-10^4~{\rm K}$, (2) a top-heavy initial mass function, and (3) formation of low-mass clusters with ${\sim}{\rm a ~few}\times 1000~M_\odot$ in massive Pop III stars. LAP1-B is consistent with recently formed Pop III stars hosted in a $\sim 5\times 10^7~M_\odot$ dark matter halo, some of which have enriched their surrounding gas either with supernovae or stellar winds. We use the semi-analytic model of Visbal et al. (2020) to predict the abundance of Pop III clusters observable at the high magnification provided by the foreground galaxy cluster MACS J0416. Using fiducial parameters unmodified from previous work, we expect about one observable Pop III galaxy similar to LAP1-B in the range $z=6-7$. At earlier times, the intrinsic abundance is higher, but Pop III systems would not have been detected because of their increased luminosity distance and lower mass dark matter halos, which would host fewer stars. Thus, we find that LAP1-B was found at the redshift theoretically expected, given current observable limits, despite the fact that most Pop III systems form much earlier.</abstract>
    </arXiv>

            </metadata>
        </record>

    </GetRecord>
</OAI-PMH>