<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<OAI-PMH xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" 
         xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance"
         xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/OAI-PMH.xsd">
    <responseDate>2026-07-13T06:25:16Z</responseDate>
                <request verb="GetRecord" identifier="oai:arXiv.org:2509.12175" metadataPrefix="arXiv">http://oaipmh.arxiv.org/oai</request>


    <GetRecord>
                <record>
                <header>
        <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:2509.12175</identifier>
        <datestamp>2026-06-23</datestamp>
            <setSpec>physics:hep-ex</setSpec>
            <setSpec>physics:astro-ph:IM</setSpec>
            <setSpec>physics:physics:ins-det</setSpec>
            <setSpec>physics:physics:optics</setSpec>
            <setSpec>physics:quant-ph</setSpec>
    </header>

            <metadata>
                        <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ https://oaipmh.arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
        <id>2509.12175</id>
        <created>2026-06-21</created>
            <updated>2026-06-23</updated>
        <authors>
                <author>
                    <keyname>Chowdhury</keyname>
                        <forenames>M. Dey</forenames>
                </author>
                <author>
                    <keyname>Manley</keyname>
                        <forenames>J. P.</forenames>
                </author>
                <author>
                    <keyname>Condos</keyname>
                        <forenames>C. A.</forenames>
                </author>
                <author>
                    <keyname>Agrawal</keyname>
                        <forenames>A. R.</forenames>
                </author>
                <author>
                    <keyname>Wilson</keyname>
                        <forenames>D. J.</forenames>
                </author>
        </authors>
        <title>Optomechanical Accelerometer Search for Ultralight Dark Matter</title>
            <categories>hep-ex astro-ph.IM physics.ins-det physics.optics quant-ph</categories>
            <comments>Minor revisions to title, abstract, conclusion, and end matter. No scientific changes</comments>
            <journal-ref>Phys. Rev. D 113, L121303 (2026)</journal-ref>
            <doi>10.1103/16yd-qj5v</doi>
            <license>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0/</license>
            <abstract>Cavity optomechanical systems have recently been proposed as detectors for ultralight dark matter, leveraging their ability to cool and probe mechanical oscillators at the quantum limit. Here we present a resonant search for ultralight dark matter using a cavity optomechanical accelerometer. The detector consists of a cryogenic Si$_3$N$_4$-membrane cavity mounted to a 4 K copper plate, with photothermal tuning used to scan its 39 kHz mechanical resonance. Shot-noise-limited displacement readout and radiation-pressure feedback cooling yield an acceleration sensitivity of $\sim 10\;\text{n}g_0/\sqrt{\text{Hz}}$ over 30 Hz near resonance. The detector&#39;s material inhomogeneity gives access to direct vector coupling to the dark-matter field. We conduct a resonant search based on matched-filter statistics, yielding upper bounds consistent with thermal noise and above those set by equivalence principle tests. No signal is observed, but the experiment demonstrates stable, quantum-limited operation and validates a scalable approach to resonant detection. With optimized test masses, lower temperature, and multiplexed arrays, the platform offers a path toward competitive constraints on vector-mediated dark-matter interactions.</abstract>
    </arXiv>

            </metadata>
        </record>

    </GetRecord>
</OAI-PMH>