<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<OAI-PMH xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" 
         xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance"
         xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/OAI-PMH.xsd">
    <responseDate>2026-07-13T00:54:25Z</responseDate>
                <request verb="GetRecord" identifier="oai:arXiv.org:2605.12448v2" metadataPrefix="arXiv">http://oaipmh.arxiv.org/oai</request>


    <GetRecord>
                <record>
                <header>
        <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:2605.12448</identifier>
        <datestamp>2026-07-03</datestamp>
            <setSpec>physics:astro-ph:HE</setSpec>
            <setSpec>physics:astro-ph:GA</setSpec>
            <setSpec>physics:gr-qc</setSpec>
            <setSpec>physics:hep-th</setSpec>
    </header>

            <metadata>
                        <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ https://oaipmh.arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
        <id>2605.12448</id>
        <created>2026-07-02</created>
            <updated>2026-07-03</updated>
        <authors>
                <author>
                    <keyname>Rodriguez</keyname>
                        <forenames>Maria J.</forenames>
                </author>
        </authors>
        <title>Precessing Black Hole Jets and Galactic Fossils</title>
            <categories>astro-ph.HE astro-ph.GA gr-qc hep-th</categories>
            <comments>44 pages, 8 Figures</comments>
            <license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license>
            <abstract>The Galactic Center gamma-ray excess (GCE) -- a surplus of gamma-ray radiation around SgrA$^{\star}$ -- has remained without a consensus interpretation for more than fifteen years. Dark-matter annihilation and unresolved millisecond-pulsar populations remain the leading candidates, yet neither connects the excess to the past activity of SgrA$^{\star}$ traced by the Fermi and eROSITA bubbles. We propose a common-origin scenario in which a contribution to the GCE arises as a fossil hadronic imprint of the same SgrA$^{\star}$ outburst associated with the bubbles. We develop a model of SgrA$^{\star}$ with a precessing paraboloidal Blandford-Znajek (BZ) jet launched from a tilted, magnetically arrested accretion disc during a ~ 7.5 Myr active phase ending ~2.6 Myr ago. In this picture, the jet drives the bipolar expansion of the Fermi/eROSITA bubbles -- contributing, alongside wider-angle outflows, to their observed extent -- and injects hadronic cosmic rays at the Galactic Center. We couple the analytic BZ injection to a two-zone diffusion numerical solver to compute the resulting GCE surface brightness and verify internal consistency: the proton Larmor radius remains small compared to the jet coherence scale, ensuring magnetic confinement of the cosmic-ray population, while attenuation of the produced $γ$ rays in the interstellar medium is negligible, leaving the medium effectively transparent. Isolating the jet contribution alone yields a spin-dependent, irreducible hadronic floor: for a SgrA$^{\star}$ spin of a$^{\star} = 0.9$, we find a robust floor at the few-percent to $\sim 10\%$ level of the observed GCE surface brightness across the inner ten degrees, highlighting a previously unexplored component relevant for comprehensive models of the GCE.</abstract>
    </arXiv>

            </metadata>
        </record>

    </GetRecord>
</OAI-PMH>