<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<OAI-PMH xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" 
         xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance"
         xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/OAI-PMH.xsd">
    <responseDate>2026-07-09T20:04:46Z</responseDate>
                <request verb="GetRecord" identifier="oai:arXiv.org:2607.02660v1" metadataPrefix="arXiv">http://oaipmh.arxiv.org/oai</request>


    <GetRecord>
                <record>
                <header>
        <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:2607.02660</identifier>
        <datestamp>2026-07-07</datestamp>
            <setSpec>physics:astro-ph:EP</setSpec>
            <setSpec>physics:astro-ph:IM</setSpec>
    </header>

            <metadata>
                        <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ https://oaipmh.arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
        <id>2607.02660</id>
        <created>2026-07-02</created>
            <updated>2026-07-07</updated>
        <authors>
                <author>
                    <keyname>Scardoni</keyname>
                        <forenames>C. E.</forenames>
                </author>
                <author>
                    <keyname>Rosotti</keyname>
                        <forenames>G. P.</forenames>
                </author>
                <author>
                    <keyname>Zagaria</keyname>
                        <forenames>F.</forenames>
                </author>
                <author>
                    <keyname>Ribas</keyname>
                        <forenames>A.</forenames>
                </author>
                <author>
                    <keyname>Villenave</keyname>
                        <forenames>M.</forenames>
                </author>
                <author>
                    <keyname>Clarke</keyname>
                        <forenames>C. J.</forenames>
                </author>
                <author>
                    <keyname>Booth</keyname>
                        <forenames>R. A.</forenames>
                </author>
        </authors>
        <title>Azimuthal brightness modulation reveals hidden rings in CI Tau</title>
            <categories>astro-ph.EP astro-ph.IM</categories>
            <comments>6 pages, 6 figures, Accepted for publication in A&amp;A</comments>
            <license>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0/</license>
            <abstract>Protoplanetary disks often host substructures such as rings and gaps, which trace key processes in planet formation and dust evolution. However, narrow rings may remain unresolved due to limited observational resolution, hiding critical information about early planetesimal formation and the amount of dust present. We apply the azimuthal brightness modulation method, based on the modulation produced by multiple unresolved optically thick rings embedded in an optically thin background Scardoni+2024, to multi-wavelength ALMA observations of CI Tau to identify unresolved rings and constrain their geometry and optical depth. We analysed CI Tau archival ALMA continuum observations in bands 3, 6, and 7, extracting azimuthal brightness profiles along narrow annuli and comparing them with forward modeled synthetic observations of inclined disks containing unresolved rings. We detect the azimuthal signature at $\sim22$ au in all three bands, consistent with unresolved, optically thick rings embedded in a lower optical depth background. Multi wavelength modelling constrains the rings&#39; geometry and optical depth, consistent with conditions expected for streaming instability and early planetesimal formation. Our results demonstrate the applicability of this azimuthal signature technique to real disks, reveal fine scale dust substructures in CI Tau, and illustrate a new method to study the early stages of planet formation below the nominal resolution limit.</abstract>
    </arXiv>

            </metadata>
        </record>

    </GetRecord>
</OAI-PMH>