<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<OAI-PMH xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" 
         xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance"
         xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/OAI-PMH.xsd">
    <responseDate>2026-07-13T21:13:34Z</responseDate>
                <request verb="GetRecord" identifier="oai:arXiv.org:2501.00037" metadataPrefix="arXiv">http://oaipmh.arxiv.org/oai</request>


    <GetRecord>
                <record>
                <header>
        <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:2501.00037</identifier>
        <datestamp>2025-01-03</datestamp>
            <setSpec>physics:physics:flu-dyn</setSpec>
            <setSpec>cs:cs:CE</setSpec>
            <setSpec>cs:cs:NA</setSpec>
            <setSpec>math:math:NA</setSpec>
    </header>

            <metadata>
                        <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ https://oaipmh.arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
        <id>2501.00037</id>
        <created>2024-12-24</created>
            <updated>2025-01-03</updated>
        <authors>
                <author>
                    <keyname>Marzouk</keyname>
                        <forenames>Osama A.</forenames>
                </author>
                <author>
                    <keyname>Huckaby</keyname>
                        <forenames>E. David</forenames>
                </author>
        </authors>
        <title>Effects of Turbulence Modeling and Parcel Approach on Dispersed Two-Phase Swirling Flow</title>
            <categories>physics.flu-dyn cs.CE cs.NA math.NA</categories>
            <comments>11 pages, 11 figures, no tables, published conference article, peer-reviewed, open access. International Conference on Modeling, Simulation and Control (ICMSC&#39;09), San Francisco, California, October 2009</comments>
            <msc-class>76Txx, 76M12, 76Fxx</msc-class>
            <acm-class>76Txx, 76M12, 76Fxx</acm-class>
            <license>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0/</license>
            <abstract>Several numerical simulations of a co-axial particle-laden swirling air flow in a vertical circular pipe were performed. The air flow was modeled using the unsteady Favre-averaged Navier-Stokes equations. A Lagrangian model was used for the particle motion. The gas and particles are coupled through two-way momentum exchange. The results of the simulations using three versions of the k-epsilon turbulence model (standard, re-normalization group (RNG), and realizable) are compared with experimental mean velocity profiles. The standard model achieved the best overall performance. The realizable model was unable to satisfactorily predict the radial velocity; it is also the most computationally-expensive model. The simulations using the RNG model predicted additional recirculation zones. We also compared the particle and parcel approaches in solving the particle motion. In the latter, multiple similar particles are grouped in a single parcel, thereby reducing the amount of computation.</abstract>
    </arXiv>

            </metadata>
        </record>

    </GetRecord>
</OAI-PMH>