<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<OAI-PMH xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" 
         xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance"
         xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/OAI-PMH.xsd">
    <responseDate>2026-07-13T06:21:50Z</responseDate>
                <request verb="GetRecord" identifier="oai:arXiv.org:2602.11923" metadataPrefix="arXiv">http://oaipmh.arxiv.org/oai</request>


    <GetRecord>
                <record>
                <header>
        <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:2602.11923</identifier>
        <datestamp>2026-02-13</datestamp>
            <setSpec>physics:astro-ph:EP</setSpec>
            <setSpec>physics:astro-ph:SR</setSpec>
    </header>

            <metadata>
                        <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ https://oaipmh.arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
        <id>2602.11923</id>
        <created>2026-02-12</created>
            <updated>2026-02-13</updated>
        <authors>
                <author>
                    <keyname>Chakrabarty</keyname>
                        <forenames>Aritra</forenames>
                </author>
                <author>
                    <keyname>Mulders</keyname>
                        <forenames>Gijs D.</forenames>
                </author>
                <author>
                    <keyname>Aguichine</keyname>
                        <forenames>Artyom</forenames>
                </author>
                <author>
                    <keyname>Batalha</keyname>
                        <forenames>Natalie</forenames>
                </author>
        </authors>
        <title>The Radius Cliff is a Waterfall: Explaining Sub-Neptune Exoplanets with Steam Worlds</title>
            <categories>astro-ph.EP astro-ph.SR</categories>
            <comments>22 pages, 9 figures, accepted for publication in ApJ</comments>
            <license>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0/</license>
            <abstract>The demographics of Kepler planets provide a key testbed for models of planet formation and evolution, particularly for explaining the radius valley separating super-Earths and sub-Neptunes. A primordial interpretation based on differences in bulk densities -- where rocky and water-rich planets form via migration pathways -- offers an alternative to atmospheric loss scenarios. Updated interior structure models of water worlds with adiabatic steam atmospheres reproduce the observed valley near $\sim2~R_\oplus$ more accurately. Furthermore, migration models from our Genesis library suggest that these formation pathways can also account for the distinct period distributions of super-Earths and sub-Neptunes, as well as the emergence of the hot Neptune desert. Motivated by this, we develop a Bayesian hierarchical mixture model for close-in Kepler planets ($P&lt;100$ days), combining rocky planets and water worlds without H/He envelopes. The inferred mass distributions of rocky and water-rich planets peak at $\sim2.6~M_\oplus$ and $\sim7~M_\oplus$, respectively, with the water mass fraction of water worlds peaking at $\sim41\%$. Water worlds provide a good representation of the Kepler sub-Neptune population, with the radius cliff emerging as a ``waterfall&#34; -- a sharp decline in their occurrence. However, our mass-radius analysis shows that water worlds alone cannot explain planets with $R \gtrsim 3~R_\oplus$, implying that at least $\sim20\%$ of sub-Neptunes in the sample are enriched in H/He gas.</abstract>
    </arXiv>

            </metadata>
        </record>

    </GetRecord>
</OAI-PMH>