<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<OAI-PMH xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" 
         xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance"
         xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/OAI-PMH.xsd">
    <responseDate>2026-07-13T21:14:06Z</responseDate>
                <request verb="GetRecord" identifier="oai:arXiv.org:2505.00145" metadataPrefix="arXiv">http://oaipmh.arxiv.org/oai</request>


    <GetRecord>
                <record>
                <header>
        <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:2505.00145</identifier>
        <datestamp>2025-05-02</datestamp>
            <setSpec>physics:quant-ph</setSpec>
            <setSpec>math:math:OC</setSpec>
    </header>

            <metadata>
                        <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ https://oaipmh.arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
        <id>2505.00145</id>
        <created>2025-04-30</created>
            <updated>2025-05-02</updated>
        <authors>
                <author>
                    <keyname>Aboumrad</keyname>
                        <forenames>Willie</forenames>
                </author>
                <author>
                    <keyname>Marthi</keyname>
                        <forenames>Phani R V</forenames>
                </author>
                <author>
                    <keyname>Debnath</keyname>
                        <forenames>Suman</forenames>
                </author>
                <author>
                    <keyname>Roetteler</keyname>
                        <forenames>Martin</forenames>
                </author>
                <author>
                    <keyname>Epifanovsky</keyname>
                        <forenames>Evgeny</forenames>
                </author>
        </authors>
        <title>A New Hybrid Quantum-Classical Algorithm for Solving the Unit Commitment Problem</title>
            <categories>quant-ph math.OC</categories>
            <comments>10 pages</comments>
            <license>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0/</license>
            <abstract>Solving problems related to planning and operations of large-scale power systems is challenging on classical computers due to their inherent nature as mixed-integer and nonlinear problems. Quantum computing provides new avenues to approach these problems. We develop a hybrid quantum-classical algorithm for the Unit Commitment (UC) problem in power systems which aims at minimizing the total cost while optimally allocating generating units to meet the hourly demand of the power loads. The hybrid algorithm combines a variational quantum algorithm (VQA) with a classical Bender&#39;s type heuristic. The resulting algorithm computes approximate solutions to UC in three stages: i) a collection of UC vectors capable meeting the power demand with lowest possible operating costs is generated based on VQA; ii) a classical sequential least squares programming (SLSQP) routine is leveraged to find the optimal power level corresponding to a predetermined number of candidate vectors; iii) in the last stage, the approximate solution of UC along with generating units power level combination is given. To demonstrate the effectiveness of the presented method, three different systems with 3 generating units, 10 generating units, and 26 generating units were tested for different time periods. In addition, convergence of the hybrid quantum-classical algorithm for select time periods is proven out on IonQ&#39;s Forte system.</abstract>
    </arXiv>

            </metadata>
        </record>

    </GetRecord>
</OAI-PMH>