<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<OAI-PMH xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" 
         xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance"
         xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/OAI-PMH.xsd">
    <responseDate>2026-07-11T22:17:58Z</responseDate>
                <request verb="GetRecord" identifier="oai:arXiv.org:2601.07374v3" metadataPrefix="arXiv">http://oaipmh.arxiv.org/oai</request>


    <GetRecord>
                <record>
                <header>
        <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:2601.07374</identifier>
        <datestamp>2026-05-14</datestamp>
            <setSpec>physics:astro-ph:GA</setSpec>
    </header>

            <metadata>
                        <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ https://oaipmh.arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
        <id>2601.07374</id>
        <created>2026-05-12</created>
            <updated>2026-05-14</updated>
        <authors>
                <author>
                    <keyname>Ferrara</keyname>
                        <forenames>Andrea</forenames>
                </author>
                <author>
                    <keyname>Carniani</keyname>
                        <forenames>Stefano</forenames>
                </author>
                <author>
                    <keyname>Morishita</keyname>
                        <forenames>Takahiro</forenames>
                </author>
                <author>
                    <keyname>Stiavelli</keyname>
                        <forenames>Massimo</forenames>
                </author>
        </authors>
        <title>Possible evidence for a pair-instability supernova nature of ultra-early JWST sources</title>
            <categories>astro-ph.GA</categories>
            <comments>10 pages, 4 Figures, Published in the Open Journal of Astrophysics. Comments welcome (andrea.ferrara@sns.it)</comments>
            <doi>10.33232/001c.162107</doi>
            <license>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0/</license>
            <abstract>Recent JWST observations have revealed a population of unexpectedly bright sources at ultra-high redshift ($z &gt; 15$), challenging current models of early galaxy formation. One extreme example is &#39;Capotauro&#39;, an F356W-dropout identified in the CEERS survey and initially interpreted as a luminous galaxy at $z\sim30$, but subsequently found to be variable over an $\sim 800$ day baseline. Motivated by this variability, we explore the alternative hypothesis that Capotauro is a pair-instability supernova (PISN) originating from a massive ($250-260\,M_\odot$), metal-free star. Using state-of-the-art PISN light curves, spectral energy distributions, and synthetic spectra, we show that a PISN at $z\simeq 15$ can plausibly reproduce the observed brightness, temporal evolution, photometry, and NIRSpec spectrum. We compare this scenario with alternative interpretations, including a local Y0 brown dwarf, and discuss observational tests to discriminate among them. If confirmed, this event would provide a rare window onto Population III stars, and highlights the importance of transient contamination in ultra-high redshift galaxy samples.</abstract>
    </arXiv>

            </metadata>
        </record>

    </GetRecord>
</OAI-PMH>