<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<OAI-PMH xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" 
         xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance"
         xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/OAI-PMH.xsd">
    <responseDate>2026-07-13T06:23:38Z</responseDate>
                <request verb="GetRecord" identifier="oai:arXiv.org:2601.17686" metadataPrefix="arXiv">http://oaipmh.arxiv.org/oai</request>


    <GetRecord>
                <record>
                <header>
        <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:2601.17686</identifier>
        <datestamp>2026-01-27</datestamp>
            <setSpec>physics:quant-ph</setSpec>
    </header>

            <metadata>
                        <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ https://oaipmh.arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
        <id>2601.17686</id>
        <created>2026-01-25</created>
            <updated>2026-01-27</updated>
        <authors>
                <author>
                    <keyname>Choi</keyname>
                        <forenames>Vicky</forenames>
                </author>
        </authors>
        <title>Exponential Quantum Speedup on Structured Hard Instances of Maximum Independent Set</title>
            <categories>quant-ph</categories>
            <comments>18 pages, 8 figures, 2 tables</comments>
            <license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license>
            <abstract>Establishing quantum speedup for computationally hard problems of practical relevance, particularly combinatorial optimization problems, remains a central challenge in quantum computation. In this work, we identify a structurally defined family of classically hard maximum independent set (MIS) instances, and design and analyze a non-stoquastic adiabatic quantum optimization algorithm that exploits this structure. The algorithm runs in polynomial time and achieves an exponential speedup over both transverse-field quantum annealing and state-of-the-art classical solvers on these instances, under assumptions supported by analytical and numerical evidence. We identify the essential quantum mechanism enabling the speedup as the use of a non-stoquastic XX-driver to access a larger sign-structured admissible subspace beyond the stoquastic regime, which allows sign-generating quantum interference to create smooth evolution paths that bypass tunneling. This identifies a distinctive quantum mechanism underlying the speedup and explains why no efficient classical analogue is likely to exist. In addition, our analysis produces scalable small-scale models, derived from our structural reduction, that capture the essential dynamics of the algorithm. These models provide a concrete opportunity for verification of the quantum advantage mechanism on currently available universal quantum computers.</abstract>
    </arXiv>

            </metadata>
        </record>

    </GetRecord>
</OAI-PMH>