<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<OAI-PMH xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" 
         xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance"
         xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/OAI-PMH.xsd">
    <responseDate>2026-07-13T06:22:45Z</responseDate>
                <request verb="GetRecord" identifier="oai:arXiv.org:2509.05233" metadataPrefix="arXiv">http://oaipmh.arxiv.org/oai</request>


    <GetRecord>
                <record>
                <header>
        <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:2509.05233</identifier>
        <datestamp>2026-05-21</datestamp>
            <setSpec>physics:hep-ph</setSpec>
            <setSpec>physics:astro-ph:CO</setSpec>
            <setSpec>physics:hep-th</setSpec>
    </header>

            <metadata>
                        <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ https://oaipmh.arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
        <id>2509.05233</id>
        <created>2025-12-14</created>
            <updated>2026-05-21</updated>
        <authors>
                <author>
                    <keyname>Antoniadis</keyname>
                        <forenames>Ignatios</forenames>
                </author>
                <author>
                    <keyname>Chatrabhuti</keyname>
                        <forenames>Auttakit</forenames>
                </author>
                <author>
                    <keyname>Isono</keyname>
                        <forenames>Hiroshi</forenames>
                </author>
        </authors>
        <title>Searching for a Dark Dimension Right-handed Neutrino in KATRIN</title>
            <categories>hep-ph astro-ph.CO hep-th</categories>
            <comments>31 pages. 5 figures; v2: typos corrected. version accepted by JHEP</comments>
            <doi>10.1007/JHEP02(2026)015</doi>
            <license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license>
            <abstract>We study the possibility that the Right-handed neutrino is a five-dimensional state propagating along a micron size extra dimension, as required in the dark dimension proposal. We work out the signatures of R-neutrino production in KATRIN experiment and compare them with those of a sterile neutrino which manifests by a kink in the electron energy spectrum of the beta-decay at a value corresponding to the sterile neutrino mass. We explore the allowed parameter space of the compactification scale and the R-neutrino bulk mass versus the Yukawa coupling, and show that a large part of it is within KATRIN&#39;s sensitivity. When the bulk mass is much smaller than the compactification scale, several kinks could be observed corresponding to the positions of the R-neutrino Kaluza-Klein excitations, while for large bulk mass there will be effectively one kink at the position of the bulk mass.</abstract>
    </arXiv>

            </metadata>
        </record>

    </GetRecord>
</OAI-PMH>