<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<OAI-PMH xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" 
         xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance"
         xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/OAI-PMH.xsd">
    <responseDate>2026-07-11T20:33:23Z</responseDate>
                <request verb="GetRecord" identifier="oai:arXiv.org:2601.02458v3" metadataPrefix="arXiv">http://oaipmh.arxiv.org/oai</request>


    <GetRecord>
                <record>
                <header>
        <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:2601.02458</identifier>
        <datestamp>2026-05-26</datestamp>
            <setSpec>physics:astro-ph:CO</setSpec>
            <setSpec>physics:gr-qc</setSpec>
            <setSpec>physics:hep-ph</setSpec>
            <setSpec>physics:hep-th</setSpec>
    </header>

            <metadata>
                        <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ https://oaipmh.arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
        <id>2601.02458</id>
        <created>2026-04-24</created>
            <updated>2026-05-26</updated>
        <authors>
                <author>
                    <keyname>Ghoshal</keyname>
                        <forenames>Anish</forenames>
                </author>
                <author>
                    <keyname>Pal</keyname>
                        <forenames>Pratyay</forenames>
                </author>
        </authors>
        <title>Cosmic Collider Gravitational Waves sourced by Right-handed Neutrino production from Bubbles: Testing Seesaw, Leptogenesis and Dark Matter</title>
            <categories>astro-ph.CO gr-qc hep-ph hep-th</categories>
            <comments>55 pages, 16 figures + appendix + references. Version accepted for publication in PRD</comments>
            <report-no>Phys. Rev. D 113, 103035</report-no>
            <doi>10.1103/1t75-24fn</doi>
            <license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license>
            <abstract>We study a minimal type-I seesaw framework in which a first-order phase transition (FOPT), driven by a singlet scalar, produces right-handed neutrinos (RHNs) through bubble collisions, realizing a cosmic-scale collider that probes ultra-high energy scales. The resulting RHN distribution sources novel low-frequency gravitational-waves (GWs) in addition to the standard bubble-collision contribution. A stable lightest RHN can account for the observed dark matter (DM) relic abundance for masses as low as $M_{1} \equiv m_{\rm DM} \gtrsim 10^{6}\,\mathrm{GeV}$, with the associated novel GW signal accessible in LISA, ET and upcoming LVK detectors. If the RHNs are unstable, their CP-violating decays generate the observed baryon asymmetry via leptogenesis for $M_{1} \gtrsim 10^{11}\,\mathrm{GeV}$ and phase transition temperatures $T_* \gtrsim 10^{6}\,\mathrm{GeV}$, for which the novel GW spectrum is detectable in ET, BBO and upcoming LVK. If RHN decays also populate a dark-sector fermion with mass $m_χ \in [10^{-4},10^{4}],\mathrm{GeV}$, successful co-genesis of baryons and asymmetric dark matter occurs for $T_* \gtrsim 10^{7}\,\mathrm{GeV}$ and $M_{1} \gtrsim 10^{9}\,\mathrm{GeV}$, naturally explaining $Ω_{\rm DM} \simeq 5Ω_{\rm B}$. The corresponding GW signals are testable with LISA, ET, and BBO. Finally, we analyze a UV-complete multi-Majoron model, based on a global $U(1)_N \times U(1)_{\rm B-L}$ extension, motivated from the hierarchy of lepton masses, which we dub as Mojaron collider. The corresponding FOPT in this model leaves a distinctive GW signature arising from RHN production during $U(1)_N$ symmetry breaking detectable by BBO, ET and upcoming LVK. Successful leptogenesis is realized for heaviest RHN mass $M_3 \sim 10^{10}\,\mathrm{GeV}$ and a $U(1)_N$ breaking vev $v_2 \sim \mathcal{O}(\mathrm{TeV})$, which sets the seesaw scale.</abstract>
    </arXiv>

            </metadata>
        </record>

    </GetRecord>
</OAI-PMH>