<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<OAI-PMH xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" 
         xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance"
         xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/OAI-PMH.xsd">
    <responseDate>2026-07-13T06:28:00Z</responseDate>
                <request verb="GetRecord" identifier="oai:arXiv.org:2512.08429" metadataPrefix="arXiv">http://oaipmh.arxiv.org/oai</request>


    <GetRecord>
                <record>
                <header>
        <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:2512.08429</identifier>
        <datestamp>2025-12-10</datestamp>
            <setSpec>physics:quant-ph</setSpec>
    </header>

            <metadata>
                        <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ https://oaipmh.arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
        <id>2512.08429</id>
        <created>2025-12-09</created>
            <updated>2025-12-10</updated>
        <authors>
                <author>
                    <keyname>Chapman</keyname>
                        <forenames>Joseph C.</forenames>
                </author>
                <author>
                    <keyname>Zhang</keyname>
                        <forenames>Yanbao</forenames>
                </author>
                <author>
                    <keyname>Lukens</keyname>
                        <forenames>Joseph M.</forenames>
                </author>
                <author>
                    <keyname>Marino</keyname>
                        <forenames>Alberto M.</forenames>
                </author>
                <author>
                    <keyname>Dumitrescu</keyname>
                        <forenames>Eugene</forenames>
                </author>
                <author>
                    <keyname>Wang</keyname>
                        <forenames>Yan</forenames>
                </author>
                <author>
                    <keyname>Peters</keyname>
                        <forenames>Nicholas A.</forenames>
                </author>
        </authors>
        <title>Real-time heralded non-Gaussian teleportation resource-state generator</title>
            <categories>quant-ph</categories>
            <comments>Main: 6 pages, 4 figures. Supplemental: 22 pages, 6 figures, 2 tables</comments>
            <license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license>
            <abstract>Quantum teleportation is a fundamental quantum communications primitive that requires an entangled resource state. In the continuous-variable regime, non-Gaussian entangled resources have been shown theoretically to improve teleportation fidelity compared to Gaussian squeezed vacuum. We experimentally demonstrate a heralded two-mode resource state for non-Gaussian teleportation capable of real-time use. We characterize this state with two-mode homodyne tomography showing it has fidelity $F=0.973\pm 0.005$ with the expected resource state. Real-time use is enabled by a photon-subtraction orchestrator system performing live coincidence detection and outputting low-jitter and low-latency heralding signals. Live collection of real-time quadrature measurements of photon-subtracted states is enabled by the development of a synchronized homodyne detection server where the orchestrator system queries to collect the real-time quadrature samples corresponding to the heralded state. These results demonstrate significant advancement in enabling the use of heralded non-Gaussian states in quantum networking protocols, especially in the context of quantum repeaters, non-Gaussian quantum sensing and measurement-based quantum computing.</abstract>
    </arXiv>

            </metadata>
        </record>

    </GetRecord>
</OAI-PMH>