<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<OAI-PMH xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" 
         xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance"
         xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/OAI-PMH.xsd">
    <responseDate>2026-07-13T06:26:25Z</responseDate>
                <request verb="GetRecord" identifier="oai:arXiv.org:2602.20789" metadataPrefix="arXiv">http://oaipmh.arxiv.org/oai</request>


    <GetRecord>
                <record>
                <header>
        <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:2602.20789</identifier>
        <datestamp>2026-05-28</datestamp>
            <setSpec>physics:astro-ph:EP</setSpec>
    </header>

            <metadata>
                        <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ https://oaipmh.arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
        <id>2602.20789</id>
        <created>2026-02-24</created>
            <updated>2026-05-28</updated>
        <authors>
                <author>
                    <keyname>Covone</keyname>
                        <forenames>Giovanni</forenames>
                </author>
                <author>
                    <keyname>Balbi</keyname>
                        <forenames>Amedeo</forenames>
                </author>
        </authors>
        <title>Photosynthetic exergy I. Thermodynamic limits for habitable-zone planets</title>
            <categories>astro-ph.EP</categories>
            <comments>10 pages, 3 figures. Submitted to MNRAS</comments>
            <journal-ref>Monthly Notices of the Royal Astronomical Society, Vol. 548, Issue 2, id.stag414 (2026)</journal-ref>
            <doi>10.1093/mnras/stag414</doi>
            <license>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0/</license>
            <abstract>Photosynthesis is central to Earth&#39;s biosphere and a prime candidate for sustaining complex life on habitable exoplanets, yet a thermodynamically consistent treatment of the work potential of stellar radiation at planetary surfaces is still lacking. We develop a radiative-thermodynamic framework that quantifies the maximum useful work extractable for a given star-planet configuration and yields exergy-based bounds on photosynthetic power and long-wavelength absorption cutoffs. From these we derive kinetically constrained red limits for high-$ΔG$ photochemistry and apply them to Earth-like planets receiving the same bolometric flux from FGK and M blackbody hosts, computing thresholded photon supplies and truncated exergy fluxes below a photosystem II red limit. For such planets the constraints confine single-photon oxygenic photosynthesis to near-infrared bands around Solar-type stars and to somewhat bluer wavelengths around late M dwarfs. Integrated over the stellar spectrum, the thresholded photon supply and truncated exergy available to drive a photosystem water-oxidation step are larger by factors $\sim 5$ around FGK hosts than around $T_\star\approx 3000$~K M dwarfs. For the Solar-Earth system, the exergy-based upper bound on O$_2$ production exceeds the observed O$_2$ throughput by several orders of magnitude, consistent with Earth&#39;s photosynthetic efficiencies. Cool M dwarfs suffer a double penalty: fewer photons above threshold and a lower shortwave exergy fraction, yielding systematically tighter ceilings on high-$ΔG$ photosynthesis than around FGK stars. Our framework provides upper limits on photosynthetically harvestable power on habitable-zone planets and enables comparisons of photosynthetic potential across exoplanetary systems, and can be extended to multi-band photosystems.</abstract>
    </arXiv>

            </metadata>
        </record>

    </GetRecord>
</OAI-PMH>