<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<OAI-PMH xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" 
         xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance"
         xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/OAI-PMH.xsd">
    <responseDate>2026-07-13T06:22:02Z</responseDate>
                <request verb="GetRecord" identifier="oai:arXiv.org:2603.22516" metadataPrefix="arXiv">http://oaipmh.arxiv.org/oai</request>


    <GetRecord>
                <record>
                <header>
        <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:2603.22516</identifier>
        <datestamp>2026-03-25</datestamp>
            <setSpec>physics:gr-qc</setSpec>
    </header>

            <metadata>
                        <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ https://oaipmh.arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
        <id>2603.22516</id>
        <created>2026-03-23</created>
            <updated>2026-03-25</updated>
        <authors>
                <author>
                    <keyname>Ewasiuk</keyname>
                        <forenames>Christopher</forenames>
                </author>
                <author>
                    <keyname>Profumo</keyname>
                        <forenames>Stefano</forenames>
                </author>
        </authors>
        <title>Quantum Tunneling of Primordial Black Holes to White Holes: Rates, Constraints, and Implications for Fast Radio Bursts</title>
            <categories>gr-qc</categories>
            <comments>28 pages, 3 figures</comments>
            <license>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0/</license>
            <abstract>We calculate the present-day and cosmological volumetric rate of primordial black hole (PBH) quantum tunneling events to white holes, incorporating the competition between Hawking evaporation and tunneling, cosmological depletion, realistic mass-dependent abundance constraints, extended mass functions, and the alternative memory-burden scenario. The burst rate is maximized along a narrow ridge in the mass--tunneling-parameter plane where the effective PBH lifetime is comparable to the age of the Universe. Within the canonical Planck-star range of tunneling timescales, FRB-level rates arise only in two highly restricted regions: a low-mass window near the evaporation boundary, and a narrow sequential window where evaporation precedes tunneling; broadening the PBH mass function does not qualitatively alter this conclusion. We further assess observational constraints from FRB repetition statistics, radio spectral properties, prompt and diffuse gamma-ray limits, host-galaxy demographics, and gravitational-wave signatures. All current observations are consistent with a subdominant white-hole contribution to the FRB population but strongly disfavor a dominant origin. The rate calculation does not generically support FRB-level event densities, and any viable FRB interpretation requires narrow, fine-tuned, and strongly assumption-dependent corners of parameter space.</abstract>
    </arXiv>

            </metadata>
        </record>

    </GetRecord>
</OAI-PMH>