<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<OAI-PMH xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" 
         xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance"
         xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/OAI-PMH.xsd">
    <responseDate>2026-07-13T06:28:35Z</responseDate>
                <request verb="GetRecord" identifier="oai:arXiv.org:2606.28640" metadataPrefix="arXiv">http://oaipmh.arxiv.org/oai</request>


    <GetRecord>
                <record>
                <header>
        <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:2606.28640</identifier>
        <datestamp>2026-06-30</datestamp>
            <setSpec>physics:quant-ph</setSpec>
            <setSpec>physics:math-ph</setSpec>
            <setSpec>math:math:MP</setSpec>
            <setSpec>physics:physics:chem-ph</setSpec>
    </header>

            <metadata>
                        <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ https://oaipmh.arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
        <id>2606.28640</id>
        <created>2026-06-26</created>
            <updated>2026-06-30</updated>
        <authors>
                <author>
                    <keyname>Lubchenko</keyname>
                        <forenames>Vassiliy</forenames>
                </author>
        </authors>
        <title>The Schrödinger equation in the complex plane and quantum entanglement</title>
            <categories>quant-ph math-ph math.MP physics.chem-ph</categories>
            <license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license>
            <abstract>We formulate a continuity equation for the Schrödinger equation in the complex space. We define a complex momentum by normalizing the complex current by the particle density. This momentum is a quantum analog of the classical, kinematic momentum analytically continued into the complex plane. The kinematic momentum and the gradient of the wavefunction&#39;s phase each represent a fluid-like flow in the complex plane; the phase-gradient flow is incompressible. The zeros of the wavefunction give rise to simple poles in the momentum. The poles manifest as irrotational vortexes in the phase-gradient flow, while critical points of the wavefunction present as rigid body-like rotational flows of the kinematic momentum. A discrete nature of elementary excitations comes about inherently because the quantity of the poles is automatically integer. An exact quantization condition is subsequently formulated, which reduces to the Bohr-Sommerfeld condition in the semiclassical limit. We establish a priori that the Bohr-Sommerfeld condition must be exact for the Harmonic Oscillator. We show that the kinetic energy is a sum of contributions of the average value and fluctuations, respectively, of the kinematic momentum. The zero-point vibrations within bound states are solely due to the fluctuations of the momentum and manifest as rigid-body flows at infinity. The momentum poles -- and hence the wavefunction&#39;s zeros -- can be viewed as emergent, consistent with the remarkable property of quantum entanglement exhibited by standing wave solutions of the Schrödinger equation.</abstract>
    </arXiv>

            </metadata>
        </record>

    </GetRecord>
</OAI-PMH>