<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<OAI-PMH xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" 
         xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance"
         xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/OAI-PMH.xsd">
    <responseDate>2026-07-13T06:23:26Z</responseDate>
                <request verb="GetRecord" identifier="oai:arXiv.org:2512.11091" metadataPrefix="arXiv">http://oaipmh.arxiv.org/oai</request>


    <GetRecord>
                <record>
                <header>
        <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:2512.11091</identifier>
        <datestamp>2025-12-15</datestamp>
            <setSpec>physics:physics:space-ph</setSpec>
            <setSpec>physics:quant-ph</setSpec>
    </header>

            <metadata>
                        <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ https://oaipmh.arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
        <id>2512.11091</id>
        <created>2025-12-11</created>
            <updated>2025-12-15</updated>
        <authors>
                <author>
                    <keyname>Saklakov</keyname>
                        <forenames>Denis</forenames>
                </author>
        </authors>
        <title>Microgravity and Near-Absolute Zero: A New Frontier in Quantum Computing Hardware</title>
            <categories>physics.space-ph quant-ph</categories>
            <comments>27 pages, 0 figures. Includes complete bibliography. Submitted to arXiv for open access distribution</comments>
            <acm-class>None</acm-class>
            <license>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0/</license>
            <abstract>Quantum computing qubits are notoriously fragile, requiring extreme isolation from environmental disturbances. This paper advances the hypothesis that a combination of microgravity and ultra-low temperature (near absolute zero) provides an almost &#34;ideal&#34; operating environment for quantum hardware. Under such conditions, gravitational perturbations, thermal noise, and vibrational disturbances are minimized, thereby significantly extending qubit coherence times and reducing error rates. We survey four leading qubit platforms - superconducting circuits, trapped ions, ultracold neutral atoms, and photonic qubits - and explain how each can benefit from a weightless, cryogenic setting. Recent experiments support this vision: Bose-Einstein condensates on the International Space Station (ISS) maintained matter-wave coherence far longer than on Earth, atomic clocks in orbit achieved record stability, and a photonic quantum computer deployed in space is demonstrating robust operation. Finally, we outline a proposed side-by-side experiment comparing identical quantum processors on the ground and in microgravity. Such a test would directly measure improvements in qubit coherence (T1, T2), gate fidelity, and readout accuracy when the influence of gravity is removed.</abstract>
    </arXiv>

            </metadata>
        </record>

    </GetRecord>
</OAI-PMH>