<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<OAI-PMH xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" 
         xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance"
         xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/OAI-PMH.xsd">
    <responseDate>2026-07-13T06:27:11Z</responseDate>
                <request verb="GetRecord" identifier="oai:arXiv.org:2605.18658" metadataPrefix="arXiv">http://oaipmh.arxiv.org/oai</request>


    <GetRecord>
                <record>
                <header>
        <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:2605.18658</identifier>
        <datestamp>2026-05-19</datestamp>
            <setSpec>physics:quant-ph</setSpec>
            <setSpec>physics:physics:atom-ph</setSpec>
    </header>

            <metadata>
                        <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ https://oaipmh.arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
        <id>2605.18658</id>
        <created>2026-05-18</created>
            <updated>2026-05-19</updated>
        <authors>
                <author>
                    <keyname>Huang</keyname>
                        <forenames>Jordan</forenames>
                </author>
                <author>
                    <keyname>Kasaba</keyname>
                        <forenames>Ethan</forenames>
                </author>
                <author>
                    <keyname>DiNapoli</keyname>
                        <forenames>Thomas J.</forenames>
                </author>
                <author>
                    <keyname>Roy</keyname>
                        <forenames>Tanay</forenames>
                </author>
                <author>
                    <keyname>Chakram</keyname>
                        <forenames>Srivatsan</forenames>
                </author>
        </authors>
        <title>Universal Jaynes-Cummings Control of an Oscillator</title>
            <categories>quant-ph physics.atom-ph</categories>
            <comments>8 pages of main text with 4 figures, 17 pages of supplementary information with 11 figures</comments>
            <license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license>
            <abstract>The Jaynes-Cummings (JC) interaction-the coherent exchange of excitations between a two-level system and a harmonic oscillator-is one of the fundamental interactions of quantum optics, realized across platforms such as cavity quantum electrodynamics, trapped ions, mechanical resonators, and superconducting circuits. Although JC interactions and qubit rotations form a universal gate set for oscillator control, practical implementations have not been demonstrated. Here we develop and experimentally demonstrate universal JC-based oscillator control by compiling arbitrary unitary gates into sequences of JC interactions and qubit rotations. In our experiment, the oscillator is realized using a mode of a high quality factor microwave cavity and the ancilla qubit using a superconducting transmon circuit, with the JC interaction implemented by a sideband interaction enabled by the Josephson nonlinearity. The native gates are constructed to be closed below a chosen cutoff photon number, encoding a qudit with suppressed leakage errors, while ancilla relaxation errors are detectable. We further find that the dispersive shift serves as a compilation resource that reduces circuit depths. We demonstrate universal qudit control and implement a single-qutrit gate set with a mean post-selected process fidelity of 96%, as well as ququart and ququint shift gates. These results establish Jaynes-Cummings control as a practical route to universal oscillator control, enabling programmable bosonic processors across a variety of quantum platforms.</abstract>
    </arXiv>

            </metadata>
        </record>

    </GetRecord>
</OAI-PMH>