<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<OAI-PMH xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" 
         xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance"
         xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/OAI-PMH.xsd">
    <responseDate>2026-07-09T15:22:48Z</responseDate>
                <request verb="GetRecord" identifier="oai:arXiv.org:2607.05629v1" metadataPrefix="arXiv">http://oaipmh.arxiv.org/oai</request>


    <GetRecord>
                <record>
                <header>
        <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:2607.05629</identifier>
        <datestamp>2026-07-08</datestamp>
            <setSpec>physics:astro-ph:IM</setSpec>
            <setSpec>physics:astro-ph:EP</setSpec>
    </header>

            <metadata>
                        <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ https://oaipmh.arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
        <id>2607.05629</id>
        <created>2026-07-06</created>
            <updated>2026-07-08</updated>
        <authors>
                <author>
                    <keyname>Duffey</keyname>
                        <forenames>Christopher S.</forenames>
                </author>
                <author>
                    <keyname>Brisset</keyname>
                        <forenames>Julie</forenames>
                </author>
                <author>
                    <keyname>Hoskinson</keyname>
                        <forenames>Myles</forenames>
                </author>
                <author>
                    <keyname>Haynes</keyname>
                        <forenames>Jakob</forenames>
                </author>
                <author>
                    <keyname>Lyakh</keyname>
                        <forenames>Kathrine</forenames>
                </author>
        </authors>
        <title>Detection of Organics in Water Ice by Optical-PhotoThermal Infrared Spectroscopy</title>
            <categories>astro-ph.IM astro-ph.EP</categories>
            <license>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0/</license>
            <abstract>The detection and characterization of organic molecules within water ice is vital for interpreting observations of icy moons and comets. However, organic-ice interactions often distort intrinsic water-ice absorption features, complicating infrared (IR) spectral analysis. This study evaluated Optical Photothermal Infrared (O-PTIR) spectroscopy as a non-destructive, sub-micrometer resolution technique to detect and quantify embedded organics. Using a temperature-controlled sample environment to maintain ice stability, frozen mixtures of amino and hydroxy acids were analyzed across a broad concentration range. L-glycine was successfully detected down to approximately $10^{-6}\text{ M}$, yielding an experimental limit of detection (LOD) of $0.2\,μ\text{M}$ and a limit of quantification (LOQ) of $3.83\,μ\text{M}$. Furthermore, O-PTIR measurements of binary mixtures containing L-glycine and lactic acid demonstrated the capacity to differentiate and quantify multiple organic components within a single ice matrix. Notably, a broad absorption feature centered near the water-bending mode appeared exclusively in organic-bearing ice samples and was absent in pure $\text{H}_2\text{O}$ and $\text{D}_2\text{O}$ controls. Comparative analysis in these matrices revealed that embedded organics actively perturb intrinsic ice features, providing new constraints on organic-ice interactions. Ultimately, these results demonstrate that O-PTIR spectroscopy can reliably detect, quantify, and spatially resolve organic compounds in water ice while preserving crucial sample context. The technique offers a promising framework for future laboratory investigations of icy planetary materials and directly informs the interpretation of spectroscopic data from volatile-rich space environments.</abstract>
    </arXiv>

            </metadata>
        </record>

    </GetRecord>
</OAI-PMH>