<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<OAI-PMH xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" 
         xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance"
         xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/OAI-PMH.xsd">
    <responseDate>2026-07-13T06:20:55Z</responseDate>
                <request verb="GetRecord" identifier="oai:arXiv.org:2508.09965" metadataPrefix="arXiv">http://oaipmh.arxiv.org/oai</request>


    <GetRecord>
                <record>
                <header>
        <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:2508.09965</identifier>
        <datestamp>2026-05-12</datestamp>
            <setSpec>physics:astro-ph:CO</setSpec>
            <setSpec>physics:astro-ph:HE</setSpec>
            <setSpec>physics:gr-qc</setSpec>
    </header>

            <metadata>
                        <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ https://oaipmh.arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
        <id>2508.09965</id>
        <created>2026-05-11</created>
            <updated>2026-05-12</updated>
        <authors>
                <author>
                    <keyname>De Luca</keyname>
                        <forenames>Valerio</forenames>
                </author>
                <author>
                    <keyname>Franciolini</keyname>
                        <forenames>Gabriele</forenames>
                </author>
                <author>
                    <keyname>Riotto</keyname>
                        <forenames>Antonio</forenames>
                </author>
        </authors>
        <title>GW231123: A Possible Primordial Black Hole Origin</title>
            <categories>astro-ph.CO astro-ph.HE gr-qc</categories>
            <comments>11 pages, 4 figures. v2: matching version published in Physical Review Letters</comments>
            <license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license>
            <abstract>GW231123, the heaviest binary black hole merger detected by the LIGO-Virgo-KAGRA Collaboration to date, lies in the pair-instability mass gap and exhibits unusually high component spins. In this Letter, we show that both merging black holes may have a primordial origin with smaller initial masses. The observed masses and, crucially, the spins of GW231123 are naturally accommodated within the most vanilla primordial black hole framework, once cosmological accretion is taken into account. Interestingly, the parameter space needed to explain the inferred GW231123 rate is at the edge of the exclusion region from x-ray and CMB observations, suggesting that this interpretation can be either confirmed or ruled out. The upcoming O5 observing run by the collaboration should detect ${\cal O}(20)$ similar events, testing their mass-spin correlation, while next-generation detectors would be capable of observing high redshift events, as predicted in this scenario.</abstract>
    </arXiv>

            </metadata>
        </record>

    </GetRecord>
</OAI-PMH>