<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<OAI-PMH xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" 
         xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance"
         xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/OAI-PMH.xsd">
    <responseDate>2026-07-12T21:13:53Z</responseDate>
                <request verb="GetRecord" identifier="oai:arXiv.org:2605.04158v2" metadataPrefix="arXiv">http://oaipmh.arxiv.org/oai</request>


    <GetRecord>
                <record>
                <header>
        <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:2605.04158</identifier>
        <datestamp>2026-05-11</datestamp>
            <setSpec>physics:gr-qc</setSpec>
            <setSpec>physics:astro-ph:HE</setSpec>
    </header>

            <metadata>
                        <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ https://oaipmh.arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
        <id>2605.04158</id>
        <created>2026-05-07</created>
            <updated>2026-05-11</updated>
        <authors>
                <author>
                    <keyname>Ghosh</keyname>
                        <forenames>Rohit</forenames>
                </author>
                <author>
                    <keyname>Ghose</keyname>
                        <forenames>Souvik</forenames>
                </author>
                <author>
                    <keyname>Raychaudhuri</keyname>
                        <forenames>Biplab</forenames>
                </author>
                <author>
                    <keyname>Das</keyname>
                        <forenames>Apashanka</forenames>
                </author>
                <author>
                    <keyname>Das</keyname>
                        <forenames>Tapas K.</forenames>
                </author>
        </authors>
        <title>Emergent gravity from nonlinear perturbation of spherical accretion with variable adiabatic index</title>
            <categories>gr-qc astro-ph.HE</categories>
            <comments>10 pages, 1 figure, revetex class</comments>
            <license>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0/</license>
            <abstract>The main aim of the present work is to demonstrate that the analogue gravity phenomena are not an artifact of linear perturbation, rather gravity-like effects emerge through the non linear higher order perturbation of transonic fluid as well. To establish that fact, a spherically accreting astrophysical system has been considered where the hydrodynamic accretion with a relativistic, multi-component equation of state with position dependent adiabatic index onto compact astrophysical objects has been considered. By extending the acoustic metric formalism beyond the linear regime, it has been shown that the aforementioned perturbations satisfy a covariant wave equation in an effective acoustic spacetime with non-linear corrections, making the analogue geometry dynamical. As a consequence, the acoustic horizon can shift (inward or outward), depending on the relative amplitudes of density, temperature, and mass accretion-rate fluctuations. This provides a more realistic framework to investigate the dynamics of the non-linear analogue spacetime in astrophysically relevant accretion flows.</abstract>
    </arXiv>

            </metadata>
        </record>

    </GetRecord>
</OAI-PMH>