<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<OAI-PMH xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" 
         xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance"
         xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/OAI-PMH.xsd">
    <responseDate>2026-07-13T06:22:26Z</responseDate>
                <request verb="GetRecord" identifier="oai:arXiv.org:2606.22376" metadataPrefix="arXiv">http://oaipmh.arxiv.org/oai</request>


    <GetRecord>
                <record>
                <header>
        <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:2606.22376</identifier>
        <datestamp>2026-06-23</datestamp>
            <setSpec>physics:quant-ph</setSpec>
    </header>

            <metadata>
                        <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ https://oaipmh.arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
        <id>2606.22376</id>
        <created>2026-06-21</created>
            <updated>2026-06-23</updated>
        <authors>
                <author>
                    <keyname>Xu</keyname>
                        <forenames>Huikai</forenames>
                </author>
                <author>
                    <keyname>Han</keyname>
                        <forenames>Jiaxiu</forenames>
                </author>
                <author>
                    <keyname>Ou</keyname>
                        <forenames>Shigang</forenames>
                </author>
                <author>
                    <keyname>Ye</keyname>
                        <forenames>Cheng</forenames>
                </author>
                <author>
                    <keyname>Shen</keyname>
                        <forenames>Zisong</forenames>
                </author>
                <author>
                    <keyname>Gao</keyname>
                        <forenames>Jing</forenames>
                </author>
                <author>
                    <keyname>Wang</keyname>
                        <forenames>Yijia</forenames>
                </author>
                <author>
                    <keyname>Che</keyname>
                        <forenames>Tianrui</forenames>
                </author>
                <author>
                    <keyname>Song</keyname>
                        <forenames>Yu</forenames>
                </author>
                <author>
                    <keyname>Liu</keyname>
                        <forenames>Weiyang</forenames>
                </author>
                <author>
                    <keyname>Wang</keyname>
                        <forenames>Lei</forenames>
                </author>
                <author>
                    <keyname>Zhang</keyname>
                        <forenames>Lin-Feng</forenames>
                </author>
                <author>
                    <keyname>Zhang</keyname>
                        <forenames>Pan</forenames>
                </author>
                <author>
                    <keyname>Yu</keyname>
                        <forenames>Hai-Feng</forenames>
                </author>
        </authors>
        <title>Vibe Calibration: Autonomous Bring-up of a 112-Qubit Superconducting Quantum Processor by a Skill-Orchestrating Language Agent</title>
            <categories>quant-ph</categories>
            <license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license>
            <abstract>Superconducting quantum computing is one of the most mature solid-state platforms for quantum computation, with processors exceeding one hundred qubits. Yet further scaling toward fault-tolerant quantum computing is increasingly constrained by calibration complexity. Conventional scripts are brittle to anomalous signals, and expert judgment is bounded by cognitive bandwidth and serial operation time, failing to keep pace with system scale. Here we report Vibe Calibration, an autonomous calibration system orchestrated by large language model agents, which distills expert tacit knowledge into reusable Skills. Each Skill is organized as a decision tree that packages parameterized measurement commands, quantitative acceptance criteria, and audit records, enabling autonomous execution and self-healing. We capture this knowledge through a three-phase human-in-the-loop distillation process and fine-tune a large language model on validated trajectories. On a 112-qubit processor with frequency-tunable transmons, the system autonomously completes calibration of 108 out of 112 qubits in 4.7 hours, achieving a 4--5$\times$ speedup over manual calibration of the full 112 qubits. A cross-validated comparison with expert manual calibration on a 16-qubit subset shows agreement on 14 out of 16 qubits. More importantly, the model demonstrates transferable calibration workflows across devices. While low-level control scripts require minor interface adaptation for different hardware platforms, the core decision logic and task orchestration generalize to new processors, demonstrating a reusable laboratory interface rather than a memorized script.This work demonstrates, for the first time, fully autonomous calibration of a hundred-qubit superconducting processor through reusable and auditable Skills, removing a critical barrier to scalable quantum hardware operation.</abstract>
    </arXiv>

            </metadata>
        </record>

    </GetRecord>
</OAI-PMH>