<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<OAI-PMH xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" 
         xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance"
         xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/OAI-PMH.xsd">
    <responseDate>2026-07-12T22:49:02Z</responseDate>
                <request verb="GetRecord" identifier="oai:arXiv.org:2605.10587v1" metadataPrefix="arXiv">http://oaipmh.arxiv.org/oai</request>


    <GetRecord>
                <record>
                <header>
        <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:2605.10587</identifier>
        <datestamp>2026-05-12</datestamp>
            <setSpec>physics:astro-ph:HE</setSpec>
            <setSpec>physics:gr-qc</setSpec>
            <setSpec>physics:hep-ph</setSpec>
    </header>

            <metadata>
                        <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ https://oaipmh.arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
        <id>2605.10587</id>
        <created>2026-05-11</created>
            <updated>2026-05-12</updated>
        <authors>
                <author>
                    <keyname>Corianò</keyname>
                        <forenames>Claudio</forenames>
                </author>
                <author>
                    <keyname>Frampton</keyname>
                        <forenames>Paul H.</forenames>
                </author>
                <author>
                    <keyname>Torcellini</keyname>
                        <forenames>Leonardo</forenames>
                </author>
        </authors>
        <title>Astrons: Reissner-Nordström Primordial Naked Singularities</title>
            <categories>astro-ph.HE gr-qc hep-ph</categories>
            <comments>10 pages, 3 Figs</comments>
            <license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license>
            <abstract>We summarize a set of constraints on a proposed population of primordial, ultra-massive, electrically charged compact objects, which we call astrons. The analysis combines charge generation, charge saturation, persistence of the charge in an ionized medium, screening by the intergalactic plasma, the Reissner--Nordström geometry of highly charged compact objects, lensing, and the cosmological implications of a sparse charged population. We also discuss the possible relation to the early structures revealed by the James Webb Space Telescope: if astrons are relevant there, they would be primordial dark seeds rather than luminous objects directly observed at high redshift. The resulting scenario is sharply constrained. Ordinary accretion saturation gives charges far below the large-charge phenomenological benchmark, screening is a serious plasma-physics issue, and a large charge can place the exterior geometry deep in the super-extremal regime. As expected at the level of a homogeneous Friedmann--Lema\^ıtre--Robertson--Walker (FLRW) description, the interaction energy of a population of charged objects scales as \(a^{-4}\), so the simplest perfect-fluid reduction does not generate asymptotically late-time acceleration; any acceleration era tied to that homogeneous component can only be transitory. The astron scenario should be regarded as a constrained framework whose viability depends on plasma physics and on a cosmological treatment beyond the homogeneous approximation.</abstract>
    </arXiv>

            </metadata>
        </record>

    </GetRecord>
</OAI-PMH>