<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<OAI-PMH xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" 
         xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance"
         xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/OAI-PMH.xsd">
    <responseDate>2026-07-13T06:23:38Z</responseDate>
                <request verb="GetRecord" identifier="oai:arXiv.org:2601.17938" metadataPrefix="arXiv">http://oaipmh.arxiv.org/oai</request>


    <GetRecord>
                <record>
                <header>
        <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:2601.17938</identifier>
        <datestamp>2026-06-23</datestamp>
            <setSpec>physics:astro-ph:CO</setSpec>
            <setSpec>physics:gr-qc</setSpec>
            <setSpec>physics:hep-ph</setSpec>
            <setSpec>physics:hep-th</setSpec>
    </header>

            <metadata>
                        <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ https://oaipmh.arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
        <id>2601.17938</id>
        <created>2026-06-21</created>
            <updated>2026-06-23</updated>
        <authors>
                <author>
                    <keyname>Sakharov</keyname>
                        <forenames>Alexander S.</forenames>
                </author>
                <author>
                    <keyname>Konoplich</keyname>
                        <forenames>Rostislav</forenames>
                </author>
                <author>
                    <keyname>Gogberashvili</keyname>
                        <forenames>Merab</forenames>
                </author>
                <author>
                    <keyname>Simoni</keyname>
                        <forenames>Jack</forenames>
                </author>
        </authors>
        <title>Hubble Tension as an Effect of Horizon Entanglement Nonequilibrium</title>
            <categories>astro-ph.CO gr-qc hep-ph hep-th</categories>
            <comments>24 pages, 8 figures, 5 tables, references added, text added, version accepted for publication</comments>
            <license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license>
            <abstract>We propose an infrared mechanism for alleviating the Hubble constant tension, based on a small departure from entanglement equilibrium at the cosmological apparent horizon. If the horizon entanglement entropy falls slightly below the Bekenstein-Hawking value, we parametrize the shortfall by a fractional deficit $δ(a)$ evolving with the FLRW scale factor $a$. The associated equipartition deficit at the Gibbons-Hawking temperature then sources a smooth, homogeneous component whose density scales as $H^{2}/G$, with a dimensionless coefficient $c_{e}^{2}(a)$ of order unity times $δ(a)$. Because this component tracks $H^{2}$, it is negligible at early times but can activate at redshifts $z\lesssim 1$, raising the late time expansion rate by a few percent without affecting recombination or the sound horizon. We present a minimal three parameter activation model for $c_{e}^{2}(a)$ and derive its impact on the background expansion, effective equation of state, and linear growth for a smooth entanglement sector. The framework predicts a small boost in $H(z)$, a mild suppression of $fσ_{8}(z)$, and a corresponding modification of the low-$z$ distance-redshift relation. We test these predictions against current low-redshift data sets, including SN~Ia distance moduli, baryon acoustic oscillation distance measurements, cosmic chronometer $H(z)$ data, and redshift space distortion constraints, and discuss whether the $H_0$ tension can be consistently interpreted as a late-time, horizon-scale information deficit rather than an early universe modification.</abstract>
    </arXiv>

            </metadata>
        </record>

    </GetRecord>
</OAI-PMH>