<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<OAI-PMH xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" 
         xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance"
         xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/OAI-PMH.xsd">
    <responseDate>2026-07-13T06:26:30Z</responseDate>
                <request verb="GetRecord" identifier="oai:arXiv.org:2602.23415" metadataPrefix="arXiv">http://oaipmh.arxiv.org/oai</request>


    <GetRecord>
                <record>
                <header>
        <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:2602.23415</identifier>
        <datestamp>2026-03-11</datestamp>
            <setSpec>physics:hep-ph</setSpec>
            <setSpec>physics:astro-ph:HE</setSpec>
            <setSpec>physics:hep-ex</setSpec>
            <setSpec>physics:physics:atom-ph</setSpec>
    </header>

            <metadata>
                        <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ https://oaipmh.arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
        <id>2602.23415</id>
        <created>2026-03-10</created>
            <updated>2026-03-11</updated>
        <authors>
                <author>
                    <keyname>Gavilan-Martin</keyname>
                        <forenames>Daniel</forenames>
                </author>
                <author>
                    <keyname>Simon</keyname>
                        <forenames>Olivier</forenames>
                </author>
                <author>
                    <keyname>Krishna</keyname>
                        <forenames>Dhashin</forenames>
                </author>
                <author>
                    <keyname>Kimball</keyname>
                        <forenames>Derek F. Jackson</forenames>
                </author>
                <author>
                    <keyname>Budker</keyname>
                        <forenames>Dmitry</forenames>
                </author>
                <author>
                    <keyname>Wickenbrock</keyname>
                        <forenames>Arne</forenames>
                </author>
        </authors>
        <title>Black hole scalar sirens in the Milky Way</title>
            <categories>hep-ph astro-ph.HE hep-ex physics.atom-ph</categories>
            <comments>v2: Updated citations. Expanded section IIIA4</comments>
            <license>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0/</license>
            <abstract>Hypothetical light scalar particles trigger the superradiant instability around spinning black holes (BHs), causing clouds of scalars to grow around the BH. In the presence of sufficiently strong particle self-interactions (characterized by the decay constant $f$), scalars are ejected from BH orbits, resulting in coherent, non-relativistic emissions that continuously carry away the BH&#39;s angular momentum. Parameters exist for which cloud growth is much faster, and scalar depletion is much slower, than the age of the Galaxy. This defines a distinct class of astrophysical sources of scalars, which we call BH scalar sirens -- BHs that persistently emit scalars effectively forever. We compute the scalar background from the expected population of $N_\text{BH}\sim 10^{8}$ isolated stellar-mass BHs in the Milky Way, which are sirens for scalars in the mass range $10^{-13}$--$10^{-11}\,$eV and $f\lesssim 10^{14}$--$10^{9}\,$GeV. This provides a detection target independent of early-universe scalar production or cosmological initial conditions. The generated observable signals are up to two orders-of-magnitude larger than those expected from a misaligned cosmic scalar in this mass range. The energy spectrum of emitted scalars is distinctly broader and at higher velocities (up to $\sim 10^{-1}c$) than that of virialized dark matter, and encodes the mass and spin distributions of the BH population. While stellar-mass Milky Way BHs are our primary target, our framework extends to supermassive, intermediate-mass and light BHs. Given the difficulty of directly observing populations of isolated BHs, scalar emissions offer a novel probe of these otherwise invisible objects, highlighting the potential for joint discovery between scalars and BHs, and broadly motivating searches for scalars over many orders-of-magnitude in mass.</abstract>
    </arXiv>

            </metadata>
        </record>

    </GetRecord>
</OAI-PMH>