<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<OAI-PMH xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" 
         xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance"
         xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/OAI-PMH.xsd">
    <responseDate>2026-07-13T21:13:18Z</responseDate>
                <request verb="GetRecord" identifier="oai:arXiv.org:2410.15776" metadataPrefix="arXiv">http://oaipmh.arxiv.org/oai</request>


    <GetRecord>
                <record>
                <header>
        <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:2410.15776</identifier>
        <datestamp>2024-10-22</datestamp>
            <setSpec>physics:cond-mat:mtrl-sci</setSpec>
    </header>

            <metadata>
                        <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ https://oaipmh.arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
        <id>2410.15776</id>
        <created>2024-10-21</created>
            <updated>2024-10-22</updated>
        <authors>
                <author>
                    <keyname>Lee</keyname>
                        <forenames>Chang-Gi</forenames>
                </author>
                <author>
                    <keyname>Nallathambi</keyname>
                        <forenames>Varatharaja</forenames>
                </author>
                <author>
                    <keyname>Kang</keyname>
                        <forenames>TaeHyeok</forenames>
                </author>
                <author>
                    <keyname>Aota</keyname>
                        <forenames>Leonardo Shoji</forenames>
                </author>
                <author>
                    <keyname>Reichenberger</keyname>
                        <forenames>Sven</forenames>
                </author>
                <author>
                    <keyname>El-Zoka</keyname>
                        <forenames>Ayman</forenames>
                </author>
                <author>
                    <keyname>Choi</keyname>
                        <forenames>Pyuck-Pa</forenames>
                </author>
                <author>
                    <keyname>Gault</keyname>
                        <forenames>Baptiste</forenames>
                </author>
                <author>
                    <keyname>Kim</keyname>
                        <forenames>Se-Ho</forenames>
                </author>
        </authors>
        <title>Magnetocaloric effect of Fe47.5Ni37.5Mn15 bulk and nanoparticles: A cost-efficient alloy for room temperature magnetic refrigeration</title>
            <categories>cond-mat.mtrl-sci</categories>
            <license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license>
            <abstract>The development of magnetic refrigerators that operate at room temperature without the use of environmentally harmful substances represents a significant advancement in eco-friendly technology. These refrigerators employ the magnetocaloric effect (MCE), which has traditionally been achieved using expensive rare-earth elements such as gadolinium. To facilitate cost-effective commercialization, it is essential to investigate alternative materials, such as transition metal alloys. In this study, an Fe47.5Ni37.5Mn15 alloy, which has a Curie temperature that is close to room temperature, is cast, and the alloy exhibits a noteworthy cooling power of 297.68 J/kg, which makes it good for cost-effective applications. To further enhance MCE performance through super-paramagnetism (e.g. size reduction), nanoparticles of the same composition are synthesized using a top-down approach via pulsed-laser ablation in ethanol. However, these nanoparticles do not exhibit a Curie temperature near room temperature, likely due to significant carbon incorporation during synthesis, which adversely affected their magnetocaloric properties. This study underscores the potential of transition metal alloys for magnetic refrigeration and highlights the need for optimized synthesis methods to achieve desired thermal properties in nanoparticulate form.</abstract>
    </arXiv>

            </metadata>
        </record>

    </GetRecord>
</OAI-PMH>