<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<OAI-PMH xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" 
         xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance"
         xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/OAI-PMH.xsd">
    <responseDate>2026-07-13T21:13:43Z</responseDate>
                <request verb="GetRecord" identifier="oai:arXiv.org:2602.13129" metadataPrefix="arXiv">http://oaipmh.arxiv.org/oai</request>


    <GetRecord>
                <record>
                <header>
        <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:2602.13129</identifier>
        <datestamp>2026-07-07</datestamp>
            <setSpec>physics:cond-mat:quant-gas</setSpec>
    </header>

            <metadata>
                        <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ https://oaipmh.arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
        <id>2602.13129</id>
        <created>2026-02-13</created>
            <updated>2026-07-07</updated>
        <authors>
                <author>
                    <keyname>Ali</keyname>
                        <forenames>Abid</forenames>
                </author>
                <author>
                    <keyname>Zhang</keyname>
                        <forenames>Pei</forenames>
                </author>
                <author>
                    <keyname>Saito</keyname>
                        <forenames>Hiroki</forenames>
                </author>
                <author>
                    <keyname>Zhang</keyname>
                        <forenames>Yong-Chang</forenames>
                </author>
        </authors>
        <title>Emergent aperiodicity in Bose-Bose mixtures induced by spin-dependent periodic potentials</title>
            <categories>cond-mat.quant-gas</categories>
            <comments>10 pages, 8 figures</comments>
            <doi>10.1103/zt4j-57hp</doi>
            <license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license>
            <abstract>We study the ground-state and low-lying metastable phases of repulsive binary Bose-Einstein condensates confined in twisted, spin-dependent periodic optical lattices. For balanced mixtures, weak intercomponent interactions yield a fourfold momentum-space symmetry dictated by the lattice geometry. Increasing the coupling strength leads to the emergence of additional momentum peaks that combine with the lattice-induced structure to produce an eightfold rotationally symmetric pattern, signaling quasicrystalline order. At intermediate interactions, global phase separation suppresses this quasicrystalline state; however, at stronger coupling, local phase separation gives rise to a long-lived metastable phase in which the eightfold symmetry is restored. In this regime, a secondary ring of dominant momentum peaks appears at smaller wave vectors, indicating longer-wavelength density modulations and a crossover from lattice-dominated to interaction-driven quasicrystalline order. In contrast, imbalanced mixtures form partially miscible density clusters with eightfold-symmetric aperiodic patterns only at intermediate coupling, while stronger interactions drive global phase separation and permanently destroy quasicrystalline order. Real-time simulations demonstrate that these aperiodic structures are dynamically stable and experimentally accessible. Our results show that quasicrystalline order can emerge in binary condensates without explicitly aperiodic lattices and reveal population balance as a key ingredient for stabilizing quantum quasicrystals.</abstract>
    </arXiv>

            </metadata>
        </record>

    </GetRecord>
</OAI-PMH>