<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<OAI-PMH xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" 
         xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance"
         xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/OAI-PMH.xsd">
    <responseDate>2026-07-13T08:46:00Z</responseDate>
                <request verb="GetRecord" identifier="oai:arXiv.org:2605.22696" metadataPrefix="arXiv">http://oaipmh.arxiv.org/oai</request>


    <GetRecord>
                <record>
                <header>
        <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:2605.22696</identifier>
        <datestamp>2026-05-22</datestamp>
            <setSpec>physics:gr-qc</setSpec>
            <setSpec>physics:astro-ph:HE</setSpec>
            <setSpec>physics:hep-ph</setSpec>
    </header>

            <metadata>
                        <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ https://oaipmh.arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
        <id>2605.22696</id>
        <created>2026-05-21</created>
            <updated>2026-05-22</updated>
        <authors>
                <author>
                    <keyname>Dhyani</keyname>
                        <forenames>Rahul</forenames>
                </author>
                <author>
                    <keyname>Sen</keyname>
                        <forenames>Sauvik</forenames>
                </author>
                <author>
                    <keyname>Banerjee</keyname>
                        <forenames>Indrani</forenames>
                </author>
                <author>
                    <keyname>Chakraborty</keyname>
                        <forenames>Ashmita</forenames>
                </author>
                <author>
                    <keyname>Chatterjee</keyname>
                        <forenames>Arindam</forenames>
                </author>
        </authors>
        <title>Dimming of Photon Ring due to Photon-Axion Conversion around Kerr Black Holes</title>
            <categories>gr-qc astro-ph.HE hep-ph</categories>
            <comments>48 pages, 13 figures, 3 tables</comments>
            <license>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0/</license>
            <abstract>We investigate photon-axion conversion in the vicinity of rotating Kerr black holes where strong gravity traps photons on near-circular trajectories, effectively enhancing the path length. We explore the observable signatures of such a conversion near the photon region. The process, driven by ambient magnetic fields, is significantly more efficient around supermassive black holes such as M87*, since the luminosity of photons increases with the mass of the BH. By numerically evaluating photon path lengths (on which the conversion depends), we analyze how key parameters-photon frequency, axion mass, photon-axion coupling, magnetic field strength, plasma density, and black hole spin-affect the conversion probability and the resultant dimming of photon spectral luminosity. We find that the conversion is most efficient at high frequencies (X-rays and gamma rays), while the frequency window associated with efficient conversion widens with an increase in the photon-axion coupling and a decrease in the electron density and the axion mass. The magnitude of dimming of the photon spectral luminosity depends primarily on the magnetic field, the photon-axion coupling and the BH spin. Our study reveals that rotating black holes generally exhibit enhanced dimming compared to static ones. Thus, if future telescopes achieving a resolution $\sim 10^{-5}$ arcsec in the X-ray/gamma-ray band detect a dimming of the photon spectral luminosity, then they can provide interesting constraints on the axion mass and its coupling with photons.</abstract>
    </arXiv>

            </metadata>
        </record>

    </GetRecord>
</OAI-PMH>