<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<OAI-PMH xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" 
         xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance"
         xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/OAI-PMH.xsd">
    <responseDate>2026-07-12T23:06:00Z</responseDate>
                <request verb="GetRecord" identifier="oai:arXiv.org:2605.12246v2" metadataPrefix="arXiv">http://oaipmh.arxiv.org/oai</request>


    <GetRecord>
                <record>
                <header>
        <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:2605.12246</identifier>
        <datestamp>2026-07-07</datestamp>
            <setSpec>physics:hep-ph</setSpec>
            <setSpec>physics:cond-mat:stat-mech</setSpec>
            <setSpec>physics:gr-qc</setSpec>
    </header>

            <metadata>
                        <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ https://oaipmh.arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
        <id>2605.12246</id>
        <created>2026-07-06</created>
            <updated>2026-07-07</updated>
        <authors>
                <author>
                    <keyname>Santos</keyname>
                        <forenames>Renato Vieira dos</forenames>
                </author>
        </authors>
        <title>Toward Charge-Dependent Tests of the Equivalence Principle: A Phenomenological Parameter and an Unexplored Frontier</title>
            <categories>hep-ph cond-mat.stat-mech gr-qc</categories>
            <comments>Version published in PRD</comments>
            <journal-ref>Physical Review D 2026</journal-ref>
            <doi>10.1103/frfk-vp26</doi>
            <license>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0/</license>
            <abstract>We introduce and define the phenomenological parameter $κ$, defined by $Δa/g = κ\, Δ(q/m)$, to quantify potential linear coupling between electric charge and gravitational acceleration. A synthesis of existing precision equivalence principle experiments yields the first quantitative estimate of the effective sensitivity to this coupling: $|κ| &lt; 2.1 \times 10^{-4}$ kg/C at 95\% confidence level. This constraint is approximately eleven orders of magnitude less stringent than corresponding bounds on composition-dependent violations, revealing that the electromagnetic axis remains a largely underexplored frontier in empirical gravity. We connect $κ$ to established frameworks -- the Standard-Model Extension and the $THεμ$ formalism -- showing that it occupies a region of parameter space untouched by existing high-precision tests. An effective field theory analysis shows that dimension-six operators that couple curvature directly to the electromagnetic field strength are suppressed by the minuscule terrestrial spacetime curvature ($G_N ρ_\oplus \sim 10^{-55}~\text{GeV}^2$) and are therefore phenomenologically irrelevant. Consequently, a future measurement of $κ$ at an accessible level would not probe minimal geometric couplings but would signal physics beyond minimal gravitational EFT, such as mediation by light scalar fields as in Einstein-Maxwell-Dilaton theory. We examine the Schiff-Barnhill effect, the primary systematic background for any such measurement, and show how it can be separated from a genuine signal. We outline the necessary experimental strategy, focused on maximizing charge-to-mass ratio differences, to transform this overlooked axis into a targeted probe for new physics.</abstract>
    </arXiv>

            </metadata>
        </record>

    </GetRecord>
</OAI-PMH>