<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<OAI-PMH xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" 
         xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance"
         xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/OAI-PMH.xsd">
    <responseDate>2026-07-13T06:26:08Z</responseDate>
                <request verb="GetRecord" identifier="oai:arXiv.org:2601.14500" metadataPrefix="arXiv">http://oaipmh.arxiv.org/oai</request>


    <GetRecord>
                <record>
                <header>
        <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:2601.14500</identifier>
        <datestamp>2026-01-22</datestamp>
            <setSpec>physics:cond-mat:supr-con</setSpec>
            <setSpec>physics:cond-mat:mes-hall</setSpec>
            <setSpec>physics:cond-mat:mtrl-sci</setSpec>
            <setSpec>physics:physics:app-ph</setSpec>
            <setSpec>physics:quant-ph</setSpec>
    </header>

            <metadata>
                        <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ https://oaipmh.arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
        <id>2601.14500</id>
        <created>2026-01-20</created>
            <updated>2026-01-22</updated>
        <authors>
                <author>
                    <keyname>Kim</keyname>
                        <forenames>Jaehwahn</forenames>
                </author>
                <author>
                    <keyname>Rens</keyname>
                        <forenames>Davis A.</forenames>
                </author>
                <author>
                    <keyname>Khalid</keyname>
                        <forenames>Waqas</forenames>
                </author>
                <author>
                    <keyname>Kim</keyname>
                        <forenames>Hyunchul</forenames>
                </author>
        </authors>
        <title>A Modulated Electron Lattice (MEL) Criterion for Metallic Superconductivity</title>
            <categories>cond-mat.supr-con cond-mat.mes-hall cond-mat.mtrl-sci physics.app-ph quant-ph</categories>
            <comments>8 pages, 3 figures</comments>
            <license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license>
            <abstract>A central unresolved question in the theory of superconductivity is why only a small subset of metallic elements exhibit a superconducting state, whereas many others remain strictly normal. Neither the conventional Bardeen Cooper Schrieffer (BCS) framework nor its extensions involving charge density wave (CDW) or pair density wave (PDW) order provide a predictive or material-selective criterion capable of distinguishing superconducting metals from non-superconducting ones. In particular, the persistent absence of superconductivity in simple noble metals with well-defined Fermi surfaces poses a challenge for all traditional approaches. Here we address this problem using the Modulated Electron Lattice (MEL) Ginzburg Landau (GL) framework introduced in our previous work. In this formulation, a coarse-grained MEL charge field $ρ_{\mathrm{MEL}}(\mathbf{r})$ with momentum dependent stiffness $α(q)$ is coupled to the superconducting (SC) order parameter $ψ(\mathbf{r})$. We show that metallic superconductivity emerges only when the system satisfies a specific ``MEL enhancement window,&#39;&#39; characterized by a negative minimum of $α(q)$ at either a finite modulation wave vector $q^{\ast}$ or at $q=0$, together with sufficiently strong coupling between $ρ_{\mathrm{MEL}}$ and $ψ$. This unified criterion naturally partitions metallic elements into three universal classes: (i) MEL-enhanced superconductors with a finite-$q^{\ast}$ charge mode, (ii) conventional BCS superconductors as the homogeneous $q^{\ast}=0$ limit of the MEL framework, and (iii) metals for which $α(q)$ remains positive for all $q$, suppressing all MEL modes and preventing any superconducting instability. By applying this criterion to simple metallic elements, we identify why some metals develop superconductivity while others do not, possibly resolving a selection problem long open within the BCS paradigm.</abstract>
    </arXiv>

            </metadata>
        </record>

    </GetRecord>
</OAI-PMH>