<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<OAI-PMH xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" 
         xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance"
         xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/OAI-PMH.xsd">
    <responseDate>2026-07-13T06:20:51Z</responseDate>
                <request verb="GetRecord" identifier="oai:arXiv.org:2606.25957" metadataPrefix="arXiv">http://oaipmh.arxiv.org/oai</request>


    <GetRecord>
                <record>
                <header>
        <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:2606.25957</identifier>
        <datestamp>2026-06-25</datestamp>
            <setSpec>cs:cs:RO</setSpec>
            <setSpec>physics:physics:app-ph</setSpec>
            <setSpec>physics:quant-ph</setSpec>
    </header>

            <metadata>
                        <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ https://oaipmh.arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
        <id>2606.25957</id>
        <created>2026-06-24</created>
            <updated>2026-06-25</updated>
        <authors>
                <author>
                    <keyname>Tovey</keyname>
                        <forenames>Samuel</forenames>
                </author>
                <author>
                    <keyname>Prestel</keyname>
                        <forenames>Stefan</forenames>
                </author>
                <author>
                    <keyname>Yamauchi</keyname>
                        <forenames>Hiroshi</forenames>
                </author>
        </authors>
        <title>From Rubble Simulation to Active Magnetic Mapping: Quantum Sensing for Disaster Response</title>
            <categories>cs.RO physics.app-ph quant-ph</categories>
            <comments>9 pages, seven figures</comments>
            <license>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0/</license>
            <abstract>Locating survivors of building collapses within the first 72 hours is a critical challenge in disaster response, and existing sensing modalities provide only partial information about the structure beneath the rubble.
  This paper proposes drone-based quantum magnetometry as a complementary modality and develops a simulation pipeline spanning rubble physics, sensor-array deployment, and active spatial reconstruction. We use Unreal Engine to generate a steel-reinforced concrete parking-garage collapse and compute the induced magnetic field via a per-triangle dipole approximation, establishing that meaningful magnetic structure is recoverable in the sub-pT to sub-nT range from roughly 1 m above the roofline. Then, we feed sparse multi-sensor samples into a Gaussian Process Regression back-end driven by Bayesian active sampling and validate the pipeline across multiple independent collapse realizations; a three-sensor array optimizes the trade-off between gradient resolution and UAV payload constraints, and active sampling reaches peak structural correlation in roughly $100$ samples. Together, these results indicate that quantum-grade sensing could become a useful tool for drone-based structural analysis and potentially void detection in collapsed buildings.</abstract>
    </arXiv>

            </metadata>
        </record>

    </GetRecord>
</OAI-PMH>