<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<OAI-PMH xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" 
         xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance"
         xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/OAI-PMH.xsd">
    <responseDate>2026-07-13T06:28:33Z</responseDate>
                <request verb="GetRecord" identifier="oai:arXiv.org:2606.17883" metadataPrefix="arXiv">http://oaipmh.arxiv.org/oai</request>


    <GetRecord>
                <record>
                <header>
        <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:2606.17883</identifier>
        <datestamp>2026-06-17</datestamp>
            <setSpec>physics:gr-qc</setSpec>
    </header>

            <metadata>
                        <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ https://oaipmh.arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
        <id>2606.17883</id>
        <created>2026-06-16</created>
            <updated>2026-06-17</updated>
        <authors>
                <author>
                    <keyname>Han</keyname>
                        <forenames>Wen-Biao</forenames>
                </author>
        </authors>
        <title>Long-Lived Ringing of Near-Extremal Kerr Black Holes Resonantly Driven by Extreme-Mass-Ratio Inspirals</title>
            <categories>gr-qc</categories>
            <comments>5pages, 3 figures</comments>
            <license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license>
            <abstract>Near-extremal Kerr black holes support zero-damped modes (ZDMs), whose small time-domain damping rates make them long-lived probes of the near-horizon region. We show that bound extreme-mass-ratio inspirals (EMRIs) can resonantly drive this response in vacuum general relativity. Using frequency-domain Teukolsky amplitudes for eccentric-inclined Kerr geodesics, we identify a source-supported orbital harmonic whose real frequency falls within one pole half-width of the fundamental gravitational ZDM. In the complex response, the pole contribution is enhanced by this small half-width, while complex-response tomography recovers the independently computed Kerr pole from real-frequency orbital data. After subtracting the smooth non-pole component, the residual exhibits the phase winding of a coherent simple pole, with a pole contribution comparable to the smooth non-pole part of the EMRI-sourced Teukolsky amplitude. The driven branch also lies in the superradiant regime and carries negative horizon flux. These results establish a pole-resolved, resonantly driven ZDM response by EMRIs and make the recovered pole half-width a route to measuring the horizon surface gravity.</abstract>
    </arXiv>

            </metadata>
        </record>

    </GetRecord>
</OAI-PMH>