<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<OAI-PMH xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" 
         xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance"
         xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/OAI-PMH.xsd">
    <responseDate>2026-07-13T06:21:29Z</responseDate>
                <request verb="GetRecord" identifier="oai:arXiv.org:2510.27416" metadataPrefix="arXiv">http://oaipmh.arxiv.org/oai</request>


    <GetRecord>
                <record>
                <header>
        <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:2510.27416</identifier>
        <datestamp>2025-11-03</datestamp>
            <setSpec>physics:astro-ph:CO</setSpec>
            <setSpec>physics:hep-ph</setSpec>
    </header>

            <metadata>
                        <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ https://oaipmh.arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
        <id>2510.27416</id>
        <created>2025-10-31</created>
            <updated>2025-11-03</updated>
        <authors>
                <author>
                    <keyname>Nakamura</keyname>
                        <forenames>Taiyo</forenames>
                </author>
                <author>
                    <keyname>Homma</keyname>
                        <forenames>Kensuke</forenames>
                </author>
        </authors>
        <title>Earth-lens telescope for distant axion-like particle sources with stimulated backward reflection</title>
            <categories>astro-ph.CO hep-ph</categories>
            <comments>12 pages, 11 figures</comments>
            <journal-ref>Universe 11 (2025) 9, 287</journal-ref>
            <doi>10.3390/universe11090287</doi>
            <license>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0/</license>
            <abstract>We propose a novel telescope concept based on Earth&#39;s gravitational lensing effect, optimized for the detection of distant dark matter sources, particularly axion-like particles (ALPs). When a unidirectional flux of dark matter passes through Earth at sufficiently high velocity, gravitational lensing can concentrate the flux at a distant focal region in space. Our method combines this lensing effect with stimulated backward reflection (SBR), arising from ALP decays that are induced by directing a coherent electromagnetic beam toward the focal point. The aim of this work is to numerically analyze the structure of the focal region and to develop a framework for estimating the sensitivity to ALP-photon coupling via this mechanism. Numerical calculations show that, assuming an average ALP velocity of 520,km/s -- as suggested by the observed stellar stream S1 -- the focal region extends from $9 \times 10^9$,m to $1.4 \times 10^{10}$,m, with peak density near $9.6 \times 10^9$,m. For a conservative point-like ALP source located approximately 8,kpc from the solar system, based on the S1 stream, the estimated sensitivity in the eV mass range reaches $g/M = \mathcal{O}(10^{-22}),\mathrm{GeV}^{-1}$. This concept thus opens a path toward a general-purpose, space-based ALP observatory that could, in principle, detect more distant sources -- well beyond $\mathcal{O}(10),\mathrm{kpc}$ -- provided that ALP-photon coupling is sufficiently strong, that is, $M \ll M_\mathrm{Planck}$.</abstract>
    </arXiv>

            </metadata>
        </record>

    </GetRecord>
</OAI-PMH>