<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<OAI-PMH xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" 
         xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance"
         xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/OAI-PMH.xsd">
    <responseDate>2026-07-11T09:55:34Z</responseDate>
                <request verb="GetRecord" identifier="oai:arXiv.org:2606.06580v1" metadataPrefix="arXiv">http://oaipmh.arxiv.org/oai</request>


    <GetRecord>
                <record>
                <header>
        <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:2606.06580</identifier>
        <datestamp>2026-06-08</datestamp>
            <setSpec>physics:hep-ph</setSpec>
            <setSpec>physics:astro-ph:HE</setSpec>
    </header>

            <metadata>
                        <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ https://oaipmh.arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
        <id>2606.06580</id>
        <created>2026-06-04</created>
            <updated>2026-06-08</updated>
        <authors>
                <author>
                    <keyname>Sarmah</keyname>
                        <forenames>Prantik</forenames>
                </author>
                <author>
                    <keyname>Chakraborty</keyname>
                        <forenames>Sovan</forenames>
                </author>
                <author>
                    <keyname>Medhi</keyname>
                        <forenames>Abinash</forenames>
                </author>
                <author>
                    <keyname>Bose</keyname>
                        <forenames>Debanjan</forenames>
                </author>
                <author>
                    <keyname>Devi</keyname>
                        <forenames>Moon Moon</forenames>
                </author>
        </authors>
        <title>Neutrino mass ordering from the next Galactic supernova at DUNE, HK, and JUNO</title>
            <categories>hep-ph astro-ph.HE</categories>
            <comments>22 pages, 9 captioned figures. Comments are most welcome!</comments>
            <license>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0/</license>
            <abstract>The next Galactic core-collapse supernova (CCSN) will offer a unique opportunity to determine the neutrino mass ordering. We focus on two observables: the electron neutrino ($횓쩍_e$) neutronization burst and the rise-time of the electron antineutrino ($\bar횓쩍_e$) flux during the accretion phase. The neutronization burst, a sharp $횓쩍_e$ peak within $\sim 20$-$30$ ms, provides a clean and robust signature of mass ordering through its appearance or disappearance. During the accretion phase, the faster rise of heavy lepton flavor neutrinos ($횓쩍_x$) leads to a distinct faster rise-time behavior of the oscillated $\bar횓쩍_e$ signal, resulting in mass ordering discrimination. Using realistic CCSN simulations for multiple progenitor masses, we compute event rates and perform a statistical analysis for a Galactic ($10$~kpc) CCSN event at DUNE, Hyper-Kamiokande (HK), and JUNO detectors. The neutronization burst remains largely independent of SN hydrodynamic simulation models, with DUNE and HK achieving $\gtrsim 6횕혘$ and $\gtrsim 4횕혘$ sensitivity for normal (NO) to inverted ordering (IO) discrimination, respectively. However, the rise-time observable is prone to progenitor degeneracies. To mitigate this cumulative and ratio-based observables constructed at characteristic timescales ($20$ ms &amp; $100$ ms) are used. The resulting confidence levels from the rise-time analysis to discriminate IO/NO in HK and JUNO are $\sim 5횕혘$ and $\sim 3횕혘$, respectively. Our results highlight the complementarity of detectors and observables, and demonstrate that combining neutronization burst and accretion phase information will be crucial for a definitive determination of the neutrino mass ordering in the next Galactic supernova.</abstract>
    </arXiv>

            </metadata>
        </record>

    </GetRecord>
</OAI-PMH>