<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<OAI-PMH xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" 
         xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance"
         xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/OAI-PMH.xsd">
    <responseDate>2026-07-13T00:13:50Z</responseDate>
                <request verb="GetRecord" identifier="oai:arXiv.org:2605.02882v1" metadataPrefix="arXiv">http://oaipmh.arxiv.org/oai</request>


    <GetRecord>
                <record>
                <header>
        <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:2605.02882</identifier>
        <datestamp>2026-05-05</datestamp>
            <setSpec>physics:astro-ph:CO</setSpec>
            <setSpec>physics:gr-qc</setSpec>
    </header>

            <metadata>
                        <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ https://oaipmh.arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
        <id>2605.02882</id>
        <created>2026-05-04</created>
            <updated>2026-05-05</updated>
        <authors>
                <author>
                    <keyname>Abdelaziz</keyname>
                        <forenames>Mariam</forenames>
                </author>
                <author>
                    <keyname>Bari</keyname>
                        <forenames>Pritha</forenames>
                </author>
                <author>
                    <keyname>Matarrese</keyname>
                        <forenames>Sabino</forenames>
                </author>
                <author>
                    <keyname>Ricciardone</keyname>
                        <forenames>Angelo</forenames>
                </author>
        </authors>
        <title>Tracing Primordial Gravitational Waves via non-Gaussian Signatures of Halo Bias</title>
            <categories>astro-ph.CO gr-qc</categories>
            <license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license>
            <abstract>Primordial gravitational waves (PGWs) generate scalar density perturbations at second order. Since the induced density contrast is quadratic in the tensor field, it is intrinsically non-Gaussian. We study the imprint of this tensor-induced non-Gaussianity (NG) on the large-scale clustering of dark matter halos through its correction to halo bias. Focusing on inflationary scenarios with a peaked primordial tensor spectrum, we derive the leading scale-dependent contribution sourced by the bispectrum of the induced density field. While yielding a percent-level bias correction for massive low-redshift halos, this effect can reach an $\mathcal{O}(1)$ modulation for rare, high-redshift halos at $z=7$. Notably, the resulting signature exhibits a distinct scale dependence that is not captured by standard primordial non-Gaussianity (PNG) templates. Our results establish halo bias as a novel probe of PGWs through their imprint on the large-scale structure, providing a complementary window into the inflationary epoch.</abstract>
    </arXiv>

            </metadata>
        </record>

    </GetRecord>
</OAI-PMH>