<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<OAI-PMH xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" 
         xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance"
         xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/OAI-PMH.xsd">
    <responseDate>2026-07-13T09:36:20Z</responseDate>
                <request verb="GetRecord" identifier="oai:arXiv.org:2605.26240" metadataPrefix="arXiv">http://oaipmh.arxiv.org/oai</request>


    <GetRecord>
                <record>
                <header>
        <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:2605.26240</identifier>
        <datestamp>2026-05-27</datestamp>
            <setSpec>physics:quant-ph</setSpec>
            <setSpec>physics:gr-qc</setSpec>
    </header>

            <metadata>
                        <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ https://oaipmh.arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
        <id>2605.26240</id>
        <created>2026-05-25</created>
            <updated>2026-05-27</updated>
        <authors>
                <author>
                    <keyname>Miki</keyname>
                        <forenames>Daisuke</forenames>
                </author>
                <author>
                    <keyname>Li</keyname>
                        <forenames>Alfred</forenames>
                </author>
                <author>
                    <keyname>Chen</keyname>
                        <forenames>Yanbei</forenames>
                </author>
        </authors>
        <title>Amplification and generation bounds of gravity-induced entanglement in pulsed optomechanical systems</title>
            <categories>quant-ph gr-qc</categories>
            <comments>22 pages, 6 figures</comments>
            <license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license>
            <abstract>We investigate gravity-induced entanglement between the output optical fields of two red-detuned pulsed optomechanical systems with their masses coupled by mutual gravitational interaction. For each individual system, the optomechanical interaction realizes a beam-splitter state swap between an incident optical pulse and its mechanical mode. Using two rectangular pulses for each system -- the first to imprint a nonclassical state on the mechanical modes and the second to read the gravitationally generated entanglement back onto the outgoing light -- we show that the amount of entanglement can be amplified by preparing the input in a squeezed or Fock state. However, the threshold for entanglement generation is set by the competition between the gravitational coupling and thermal decoherence, $g_G&gt;2γ_m N_{\rm th}$, and cannot be lowered by any choice of input state. We prove this bound for two-mode Gaussian inputs and show that it continues to hold for Fock-state inputs. We further analyze how imperfect detection modifies the threshold and identify the entanglement-annihilating and entanglement-breaking regimes, which are set by the thermal decoherence accumulated over the interaction time, independent of the gravitational coupling.</abstract>
    </arXiv>

            </metadata>
        </record>

    </GetRecord>
</OAI-PMH>