<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<OAI-PMH xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" 
         xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance"
         xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/OAI-PMH.xsd">
    <responseDate>2026-07-11T07:34:24Z</responseDate>
                <request verb="GetRecord" identifier="oai:arXiv.org:2606.02692v1" metadataPrefix="arXiv">http://oaipmh.arxiv.org/oai</request>


    <GetRecord>
                <record>
                <header>
        <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:2606.02692</identifier>
        <datestamp>2026-06-03</datestamp>
            <setSpec>physics:astro-ph:HE</setSpec>
    </header>

            <metadata>
                        <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ https://oaipmh.arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
        <id>2606.02692</id>
        <created>2026-06-01</created>
            <updated>2026-06-03</updated>
        <authors>
                <author>
                    <keyname>Bandopadhyay</keyname>
                        <forenames>Ananya</forenames>
                </author>
                <author>
                    <keyname>Amend</keyname>
                        <forenames>Benjamin</forenames>
                </author>
                <author>
                    <keyname>Coughlin</keyname>
                        <forenames>Eric R.</forenames>
                </author>
                <author>
                    <keyname>Nixon</keyname>
                        <forenames>C. J.</forenames>
                </author>
                <author>
                    <keyname>Pasham</keyname>
                        <forenames>Dheeraj R.</forenames>
                </author>
                <author>
                    <keyname>Wevers</keyname>
                        <forenames>T.</forenames>
                </author>
        </authors>
        <title>The Role of Stellar Spin in Repeating Partial Tidal Disruption Events</title>
            <categories>astro-ph.HE</categories>
            <comments>9 pages, 5 figures, 1 appendix; submitted</comments>
            <license>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-sa/4.0/</license>
            <abstract>The repeated tidal stripping of a star by a supermassive black hole, known as a repeating partial tidal disruption event (rpTDE), can give rise to a transient that rebrightens months to years after the first outburst. Among the rpTDE candidates so far observed, some exhibit dimmer peak luminosities during each successive outburst, which is a trend that has not been reproduced from theoretical models when the star survives more than one encounter with the black hole. Here we suggest that this trend can be recovered if the partially disrupted star is initially (i.e., prior to its first mass-stripping event) rapidly rotating, which is expected if the star was placed on its orbit through the Hills breakup of a tidally locked and tight binary. We test this hypothesis with hydrodynamical simulations of high-mass ($\geqslant 1 M_{\odot}$) main sequence stars repeatedly partially disrupted by a $10^6 M_{\odot}$ black hole, and demonstrate that successively dimmer outbursts are indeed recovered for high (tens of percent breakup) and prograde (i.e., aligned with the orbital angular momentum) stellar spins. Our results provide strong indirect evidence for the operation of the Hills mechanism in seeding the stars in rpTDEs.</abstract>
    </arXiv>

            </metadata>
        </record>

    </GetRecord>
</OAI-PMH>