<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<OAI-PMH xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" 
         xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance"
         xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/OAI-PMH.xsd">
    <responseDate>2026-07-13T06:28:27Z</responseDate>
                <request verb="GetRecord" identifier="oai:arXiv.org:2605.19706" metadataPrefix="arXiv">http://oaipmh.arxiv.org/oai</request>


    <GetRecord>
                <record>
                <header>
        <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:2605.19706</identifier>
        <datestamp>2026-06-02</datestamp>
            <setSpec>physics:quant-ph</setSpec>
            <setSpec>physics:math-ph</setSpec>
            <setSpec>math:math:MP</setSpec>
    </header>

            <metadata>
                        <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ https://oaipmh.arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
        <id>2605.19706</id>
        <created>2026-05-30</created>
            <updated>2026-06-02</updated>
        <authors>
                <author>
                    <keyname>Edalat</keyname>
                        <forenames>Abbas</forenames>
                </author>
        </authors>
        <title>Finite-Precision Quantum Mechanics</title>
            <categories>quant-ph math-ph math.MP</categories>
            <comments>This version makes a correction to the updating of a double-parcel and polishes the paper</comments>
            <msc-class>81P05, 81P16, 46N50, 81R15</msc-class>
            <acm-class>81P05, 81P16, 46N50, 81R15</acm-class>
            <license>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0/</license>
            <abstract>Standard quantum mechanics is an idealisation based on infinite-precision objects: point states, exact probabilities, and sharp measurements. Yet every real experiment has finite resolution, and for macroscopic systems we never have access to the microscopic state. Following Heisenberg&#39;s call for a theory built only on observable quantities, and von Neumann&#39;s insight that a complete description of a macroscopic system is neither possible nor necessary, we elevate the macroscopic state to a fundamental concept.
  We introduce Interval Quantum Mechanics (IQM), in which the state of a quantum system is never a point but a quantum parcel -- a convex weak open set of density matrices defined by finitely many open expectation intervals, representing exactly the set of microscopic states compatible with a finite set of macroscopic measurements.
  We show that unitary evolution lifts to a deterministic flow on parcels, and that a fuzzy measurement is represented by a volume-contracting update, strictly increasing the geometric information defined as the inverse of the Hilbert-Schmidt volume. By introducing a second impossible set we obtain a double-parcel whose geometric information increases monotonically -- dissolving the entropy stagnation problem, since von Neumann entropy is defined on point states that no finite-precision experiment can certify.
  The framework reformulates foundational puzzles without additional interpretational assumptions: wave-particle duality becomes a smooth trade-off; Schroedinger&#39;s cat is described by a parcel containing many microscopically distinct states; and spooky action at a distance disappears, replaced by a purely epistemic geometric update. All empirical predictions of standard quantum mechanics are recovered in the infinite-precision limit, which is never physically attained.</abstract>
    </arXiv>

            </metadata>
        </record>

    </GetRecord>
</OAI-PMH>