<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<OAI-PMH xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" 
         xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance"
         xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/OAI-PMH.xsd">
    <responseDate>2026-07-13T06:20:45Z</responseDate>
                <request verb="GetRecord" identifier="oai:arXiv.org:2603.00402" metadataPrefix="arXiv">http://oaipmh.arxiv.org/oai</request>


    <GetRecord>
                <record>
                <header>
        <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:2603.00402</identifier>
        <datestamp>2026-05-29</datestamp>
            <setSpec>physics:astro-ph:EP</setSpec>
            <setSpec>physics:astro-ph:IM</setSpec>
    </header>

            <metadata>
                        <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ https://oaipmh.arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
        <id>2603.00402</id>
        <created>2026-04-20</created>
            <updated>2026-05-29</updated>
        <authors>
                <author>
                    <keyname>Turyshev</keyname>
                        <forenames>Slava G.</forenames>
                </author>
        </authors>
        <title>Terraforming Mars: Mass, Forcing, and Industrial Throughput Constraints</title>
            <categories>astro-ph.EP astro-ph.IM</categories>
            <comments>36 pages, 4 figures, and 15 tables</comments>
            <journal-ref>APS Open Sci. 1, 000029 (2026)</journal-ref>
            <doi>10.1103/krb8-h3v3</doi>
            <license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license>
            <abstract>Terraforming Mars can be evaluated with a set of system-level constraints linking (i) target pressures &amp; compositions to required atmospheric inventories, (ii) target surface temperatures to the required radiative control, (iii) inventories &amp; climate agents to sustained industrial throughput &amp; power over a build time, (iv) persistence against collapse, escape, geochemical sinks. We use order-of-magnitude scalings to compare endogenous CO2 release, synthetic super-greenhouse gases, CO2-H2 collision-induced absorption, engineered aerosols/nanoparticles, orbital mirrors, regional paraterraforming. We find: (1) human-relevant pressures imply exaton-class inventories, because Mars requires 3.89 x 10^15 kg of atmosphere per mbar of global mean surface pressure; (2) accessible endogenous CO2 is best treated as ~10s of mbar resource, with a 20 mbar case yielding &lt;10 K warming under present insolation; (3) mean surface temperatures of 250-273 K require either effective IR opacity of ~2-4 or direct absorbed-solar forcing of ~100 W/m^2, implying reflector areas of ~10^{13}-10^{14} m^2 together with large deployment, control, durability, replacement burdens; (4) breathable open-surface endpoints are dominated by O2 and N2 inventories and by a minimum oxygenation work exceeding 10^{25} J, implying average build rates of 10^7-10^8 kg/s and average power from multi-100 TW to PW for century-to-millennial build times before inefficiencies and sink filling. We conclude that regional habitability via paraterraforming/covered-area strategies are plausible on near-term industrial scales, whereas no credible open-atmosphere pathway is identified to a Mars permitting pressure-unassisted human exposure or a breathable surface atmosphere without exaton-class volatile supply, multi-century planetary industry, + sustained climate actuation, retention, durability management, replacement against sinks and loss.</abstract>
    </arXiv>

            </metadata>
        </record>

    </GetRecord>
</OAI-PMH>