<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<OAI-PMH xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" 
         xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance"
         xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/OAI-PMH.xsd">
    <responseDate>2026-07-13T06:20:54Z</responseDate>
                <request verb="GetRecord" identifier="oai:arXiv.org:2508.07153" metadataPrefix="arXiv">http://oaipmh.arxiv.org/oai</request>


    <GetRecord>
                <record>
                <header>
        <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:2508.07153</identifier>
        <datestamp>2025-10-28</datestamp>
            <setSpec>physics:astro-ph:HE</setSpec>
            <setSpec>physics:gr-qc</setSpec>
            <setSpec>physics:hep-ph</setSpec>
    </header>

            <metadata>
                        <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ https://oaipmh.arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
        <id>2508.07153</id>
        <created>2025-10-27</created>
            <updated>2025-10-28</updated>
        <authors>
                <author>
                    <keyname>Ofengeim</keyname>
                        <forenames>Dmitry D.</forenames>
                </author>
                <author>
                    <keyname>Piran</keyname>
                        <forenames>Tsvi</forenames>
                </author>
        </authors>
        <title>The 300 TeV photon from GRB 221009A: a Hint at Non-linear Lorentz Invariance Violation?</title>
            <categories>astro-ph.HE gr-qc hep-ph</categories>
            <comments>9 pages, 4 figures</comments>
            <journal-ref>Phys. Rev. D 112, 083055 (2025)</journal-ref>
            <doi>10.1103/cydc-6j4z</doi>
            <license>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0/</license>
            <abstract>The air shower array Carpet-3 detected a 300 TeV photon from the direction of GRB 221009A at 4536 s after the Fermi-GBM trigger for this event. If the association with this gamma-ray burst is real, it poses two puzzles. First, why was this photon not absorbed by the extragalactic background light? ``New physics&#39;&#39; beyond the Standard Model is required to explain how it managed to reach Earth from a cosmological distance. Second, why was this photon detected when the VHE afterglow observed by LHAASO already faded? A novel astrophysical mechanism is required to explain this delay. In this work we show that Lorentz invariance violation (LIV), which arises as a low-energy limit of certain quantum gravity theories, can solve both puzzles. It shifts thresholds of particle interaction and changes the opacity of the extragalactic background, and cause energy-dependent variations of the photon velocity, which changes the photon time of flight. We investigate the LIV parameter space assuming that the 300 TeV photon is a part of the VHE afterglow detected by LHAASO in the TeV range. We identify viable solutions and place stringent two-sided constraints on the LIV energy scale required to resolve the observational puzzles. First-order LIV appears to be incompatible with the constraints set by analyzing the TeV afterglow of this GRB. Viable solutions emerge for higher orders. In particular, the commonly studied second-order subluminal LIV with $E_{\rm LIV2} = 1.30_{-0.35}^{+0.56} \times 10^{-7} E_{\rm Pl}$ (95.4% credibility level; $E_{\rm Pl}$ is the Planck energy) is consistent with all the observed data.</abstract>
    </arXiv>

            </metadata>
        </record>

    </GetRecord>
</OAI-PMH>