<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<OAI-PMH xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" 
         xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance"
         xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/OAI-PMH.xsd">
    <responseDate>2026-07-13T06:23:36Z</responseDate>
                <request verb="GetRecord" identifier="oai:arXiv.org:2601.16259" metadataPrefix="arXiv">http://oaipmh.arxiv.org/oai</request>


    <GetRecord>
                <record>
                <header>
        <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:2601.16259</identifier>
        <datestamp>2026-01-26</datestamp>
            <setSpec>physics:hep-ph</setSpec>
            <setSpec>physics:astro-ph:CO</setSpec>
    </header>

            <metadata>
                        <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ https://oaipmh.arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
        <id>2601.16259</id>
        <created>2026-01-22</created>
            <updated>2026-01-26</updated>
        <authors>
                <author>
                    <keyname>Brzeminski</keyname>
                        <forenames>Dawid</forenames>
                </author>
                <author>
                    <keyname>Pierce</keyname>
                        <forenames>Aaron</forenames>
                </author>
        </authors>
        <title>Searching for Ultralight Scalar Dark Matter with Clocks in Low Earth Orbit</title>
            <categories>hep-ph astro-ph.CO</categories>
            <comments>30 pages, 9 figures</comments>
            <report-no>LITP-26-03</report-no>
            <license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license>
            <abstract>The density of ultralight dark matter can be modified in the vicinity of macroscopic bodies when the dark matter possesses quadratic couplings to the Standard Model. If these couplings are sufficiently strong, Earth&#39;s atmosphere acts to shield the dark matter, thereby limiting the effectiveness of laboratory-based experiments. Experiments performed at altitudes exceeding the dark matter de Broglie wavelength experience the same orbit-averaged field amplitude as in the absence of scattering. Quantum clocks are capable of detecting variations in fundamental parameters due to the dark matter background. If based on the International Space Station, they are therefore well-suited to probe dark matter masses $m_{\rm DM}\gtrsim 10^{-9} \text{\, eV}$. Moreover, when the dark matter de Broglie wavelength is smaller than Earth&#39;s radius ($m_{\rm DM} \gtrsim 10^{-10}$ eV), the dark matter profile around Earth exhibits a dipole feature. In Low Earth Orbits this dipole temporally modulates potential dark matter signals. This provides a powerful cross-check of the orbit-averaged effect and can enhance the sensitivity of these experiments. We find optical clocks could give rise to world-leading constraints in some cases. Orbiting nuclear clocks could probe even more of the parameter space inaccessible to ground-based experiments.</abstract>
    </arXiv>

            </metadata>
        </record>

    </GetRecord>
</OAI-PMH>