<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<OAI-PMH xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" 
         xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance"
         xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/OAI-PMH.xsd">
    <responseDate>2026-07-12T14:25:02Z</responseDate>
                <request verb="GetRecord" identifier="oai:arXiv.org:2505.00266v1" metadataPrefix="arXiv">http://oaipmh.arxiv.org/oai</request>


    <GetRecord>
                <record>
                <header>
        <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:2505.00266</identifier>
        <datestamp>2025-05-02</datestamp>
            <setSpec>physics:quant-ph</setSpec>
            <setSpec>physics:cond-mat:mes-hall</setSpec>
    </header>

            <metadata>
                        <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ https://oaipmh.arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
        <id>2505.00266</id>
        <created>2025-05-01</created>
            <updated>2025-05-02</updated>
        <authors>
                <author>
                    <keyname>Pan</keyname>
                        <forenames>Xue-Feng</forenames>
                </author>
                <author>
                    <keyname>Li</keyname>
                        <forenames>Peng-Bo</forenames>
                </author>
        </authors>
        <title>Tripartite hybrid quantum systems: Skyrmion-mediated quantum interactions between single NV centers and superconducting qubits</title>
            <categories>quant-ph cond-mat.mes-hall</categories>
            <comments>20 pages,13 figures</comments>
            <license>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0/</license>
            <abstract>Nitrogen-vacancy (NV) centers in diamond and superconducting qubits are two promising solid-state quantum systems for quantum science and technology, but the realization of controlled interfaces between individual solid-state spins and superconducting qubits remains fundamentally challenging. Here, we propose and analyze a hybrid quantum system consisting of a magnetic skyrmion, an NV center, and a superconducting qubit, where the solid-state qubits are both positioned in proximity to the skyrmion structure in a thin magnetic disk. We show that it is experimentally feasible to achieve strong magnetic (coherent or dissipative) coupling between the NV center and the superconducting qubit by using the \textit{quantized gyration mode of the skyrmion} as an intermediary. This allows coherent information transfer and nonreciprocal responses between the NV center and the superconducting qubit at the single quantum level with high controllability. The proposed platform provides a scalable pathway for implementing quantum protocols that synergistically exploit the complementary advantages of spin-based quantum memories, microwave-frequency superconducting circuits, and topologically protected magnetic excitations.</abstract>
    </arXiv>

            </metadata>
        </record>

    </GetRecord>
</OAI-PMH>