<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<OAI-PMH xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" 
         xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance"
         xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/OAI-PMH.xsd">
    <responseDate>2026-07-13T06:29:08Z</responseDate>
                <request verb="GetRecord" identifier="oai:arXiv.org:2511.20747" metadataPrefix="arXiv">http://oaipmh.arxiv.org/oai</request>


    <GetRecord>
                <record>
                <header>
        <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:2511.20747</identifier>
        <datestamp>2026-03-02</datestamp>
            <setSpec>physics:hep-th</setSpec>
            <setSpec>physics:quant-ph</setSpec>
    </header>

            <metadata>
                        <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ https://oaipmh.arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
        <id>2511.20747</id>
        <created>2026-02-27</created>
            <updated>2026-03-02</updated>
        <authors>
                <author>
                    <keyname>Mori</keyname>
                        <forenames>Takato</forenames>
                </author>
                <author>
                    <keyname>Yoshida</keyname>
                        <forenames>Beni</forenames>
                </author>
        </authors>
        <title>Baby universe as logical qubits: information recovery in random encoding</title>
            <categories>hep-th quant-ph</categories>
            <comments>25 pages, 4 figures</comments>
            <report-no>RUP-25-23</report-no>
            <license>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0/</license>
            <abstract>We revisit whether a semiclassical closed baby universe in AdS/CFT necessarily possess a trivial one-dimensional Hilbert space or may instead carry a large entropy. Recent results on Haar random encoding suggest a breakdown of complementary recovery, in which no logical operators can be reconstructed from individual bipartite subsystems. Motivated by this, we propose an interpretation where a baby universe emerges as logical degrees of freedom that cannot be accessed from either boundary alone, assuming pseudorandom dynamics in holographic CFT correlators. We then analyze two conceptual puzzles: an apparent cloning of baby-universe microstates and its eventual fate at the singularity. Both puzzles are avoided because no single boundary observer can access the baby-universe degrees of freedom, be it classical or quantum, reflecting an emergent form of complementarity due to the structure of random encoding. In this interpretation, observers arise naturally: the same heavy operator that prepares the baby-universe geometry also serves as observer-like degrees of freedom that define an observer-dependent baby-universe microstate.</abstract>
    </arXiv>

            </metadata>
        </record>

    </GetRecord>
</OAI-PMH>