<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<OAI-PMH xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" 
         xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance"
         xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/OAI-PMH.xsd">
    <responseDate>2026-07-13T06:23:08Z</responseDate>
                <request verb="GetRecord" identifier="oai:arXiv.org:2511.02218" metadataPrefix="arXiv">http://oaipmh.arxiv.org/oai</request>


    <GetRecord>
                <record>
                <header>
        <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:2511.02218</identifier>
        <datestamp>2026-01-09</datestamp>
            <setSpec>physics:cond-mat:quant-gas</setSpec>
            <setSpec>physics:quant-ph</setSpec>
    </header>

            <metadata>
                        <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ https://oaipmh.arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
        <id>2511.02218</id>
        <created>2026-01-08</created>
            <updated>2026-01-09</updated>
        <authors>
                <author>
                    <keyname>Zhang</keyname>
                        <forenames>Chao</forenames>
                </author>
        </authors>
        <title>Interaction-Induced Quasicrystalline Order: Emergence of Quasi-Solid and Quasi-Supersolid Phases</title>
            <categories>cond-mat.quant-gas quant-ph</categories>
            <license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license>
            <abstract>Deterministic quasiperiodicity in quantum systems has long been associated with localization, criticality, or glassy behavior, and has therefore been believed to suppress long-range order rather than stabilize it. Here we demonstrate the opposite: quasiperiodicity in interactions--without any quasiperiodic potential, disorder, or geometric modulation--can generate coherent, ordered quantum phases. We study hard-core bosons in one dimension with quasiperiodic long-range interactions, V_{ij}=V_0 \cos(παi)\cos(παj), where n=α=(\sqrt{5}-1)/2 is the inverse golden ratio. Using large-scale path-integral quantum Monte Carlo simulations, we uncover thermodynamically stable incompressible plateaus at irrational densities tied to Fibonacci ratios. These plateaus exhibit sharp incommensurate Bragg peaks, signaling an emergent quasi-solid with long-range quasicrystalline density order. More strikingly, at nearby fillings and interaction strengths, we identify a quasi-supersolid phase that supports both Fibonacci density ordering and finite superfluid density--demonstrating that interaction-induced quasiperiodicity can stabilize supersolid coherence. Our results establish a new mechanism for realizing ordered quasicrystalline quantum matter, and provide realistic guidance for implementation in Rydberg atom arrays, multimode cavity-QED systems, and trapped-ion quantum simulators.</abstract>
    </arXiv>

            </metadata>
        </record>

    </GetRecord>
</OAI-PMH>