<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<OAI-PMH xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" 
         xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance"
         xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/OAI-PMH.xsd">
    <responseDate>2026-07-13T06:25:10Z</responseDate>
                <request verb="GetRecord" identifier="oai:arXiv.org:2607.06967" metadataPrefix="arXiv">http://oaipmh.arxiv.org/oai</request>


    <GetRecord>
                <record>
                <header>
        <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:2607.06967</identifier>
        <datestamp>2026-07-09</datestamp>
            <setSpec>physics:quant-ph</setSpec>
            <setSpec>physics:gr-qc</setSpec>
    </header>

            <metadata>
                        <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ https://oaipmh.arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
        <id>2607.06967</id>
        <created>2026-07-08</created>
            <updated>2026-07-09</updated>
        <authors>
                <author>
                    <keyname>Zhong</keyname>
                        <forenames>Wenjie</forenames>
                </author>
                <author>
                    <keyname>Liu</keyname>
                        <forenames>Yubao</forenames>
                </author>
                <author>
                    <keyname>Chen</keyname>
                        <forenames>Yanbei</forenames>
                </author>
                <author>
                    <keyname>Miao</keyname>
                        <forenames>Haixing</forenames>
                </author>
                <author>
                    <keyname>Ma</keyname>
                        <forenames>Yiqiu</forenames>
                </author>
        </authors>
        <title>Tomography of a Macroscopic Quantum State influenced by Classical Self-Gravity</title>
            <categories>quant-ph gr-qc</categories>
            <comments>17 pages, 7 figures</comments>
            <license>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0/</license>
            <abstract>Macroscopic optomechanical systems offer a promising testbed for distinguishing whether gravity acts as a quantum interaction or as a classical field. Schrodinger-Newton (SN) theory is the nonrelativistic limit of semi-classical gravity where quantum matter couples to classical gravity. Based on SN theory, this work investigates how classical self-gravity affects continuous quantum state tomography of a macroscopic mechanical oscillator monitored by variable-angle homodyne detection. In the Schrodinger-Newton (SN) theory, the measurement record arises from a different conditional test mass dynamics from that in quantum-gravity (QG)/standard quantum mechanics, consequently, applying the QG-optimised reconstruction map introduces an additional state-dependent contribution. We show that this contribution makes the reconstructed covariance depend on the chosen set of tomography angles and can drive the SN covariance--after QG filtering--outside the standard Gaussian-covariance domain set by the Heisenberg uncertainty principle. We quantify the resulting QG-SN distinguishability via the Hellinger distance and analyse its dependence on measurement strength and temperature. We then formulate the same issue in the broader setting of nonlinear quantum mechanics: when the system&#39;s conditional dynamics during the readout process depends on the state being inferred, the tomographic map acquires nonlinear, model-dependent corrections to the usual Radon or Gaussian reconstruction map.</abstract>
    </arXiv>

            </metadata>
        </record>

    </GetRecord>
</OAI-PMH>