<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<OAI-PMH xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" 
         xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance"
         xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/OAI-PMH.xsd">
    <responseDate>2026-07-13T06:22:25Z</responseDate>
                <request verb="GetRecord" identifier="oai:arXiv.org:2606.21105" metadataPrefix="arXiv">http://oaipmh.arxiv.org/oai</request>


    <GetRecord>
                <record>
                <header>
        <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:2606.21105</identifier>
        <datestamp>2026-06-23</datestamp>
            <setSpec>physics:astro-ph:HE</setSpec>
            <setSpec>physics:astro-ph:GA</setSpec>
    </header>

            <metadata>
                        <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ https://oaipmh.arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
        <id>2606.21105</id>
        <created>2026-06-19</created>
            <updated>2026-06-23</updated>
        <authors>
                <author>
                    <keyname>Zhou</keyname>
                        <forenames>Shuying</forenames>
                </author>
                <author>
                    <keyname>Sun</keyname>
                        <forenames>Mouyuan</forenames>
                </author>
                <author>
                    <keyname>Ji</keyname>
                        <forenames>Xihan</forenames>
                </author>
                <author>
                    <keyname>Li</keyname>
                        <forenames>Ya-Ping</forenames>
                </author>
                <author>
                    <keyname>Ho</keyname>
                        <forenames>Luis C.</forenames>
                </author>
                <author>
                    <keyname>Maiolino</keyname>
                        <forenames>Roberto</forenames>
                </author>
                <author>
                    <keyname>Cai</keyname>
                        <forenames>Zhen-Yi</forenames>
                </author>
                <author>
                    <keyname>Feng</keyname>
                        <forenames>Hai-Cheng</forenames>
                </author>
                <author>
                    <keyname>Fu</keyname>
                        <forenames>Manqi</forenames>
                </author>
                <author>
                    <keyname>Gu</keyname>
                        <forenames>Wei-Min</forenames>
                </author>
                <author>
                    <keyname>Liu</keyname>
                        <forenames>Tong</forenames>
                </author>
                <author>
                    <keyname>Wang</keyname>
                        <forenames>Junfeng</forenames>
                </author>
                <author>
                    <keyname>Wu</keyname>
                        <forenames>Jianfeng</forenames>
                </author>
                <author>
                    <keyname>Xue</keyname>
                        <forenames>Yongquan</forenames>
                </author>
        </authors>
        <title>Little Red Dots as Supermassive Analogs of SS 433</title>
            <categories>astro-ph.HE astro-ph.GA</categories>
            <comments>21 pages, 10 figures, comments welcome</comments>
            <license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license>
            <abstract>High-redshift little red dots (LRDs) are compact sources characterized by V-shaped spectral energy distributions (SEDs), broad emission lines, and often prominent Balmer breaks. Their high number density and apparently large black hole masses suggest that they are essential to the early evolution of galaxies and supermassive black holes (SMBHs); however, the nature of their central engines remains uncertain. Here, we propose that LRDs are the supermassive, high-redshift analogs of the hyper-Eddington accreting Galactic microquasar SS~433, viewed at high inclinations. By scaling the hyper-Eddington accretion physics from stellar-mass black holes to supermassive scales, we show that the observed LRD features, including X-ray weakness, soft optical SEDs, apparent sub-Eddington accretion ratio, and Balmer breaks, emerge naturally from the self-shielding geometry of a puffed-up accretion disk. In this framework, the broad-line regions are ionized by anisotropic radiation escaping from the inner disk, analogous to the unseen UV/X-ray emission revealed by the W50 nebula in SS 433. Their low-inclination or lower-accretion-rate counterparts would appear as little blue dots (LBDs) or normal active galactic nuclei. Our model predicts that the Balmer break strength positively correlates with the broad-line width, that the emission lines are more variable than the optical continuum, that LRDs are intrinsically more luminous than observed, and that LBDs are more variable than LRDs. This unified-scale model redefines LRDs as the essential laboratories for observing the rapid accretion-driven growth that shaped the early assembly of galaxies and their central SMBHs.</abstract>
    </arXiv>

            </metadata>
        </record>

    </GetRecord>
</OAI-PMH>