<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<OAI-PMH xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" 
         xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance"
         xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/OAI-PMH.xsd">
    <responseDate>2026-07-13T06:23:50Z</responseDate>
                <request verb="GetRecord" identifier="oai:arXiv.org:2602.13609" metadataPrefix="arXiv">http://oaipmh.arxiv.org/oai</request>


    <GetRecord>
                <record>
                <header>
        <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:2602.13609</identifier>
        <datestamp>2026-02-17</datestamp>
            <setSpec>physics:gr-qc</setSpec>
            <setSpec>physics:hep-th</setSpec>
    </header>

            <metadata>
                        <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ https://oaipmh.arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
        <id>2602.13609</id>
        <created>2026-02-14</created>
            <updated>2026-02-17</updated>
        <authors>
                <author>
                    <keyname>Koga</keyname>
                        <forenames>Yasutaka</forenames>
                </author>
                <author>
                    <keyname>Maeda</keyname>
                        <forenames>Ryota</forenames>
                </author>
                <author>
                    <keyname>Saito</keyname>
                        <forenames>Daiki</forenames>
                </author>
                <author>
                    <keyname>Yoshida</keyname>
                        <forenames>Daisuke</forenames>
                </author>
        </authors>
        <title>Dynamical Formation of Self-Similar Wormholes</title>
            <categories>gr-qc hep-th</categories>
            <comments>28 pages, 8 figures</comments>
            <report-no>YITP-26-15, KUNS-3091</report-no>
            <license>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0/</license>
            <abstract>We study spherically symmetric, self-similar wormhole solutions supported by colliding streams of negative-energy null dust, and their dynamical formation. Under the assumption of self-similarity, the Einstein equations reduce to a system of ordinary differential equations, which we solve numerically under boundary conditions enforcing the existence of a minimal areal radius (the throat) on constant-time hypersurfaces. For a sufficiently large throat radius, the resulting geometries remain regular at both spatial and future null infinity, while a singularity is retained in the past direction. We then construct a dynamical formation scenario by patching together three regions: a Schwarzschild black hole, negative-energy Vaidya spacetimes, and the self-similar wormhole geometry. These regions are joined across null shells using the Barrabes--Israel formalism, which provides explicit relations among the throat radius, the black hole&#39;s mass and the energy injection by the shell, demonstrating that an initial black hole can evolve into a wormhole. Our analysis generalizes the formation model for static wormhole solutions proposed by Hayward and Koyama in 2004 to non-static wormhole solutions, offering a novel perspective on the formation of regular traversable wormholes.</abstract>
    </arXiv>

            </metadata>
        </record>

    </GetRecord>
</OAI-PMH>