<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<OAI-PMH xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" 
         xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance"
         xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/OAI-PMH.xsd">
    <responseDate>2026-07-13T01:48:19Z</responseDate>
                <request verb="GetRecord" identifier="oai:arXiv.org:2605.14794v2" metadataPrefix="arXiv">http://oaipmh.arxiv.org/oai</request>


    <GetRecord>
                <record>
                <header>
        <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:2605.14794</identifier>
        <datestamp>2026-06-23</datestamp>
            <setSpec>physics:hep-th</setSpec>
            <setSpec>physics:gr-qc</setSpec>
    </header>

            <metadata>
                        <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ https://oaipmh.arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
        <id>2605.14794</id>
        <created>2026-06-22</created>
            <updated>2026-06-23</updated>
        <authors>
                <author>
                    <keyname>Kumar</keyname>
                        <forenames>Naman</forenames>
                </author>
        </authors>
        <title>An Algebraic Resolution of the Firewall Paradox</title>
            <categories>hep-th gr-qc</categories>
            <comments>Honorable Mention, Gravity Research Foundation Awards for Essays on Gravitation 2026. An expanded version, including a discussion of island physics, has been accepted for publication in International Journal of Modern Physics D as part of the special issue on the Gravity Research Foundation Awards 2026</comments>
            <license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license>
            <abstract>The AMPS firewall argument relies on treating early radiation, late outgoing Hawking modes, and interior partner modes as approximately independent quantum subsystems. In diffeomorphism-invariant quantum gravity, however, gravitational dressing and asymptotic constraints obstruct such a tensor-product factorization of physical observables. In this essay, we sharpen this obstruction by formulating subsystem independence directly in operator-algebraic terms. Using modular theory, half-sided modular inclusions along null directions, and the sector-wise maximality of the dressed radiation algebra at future null infinity, we show that -- within a fixed asymptotic charge sector -- the algebra associated with the interior Hawking partner cannot form an independent commuting subalgebra, but must be contained as a (non-commuting) subalgebra of the radiation algebra itself. The subsystem-independence assumption underlying the AMPS paradox therefore fails, and the entanglement-monogamy step never becomes applicable. As a result, unitary black hole evaporation and semiclassical horizon smoothness are compatible in asymptotically flat quantum gravity, without invoking entanglement islands, replica wormholes, or modifications of semiclassical horizon physics.</abstract>
    </arXiv>

            </metadata>
        </record>

    </GetRecord>
</OAI-PMH>