<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<OAI-PMH xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" 
         xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance"
         xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/OAI-PMH.xsd">
    <responseDate>2026-07-13T06:26:50Z</responseDate>
                <request verb="GetRecord" identifier="oai:arXiv.org:2604.14721" metadataPrefix="arXiv">http://oaipmh.arxiv.org/oai</request>


    <GetRecord>
                <record>
                <header>
        <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:2604.14721</identifier>
        <datestamp>2026-04-17</datestamp>
            <setSpec>physics:quant-ph</setSpec>
            <setSpec>physics:cond-mat:quant-gas</setSpec>
            <setSpec>physics:physics:atom-ph</setSpec>
    </header>

            <metadata>
                        <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ https://oaipmh.arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
        <id>2604.14721</id>
        <created>2026-04-16</created>
            <updated>2026-04-17</updated>
        <authors>
                <author>
                    <keyname>Ton</keyname>
                        <forenames>K.</forenames>
                </author>
                <author>
                    <keyname>Kestler</keyname>
                        <forenames>G.</forenames>
                </author>
                <author>
                    <keyname>Steck</keyname>
                        <forenames>D. A.</forenames>
                </author>
                <author>
                    <keyname>Barreiro</keyname>
                        <forenames>J. T.</forenames>
                </author>
        </authors>
        <title>Spectroscopic measurement of the Casimir-Polder force in the intermediate regime</title>
            <categories>quant-ph cond-mat.quant-gas physics.atom-ph</categories>
            <comments>11 pages, 8 figures</comments>
            <license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license>
            <abstract>The Casimir-Polder (CP) effect -- the force between a neutral atom and an uncharged conducting plate in empty space -- is an intriguing consequence of quantum vacuum fluctuations. The typically attractive CP potential crosses over from a scaling of $z^{-3}$ at short separations to $z^{-4}$ at long distances, where retardation effects due to the finite speed of light become important. At intermediate distances, where the atom--surface separation is of the order of the wavelength of the dominant atomic transition, experiments have so far relied on indirect methods, such as diffraction or quantum reflection, to observe the CP effect. Here, we directly reveal the CP force between strontium atoms and a dielectric surface via the induced shifts in the atomic energy levels in the intermediate regime. We spectroscopically probe the CP-induced kHz-frequency shift of ultracold atoms confined by a magic-wavelength optical lattice at 189(2)~nm from the surface -- on the scale of the dominant 461-nm transition. Our measurements agree well with QED calculations and differ from the short-range approximation, while excluding the long-distance one. This paves the way for studying the CP effect across various surface properties and geometries, as well as exploring the tensor nature of the atom-surface potential -- all important for the development of hybrid atomic optical-magnetic quantum devices.</abstract>
    </arXiv>

            </metadata>
        </record>

    </GetRecord>
</OAI-PMH>