<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<OAI-PMH xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" 
         xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance"
         xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/OAI-PMH.xsd">
    <responseDate>2026-07-13T04:41:51Z</responseDate>
                <request verb="GetRecord" identifier="oai:arXiv.org:2605.00391" metadataPrefix="arXiv">http://oaipmh.arxiv.org/oai</request>


    <GetRecord>
                <record>
                <header>
        <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:2605.00391</identifier>
        <datestamp>2026-05-04</datestamp>
            <setSpec>physics:astro-ph:IM</setSpec>
            <setSpec>physics:astro-ph:HE</setSpec>
            <setSpec>physics:gr-qc</setSpec>
    </header>

            <metadata>
                        <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ https://oaipmh.arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
        <id>2605.00391</id>
        <created>2026-05-01</created>
            <updated>2026-05-04</updated>
        <authors>
                <author>
                    <keyname>Raza</keyname>
                        <forenames>Nayyer</forenames>
                </author>
                <author>
                    <keyname>Chan</keyname>
                        <forenames>Man Leong</forenames>
                </author>
                <author>
                    <keyname>Haggard</keyname>
                        <forenames>Daryl</forenames>
                </author>
                <author>
                    <keyname>Mahabal</keyname>
                        <forenames>Ashish</forenames>
                </author>
                <author>
                    <keyname>McIver</keyname>
                        <forenames>Jess</forenames>
                </author>
                <author>
                    <keyname>Durand</keyname>
                        <forenames>Audrey</forenames>
                </author>
                <author>
                    <keyname>Larouche</keyname>
                        <forenames>Alexandre</forenames>
                </author>
                <author>
                    <keyname>Moazen</keyname>
                        <forenames>Hadi</forenames>
                </author>
        </authors>
        <title>Training a neural network to rapidly identify candidate gravitational-wave events in the lower mass gap</title>
            <categories>astro-ph.IM astro-ph.HE gr-qc</categories>
            <comments>15 pages, 7 figures, 2 tables, submitted to ApJ</comments>
            <license>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0/</license>
            <abstract>The physics governing the boundary between the most massive neutron stars (NSs) and the least massive black holes (BHs) is currently uncertain, but could potentially be constrained with new observations. While NSs have been observed with masses up to $\sim2~M_{\odot}$, there is a dearth of electromagnetic observations of compact objects in the $\sim2-5~M_{\odot}$ range, known as the lower mass gap. Recent observations of gravitational-wave (GW) signals from binary mergers detected by the LIGO-Virgo-KAGRA (LVK) collaboration indicate that this gap is likely not empty. Rapidly distinguishing whether a candidate GW event has components in this purported mass gap can indicate the likelihood of a detectable electromagnetic counterpart, and thus inform decisions for follow-up observations. In this work we train a neural network model, GWSkyNet-MassGap, that simultaneously predicts the probability that a candidate merger has a component in the lower mass gap ($P_{\mathrm{MassGap}}$) and the probability that it involves a NS ($P_{\mathrm{NS}}$). We find that the model is able to infer information about the source chirp mass to predict $P_{\mathrm{MassGap}}$ and $P_{\mathrm{NS}}$, leading to correct predictions for high-mass mergers with $\mathcal{M}_c\gtrsim15~M_{\odot}$, but less accurate predictions for lower-mass systems which require knowledge of the binary mass ratio to break the mass degeneracy. For candidate events in the first part of LVK&#39;s fourth observing run (O4a), the model has a mean prediction error of 9% for $P_{\mathrm{MassGap}}$ and 6% for $P_{\mathrm{NS}}$. The model could be further developed to rapidly predict the source chirp mass for candidate events in future observing runs.</abstract>
    </arXiv>

            </metadata>
        </record>

    </GetRecord>
</OAI-PMH>