<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<OAI-PMH xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" 
         xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance"
         xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/OAI-PMH.xsd">
    <responseDate>2026-07-13T21:13:43Z</responseDate>
                <request verb="GetRecord" identifier="oai:arXiv.org:2511.17398" metadataPrefix="arXiv">http://oaipmh.arxiv.org/oai</request>


    <GetRecord>
                <record>
                <header>
        <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:2511.17398</identifier>
        <datestamp>2025-11-27</datestamp>
            <setSpec>physics:cond-mat:mtrl-sci</setSpec>
            <setSpec>physics:cond-mat:str-el</setSpec>
    </header>

            <metadata>
                        <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ https://oaipmh.arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
        <id>2511.17398</id>
        <created>2025-11-26</created>
            <updated>2025-11-27</updated>
        <authors>
                <author>
                    <keyname>Nayak</keyname>
                        <forenames>Abhijeet</forenames>
                </author>
                <author>
                    <keyname>Jamaluddin</keyname>
                        <forenames>Sk</forenames>
                </author>
                <author>
                    <keyname>Wu</keyname>
                        <forenames>Fan</forenames>
                </author>
                <author>
                    <keyname>Rapp</keyname>
                        <forenames>Emily</forenames>
                </author>
                <author>
                    <keyname>Regmi</keyname>
                        <forenames>Resham Babu</forenames>
                </author>
                <author>
                    <keyname>Gazzah</keyname>
                        <forenames>Mohamed El</forenames>
                </author>
                <author>
                    <keyname>Márkus</keyname>
                        <forenames>Bence G.</forenames>
                </author>
                <author>
                    <keyname>Forró</keyname>
                        <forenames>László</forenames>
                </author>
                <author>
                    <keyname>Ghimire</keyname>
                        <forenames>Madhav P.</forenames>
                </author>
                <author>
                    <keyname>Oliver</keyname>
                        <forenames>Allen</forenames>
                </author>
                <author>
                    <keyname>Foyevtsova</keyname>
                        <forenames>Kateryna</forenames>
                </author>
                <author>
                    <keyname>Mazin</keyname>
                        <forenames>Igor I.</forenames>
                </author>
                <author>
                    <keyname>Ghimire</keyname>
                        <forenames>Nirmal J.</forenames>
                </author>
        </authors>
        <title>Crystal Growth and Physical Properties of Orthorhombic Kagome Lattice Magnets $R$Fe$_6$Ge$_6$ ($R$=Y, Tb, Dy)</title>
            <categories>cond-mat.mtrl-sci cond-mat.str-el</categories>
            <license>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0/</license>
            <abstract>Kagome magnets represent a promising class of materials that exhibit intriguing electronic and magnetic properties, and they have recently garnered significant attention. While most kagome-lattice compounds are hexagonal, we report here single-crystal growth and physical property measurements of $R$Fe$_6$Ge$_6$ ($R$ = Y, Dy, Tb) compounds, which crystallize in an orthorhombic structure. The structure can be derived from a hexagonal prototype $R$Fe$_3$Ge$_2$ by replacing every other $R$ atom with a covalent Ge$_2$ dimer. Ordering of these dimers renders the structure orthorhombic, slightly distorts the kagome net, and makes the three Fe sites formally inequivalent. The iron and rare-earth sublattices order independently. Fe moments order above 400 K, forming ferromagnetic kagome planes stacked antiferromagnetically, while rare-earth moments order below 9 K. TbFe$_6$Ge$_6$ exhibits a single magnetic ordering transition associated with the Tb atoms, whereas DyFe$_6$Ge$_6$ shows two distinct magnetic phase transitions, strongly influenced by crystal electric field effects on the Dy$^{3+}$ ions. Density functional theory (DFT) calculations indicate that the ferromagnetic ordering of the Fe planes is driven by a high density of states at the Fermi energy. They also reveal three dramatically different structural energy scales: $R$ and Ge$_2$ form alternating 1D chains perpendicular to the kagome planes, and violating this alternation incurs a large energy cost. Aligning these chains is less costly, and achieving a two-dimensional order of anti-aligned chains requires very little energy. These compounds represent a unique class of materials, offering new opportunities to investigate the interplay between the distinct crystal lattice geometry and the underlying electronic and magnetic properties.</abstract>
    </arXiv>

            </metadata>
        </record>

    </GetRecord>
</OAI-PMH>