<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<OAI-PMH xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" 
         xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance"
         xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/OAI-PMH.xsd">
    <responseDate>2026-07-13T06:27:05Z</responseDate>
                <request verb="GetRecord" identifier="oai:arXiv.org:2605.07652" metadataPrefix="arXiv">http://oaipmh.arxiv.org/oai</request>


    <GetRecord>
                <record>
                <header>
        <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:2605.07652</identifier>
        <datestamp>2026-05-11</datestamp>
            <setSpec>physics:astro-ph:EP</setSpec>
            <setSpec>physics:astro-ph:GA</setSpec>
    </header>

            <metadata>
                        <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ https://oaipmh.arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
        <id>2605.07652</id>
        <created>2026-05-08</created>
            <updated>2026-05-11</updated>
        <authors>
                <author>
                    <keyname>Hutsemékers</keyname>
                        <forenames>Damien</forenames>
                </author>
                <author>
                    <keyname>Manfroid</keyname>
                        <forenames>Jean</forenames>
                </author>
                <author>
                    <keyname>Opitom</keyname>
                        <forenames>Cyrielle</forenames>
                </author>
                <author>
                    <keyname>Jehin</keyname>
                        <forenames>Emmanuël</forenames>
                </author>
                <author>
                    <keyname>Krishnakumar</keyname>
                        <forenames>Aravind</forenames>
                </author>
                <author>
                    <keyname>Fernandes</keyname>
                        <forenames>Fernando Massa</forenames>
                </author>
                <author>
                    <keyname>Bannister</keyname>
                        <forenames>Michele</forenames>
                </author>
                <author>
                    <keyname>Bodewits</keyname>
                        <forenames>Dennis</forenames>
                </author>
                <author>
                    <keyname>Dorsey</keyname>
                        <forenames>Rosemary</forenames>
                </author>
                <author>
                    <keyname>La Forgia</keyname>
                        <forenames>Fiorangela</forenames>
                </author>
                <author>
                    <keyname>Murphy</keyname>
                        <forenames>Brian</forenames>
                </author>
        </authors>
        <title>Origin and evolution of NiI and FeI in the coma of the interstellar comet 3I/ATLAS throughout its trajectory</title>
            <categories>astro-ph.EP astro-ph.GA</categories>
            <comments>Submitted to A&amp;A</comments>
            <license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license>
            <abstract>We present high-resolution UVES+VLT observations of neutral nickel and iron atoms in the coma of the interstellar comet 3I/ATLAS taken after perihelion. Metal emission was strong shortly after perihelion and persisted at large heliocentric distances. At $r_h \sim 2$ au the total metal production rate was found to be at least an order of magnitude larger than that of typical solar-system comets. Post-perihelion production rates exhibit pronounced asymmetry compared to the pre-perihelion behavior: production rates are higher after perihelion and decline more gradually with $r_h$, the difference being stronger for FeI. The NiI/FeI abundance ratio, initially anomalously large before perihelion, evolved toward values comparable to solar-system comets near 2 au, and shows a weaker $r_h$ dependence after perihelion. To interpret these results, we revisited and extended the carbonyl hypothesis in which FeI and NiI are produced by the rapid photodissociation of Fe(CO)$_5$ and Ni(CO)$_4$ vaporized from the nucleus. Fits that include direct sublimation of carbonyls reproduce the observed rates and the high NiI/FeI line ratio, which is determined by the higher volatility of Ni(CO)$_4$. Desorption of carbonyls from sublimating CO$_2$ and H$_2$O ices is found to be negligible. The temperature profiles needed to reproduce the observations were found to be shallower than the equilibrium $T \propto r_h^{-1/2}$ relation, suggesting that the sublimation could occur below the surface of the nucleus. Fits using temperature profiles from thermal models require sublimation from depths of several cm, especially post-perihelion. An additional transient heat source ($T \simeq$ 100-140~K), possibly linked to the amorphous-crystalline ice transition, is proposed to explain the early NiI excess before perihelion.</abstract>
    </arXiv>

            </metadata>
        </record>

    </GetRecord>
</OAI-PMH>