<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<OAI-PMH xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" 
         xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance"
         xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/OAI-PMH.xsd">
    <responseDate>2026-07-13T06:20:45Z</responseDate>
                <request verb="GetRecord" identifier="oai:arXiv.org:2603.10883" metadataPrefix="arXiv">http://oaipmh.arxiv.org/oai</request>


    <GetRecord>
                <record>
                <header>
        <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:2603.10883</identifier>
        <datestamp>2026-03-12</datestamp>
            <setSpec>physics:quant-ph</setSpec>
    </header>

            <metadata>
                        <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ https://oaipmh.arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
        <id>2603.10883</id>
        <created>2026-03-11</created>
            <updated>2026-03-12</updated>
        <authors>
                <author>
                    <keyname>Ding</keyname>
                        <forenames>Dawei</forenames>
                </author>
                <author>
                    <keyname>Xu</keyname>
                        <forenames>Xinyu</forenames>
                </author>
        </authors>
        <title>Quantum Telepathy: A Quantum Technology with Near-Term Applications</title>
            <categories>quant-ph</categories>
            <comments>17 pages, 9 figures</comments>
            <license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license>
            <abstract>Quantum telepathy is the concept of using quantum entanglement to solve real-world problems involving decision coordination between parties with restricted communication. One possible reason for this restriction is a latency constraint: some pairs of parties do not have enough time to communicate with each other before they have to produce their outputs. Example scenarios include high frequency trading and distributed systems. Another reason is isolation: for some pairs of parties, there is an obstacle to communication. Example scenarios include locating a stray traveler by a rescue team and coordination within a network where nodes are owned by competing firms. In this paper we give a concise overview of the different application areas of quantum telepathy. We find that these real-world problems can be modeled as nonlocal games or its generalizations. We also discuss possible physical implementations. Quantum telepathy guarantees a quantum advantage via Bell&#39;s theorem and can directly solve real-world problems, such as reducing risk in high frequency trading or balancing data loads efficiently in ad hoc networks. Moreover, this quantum advantage can be physically realized with existing NISQ hardware.</abstract>
    </arXiv>

            </metadata>
        </record>

    </GetRecord>
</OAI-PMH>