<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<OAI-PMH xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" 
         xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance"
         xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/OAI-PMH.xsd">
    <responseDate>2026-07-13T08:33:24Z</responseDate>
                <request verb="GetRecord" identifier="oai:arXiv.org:2605.21640" metadataPrefix="arXiv">http://oaipmh.arxiv.org/oai</request>


    <GetRecord>
                <record>
                <header>
        <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:2605.21640</identifier>
        <datestamp>2026-05-22</datestamp>
            <setSpec>physics:gr-qc</setSpec>
    </header>

            <metadata>
                        <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ https://oaipmh.arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
        <id>2605.21640</id>
        <created>2026-05-20</created>
            <updated>2026-05-22</updated>
        <authors>
                <author>
                    <keyname>Lange</keyname>
                        <forenames>Jacob</forenames>
                </author>
                <author>
                    <keyname>Chiaramello</keyname>
                        <forenames>Danilo</forenames>
                </author>
                <author>
                    <keyname>Lott</keyname>
                        <forenames>Peter</forenames>
                </author>
                <author>
                    <keyname>Henshaw</keyname>
                        <forenames>Chad</forenames>
                </author>
                <author>
                    <keyname>Nagar</keyname>
                        <forenames>Alessandro</forenames>
                </author>
                <author>
                    <keyname>O&#39;Shaughnessy</keyname>
                        <forenames>Richard</forenames>
                </author>
                <author>
                    <keyname>Cadonati</keyname>
                        <forenames>Laura</forenames>
                </author>
        </authors>
        <title>Gravitational Wave Hyperbolic Catalog: Reanalyzing High-Mass Gravitational Wave Signals Using Hyperbolic Waveforms</title>
            <categories>gr-qc</categories>
            <comments>19 pages, 6 figures, submitted to PRD</comments>
            <license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license>
            <abstract>Close hyperbolic encounters between black holes produce distinctive bursts of gravitational radiation with a time-frequency morphology that is qualitatively different from that of quasi-circular inspirals. Expected to arise in dense stellar environments through dynamical interactions, these encounters probe formation channels and mass ranges inaccessible to isolated binary evolution, making them a compelling target for current and next-generation detectors. In this work, we reanalyze \totalevents high-mass events from the LIGO-Virgo-KAGRA catalogs using the hyperbolic configuration of the~\dali~waveform model. We compare these with analyses using the quasi-circular, precessing configuration of the same model, computing Bayes factors to evaluate which description is favored by the data. We find that most events strongly to mildly favor the quasi-circular, precessing scenario, except for GW190521. For this event, we find that the signal is best fit by a dynamical capture waveform, with Bayes factor $\ln \mathcal{B}^{\rm hyp}_{\rm prec}=3.71^{+0.11}_{-0.11}$. We confirm this preference via further analyses with~\dali~in different configurations (quasi-circular, non-precessing; eccentric, non-precessing; and eccentric, precessing), as well as one using the quasi-circular, precessing numerical relativity surrogate model \nrsur. We also highlight the results we obtain for GW231123, another high-mass signal linked to evidence of strong precession, for which we find strong preference for the quasi-circular, precessing scenario, with $\ln \mathcal{B}^{\rm hyp}_{\rm prec}=-15.80^{+0.24}_{-0.24}$. The analysis of mock signals generated with the best fitting waveforms for GW190521 and GW231123 suggest that the former might belong to a region of parameter space where high-mass, bound, precessing signals can be hard to distinguish from dynamical captures in parameter estimation.</abstract>
    </arXiv>

            </metadata>
        </record>

    </GetRecord>
</OAI-PMH>