<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<OAI-PMH xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" 
         xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance"
         xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/OAI-PMH.xsd">
    <responseDate>2026-07-11T21:50:42Z</responseDate>
                <request verb="GetRecord" identifier="oai:arXiv.org:2601.05601v1" metadataPrefix="arXiv">http://oaipmh.arxiv.org/oai</request>


    <GetRecord>
                <record>
                <header>
        <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:2601.05601</identifier>
        <datestamp>2026-01-12</datestamp>
            <setSpec>physics:astro-ph:HE</setSpec>
    </header>

            <metadata>
                        <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ https://oaipmh.arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
        <id>2601.05601</id>
        <created>2026-01-09</created>
            <updated>2026-01-12</updated>
        <authors>
                <author>
                    <keyname>Zhou</keyname>
                        <forenames>Tianyao</forenames>
                </author>
                <author>
                    <keyname>Shu</keyname>
                        <forenames>Xinwen</forenames>
                </author>
                <author>
                    <keyname>Mou</keyname>
                        <forenames>Guobin</forenames>
                </author>
                <author>
                    <keyname>Yang</keyname>
                        <forenames>Lei</forenames>
                </author>
                <author>
                    <keyname>Sun</keyname>
                        <forenames>Luming</forenames>
                </author>
                <author>
                    <keyname>Peng</keyname>
                        <forenames>Fangkun</forenames>
                </author>
                <author>
                    <keyname>Zhang</keyname>
                        <forenames>Fabao</forenames>
                </author>
                <author>
                    <keyname>Ding</keyname>
                        <forenames>Hucheng</forenames>
                </author>
                <author>
                    <keyname>Jiang</keyname>
                        <forenames>Ning</forenames>
                </author>
                <author>
                    <keyname>Wang</keyname>
                        <forenames>Tinggui</forenames>
                </author>
                <author>
                    <keyname>Chandola</keyname>
                        <forenames>Yogesh</forenames>
                </author>
                <author>
                    <keyname>Liu</keyname>
                        <forenames>Daizhong</forenames>
                </author>
                <author>
                    <keyname>Dou</keyname>
                        <forenames>Liming</forenames>
                </author>
                <author>
                    <keyname>Wang</keyname>
                        <forenames>Yibo</forenames>
                </author>
                <author>
                    <keyname>Wang</keyname>
                        <forenames>Jianguo</forenames>
                </author>
                <author>
                    <keyname>Wu</keyname>
                        <forenames>Zhongzu</forenames>
                </author>
                <author>
                    <keyname>Yang</keyname>
                        <forenames>Chenwei</forenames>
                </author>
        </authors>
        <title>Dust-obscured radio-emitting tidal disruption event coincident with a high-energy neutrino event</title>
            <categories>astro-ph.HE</categories>
            <comments>15 pages, 6 figures; accepted for publication in PRD</comments>
            <license>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0/</license>
            <abstract>Despite the growing number of high-energy neutrinos (TeV-PeV) detected by IceCube, their astrophysical origins remain largely unidentified. Recent observations have linked a few tidal disruption events (TDEs) to the production of high-energy neutrino emission, all of which display dust-reprocessed infrared flares, indicating a dust- and gas-rich environment. By cross-matching the neutrino events and a sample of mid-infrared outbursts in nearby galaxies with transient radio flares, we uncover an optically obscured TDE candidate, SDSS J151345.75 $+$ 311125.2, which shows both spatial and temporal coincidence with the sub-PeV neutrino event IC170514B. Using a standard equipartition analysis of the synchrotron spectral evolution spanning 605 days post mid-infrared discovery, we find a little evolution in the radio-emitting region, with a kinetic energy up to $10^{51}$ erg, depending on the outflow geometry and shock acceleration efficiency assumed. High-resolution European VLBI Network imaging reveals a compact radio emission that is unresolved at a scale of $&lt;$ 2.1 pc, with a brightness temperature of $T_b&gt;5\times10^6$ K, suggesting that the observed late-time radio emission might originate from the interaction between a decelerating outflow and a dense circumnuclear medium. If the association is genuine, the neutrino production is possibly related to the acceleration of protons through pp collisions during the outflow expanding process, implying that the outflow-cloud interaction could provide a physical site with a high-density environment for producing the sub-PeV neutrinos. Such a scenario can be tested with future identifications of radio transients coincident with high-energy neutrinos.</abstract>
    </arXiv>

            </metadata>
        </record>

    </GetRecord>
</OAI-PMH>