<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<OAI-PMH xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" 
         xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance"
         xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/OAI-PMH.xsd">
    <responseDate>2026-07-13T06:28:50Z</responseDate>
                <request verb="GetRecord" identifier="oai:arXiv.org:2512.14899" metadataPrefix="arXiv">http://oaipmh.arxiv.org/oai</request>


    <GetRecord>
                <record>
                <header>
        <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:2512.14899</identifier>
        <datestamp>2025-12-18</datestamp>
            <setSpec>physics:quant-ph</setSpec>
    </header>

            <metadata>
                        <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ https://oaipmh.arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
        <id>2512.14899</id>
        <created>2025-12-16</created>
            <updated>2025-12-18</updated>
        <authors>
                <author>
                    <keyname>Sumaya-Martinez</keyname>
                        <forenames>J.</forenames>
                </author>
        </authors>
        <title>Quantum Fisher-information limits of resonant nanophotonic sensors: why high-Q is not optimal even at the quantum limit</title>
            <categories>quant-ph</categories>
            <license>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0/</license>
            <abstract>We develop a quantum metrological framework for resonant nanophotonic sensors based on subwavelength Fabry--Perot slit cavities. Building on classical Fisher-information analyses of resonant transmission sensors, we model parameter encoding as a phase-and-loss quantum channel embedded in one arm of a Mach-Zehnder interferometer. We derive the quantum Fisher information (QFI) for coherent and Gaussian probe states under linear loss and show that, even at the quantum limit, optimal estimation precision is governed by the generator of parameter-dependent phase shifts rather than by the cavity quality factor. Consequently, the operating point that maximizes the QFI does not generally coincide with the maximum-Q resonance. Quantum resources enhance sensitivity but do not redefine the optimal geometry. Our results provide physically transparent design principles for quantum-enhanced nanophotonic sensing.</abstract>
    </arXiv>

            </metadata>
        </record>

    </GetRecord>
</OAI-PMH>