<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<OAI-PMH xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" 
         xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance"
         xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/OAI-PMH.xsd">
    <responseDate>2026-07-13T21:13:13Z</responseDate>
                <request verb="GetRecord" identifier="oai:arXiv.org:2506.13988" metadataPrefix="arXiv">http://oaipmh.arxiv.org/oai</request>


    <GetRecord>
                <record>
                <header>
        <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:2506.13988</identifier>
        <datestamp>2025-06-18</datestamp>
            <setSpec>physics:cond-mat:mes-hall</setSpec>
            <setSpec>physics:quant-ph</setSpec>
    </header>

            <metadata>
                        <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ https://oaipmh.arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
        <id>2506.13988</id>
        <created>2025-06-16</created>
            <updated>2025-06-18</updated>
        <authors>
                <author>
                    <keyname>Hoffman</keyname>
                        <forenames>Silas</forenames>
                </author>
                <author>
                    <keyname>Tahan</keyname>
                        <forenames>Charles</forenames>
                </author>
        </authors>
        <title>Resolving Andreev spin qubits in germanium-based Josephson junctions</title>
            <categories>cond-mat.mes-hall quant-ph</categories>
            <comments>9 pages, 9 figures</comments>
            <license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license>
            <abstract>Andreev spin qubits (ASQs) are a promising platform for quantum information processing which benefit from both the small footprint of semiconducting spin qubits and the long range connectivity of superconducting qubits. While state-of-the-art experiments have developed ASQs in InAs nanowires, these realizations are coherence-time limited by nuclear magnetic noise which cannot be removed by isotopic purification. In Ge-based Josephson junctions, which can be isotopically purified, Andreev states have been experimentally observed but spin-resolved Andreev states remain elusive. Here, we theoretically demonstrate that the geometry of the Josephson junction can limit the qubit frequency to values below typical experimental temperatures and render the ASQ effectively invisible. ASQs could be experimentally resolved by judiciously choosing the geometry of the junction and filling of the underlying Ge. Our comprehensive study of ASQ frequency on in situ and ex situ experimentally controllable parameters provides design guidance of Ge-based Josephson junctions and paves the way towards realization of high-coherence ASQs.</abstract>
    </arXiv>

            </metadata>
        </record>

    </GetRecord>
</OAI-PMH>