<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<OAI-PMH xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" 
         xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance"
         xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/OAI-PMH.xsd">
    <responseDate>2026-07-13T06:27:13Z</responseDate>
                <request verb="GetRecord" identifier="oai:arXiv.org:2605.21346" metadataPrefix="arXiv">http://oaipmh.arxiv.org/oai</request>


    <GetRecord>
                <record>
                <header>
        <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:2605.21346</identifier>
        <datestamp>2026-05-21</datestamp>
            <setSpec>physics:quant-ph</setSpec>
    </header>

            <metadata>
                        <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ https://oaipmh.arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
        <id>2605.21346</id>
        <created>2026-05-20</created>
            <updated>2026-05-21</updated>
        <authors>
                <author>
                    <keyname>Danaci</keyname>
                        <forenames>Onur</forenames>
                </author>
                <author>
                    <keyname>Patel</keyname>
                        <forenames>Yash J.</forenames>
                </author>
                <author>
                    <keyname>Molteni</keyname>
                        <forenames>Riccardo</forenames>
                </author>
                <author>
                    <keyname>van Nieuwenburg</keyname>
                        <forenames>Evert</forenames>
                </author>
                <author>
                    <keyname>Dunjko</keyname>
                        <forenames>Vedran</forenames>
                </author>
                <author>
                    <keyname>Krzywda</keyname>
                        <forenames>Jan A.</forenames>
                </author>
        </authors>
        <title>Evidence of Quantum Machine Learning Advantage with Tens of Noisy Qubits</title>
            <categories>quant-ph</categories>
            <comments>11 pages, GitHub Repo: https://github.com/jaq-lab/noisy-learning-advantage</comments>
            <license>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0/</license>
            <abstract>Learning problems involving quantum data are natural candidates for demonstrating an advantage in quantum machine learning. Recent results indicate that, for certain tasks and under noiseless conditions, coherent processing of quantum data outperforms fixed-measurement schemes followed by classical processing. It remained uncertain whether this performance gap persists at a finite scale, and in the presence of noise that is unavoidable with current quantum devices. In this work, we present simulations and analysis of the performance of existing hardware on a learning problem known to exhibit asymptotic advantage, now subjected to noisy quantum data. Comparing coherent quantum processing directly against fixed-measurement schemes, our results demonstrate a clear performance separation at a scale of just 30 to 40 noisy qubits. Already at this scale, the fundamental bottleneck is no longer classical computation but data acquisition; matching the noisy coherent protocol with measure-first strategies would still require months or even years of measurements. By systematically evaluating hardware constraints such as state preparation, gate errors, readout errors, connectivity, and coherence times, we provide evidence that a demonstration of such a strong learning advantage is accessible on near-term devices.</abstract>
    </arXiv>

            </metadata>
        </record>

    </GetRecord>
</OAI-PMH>