<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<OAI-PMH xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" 
         xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance"
         xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/OAI-PMH.xsd">
    <responseDate>2026-07-13T06:26:11Z</responseDate>
                <request verb="GetRecord" identifier="oai:arXiv.org:2601.16894" metadataPrefix="arXiv">http://oaipmh.arxiv.org/oai</request>


    <GetRecord>
                <record>
                <header>
        <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:2601.16894</identifier>
        <datestamp>2026-05-27</datestamp>
            <setSpec>physics:nucl-th</setSpec>
            <setSpec>physics:astro-ph:HE</setSpec>
            <setSpec>physics:astro-ph:SR</setSpec>
            <setSpec>physics:nucl-ex</setSpec>
    </header>

            <metadata>
                        <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ https://oaipmh.arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
        <id>2601.16894</id>
        <created>2026-05-26</created>
            <updated>2026-05-27</updated>
        <authors>
                <author>
                    <keyname>Koliogiannis</keyname>
                        <forenames>P. S.</forenames>
                </author>
                <author>
                    <keyname>Ghosh</keyname>
                        <forenames>T.</forenames>
                </author>
                <author>
                    <keyname>Yuksel</keyname>
                        <forenames>E.</forenames>
                </author>
                <author>
                    <keyname>Paar</keyname>
                        <forenames>N.</forenames>
                </author>
        </authors>
        <title>Universal relation between dipole polarizability of finite nuclei and neutron-star compactness</title>
            <categories>nucl-th astro-ph.HE astro-ph.SR nucl-ex</categories>
            <comments>v1: 10 pages, 4 figures, 4 tables; v2: 10 pages, 4 figures, 4 tables; matched published version in Physical Review C</comments>
            <journal-ref>Phys. Rev. C 113, 055809 (2026)</journal-ref>
            <doi>10.1103/9mnb-t3yz</doi>
            <license>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0/</license>
            <abstract>The nuclear equation of state, which determines the structure and properties of neutron stars, remains subject to substantial theoretical uncertainties, leading to model dependence in predicted observables. Universal relations have emerged as a powerful tool to mitigate this dependence by linking neutron star observables in a framework-independent manner. In this work, we introduce a new universal relation that \emph{bridges} finite nuclei and neutron stars through the dimensionless quantity $ζ= β_{1.4}\tilde{L}^{-1}$, which couples the compactness of a $1.4~M_{\odot}$ neutron star to the slope of the nuclear symmetry energy at saturation. The relation is examined under a broad set of relativistic energy density functionals with point-coupling and meson-exchange interactions, as well as non-relativistic Skyrme functionals. We demonstrate that $ζ$ exhibits a strong exponential correlation with the electric dipole polarizability $α_D$ in finite nuclei across all considered equations of state. By exploiting experimental $α_D$ data for selected neutron-rich nuclei, we constrain $ζ$ and translate these constraints into equation-of-state independent bounds on the neutron star radius $R_{1.4}$ and the symmetry-energy slope $L$, providing insights into the properties of neutron star matter.</abstract>
    </arXiv>

            </metadata>
        </record>

    </GetRecord>
</OAI-PMH>