<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<OAI-PMH xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" 
         xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance"
         xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/OAI-PMH.xsd">
    <responseDate>2026-07-13T06:27:00Z</responseDate>
                <request verb="GetRecord" identifier="oai:arXiv.org:2604.22924" metadataPrefix="arXiv">http://oaipmh.arxiv.org/oai</request>


    <GetRecord>
                <record>
                <header>
        <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:2604.22924</identifier>
        <datestamp>2026-04-28</datestamp>
            <setSpec>physics:astro-ph:GA</setSpec>
    </header>

            <metadata>
                        <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ https://oaipmh.arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
        <id>2604.22924</id>
        <created>2026-04-24</created>
            <updated>2026-04-28</updated>
        <authors>
                <author>
                    <keyname>Rantala</keyname>
                        <forenames>Antti</forenames>
                </author>
        </authors>
        <title>Supermassive stars with embedded stellar black hole cores: dense assembling star clusters as faint multiple Little Red Dot systems</title>
            <categories>astro-ph.GA</categories>
            <comments>11 pages, 5 figures, submitted to MNRAS</comments>
            <license>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0/</license>
            <abstract>Numerical simulations have established that star clusters with densities comparable to the high redshift ($z&gt;6$-$10$) James Webb Space Telescope (JWST) proto globular clusters may build up extremely massive (EMSs; $m_\mathrm{\star}&gt;1000 M_\odot$) or even supermassive stars (SMSs; $m_\mathrm{\star}&gt;10000 M_\odot$) and potentially intermediate mass black holes (IMBHs) through runaway stellar collisions. Using direct simulations of assembling star clusters including post-Newtonian black hole dynamics and stellar evolution, we demonstrate that in such dense environments ($Σ_\mathrm{h} \gtrsim 10^6 M_\odot$pc$^\mathrm{-2}$) stellar BHs ($m_\bullet \lesssim 60 M_\odot$), driven by rapid mass segregation and relaxation effects within the sphere of influence of the EMSs/SMSs, may strongly interact with the extremely massive stars and become embedded within their gaseous layers. We suggest that this quasi-star (QS) like embedded BH phase is a natural outcome of the runaway formation of EMSs/SMSs in the densest star clusters. The QS phase is orders of magnitude longer in duration than the lifetime of the SMS, enabling an extended growth period by stellar collisions, and allows the formation of embedded gravitational wave sources if the QS captures more than a single stellar BH. The star cluster assembly region sizes ($\sim100$ pc), QS masses ($\gtrsim 10^4 M_\odot$) and their proximity to young, massive blue star forming clumps are consistent with the faint population of multiple little red dots (LRDs) recently discovered by the JWST.</abstract>
    </arXiv>

            </metadata>
        </record>

    </GetRecord>
</OAI-PMH>