<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<OAI-PMH xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" 
         xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance"
         xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/OAI-PMH.xsd">
    <responseDate>2026-07-12T16:06:11Z</responseDate>
                <request verb="GetRecord" identifier="oai:arXiv.org:2506.03455v1" metadataPrefix="arXiv">http://oaipmh.arxiv.org/oai</request>


    <GetRecord>
                <record>
                <header>
        <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:2506.03455</identifier>
        <datestamp>2025-06-05</datestamp>
            <setSpec>physics:quant-ph</setSpec>
    </header>

            <metadata>
                        <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ https://oaipmh.arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
        <id>2506.03455</id>
        <created>2025-06-03</created>
            <updated>2025-06-05</updated>
        <authors>
                <author>
                    <keyname>Tapia-Maureira</keyname>
                        <forenames>Hachisko</forenames>
                </author>
                <author>
                    <keyname>He</keyname>
                        <forenames>Bing</forenames>
                </author>
                <author>
                    <keyname>Di Ventra</keyname>
                        <forenames>Massimiliano</forenames>
                </author>
                <author>
                    <keyname>Norambuena</keyname>
                        <forenames>Ariel</forenames>
                </author>
        </authors>
        <title>Memory effects in pulsed optomechanical systems</title>
            <categories>quant-ph</categories>
            <comments>12 pages, 6 figures, 1 table</comments>
            <license>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0/</license>
            <abstract>Memory, understood as time non-locality, is a fundamental property of any physical system, whether classical or quantum, and has important applications in a wide variety of technologies. In the context of quantum technologies, systems with memory can be used in quantum information, communication, and sensing. Here, we demonstrate that cavity optomechanical systems driven by a pulsed laser can operate as programmable quantum memory elements. By engineering the adiabatic and non-adiabatic pulses, particularly the Gaussian and sinusoidal, we induce and control diverse memory phenomena such as dynamical hysteresis, quantized phononic transitions, and distinct energy-storing responses. Within a mean-field approach, we derive the analytical and numerical criteria under which the photonic and phononic observables manifest the memory effects in strongly driven regimes. The memory effects are quantified through a dimensionless geometric form factor, which provides a versatile metric to characterize the memory efficiency. Our protocol is readily compatible with the current optomechanical platforms, highlighting the new possibilities for advanced memory functionalities in quantum technologies.</abstract>
    </arXiv>

            </metadata>
        </record>

    </GetRecord>
</OAI-PMH>