<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<OAI-PMH xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" 
         xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance"
         xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/OAI-PMH.xsd">
    <responseDate>2026-07-13T06:26:15Z</responseDate>
                <request verb="GetRecord" identifier="oai:arXiv.org:2601.22247" metadataPrefix="arXiv">http://oaipmh.arxiv.org/oai</request>


    <GetRecord>
                <record>
                <header>
        <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:2601.22247</identifier>
        <datestamp>2026-04-14</datestamp>
            <setSpec>physics:quant-ph</setSpec>
            <setSpec>physics:cond-mat:stat-mech</setSpec>
    </header>

            <metadata>
                        <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ https://oaipmh.arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
        <id>2601.22247</id>
        <created>2026-04-12</created>
            <updated>2026-04-14</updated>
        <authors>
                <author>
                    <keyname>Vaknin</keyname>
                        <forenames>David</forenames>
                </author>
        </authors>
        <title>Temperature as a Dynamically Maintained Steady State: Photonic Mechanisms, Maintenance Cost, and the Limits of the Infinite-Reservoir Idealization</title>
            <categories>quant-ph cond-mat.stat-mech</categories>
            <license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license>
            <abstract>Classical thermodynamics treats temperature as a state variable characterizing systems in equilibrium with idealized infinite reservoirs. We argue that this framing, while computationally exact, obscures an essential physical reality: any system at finite characteristic energy $E_c = k_B T$ continuously emits thermal radiation and cools unless energy input compensates these losses. What thermodynamics calls ``thermal equilibrium&#39;&#39; is, at the microscopic level, a dynamically sustained steady state maintained by continuous photon exchange.
  We derive that the average photon energy required to sustain a Planck distribution is $\langle hν\rangle = π^4 E_c/[30\,ζ(3)] \approx 2.701\,E_c$, quantifying the energetic throughput that any real system must sustain to maintain a given temperature. We resolve the apparent contradiction with the purely mechanical Maxwell velocity distribution: billiard-ball kinetics correctly describe the \emph{shape} of the distribution at a given $E_c$, but cannot account for how $E_c$ is established or maintained against radiative losses in any real system of charged particles. We further show that every finite thermal reservoir is itself maintained by photon exchange at a larger scale, organizing physical systems into a natural hierarchy from individual samples through cryostats, laboratories, and planetary surfaces to stellar interiors, with the classical infinite reservoir emerging as the large-capacity limit within that hierarchy rather than a fundamental physical entity. We also comment on the relation between thermodynamic entropy $S = k_B \ln W$ and the dimensionless entropy $\mathcal{S} = \ln W$, emphasizing that $k_B$ primarily fixes units (J/K) rather than introducing new statistical content. These results do not modify thermodynamics but provide its mechanistic interpretation in terms of quantum electrodynamics.</abstract>
    </arXiv>

            </metadata>
        </record>

    </GetRecord>
</OAI-PMH>