<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<OAI-PMH xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" 
         xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance"
         xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/OAI-PMH.xsd">
    <responseDate>2026-07-13T06:26:16Z</responseDate>
                <request verb="GetRecord" identifier="oai:arXiv.org:2602.05296" metadataPrefix="arXiv">http://oaipmh.arxiv.org/oai</request>


    <GetRecord>
                <record>
                <header>
        <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:2602.05296</identifier>
        <datestamp>2026-02-06</datestamp>
            <setSpec>physics:astro-ph:GA</setSpec>
    </header>

            <metadata>
                        <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ https://oaipmh.arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
        <id>2602.05296</id>
        <created>2026-02-05</created>
            <updated>2026-02-06</updated>
        <authors>
                <author>
                    <keyname>Yamsiri</keyname>
                        <forenames>Pavadol</forenames>
                </author>
                <author>
                    <keyname>Bland-Hawthorn</keyname>
                        <forenames>Joss</forenames>
                </author>
                <author>
                    <keyname>Tepper-Garcia</keyname>
                        <forenames>Thor</forenames>
                </author>
        </authors>
        <title>Galactic seismology: can a disc-crossing impulse explain the large-scale perturbations in the Milky Way&#39;s disc?</title>
            <categories>astro-ph.GA</categories>
            <comments>19 pages, 21 figures, submitted to MNRAS</comments>
            <license>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0/</license>
            <abstract>Prior to its infall, the Sagittarius (Sgr) dwarf galaxy was a major satellite with a mass of $M_{\rm sgr}\sim 10^{11}$ M$_\odot$. For the past $5-6~\mathrm{Gyr}$ , it has been heavily stripped by the Milky Way (MW), losing most of its mass while crossing the MW disc multiple times. Recent models of Milky Way disc perturbations $-$ including the spiral arms, the stellar bar, the Gaia phase spiral, and stellar and gaseous disc corrugations $-$ have identified these crossings as possible formation triggers, but have generally treated each perturbation in isolation. Here, we adopt a holistic perspective and ask whether a single disc-crossing impulse can simultaneously account for these features as observed today. We focus on simulations of single disc-crossing events by a Sgr-like perturber, and present a forensic analysis of the role of the powerful impulse in forming spiral arms, disc corrugations, the phase spiral and the `$L_{z}-\bar{V}_{R}$ wave&#39;, determined from a star&#39;s angular momentum and radial velocity, respectively. We find that a single disc crossing can reproduce reasonably well (e.g. structure, amplitude, phase) the observed local disc corrugation, and the Outer, Local and Sagittarius-Carina arm segments, implying that the last significant impulse due to a transit took place $700-1200~\mathrm{Myr}$ ago. Moreover, the $L_{z}-\bar{V}_{R}$ wave and phase spiral appear within the simulations over the same epoch and their general structure is reasonably well replicated, but not in detail. We conclude that Sgr&#39;s last significant crossing roughly a Gyr ago could be the primary cause of large-scale MW disc perturbations, but it cannot fully account for the $L_{z}-\bar{V}_{R}$ wave. Consequently, other triggers, possibly the Galactic bar or interactions with other satellites, must be considered in order to fully explain the current dynamical state of the MW&#39;s disc.</abstract>
    </arXiv>

            </metadata>
        </record>

    </GetRecord>
</OAI-PMH>