<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<OAI-PMH xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" 
         xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance"
         xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/OAI-PMH.xsd">
    <responseDate>2026-07-13T21:14:07Z</responseDate>
                <request verb="GetRecord" identifier="oai:arXiv.org:2408.01421" metadataPrefix="arXiv">http://oaipmh.arxiv.org/oai</request>


    <GetRecord>
                <record>
                <header>
        <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:2408.01421</identifier>
        <datestamp>2024-11-19</datestamp>
            <setSpec>physics:cond-mat:str-el</setSpec>
    </header>

            <metadata>
                        <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ https://oaipmh.arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
        <id>2408.01421</id>
        <created>2024-11-18</created>
            <updated>2024-11-19</updated>
        <authors>
                <author>
                    <keyname>Di Salvo</keyname>
                        <forenames>E.</forenames>
                </author>
                <author>
                    <keyname>Moustaj</keyname>
                        <forenames>A.</forenames>
                </author>
                <author>
                    <keyname>Xu</keyname>
                        <forenames>C.</forenames>
                </author>
                <author>
                    <keyname>Fritz</keyname>
                        <forenames>L.</forenames>
                </author>
                <author>
                    <keyname>Mitchell</keyname>
                        <forenames>A. K.</forenames>
                </author>
                <author>
                    <keyname>Smith</keyname>
                        <forenames>C. Morais</forenames>
                </author>
                <author>
                    <keyname>Schuricht</keyname>
                        <forenames>D.</forenames>
                </author>
        </authors>
        <title>Topological phases of the interacting Su-Schrieffer-Heeger model: An analytical study</title>
            <categories>cond-mat.str-el</categories>
            <comments>18 pages, 6 figures to be submitted to PRB. Comments are welcome</comments>
            <journal-ref>Physical Review B 110, 165145 (2024)</journal-ref>
            <doi>10.1103/PhysRevB.110.165145</doi>
            <license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license>
            <abstract>The interacting SSH model provides an ideal ground to study the interplay between topologically insulating phases and electron-electron interactions. We study the polarization density as a topological invariant and provide an analytic treatment of its behavior in the low-energy sector of the one-dimensional interacting SSH model. By formulating the topological invariant in terms of Green&#39;s functions, we use the low-energy field theory of the Thirring model to derive the behavior of the polarization density. We show that the polarization density in the continuum theory describes the usual topological insulating phases. Still, it contains an extra factor from the fields&#39; scaling dimensions in the low-energy quantum field theory. We interpret this as a measure of the modified charge of the new excitations in the system. We find two distinct contributions: a renormalization of the electronic charge $e$ of a Fermi liquid because of quasiparticle smearing and an additional contribution coming from the topological charge of the soliton arising in the bosonized version of the Thirring model, the sine-Gordon model.</abstract>
    </arXiv>

            </metadata>
        </record>

    </GetRecord>
</OAI-PMH>