<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<OAI-PMH xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" 
         xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance"
         xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/OAI-PMH.xsd">
    <responseDate>2026-07-13T06:27:21Z</responseDate>
                <request verb="GetRecord" identifier="oai:arXiv.org:2606.04099" metadataPrefix="arXiv">http://oaipmh.arxiv.org/oai</request>


    <GetRecord>
                <record>
                <header>
        <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:2606.04099</identifier>
        <datestamp>2026-06-04</datestamp>
            <setSpec>physics:gr-qc</setSpec>
            <setSpec>physics:hep-ph</setSpec>
            <setSpec>physics:hep-th</setSpec>
            <setSpec>physics:quant-ph</setSpec>
    </header>

            <metadata>
                        <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ https://oaipmh.arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
        <id>2606.04099</id>
        <created>2026-06-02</created>
            <updated>2026-06-04</updated>
        <authors>
                <author>
                    <keyname>Takeda</keyname>
                        <forenames>Hiroki</forenames>
                </author>
                <author>
                    <keyname>Tomizuka</keyname>
                        <forenames>Shogo</forenames>
                </author>
                <author>
                    <keyname>Tanaka</keyname>
                        <forenames>Takahiro</forenames>
                </author>
        </authors>
        <title>Gravitationally Induced Quantum Decoherence of Macroscopic Objects</title>
            <categories>gr-qc hep-ph hep-th quant-ph</categories>
            <comments>18 pages, 3 figures</comments>
            <license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license>
            <abstract>We formulate the gravitationally induced quantum decoherence of a massive object prepared in a spatial superposition. Starting from linearized gravity coupled to a massive system particle and an environmental scalar field, we derive a closed-time-path influence functional governing the reduced system dynamics. In the nonrelativistic and quasi-static regime, the decoherence exponent can be written as a bilinear functional of the difference of the system stress-energy tensors and an effective noise kernel obtained by dressing the environmental stress-energy tensor correlator with graviton propagators. We then apply this framework to the Newtonian long-range gravitational interaction and evaluate the resulting decoherence function for a dilute nonrelativistic gas modeled by finite wave packets and coarse-grained in time and space. By performing controlled approximations, we obtain analytic expressions for the cumulative decoherence function and show that the dominant contribution is accumulated logarithmically over a broad range of distances, while remaining subdominant to conventional collisional decoherence under realistic conditions.</abstract>
    </arXiv>

            </metadata>
        </record>

    </GetRecord>
</OAI-PMH>