<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<OAI-PMH xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" 
         xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance"
         xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/OAI-PMH.xsd">
    <responseDate>2026-07-13T06:21:16Z</responseDate>
                <request verb="GetRecord" identifier="oai:arXiv.org:2509.09472" metadataPrefix="arXiv">http://oaipmh.arxiv.org/oai</request>


    <GetRecord>
                <record>
                <header>
        <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:2509.09472</identifier>
        <datestamp>2025-09-12</datestamp>
            <setSpec>physics:astro-ph:CO</setSpec>
            <setSpec>physics:hep-ph</setSpec>
    </header>

            <metadata>
                        <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ https://oaipmh.arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
        <id>2509.09472</id>
        <created>2025-09-11</created>
            <updated>2025-09-12</updated>
        <authors>
                <author>
                    <keyname>Setabuddin</keyname>
                </author>
                <author>
                    <keyname>Haque</keyname>
                        <forenames>Md Riajul</forenames>
                </author>
                <author>
                    <keyname>Karmakar</keyname>
                        <forenames>Rajesh</forenames>
                </author>
                <author>
                    <keyname>Pal</keyname>
                        <forenames>Supratik</forenames>
                </author>
        </authors>
        <title>Axion-Photon Conversion in FLRW with Primordial Magnetic Fields: Explaining the Radio Excess</title>
            <categories>astro-ph.CO hep-ph</categories>
            <comments>32 pages, 8 figures, 1 table. Comments are welcome</comments>
            <license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license>
            <abstract>We explore the possibility of axion-photon conversion as a common origin of two low-frequency anomalies: the isotropic radio excess (ARCADE2) and the deep global 21-cm absorption trough (EDGES). From the axion-photon action in an FLRW background with primordial magnetic fields (PMFs), we derive the scale-dependent conversion probability including plasma effects. Resonant conversion, arising when the axion mass matches the plasma-induced photon mass, produces soft photons in the MHz-GHz range. By modeling stochastic PMFs with amplitude $B_0$ and spectral index $n_{\rm B}$, we show that axion-like particles with mass $\sim 10^{-14}$-$10^{-12}\,\mathrm{eV}$ and nanogauss-level nearly scale invariant PMFs can explain both ARCADE2 and EDGES. Heating from PMF dissipation via ambipolar diffusion and turbulent decay reduces the 21-cm trough, shifting the viable parameter space. Our results stem from a consistent theoretical framework developed from first principles and a combined analysis of the radio excess and global 21-cm signal, while remaining consistent with CMB bounds on PMFs and $ΔN_{\rm eff}$. We conclude that global 21-cm observations may offer potential sensitivity to axions, primordial magnetism, and dark-sector physics.</abstract>
    </arXiv>

            </metadata>
        </record>

    </GetRecord>
</OAI-PMH>