<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<OAI-PMH xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" 
         xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance"
         xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/OAI-PMH.xsd">
    <responseDate>2026-07-11T20:20:25Z</responseDate>
                <request verb="GetRecord" identifier="oai:arXiv.org:2601.01563v2" metadataPrefix="arXiv">http://oaipmh.arxiv.org/oai</request>


    <GetRecord>
                <record>
                <header>
        <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:2601.01563</identifier>
        <datestamp>2026-07-07</datestamp>
            <setSpec>physics:astro-ph:HE</setSpec>
    </header>

            <metadata>
                        <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ https://oaipmh.arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
        <id>2601.01563</id>
        <created>2026-07-06</created>
            <updated>2026-07-07</updated>
        <authors>
                <author>
                    <keyname>Sarkar</keyname>
                        <forenames>Saptarshi</forenames>
                </author>
                <author>
                    <keyname>Roy</keyname>
                        <forenames>Jayanta</forenames>
                </author>
                <author>
                    <keyname>Bhattacharyya</keyname>
                        <forenames>Bhaswati</forenames>
                </author>
                <author>
                    <keyname>Ray</keyname>
                        <forenames>Paul</forenames>
                </author>
                <author>
                    <keyname>Kudale</keyname>
                        <forenames>Sanjay</forenames>
                </author>
                <author>
                    <keyname>Freire</keyname>
                        <forenames>Paulo</forenames>
                </author>
                <author>
                    <keyname>Weltevrede</keyname>
                        <forenames>Patrick</forenames>
                </author>
                <author>
                    <keyname>Kerr</keyname>
                        <forenames>Matthew</forenames>
                </author>
        </authors>
        <title>Detection of giant pulses from the transitional millisecond pulsar J1227$-$4853</title>
            <categories>astro-ph.HE</categories>
            <comments>12 pages, 7 figures, 2 tables. Revised version, accepted for publication in ApJ</comments>
            <license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license>
            <abstract>We report the discovery of giant pulse (GP) emission from the transitional millisecond pulsar (tMSP) PSR J1227$-$4853, using 174 hours of single-pulse data from the upgraded Giant Metrewave Radio Telescope (uGMRT). This marks the first detection of GPs from a transitional MSP and adds to the small number of millisecond pulsars known to exhibit such extreme variability. A total of 235 GPs were detected across observations at 550-750 MHz, with widths as narrow as 1.28 $μ$s and flux densities up to $\sim 10^4$ times the pulsar&#39;s mean flux density. The GPs are strongly localized in pulse phase, originating predominantly from the second and third main-pulse components, and are absent in the inter-pulse region. Their cumulative fluence distribution follows a power law above the completeness threshold, consistent with a defining characteristic of GP emission. The arrival times of the GPs deviate significantly from Poisson statistics, with the waiting-time distribution well described by a Weibull model having a shape parameter of $k = 0.30$, indicative of strong temporal clustering. During an epoch of enhanced activity, the GP rate increased by nearly two orders of magnitude to 124 $\mathrm{hr}^{-1}$, with a corresponding shape parameter of $k = 0.47$. This value is similar to that reported for a burst storm from the repeating fast radio burst FRB 20200120E, suggesting possible phenomenological parallels between GPs from compact binary systems and repeating FRBs.</abstract>
    </arXiv>

            </metadata>
        </record>

    </GetRecord>
</OAI-PMH>