<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<OAI-PMH xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" 
         xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance"
         xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/OAI-PMH.xsd">
    <responseDate>2026-07-13T06:23:38Z</responseDate>
                <request verb="GetRecord" identifier="oai:arXiv.org:2601.16567" metadataPrefix="arXiv">http://oaipmh.arxiv.org/oai</request>


    <GetRecord>
                <record>
                <header>
        <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:2601.16567</identifier>
        <datestamp>2026-05-22</datestamp>
            <setSpec>physics:gr-qc</setSpec>
            <setSpec>physics:astro-ph:EP</setSpec>
            <setSpec>physics:astro-ph:HE</setSpec>
            <setSpec>physics:physics:geo-ph</setSpec>
    </header>

            <metadata>
                        <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ https://oaipmh.arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
        <id>2601.16567</id>
        <created>2026-05-21</created>
            <updated>2026-05-22</updated>
        <authors>
                <author>
                    <keyname>Zhang</keyname>
                        <forenames>Lei</forenames>
                </author>
                <author>
                    <keyname>Yan</keyname>
                        <forenames>Han</forenames>
                </author>
                <author>
                    <keyname>Chen</keyname>
                        <forenames>Xian</forenames>
                </author>
                <author>
                    <keyname>Zhang</keyname>
                        <forenames>Jinhai</forenames>
                </author>
        </authors>
        <title>Thick Lunar Crust Amplifies Deci-Hertz Gravitational-Wave Signal</title>
            <categories>gr-qc astro-ph.EP astro-ph.HE physics.geo-ph</categories>
            <license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license>
            <abstract>Gravitational waves (GWs) in the $0.01\sim1$ Hz band encode unique signatures of the early universe and merging compact objects, but they are beyond the reach of existing observatories. Theoretical models suggest that the Moon could act as a resonant detector, but the unknown influence of its rugged surface and heterogeneous interior poses a challenge to the accurate modeling of its response. Here, we address this long-standing uncertainty by constructing the first high-resolution, two-dimensional model of the lunar GW response, more realistic than previous ones. We achieve this by combining high-fidelity spectral-element simulations with the analytical power of normal-mode perturbation theory, thereby resolving topographical effects down to 2 km grid spacing while maintaining the capacity to discern global free-oscillation patterns. This dual-methodology approach not only recovers the expected predominant quadrupole ($l=2$) oscillation mode, but also exposes a systematic signal amplification in thick-crust regions. This enhancement is traced by our normal-mode analysis to a mode-coupling process, in which the original quadrupolar oscillation induced by the passing GW distributes energy into a series of higher-order modes, the hybridized eigenmodes of a laterally heterogeneous Moon. In certain narrow frequency ranges, we observe up to tenfold amplification spanning into the deci-hertz band, highlighting the power of numerical simulations in resolving these structurally fine-tuned features for designing future detectors. Our work establishes the Moon as a resonant GW detector albeit its complex topographical structures, and the resulting amplification maps provide quantitative guide for the optimal landing site selection.</abstract>
    </arXiv>

            </metadata>
        </record>

    </GetRecord>
</OAI-PMH>