<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<OAI-PMH xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" 
         xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance"
         xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/OAI-PMH.xsd">
    <responseDate>2026-07-13T06:27:41Z</responseDate>
                <request verb="GetRecord" identifier="oai:arXiv.org:2509.15792" metadataPrefix="arXiv">http://oaipmh.arxiv.org/oai</request>


    <GetRecord>
                <record>
                <header>
        <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:2509.15792</identifier>
        <datestamp>2025-09-22</datestamp>
            <setSpec>physics:astro-ph:HE</setSpec>
    </header>

            <metadata>
                        <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ https://oaipmh.arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
        <id>2509.15792</id>
        <created>2025-09-19</created>
            <updated>2025-09-22</updated>
        <authors>
                <author>
                    <keyname>Shao</keyname>
                        <forenames>Yi-xuan</forenames>
                </author>
                <author>
                    <keyname>Zhou</keyname>
                        <forenames>Ping</forenames>
                </author>
                <author>
                    <keyname>Zhang</keyname>
                        <forenames>Xiao</forenames>
                </author>
                <author>
                    <keyname>Zhang</keyname>
                        <forenames>Zhi-Yu</forenames>
                </author>
                <author>
                    <keyname>Chen</keyname>
                        <forenames>Yang</forenames>
                </author>
                <author>
                    <keyname>Han</keyname>
                        <forenames>Qin</forenames>
                </author>
                <author>
                    <keyname>Li</keyname>
                        <forenames>Di</forenames>
                </author>
                <author>
                    <keyname>Li</keyname>
                        <forenames>Xiang-Dong</forenames>
                </author>
                <author>
                    <keyname>Weng</keyname>
                        <forenames>Jian-Bin</forenames>
                </author>
                <author>
                    <keyname>Shao</keyname>
                        <forenames>Yong</forenames>
                </author>
        </authors>
        <title>Absence of Radio Emission Reveals an Exceptionally Weak Explosion of the Putative Historical Supernova Pa 30</title>
            <categories>astro-ph.HE</categories>
            <comments>10 pages, 3 figures. Accepted for publication in ApJL</comments>
            <license>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0/</license>
            <abstract>We present the first deep radio continuum observations of Pa 30, a nebula hosting a unique optical source driven by an ultrafast outflow with a velocity of 16,000 km s$^{-1}$. The nebula was proposed to be the remnant of a white dwarf merger that occurred in 1181CE. We report no detection of the radio diffuse emission from Pa 30 or radio emission from the central source, setting $3σ$ upper limit flux densities of $0.84\,\rm mJy$ and $0.29\,\rm mJy$ at 1.5 GHz and 6 GHz, respectively, for Pa 30. The radio surface brightness of Pa 30 is $\sim 3$ orders of magnitude smaller than that of typical supernova remnants (SNRs) with comparable angular size. If Pa 30 is an SNR, our observations show it to be the faintest known in the radio band. Considering that 10\% of the supernova (SN) kinetic energy is transferred to cosmic rays (CRs), the absence of radio synchrotron emission suggests that the SN kinetic energy $\lesssim3\times 10^{47}(B/10 μ\rm G)^{-1.65}$ erg, which is 3 to 4 orders of magnitude lower than that of typical SNRs and the lowest measured among Galactic SNRs. There is also an indication of inefficient CR acceleration for this source. The low SN kinetic energy either implies the potential existence of many more radio-faint, sub-energetic SNRs in our Galaxy or challenges the SNR interpretation of Pa 30.</abstract>
    </arXiv>

            </metadata>
        </record>

    </GetRecord>
</OAI-PMH>