<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<OAI-PMH xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" 
         xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance"
         xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/OAI-PMH.xsd">
    <responseDate>2026-07-13T06:23:52Z</responseDate>
                <request verb="GetRecord" identifier="oai:arXiv.org:2602.15935" metadataPrefix="arXiv">http://oaipmh.arxiv.org/oai</request>


    <GetRecord>
                <record>
                <header>
        <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:2602.15935</identifier>
        <datestamp>2026-02-24</datestamp>
            <setSpec>physics:astro-ph:GA</setSpec>
            <setSpec>physics:astro-ph:CO</setSpec>
            <setSpec>physics:astro-ph:SR</setSpec>
    </header>

            <metadata>
                        <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ https://oaipmh.arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
        <id>2602.15935</id>
        <created>2026-02-22</created>
            <updated>2026-02-24</updated>
        <authors>
                <author>
                    <keyname>Chisholm</keyname>
                        <forenames>John</forenames>
                </author>
                <author>
                    <keyname>Berg</keyname>
                        <forenames>Danielle A.</forenames>
                </author>
                <author>
                    <keyname>Boylan-Kolchin</keyname>
                        <forenames>Michael</forenames>
                </author>
                <author>
                    <keyname>de Graaff</keyname>
                        <forenames>Anna</forenames>
                </author>
                <author>
                    <keyname>Furtak</keyname>
                        <forenames>Lukas J.</forenames>
                </author>
                <author>
                    <keyname>Kokorev</keyname>
                        <forenames>Vasily</forenames>
                </author>
                <author>
                    <keyname>Matthee</keyname>
                        <forenames>Jorryt</forenames>
                </author>
                <author>
                    <keyname>Muñoz</keyname>
                        <forenames>Julian B.</forenames>
                </author>
                <author>
                    <keyname>Naidu</keyname>
                        <forenames>Rohan P.</forenames>
                </author>
                <author>
                    <keyname>Sander</keyname>
                        <forenames>Andreas A. C.</forenames>
                </author>
        </authors>
        <title>Little Red Dots as Globular Clusters in Formation</title>
            <categories>astro-ph.GA astro-ph.CO astro-ph.SR</categories>
            <comments>8 pages, 4 figures</comments>
            <license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license>
            <abstract>Little Red Dots (LRDs), among the most enigmatic high-redshift discoveries by JWST, are commonly believed to be powered by accreting supermassive black holes. Here, we explore the possibility that these sources are globular clusters in formation, with rest-frame UV arising from a very young stellar population and rest-frame optical from a short-lived supermassive ($&gt;10^4$ M$_\odot$) star. The spectral profiles of LRDs are broadly consistent with this scenario, though the observed temperatures and bolometric luminosities favor emission reprocessed by optically thick, continuum-driven winds not fully captured by current models. The LRD $z\sim5-7$ UV luminosity function naturally evolves, under standard evolutionary and mass-loss prescriptions, into a present-day mass function with a turnover at $\log_{10}(M_\ast$/$M_\odot)=5.3$ and an exponential cutoff at high masses, consistent with local globular-cluster populations. We estimate the total present-day number density of LRDs formed across all redshifts to be $\approx0.3$ Mpc$^{-3}$, similar to local globular clusters. The observed LRD redshift range matches the age distribution of metal-poor globular clusters, without current LRD counterparts to the metal-rich population. If LRDs are globular clusters in formation, we predict chemical abundance patterns characteristic of multiple stellar populations, including enhanced He and N, and potential Na-O and Al-Mg anti-correlations. These results offer a local perspective to explore this surprisingly abundant population of distant sources, and a potential new window into extreme stellar astrophysics in the early Universe.</abstract>
    </arXiv>

            </metadata>
        </record>

    </GetRecord>
</OAI-PMH>