<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<OAI-PMH xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" 
         xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance"
         xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/OAI-PMH.xsd">
    <responseDate>2026-07-11T21:28:07Z</responseDate>
                <request verb="GetRecord" identifier="oai:arXiv.org:2601.05316v1" metadataPrefix="arXiv">http://oaipmh.arxiv.org/oai</request>


    <GetRecord>
                <record>
                <header>
        <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:2601.05316</identifier>
        <datestamp>2026-01-12</datestamp>
            <setSpec>physics:astro-ph:GA</setSpec>
    </header>

            <metadata>
                        <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ https://oaipmh.arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
        <id>2601.05316</id>
        <created>2026-01-08</created>
            <updated>2026-01-12</updated>
        <authors>
                <author>
                    <keyname>Su</keyname>
                        <forenames>Tong</forenames>
                </author>
                <author>
                    <keyname>Guo</keyname>
                        <forenames>Qi</forenames>
                </author>
                <author>
                    <keyname>Pei</keyname>
                        <forenames>Wenxiang</forenames>
                </author>
                <author>
                    <keyname>Jiang</keyname>
                        <forenames>Linhua</forenames>
                </author>
        </authors>
        <title>Revised AGN Spectral Model Reveals a More Significant Role in Cosmic Reionization</title>
            <categories>astro-ph.GA</categories>
            <comments>12 pages, 7 figures. Accepted for publication in the Astrophysical Journal Letter</comments>
            <license>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0/</license>
            <abstract>Reionization marks one of the most important phase transitions in the history of the Universe, during which neutral baryonic matter was transformed into ionized plasma. While star-forming galaxies are widely regarded as the primary drivers of this process, the extent to which active galactic nuclei (AGNs) contribute remains a subject of ongoing investigation. In this study, we integrate a physically motivated AGN spectral energy distribution (SED) model with state-of-the-art observations to reassess the contribution of AGNs to cosmic reionization. Our findings indicate that adopting a more sophisticated AGN SED model could substantially increase the predicted ionizing photon output by a factor of 3$\sim$4, elevating AGNs to a more significant role ($\approx$20\%) in maintaining reionization than previously estimated. The inclusion of abundant faint AGNs further amplifies this contribution by a factor of a few. These conclusions remain robust across a wide range of accretion rates and ionizing photon escape fractions. Collectively, our results suggest that AGNs may have played a more prominent and previously underestimated role in the reionization of the Universe.</abstract>
    </arXiv>

            </metadata>
        </record>

    </GetRecord>
</OAI-PMH>