<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<OAI-PMH xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" 
         xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance"
         xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/OAI-PMH.xsd">
    <responseDate>2026-07-13T06:26:05Z</responseDate>
                <request verb="GetRecord" identifier="oai:arXiv.org:2601.14083" metadataPrefix="arXiv">http://oaipmh.arxiv.org/oai</request>


    <GetRecord>
                <record>
                <header>
        <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:2601.14083</identifier>
        <datestamp>2026-02-17</datestamp>
            <setSpec>physics:quant-ph</setSpec>
            <setSpec>physics:cond-mat:dis-nn</setSpec>
    </header>

            <metadata>
                        <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ https://oaipmh.arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
        <id>2601.14083</id>
        <created>2026-01-20</created>
            <updated>2026-02-17</updated>
        <authors>
                <author>
                    <keyname>Longhi</keyname>
                        <forenames>Stefano</forenames>
                </author>
        </authors>
        <title>Quantum Pontus-Mpemba Effect Enabled by the Liouvillian Skin Effect</title>
            <categories>quant-ph cond-mat.dis-nn</categories>
            <comments>14 pages, 6 figures, submitted for the special issue on &#34;Mpemba Effects and Anomalous Nonequilibrium Relaxations in Classical and Quantum Systems&#34;, J. Phys. A</comments>
            <journal-ref>J. Phys. A: Math. Theor. 59, 065304 (2026)</journal-ref>
            <doi>10.1088/1751-8121/ae4079</doi>
            <license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license>
            <abstract>We unveil a quantum Pontus-Mpemba effect enabled by the Liouvillian skin effect in a dissipative tight-binding chain with asymmetric incoherent hopping and coherent boundary coupling. The skin effect, induced by non-reciprocal dissipation, localizes relaxation modes near the system boundaries and gives rise to non-orthogonal spectral geometry. While such non-normality is often linked to slow relaxation, we show that it can instead accelerate relaxation through a two-step protocol - realizing a quantum Pontus-Mpemba effect. Specifically, we consider a one-dimensional open chain with coherent hopping $J$, asymmetric incoherent hoppings $J_{\rm R} \neq J_{\rm L}$, and a controllable end-to-end coupling $ε$. For $ε=0$, the system exhibits the Liouvillian skin effect, with left and right eigenmodes localized at opposite edges. We compare two relaxation protocols toward the same stationary state: (i) a direct relaxation with $ε=0$, and (ii) a two-step (Pontus) protocol where a brief coherent evolution transfers the excitation across the lattice before relaxation. Although both share the same asymptotic decay rate, the two-step protocol relaxes significantly faster due to its reduced overlap with the slow boundary-localized Liouvillian mode. The effect disappears when $J_{\rm R}=J_{\rm L}$, i.e., when the skin effect vanishes. Our results reveal a clear connection between boundary-induced non-normality and protocol-dependent relaxation acceleration, suggesting new routes for controlling dissipation and transient dynamics in open quantum systems.</abstract>
    </arXiv>

            </metadata>
        </record>

    </GetRecord>
</OAI-PMH>