<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<OAI-PMH xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" 
         xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance"
         xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/OAI-PMH.xsd">
    <responseDate>2026-07-13T06:28:20Z</responseDate>
                <request verb="GetRecord" identifier="oai:arXiv.org:2604.24744" metadataPrefix="arXiv">http://oaipmh.arxiv.org/oai</request>


    <GetRecord>
                <record>
                <header>
        <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:2604.24744</identifier>
        <datestamp>2026-04-28</datestamp>
            <setSpec>physics:cond-mat:quant-gas</setSpec>
            <setSpec>physics:cond-mat:str-el</setSpec>
            <setSpec>physics:hep-lat</setSpec>
            <setSpec>physics:physics:atom-ph</setSpec>
            <setSpec>physics:quant-ph</setSpec>
    </header>

            <metadata>
                        <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ https://oaipmh.arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
        <id>2604.24744</id>
        <created>2026-04-27</created>
            <updated>2026-04-28</updated>
        <authors>
                <author>
                    <keyname>Karch</keyname>
                        <forenames>Simon</forenames>
                </author>
                <author>
                    <keyname>Will</keyname>
                        <forenames>Melissa</forenames>
                </author>
                <author>
                    <keyname>Rodriguez</keyname>
                        <forenames>Irene Prieto</forenames>
                </author>
                <author>
                    <keyname>Liebster</keyname>
                        <forenames>Nikolas</forenames>
                </author>
                <author>
                    <keyname>Huh</keyname>
                        <forenames>SeungJung</forenames>
                </author>
                <author>
                    <keyname>Knap</keyname>
                        <forenames>Michael</forenames>
                </author>
                <author>
                    <keyname>Pollmann</keyname>
                        <forenames>Frank</forenames>
                </author>
                <author>
                    <keyname>Kuhlenkamp</keyname>
                        <forenames>Clemens</forenames>
                </author>
                <author>
                    <keyname>Bloch</keyname>
                        <forenames>Immanuel</forenames>
                </author>
                <author>
                    <keyname>Aidelsburger</keyname>
                        <forenames>Monika</forenames>
                </author>
        </authors>
        <title>Dynamical preparation of U(1) quantum spin liquids in an analogue quantum simulator</title>
            <categories>cond-mat.quant-gas cond-mat.str-el hep-lat physics.atom-ph quant-ph</categories>
            <license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license>
            <abstract>Locally constrained gauge theories underpin our understanding of fundamental interactions in particle physics and the emergent behaviour of quantum materials. In strongly correlated systems, they can give rise to quantum spin liquids that lack conventional order and are defined by coherent superpositions of an extensive number of many-body configurations. Realising and probing such exotic states experimentally is an outstanding challenge both in solid-state and synthetic quantum systems, not least due to the difficulty of detecting the fragile coherences between many-body states. Here, we report a large-scale (&gt;3,000 sites) realisation of a two-dimensional U(1) lattice gauge theory with ultracold atoms in a square optical superlattice and demonstrate non-equilibrium preparation of extended regions of U(1) quantum spin liquids. We demonstrate Gauss&#39;s law validity in a quench experiment, enabled by a new microscopy technique for detecting doubly occupied sites. We observe characteristic real-space correlations and momentum-space pinch points, hallmarks of the emergent U(1) gauge structure. Using round-trip interferometric protocols, we directly observe large-scale coherence between many-body configurations, providing strong evidence for quantum spin liquid regions extending over ~100 lattice sites. Our results establish non-equilibrium quantum simulation protocols as a powerful route for accessing and probing exotic, highly-entangled states beyond those hosted by the engineered Hamiltonian in thermal equilibrium.</abstract>
    </arXiv>

            </metadata>
        </record>

    </GetRecord>
</OAI-PMH>