<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<OAI-PMH xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" 
         xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance"
         xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/OAI-PMH.xsd">
    <responseDate>2026-07-13T06:27:18Z</responseDate>
                <request verb="GetRecord" identifier="oai:arXiv.org:2605.24935" metadataPrefix="arXiv">http://oaipmh.arxiv.org/oai</request>


    <GetRecord>
                <record>
                <header>
        <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:2605.24935</identifier>
        <datestamp>2026-05-26</datestamp>
            <setSpec>physics:quant-ph</setSpec>
    </header>

            <metadata>
                        <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ https://oaipmh.arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
        <id>2605.24935</id>
        <created>2026-05-24</created>
            <updated>2026-05-26</updated>
        <authors>
                <author>
                    <keyname>Gao</keyname>
                        <forenames>Ying-Bo</forenames>
                </author>
                <author>
                    <keyname>Dou</keyname>
                        <forenames>Fu-Quan</forenames>
                </author>
        </authors>
        <title>Towards a nuclear isomer quantum battery</title>
            <categories>quant-ph</categories>
            <comments>8+5 pages, 4+3 figures</comments>
            <license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license>
            <abstract>Quantum batteries (QBs) -- quantum devices governed by the principles of quantum mechanics -- hold great promise for next-generation energy storage. However, most existing research efforts focus on atomic or molecular systems featuring low-energy and short-lived energy levels, leaving the exploitation of high-energy, ultra-stable nuclear energy levels for energy storage as a critical unaddressed challenge. Here, we propose an innovative design of referred to as nuclear isomer quantum batteries (NIQBs), whose energy storage unit is typically composed of two-level and three-level nuclei incorporating nuclear isomers. The charging dynamics is driven by the interaction between the nuclear system and x-ray free electron laser (XFEL). Compared to QBs based on atomic systems, NIQBs deliver substantial performance enhancements, with stored energy and average charging power enhanced by factors of $10^{1}$--$10^{6}$ and $10^{6}$--$10^{11}$, respectively, and a markedly extended lifetime range spanning from microseconds to $10^5$ years. Notably, the vast majority of NIQBs enable complete energy extraction as their excited-state lifetimes exceed the laser-nuclear interaction time, rendering spontaneous emission negligible. The proposed NIQBs framework is compatible with diverse nuclear systems, enabling tailored nucleus selection for varied operating conditions. Our results provide a feasible pathway toward realizing high-performance QBs with superior energy-storage efficiency.</abstract>
    </arXiv>

            </metadata>
        </record>

    </GetRecord>
</OAI-PMH>