<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<OAI-PMH xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" 
         xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance"
         xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/OAI-PMH.xsd">
    <responseDate>2026-07-11T09:45:43Z</responseDate>
                <request verb="GetRecord" identifier="oai:arXiv.org:2606.06577v1" metadataPrefix="arXiv">http://oaipmh.arxiv.org/oai</request>


    <GetRecord>
                <record>
                <header>
        <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:2606.06577</identifier>
        <datestamp>2026-06-08</datestamp>
            <setSpec>physics:astro-ph:SR</setSpec>
            <setSpec>physics:physics:space-ph</setSpec>
    </header>

            <metadata>
                        <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ https://oaipmh.arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
        <id>2606.06577</id>
        <created>2026-06-04</created>
            <updated>2026-06-08</updated>
        <authors>
                <author>
                    <keyname>To</keyname>
                        <forenames>Andy S. H.</forenames>
                </author>
                <author>
                    <keyname>Russell</keyname>
                        <forenames>Alexander J. B.</forenames>
                </author>
        </authors>
        <title>Nonthermal line broadening at solar flare footpoints is primarily field-aligned</title>
            <categories>astro-ph.SR physics.space-ph</categories>
            <comments>22 pages, 5 figures, 3 tables, submitted for review</comments>
            <license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license>
            <abstract>Magnetic reconnection powers solar and stellar flares, but a full understanding of how the released energy is transported and converted within the solar atmosphere remains elusive. One clue lies at solar-flare footpoints, where spectral lines are far broader than the electron temperature alone can explain. Unresolved flows, waves, turbulence and ion heating have all been proposed, but observations have not yet conclusively distinguished between these mechanisms. Here we perform an unprecedented geometric test for flare footpoints, using 4,593 Hinode/EIS spectra from 407 C- to M-class flares. Line widths decrease systematically from disk centre to limb in all coronal emission lines, showing that the dominant broadening component is magnetic field aligned rather than isotropic or transverse. Cooler lines retain substantial broadening into the early decay phase, consistent with persistent unresolved field-aligned flows or line-of-sight velocity gradients. Hotter lines show an impulsive component that decays rapidly after the soft X-ray peak, consistent with preferential ion heating and ion temperature anisotropy. These findings resolve the long-standing question of the nature of line broadening at flare footpoints, place direct limits on flare energetics, and motivate a new direction in flare physics incorporating distinct field-aligned and perpendicular ion temperatures that exceed the electron temperature.</abstract>
    </arXiv>

            </metadata>
        </record>

    </GetRecord>
</OAI-PMH>