<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<OAI-PMH xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" 
         xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance"
         xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/OAI-PMH.xsd">
    <responseDate>2026-07-13T06:25:10Z</responseDate>
                <request verb="GetRecord" identifier="oai:arXiv.org:2607.08120" metadataPrefix="arXiv">http://oaipmh.arxiv.org/oai</request>


    <GetRecord>
                <record>
                <header>
        <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:2607.08120</identifier>
        <datestamp>2026-07-10</datestamp>
            <setSpec>physics:astro-ph:CO</setSpec>
            <setSpec>physics:gr-qc</setSpec>
            <setSpec>physics:hep-th</setSpec>
    </header>

            <metadata>
                        <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ https://oaipmh.arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
        <id>2607.08120</id>
        <created>2026-07-09</created>
            <updated>2026-07-10</updated>
        <authors>
                <author>
                    <keyname>Liu</keyname>
                        <forenames>Jinglong</forenames>
                </author>
                <author>
                    <keyname>Manton</keyname>
                        <forenames>Tucker</forenames>
                </author>
                <author>
                    <keyname>Cai</keyname>
                        <forenames>Yifu</forenames>
                </author>
                <author>
                    <keyname>Marciano</keyname>
                        <forenames>Antonino</forenames>
                </author>
        </authors>
        <title>Phantom crossing from the Standard Model and General Relativity</title>
            <categories>astro-ph.CO gr-qc hep-th</categories>
            <comments>6 pages, 3 figures</comments>
            <license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license>
            <abstract>Suggestions of a late-time phantom crossing from DESI baryon acoustic oscillation measurements, combined with cosmic microwave background and Type-Ia supernova observations, have renewed interest in non-standard dark energy models. In this Letter, we propose a new realization of a low redshift phantom crossing using only well understood ingredients from fermion condensation and general relativity. Our construction relies on the interplay between effective quintom-like dark energy and backreaction from non-linear structure formation. The full cosmological evolution is consistent with $Λ$CDM until low redshift, where the backreaction starts to become prominent and a phase transition occurs. At this point, the total dark energy equation of state first crosses $w_{\text{DE}}=-1$ from above. For benchmark values of the backreaction energy density, a second crossing from below occurs at a lower redshift, as suggested by recent observation. Fitting our theoretical model with CPL parametrization, we find the result is consistent with the combined DESI+CMB+SNIa data analysis with DESY5, PantheonPlus, and Union3 datasets. Specifically, for backreaction density parameter $Ω_{\rm BR}(z=0) = 0.0572$, the CPL parametrization gives the phantom crossing redshift $z_* \simeq 0.35$, $w_0 \simeq -0.76 $ and $w_a \simeq -0.93$.</abstract>
    </arXiv>

            </metadata>
        </record>

    </GetRecord>
</OAI-PMH>