<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<OAI-PMH xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" 
         xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance"
         xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/OAI-PMH.xsd">
    <responseDate>2026-07-08T01:44:12Z</responseDate>
                <request verb="GetRecord" identifier="oai:arXiv.org:2607.01479v1" metadataPrefix="arXiv">http://oaipmh.arxiv.org/oai</request>


    <GetRecord>
                <record>
                <header>
        <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:2607.01479</identifier>
        <datestamp>2026-07-03</datestamp>
            <setSpec>physics:astro-ph:GA</setSpec>
            <setSpec>physics:astro-ph:HE</setSpec>
            <setSpec>physics:astro-ph:IM</setSpec>
    </header>

            <metadata>
                        <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ https://oaipmh.arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
        <id>2607.01479</id>
        <created>2026-07-01</created>
            <updated>2026-07-03</updated>
        <authors>
                <author>
                    <keyname>Naddaf</keyname>
                        <forenames>Mohammad Hassan</forenames>
                </author>
        </authors>
        <title>Radiative filtering unifies broad-line phenomenology in active galactic nuclei</title>
            <categories>astro-ph.GA astro-ph.HE astro-ph.IM</categories>
            <comments>12 pages, 5 figures, as Letter to Astrophysical Journal</comments>
            <license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license>
            <abstract>Broad emission lines (BELs) are a defining feature of active galactic nuclei (AGNs), yet they weaken or disappear in both very low- and very high-accretion systems. These regimes are typically treated separately, and a unified physical explanation has remained elusive. Here we show that this behavior arises if line formation is governed not by the intrinsic luminosity of the central engine, but by the ionizing radiation field that survives filtering before reaching the broad-line region (BLR). In this picture, line production depends on the product of intrinsic ionizing capability and an effective transmission. Because the former increases from low accretion rates while the latter declines at high accretion rates, the effective ionizing field naturally develops a finite and non-universal window for BEL formation. This framework unifies the absence or extreme faintness of BELs in low-luminosity AGNs, LINERs, and weak-line quasars (WLQs), and accounts for the Baldwin effect and the $R_{\rm Fe}$ trend. It also necessarily implies the breakdown of standard BLR-based scaling relations in extreme accretion regimes. We show that a minimal quantitative realization reproduces this behavior across black-hole mass, accretion rate, and radiative efficiency. These results suggest that AGN emission-line phenomenology is governed by global regulation of the ionizing radiation field rather than by mere presence or condition of local gas.</abstract>
    </arXiv>

            </metadata>
        </record>

    </GetRecord>
</OAI-PMH>