<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<OAI-PMH xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" 
         xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance"
         xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/OAI-PMH.xsd">
    <responseDate>2026-07-13T06:28:03Z</responseDate>
                <request verb="GetRecord" identifier="oai:arXiv.org:2512.14834" metadataPrefix="arXiv">http://oaipmh.arxiv.org/oai</request>


    <GetRecord>
                <record>
                <header>
        <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:2512.14834</identifier>
        <datestamp>2025-12-18</datestamp>
            <setSpec>physics:quant-ph</setSpec>
    </header>

            <metadata>
                        <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ https://oaipmh.arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
        <id>2512.14834</id>
        <created>2025-12-16</created>
            <updated>2025-12-18</updated>
        <authors>
                <author>
                    <keyname>Schlegel</keyname>
                        <forenames>Samuel</forenames>
                </author>
                <author>
                    <keyname>Dakić</keyname>
                        <forenames>Borivoje</forenames>
                </author>
                <author>
                    <keyname>Del Santo</keyname>
                        <forenames>Flavio</forenames>
                </author>
        </authors>
        <title>Entanglement without Quantum Mechanics: Operational Constraints on the Quantum Signature</title>
            <categories>quant-ph</categories>
            <license>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0/</license>
            <abstract>Entanglement is often regarded as an inherently quantum feature. We show that this does not have to be the case: under restricted operational access, classical correlations can appear nonseparable when expressed in the formalism of quantum mechanics. If an observer is limited to a constrained set of measurements and transformations, certain classical phase-space distributions can mimic entanglement-like behaviours. Imposing positivity of the associated Hilbert space operator as a physicality requirement removes some of these representational artifacts, revealing a regime in which nonseparability is genuine but still reproducible by classical models. Only when the operational restrictions on the observer are lifted further--allowing operational tests of measurement incompatibility or other nonclassical signatures--does one obtain entanglement that can no longer be captured by any classical description. This operational hierarchy distinguishes classical artifacts, classically reproducible nonseparability, and genuine entanglement.</abstract>
    </arXiv>

            </metadata>
        </record>

    </GetRecord>
</OAI-PMH>