<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<OAI-PMH xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" 
         xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance"
         xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/OAI-PMH.xsd">
    <responseDate>2026-07-13T21:13:48Z</responseDate>
                <request verb="GetRecord" identifier="oai:arXiv.org:2510.22176" metadataPrefix="arXiv">http://oaipmh.arxiv.org/oai</request>


    <GetRecord>
                <record>
                <header>
        <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:2510.22176</identifier>
        <datestamp>2026-03-03</datestamp>
            <setSpec>physics:physics:optics</setSpec>
            <setSpec>physics:physics:comp-ph</setSpec>
    </header>

            <metadata>
                        <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ https://oaipmh.arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
        <id>2510.22176</id>
        <created>2026-02-28</created>
            <updated>2026-03-03</updated>
        <authors>
                <author>
                    <keyname>Park</keyname>
                        <forenames>Junho</forenames>
                </author>
                <author>
                    <keyname>Kim</keyname>
                        <forenames>Taehan</forenames>
                </author>
                <author>
                    <keyname>Ali</keyname>
                        <forenames>Mohammad</forenames>
                </author>
                <author>
                    <keyname>Liang</keyname>
                        <forenames>Di</forenames>
                </author>
        </authors>
        <title>Interpretable Geometry Sensitivity for Inverse Design of Integrated Photonics</title>
            <categories>physics.optics physics.comp-ph</categories>
            <license>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0/</license>
            <abstract>As an increasingly powerful technique in integrated photonics, inverse design uses optimization algorithms to automatically create compact, high-performance photonic structures, often yielding non-intuitive layouts far more compact than conventional designs. While adjoint-based inverse design is a prominent optimization method, the resulting free-form layouts are difficult to interpret or diagnose under fabrication variability, even for experienced photonic device designers. We present an experimentally validated interpretability workflow that produces pixel-level sensitivity maps directly on the binary mask of an inverse-designed device. Using wavelength-division demultiplexers (WDMs) at 1310/1550 nm as examples, we train a lightweight convolutional surrogate to regress figures of merit (FoMs) and apply Integrated Gradients (IG) to attribute predicted transmission to individual pixels. We demonstrate that high-attribution hotspots correspond to physically meaningful substructures, such as splitter hubs and high-curvature edges. Experimental results show that controlled perturbations in these high-sensitivity regions result in up to an 11x higher excess insertion loss compared to perturbations in non-sensitive regions, consistent with full-wave simulations. This approach adds a practical explainability layer to existing pipelines, offering a clear pathway for foundry-compatible design-rule checking and fabrication-aware constraint allocation without modifying the underlying electromagnetic solver.</abstract>
    </arXiv>

            </metadata>
        </record>

    </GetRecord>
</OAI-PMH>