<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<OAI-PMH xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" 
         xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance"
         xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/OAI-PMH.xsd">
    <responseDate>2026-07-13T06:22:18Z</responseDate>
                <request verb="GetRecord" identifier="oai:arXiv.org:2605.08307" metadataPrefix="arXiv">http://oaipmh.arxiv.org/oai</request>


    <GetRecord>
                <record>
                <header>
        <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:2605.08307</identifier>
        <datestamp>2026-07-07</datestamp>
            <setSpec>physics:physics:bio-ph</setSpec>
            <setSpec>physics:quant-ph</setSpec>
    </header>

            <metadata>
                        <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ https://oaipmh.arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
        <id>2605.08307</id>
        <created>2026-07-05</created>
            <updated>2026-07-07</updated>
        <authors>
                <author>
                    <keyname>Raghuvanshi</keyname>
                        <forenames>Parul</forenames>
                </author>
                <author>
                    <keyname>Poonia</keyname>
                        <forenames>Vishvendra Singh</forenames>
                </author>
        </authors>
        <title>Chiral-Induced Spin Selectivity Regulates Triplet formation in Heliobacterial Photosynthesis</title>
            <categories>physics.bio-ph quant-ph</categories>
            <license>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0/</license>
            <abstract>Triplet formation and its regulation have always been of central interest in understanding the photophysical behavior of living systems. In organic systems, excessive triplet formation poses significant challenges, as it can promote photochemical damage and reduce the efficiency of charge separation processes, making its regulation critically important.Here, we present a theoretical investigation of the intrinsic quantum spin dynamics governing triplet formation in the heliobacterial reaction center, a system that operates without any internal magnetic field. Using an open quantum systems approach based on the Lindblad formalism, we simulate the spin-correlated radical pair dynamics occurring during charge separation in the heliobacterial reaction center. The study systematically examines how triplet formation is regulated by variations in two key parameters, hyperfine coupling strengths and recombination rates, and how this regulation is further influenced by the inclusion of chirality-induced spin selectivity (CISS) in conjunction with the radical pair mechanism (RPM). Our results demonstrate that the CISS effect significantly suppresses triplet formation across the parameter space relevant to the heliobacterial molecular environment, revealing an intrinsic quantum protective mechanism operating through spin control in heliobacterial photosynthesis.</abstract>
    </arXiv>

            </metadata>
        </record>

    </GetRecord>
</OAI-PMH>