<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<OAI-PMH xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" 
         xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance"
         xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/OAI-PMH.xsd">
    <responseDate>2026-07-13T21:13:34Z</responseDate>
                <request verb="GetRecord" identifier="oai:arXiv.org:2605.22783" metadataPrefix="arXiv">http://oaipmh.arxiv.org/oai</request>


    <GetRecord>
                <record>
                <header>
        <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:2605.22783</identifier>
        <datestamp>2026-05-22</datestamp>
            <setSpec>physics:cond-mat:mtrl-sci</setSpec>
    </header>

            <metadata>
                        <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ https://oaipmh.arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
        <id>2605.22783</id>
        <created>2026-05-21</created>
            <updated>2026-05-22</updated>
        <authors>
                <author>
                    <keyname>Candia</keyname>
                        <forenames>Adriana E.</forenames>
                </author>
                <author>
                    <keyname>Peláez-Sifonte</keyname>
                        <forenames>Eliecer</forenames>
                </author>
                <author>
                    <keyname>Thakur</keyname>
                        <forenames>Amitayush Jha</forenames>
                </author>
                <author>
                    <keyname>Hadjadj</keyname>
                        <forenames>Sebastien E.</forenames>
                </author>
                <author>
                    <keyname>Kerschbaumer</keyname>
                        <forenames>Samuel</forenames>
                </author>
                <author>
                    <keyname>Saunot</keyname>
                        <forenames>Aymeric</forenames>
                </author>
                <author>
                    <keyname>Corso</keyname>
                        <forenames>Martina</forenames>
                </author>
                <author>
                    <keyname>Ilyn</keyname>
                        <forenames>Maxim</forenames>
                </author>
                <author>
                    <keyname>Lobo-Checa</keyname>
                        <forenames>Jorge</forenames>
                </author>
                <author>
                    <keyname>Rogero</keyname>
                        <forenames>Celia</forenames>
                </author>
                <author>
                    <keyname>Serrate</keyname>
                        <forenames>David</forenames>
                </author>
        </authors>
        <title>Atomic scale demonstration of ferromagnetism in a single layer FeCl2 on Au(111)</title>
            <categories>cond-mat.mtrl-sci</categories>
            <license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license>
            <abstract>FeCl2 is a promising single-layer material with sizeable magnetic susceptibility and insulating character that can be easily grown by molecular beam epitaxy on various surfaces. In order to include it into the select palette of van der Waals materials used to engineer functional heterostructures, it is necessary to confirm its magnetic and electronic ground states, and understand the influence of the supporting substrate. In this work, we unambiguously demonstrate ferromagnetic ordering in a single-layer FeCl2 on Au(111) by means of spin-polarized scanning tunnelling microscopy. The material features a relatively wide insulating gap of 3.3 eV and a strongly spin-polarized conduction band that emerges at 1.5 eV above the Fermi level. Atomic scale defects with triangular shape play a primary role in the electronic gap and spin density distribution. Specifically, in a region of 1.6 nm around each defect, the conduction band is locally suppressed and the tunnelling magneto-conductance is reduced a factor of four. By tracking the spin-dependent tunnelling conductance as a function of the applied magnetic field, we record atomically resolved hysteresis loops, revealing a soft ferromagnetic ground state with pronounced out-of-plane anisotropy and coercive fields in the range of 15-50 mT.</abstract>
    </arXiv>

            </metadata>
        </record>

    </GetRecord>
</OAI-PMH>