<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<OAI-PMH xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" 
         xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance"
         xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/OAI-PMH.xsd">
    <responseDate>2026-07-13T06:21:55Z</responseDate>
                <request verb="GetRecord" identifier="oai:arXiv.org:2603.08916" metadataPrefix="arXiv">http://oaipmh.arxiv.org/oai</request>


    <GetRecord>
                <record>
                <header>
        <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:2603.08916</identifier>
        <datestamp>2026-06-05</datestamp>
            <setSpec>physics:quant-ph</setSpec>
    </header>

            <metadata>
                        <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ https://oaipmh.arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
        <id>2603.08916</id>
        <created>2026-06-04</created>
            <updated>2026-06-05</updated>
        <authors>
                <author>
                    <keyname>Bhattacharyya</keyname>
                        <forenames>Archishna</forenames>
                </author>
                <author>
                    <keyname>Broadbent</keyname>
                        <forenames>Anne</forenames>
                </author>
                <author>
                    <keyname>Culf</keyname>
                        <forenames>Eric</forenames>
                </author>
        </authors>
        <title>The uncloneable bit exists</title>
            <categories>quant-ph</categories>
            <comments>27 pages, 2 figures, v1 contained a flaw that has been mended by a significantly updated analysis in v2</comments>
            <license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license>
            <abstract>We establish quantum uncloneable encryption with unconditional security, preventing two non-communicating adversaries from simultaneously decrypting a single ciphertext $-$ even when both are given the key. Our construction achieves security that approaches the ideal limit at a rate that is exponentially small in the security parameter, without employing any assumptions. Our proof invokes unitary invariance of the shared entangled state and simplifies the adversarial strategies by enforcing this symmetry. Crucially, it then rules out the sender being highly correlated with two non-communicating adversaries at once by an approximation property that we develop, for such unitarily invariant states, which yields a near-optimal bound on the probability of cloning. Consequently, no coordinated strategy beats random guessing of the encrypted bit, establishing unconditional uncloneability. This reveals the existence of an uncloneable bit in Nature and delineates a fundamental, physically enforced cryptographic primitive unavailable in classical settings.</abstract>
    </arXiv>

            </metadata>
        </record>

    </GetRecord>
</OAI-PMH>