<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<OAI-PMH xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" 
         xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance"
         xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/OAI-PMH.xsd">
    <responseDate>2026-07-11T07:16:01Z</responseDate>
                <request verb="GetRecord" identifier="oai:arXiv.org:2606.02778v3" metadataPrefix="arXiv">http://oaipmh.arxiv.org/oai</request>


    <GetRecord>
                <record>
                <header>
        <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:2606.02778</identifier>
        <datestamp>2026-06-12</datestamp>
            <setSpec>physics:astro-ph:EP</setSpec>
            <setSpec>physics:astro-ph:IM</setSpec>
            <setSpec>cs:cs:LG</setSpec>
    </header>

            <metadata>
                        <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ https://oaipmh.arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
        <id>2606.02778</id>
        <created>2026-06-10</created>
            <updated>2026-06-12</updated>
        <authors>
                <author>
                    <keyname>Priyanshu</keyname>
                        <forenames>Pratik</forenames>
                </author>
        </authors>
        <title>One Transit Is All You Need: Detecting Exoplanets Through Learned Stellar Behaviour with EXOVEIL</title>
            <categories>astro-ph.EP astro-ph.IM cs.LG</categories>
            <comments>v3: appendix gallery of confirmed-planet recoveries added; Section 6 candidate catalogue reframed as transit-like anomalies for follow-up; TLS comparison table expanded</comments>
            <acm-class>None</acm-class>
            <license>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0/</license>
            <abstract>I present EXOVEIL, a transit detection system that learns what a star&#39;s brightness should look like and flags when reality disagrees. Unlike existing systems that require phase-folded input, EXOVEIL operates on raw flux time series and can detect planets that transit only once.A Transformer world model, trained on 16,499 Kepler light curves with transit-masked self-supervised learning, predicts expected stellar flux. A matched-filter detector with variance weighting extracts transit signals from the prediction residuals. A learned classifier (XGBoost) separates planets from false positives, achieving AUC 0.938 on Kepler DR25. Applied to single-transit injection-recovery, EXOVEIL recovers 32% of transits at 1000 ppm depth a task where all classification-based systems score 0% by construction. A blind search of 3,737 Kepler stars yields 179 new transit-like signals not present in the DR25 TCE catalogue, including 46 monotransit candidates. Applied withoutretraining to 47 confirmed TESS planets in the PLATO LOPS2 field, EXOVEIL achieves 100% recovery, demonstrating zero-shot cross-mission transfer. At PLATO&#39;s 25-second cadence, detection reaches 100 ppm -- approaching the Earth-analog regime. I provide the first application of conformal prediction to transit detection (95.9% empirical coverage) and release the system as pip install exoveil with pretrained weights and a candidate catalogue.</abstract>
    </arXiv>

            </metadata>
        </record>

    </GetRecord>
</OAI-PMH>