<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<OAI-PMH xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" 
         xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance"
         xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/OAI-PMH.xsd">
    <responseDate>2026-07-13T06:21:32Z</responseDate>
                <request verb="GetRecord" identifier="oai:arXiv.org:2511.02678" metadataPrefix="arXiv">http://oaipmh.arxiv.org/oai</request>


    <GetRecord>
                <record>
                <header>
        <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:2511.02678</identifier>
        <datestamp>2025-11-05</datestamp>
            <setSpec>physics:cond-mat:mtrl-sci</setSpec>
            <setSpec>physics:quant-ph</setSpec>
    </header>

            <metadata>
                        <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ https://oaipmh.arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
        <id>2511.02678</id>
        <created>2025-11-04</created>
            <updated>2025-11-05</updated>
        <authors>
                <author>
                    <keyname>Ghosh</keyname>
                        <forenames>Arnab</forenames>
                </author>
                <author>
                    <keyname>Brosseau</keyname>
                        <forenames>Patrick</forenames>
                </author>
                <author>
                    <keyname>Dirin</keyname>
                        <forenames>Dmitry N.</forenames>
                </author>
                <author>
                    <keyname>Kovalenko</keyname>
                        <forenames>Maksym V.</forenames>
                </author>
                <author>
                    <keyname>Kambhampati</keyname>
                        <forenames>Patanjali</forenames>
                </author>
        </authors>
        <title>Time-Reversed Superfluorescence in a Polaronic Quantum Material</title>
            <categories>cond-mat.mtrl-sci quant-ph</categories>
            <license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license>
            <abstract>Superfluorescence, the cooperative burst of spontaneous emission from an ensemble of dipoles, arises when microscopic oscillators spontaneously synchronize their phases. Here we show that this process can be reversed in time within quantum materials. Coherent multidimensional spectroscopy of halide perovskite quantum dots reveals a delayed cooperative absorption burst, the mirror image of superfluorescent emission, driven by transient polaron fields that phase-lock unit-cell dipoles within 100 fs. The effect scales systematically with quantum-dot size and halide composition, reaching near-unity coherence fidelity even at 300 K. A microscopic exciton-polaron model reproduces the buildup and decay of the coherent state, identifying lattice polarons as the mediators of synchronization. These results demonstrate that many-body temporal coherence can self-organize and persist at room temperature, opening routes toward engineered collective optical states and superabsorbing quantum devices.</abstract>
    </arXiv>

            </metadata>
        </record>

    </GetRecord>
</OAI-PMH>