<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<OAI-PMH xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" 
         xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance"
         xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/OAI-PMH.xsd">
    <responseDate>2026-07-11T21:17:05Z</responseDate>
                <request verb="GetRecord" identifier="oai:arXiv.org:2601.03539v1" metadataPrefix="arXiv">http://oaipmh.arxiv.org/oai</request>


    <GetRecord>
                <record>
                <header>
        <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:2601.03539</identifier>
        <datestamp>2026-01-08</datestamp>
            <setSpec>physics:astro-ph:SR</setSpec>
            <setSpec>physics:astro-ph:EP</setSpec>
    </header>

            <metadata>
                        <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ https://oaipmh.arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
        <id>2601.03539</id>
        <created>2026-01-07</created>
            <updated>2026-01-08</updated>
        <authors>
                <author>
                    <keyname>Wallace</keyname>
                        <forenames>A. L.</forenames>
                </author>
                <author>
                    <keyname>Casey</keyname>
                        <forenames>A. R.</forenames>
                </author>
        </authors>
        <title>Perhaps there is no brown dwarf desert? A study of sub-stellar companions with Gaia DR3</title>
            <categories>astro-ph.SR astro-ph.EP</categories>
            <comments>11 pages, 14 figures, accepted for publication by PASA</comments>
            <license>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0/</license>
            <abstract>The brown dwarf desert describes a range of orbital periods (&lt;5 years) in which fewer brown dwarf-mass companions have been observed around Sun-like stars, when compared to planets and low mass stellar companions. It is therefore theorised that brown dwarf companions are unlikely to form or remain in this period range. The Gaia space telescope is uniquely sensitive to companions in this period range, making it an ideal tool to conduct a survey of the brown dwarf desert. In this study, we use Bayesian inference to analyse data from nearby (&lt;200pc) Sun-like stars in Gaia&#39;s DR3 catalogue, assuming single companions. From this, we identify 2673 systems (2.41% of the sample) with possible brown dwarf companions in this period range. Accounting for observational biases, we find that 10.4+0.8-0.6% of nearby Sun-like stars have astrometric errors consistent with a brown dwarf-mass companion with a period less than 5 years, significantly higher than previous studies which reported occurrence rates of &lt;1%. However, we acknowledge the limitations of DR3 and are unable to make a definitive statement without epoch data. By simulating epoch data with multiple companions, we find that, while some of the data can be explained by multiple low-mass brown dwarf companions and high-mass planets (&gt;10MJ), high-mass brown dwarfs (&gt;50MJ) in this period range are comparatively rare. Finally, we used our studies of the brown dwarf distribution to predict the number of companions in the brown dwarf desert we can expect to discover in DR4.</abstract>
    </arXiv>

            </metadata>
        </record>

    </GetRecord>
</OAI-PMH>