<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<OAI-PMH xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" 
         xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance"
         xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/OAI-PMH.xsd">
    <responseDate>2026-07-11T07:52:25Z</responseDate>
                <request verb="GetRecord" identifier="oai:arXiv.org:2606.01699v1" metadataPrefix="arXiv">http://oaipmh.arxiv.org/oai</request>


    <GetRecord>
                <record>
                <header>
        <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:2606.01699</identifier>
        <datestamp>2026-06-02</datestamp>
            <setSpec>physics:gr-qc</setSpec>
            <setSpec>physics:astro-ph:HE</setSpec>
            <setSpec>physics:hep-th</setSpec>
    </header>

            <metadata>
                        <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ https://oaipmh.arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
        <id>2606.01699</id>
        <created>2026-06-01</created>
            <updated>2026-06-02</updated>
        <authors>
                <author>
                    <keyname>Takahashi</keyname>
                        <forenames>Mikiya M.</forenames>
                </author>
                <author>
                    <keyname>Nakashi</keyname>
                        <forenames>Keisuke</forenames>
                </author>
        </authors>
        <title>Ellis-Bronnikov Wormhole Shadows with Spherically Symmetric Accretion Flow</title>
            <categories>gr-qc astro-ph.HE hep-th</categories>
            <comments>28 pages, 8 figures</comments>
            <license>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0/</license>
            <abstract>We investigate the observational differences between the Ellis--Bronnikov (EB) wormhole and the Schwarzschild black hole (BH) by performing general relativistic radiative transfer (GRRT) simulations. We consider a spherically symmetric steady-state accretion flow and perform GRRT simulations incorporating synchrotron emission. For both the EB wormhole and the Schwarzschild BH, the simulated images consist of a central shadow region and a bright photon ring. We find that both the shadow region and the photon ring of the EB wormhole are brighter than those of the Schwarzschild BH. These differences arise from the absence of an event horizon in the EB wormhole, allowing the emission from the accreting matter around and beyond the throat to contribute to the observed intensity. We also compare the simulated images with the Event Horizon Telescope (EHT) observations of M87* and find that both the EB wormhole and the Schwarzschild BH are in reasonable agreement with the current EHT results.</abstract>
    </arXiv>

            </metadata>
        </record>

    </GetRecord>
</OAI-PMH>