<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<OAI-PMH xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" 
         xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance"
         xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/OAI-PMH.xsd">
    <responseDate>2026-07-13T00:29:14Z</responseDate>
                <request verb="GetRecord" identifier="oai:arXiv.org:2605.05375v1" metadataPrefix="arXiv">http://oaipmh.arxiv.org/oai</request>


    <GetRecord>
                <record>
                <header>
        <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:2605.05375</identifier>
        <datestamp>2026-05-08</datestamp>
            <setSpec>physics:hep-th</setSpec>
            <setSpec>physics:gr-qc</setSpec>
    </header>

            <metadata>
                        <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ https://oaipmh.arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
        <id>2605.05375</id>
        <created>2026-05-06</created>
            <updated>2026-05-08</updated>
        <authors>
                <author>
                    <keyname>Oppenheim</keyname>
                        <forenames>Jonathan</forenames>
                </author>
                <author>
                    <keyname>Sajjad</keyname>
                        <forenames>Muhammad</forenames>
                </author>
        </authors>
        <title>Stochastic modes in postquantum classical gravity</title>
            <categories>hep-th gr-qc</categories>
            <license>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-sa/4.0/</license>
            <abstract>We study fluctuations of the metric in the postquantum theory of classical gravity, a covariant theory which couples a classical spacetime with quantum matter fields. Mathematical consistency requires spacetime to evolve stochastically. Starting from the classical-quantum path integral, we linearize around Minkowski space and perform a scalar-vector-tensor decomposition, identifying the stochastic modes: a classical spin-2 field and spin-0 scalar, both diffusing around their respective wave equations. There is also a non-dynamical vector and scalar field. These are related to the degrees of freedom found in quadratic gravity, but here interpreted as stochastic contributions to spacetime. We show that the action is positive semi-definite (PSD) on all dynamical modes, which is a necessary condition for the theory to consistently treat spacetime classically. We compute the two-point function and power spectral density corresponding to fluctuations of the Newtonian potential, and compare it to the excess noise found in LISA Pathfinder. This sets a bound on one combination of the two dimensionless coupling constants of the theory, while bounds on the stochastic gravitational wave energy density in a FLRW background constrain another combination. We derive the effective action for matter distributions, and find that bounds from decoherence experiments are constrained by fluctuations in the Newtonian potential $Φ$ and the curvature perturbation $ψ$. Finally, we show consistency between different formulations of the pure gravity theory, the Onsager-Machlup form of the action, the Martin-Siggia-Rose form, and that given by stochastic differential equations.</abstract>
    </arXiv>

            </metadata>
        </record>

    </GetRecord>
</OAI-PMH>