<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<OAI-PMH xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" 
         xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance"
         xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/OAI-PMH.xsd">
    <responseDate>2026-07-13T06:21:04Z</responseDate>
                <request verb="GetRecord" identifier="oai:arXiv.org:2508.18348" metadataPrefix="arXiv">http://oaipmh.arxiv.org/oai</request>


    <GetRecord>
                <record>
                <header>
        <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:2508.18348</identifier>
        <datestamp>2025-08-27</datestamp>
            <setSpec>physics:astro-ph:SR</setSpec>
            <setSpec>physics:astro-ph:EP</setSpec>
    </header>

            <metadata>
                        <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ https://oaipmh.arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
        <id>2508.18348</id>
        <created>2025-08-25</created>
            <updated>2025-08-27</updated>
        <authors>
                <author>
                    <keyname>Guidry</keyname>
                        <forenames>Joseph A.</forenames>
                </author>
                <author>
                    <keyname>Vanderbosch</keyname>
                        <forenames>Zachary P.</forenames>
                </author>
                <author>
                    <keyname>Hermes</keyname>
                        <forenames>J. J.</forenames>
                </author>
                <author>
                    <keyname>Veras</keyname>
                        <forenames>Dimitri</forenames>
                </author>
                <author>
                    <keyname>Hollands</keyname>
                        <forenames>Mark A.</forenames>
                </author>
                <author>
                    <keyname>Bhattacharjee</keyname>
                        <forenames>Soumyadeep</forenames>
                </author>
                <author>
                    <keyname>Caiazzo</keyname>
                        <forenames>Ilaria</forenames>
                </author>
                <author>
                    <keyname>El-Badry</keyname>
                        <forenames>Kareem</forenames>
                </author>
                <author>
                    <keyname>Kao</keyname>
                        <forenames>Malia L.</forenames>
                </author>
                <author>
                    <keyname>Rouis</keyname>
                        <forenames>Lou Baya Ould</forenames>
                </author>
                <author>
                    <keyname>Rodriguez</keyname>
                        <forenames>Antonio C.</forenames>
                </author>
                <author>
                    <keyname>van Roestel</keyname>
                        <forenames>Jan</forenames>
                </author>
        </authors>
        <title>Transiting Planetary Debris near the Roche Limit of a White Dwarf on a 4.97$\,$hr Orbit -- and its Vanishing</title>
            <categories>astro-ph.SR astro-ph.EP</categories>
            <comments>The first two authors listed are both lead authors. 23 pages, 9 figures, accepted for publication in The Astrophysical Journal. For a Zenodo library housing all the follow-up time-series photometry we collected and analyzed, see https://doi.org/10.5281/zenodo.16942613</comments>
            <license>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0/</license>
            <abstract>We present the discovery of deep, irregular, periodic transits towards the white dwarf ZTF$\,$J1944$+$4557 using follow-up time-series photometry and spectroscopy from Palomar, Keck, McDonald, Perkins, and Lowell observatories. We find a predominant period of 4.9704$\,$hr, consistent with an orbit near the Roche limit of the white dwarf, with individual dips over 30$\%$ deep and lasting between 15 and 40 minutes. Similar to the first known white dwarf with transiting debris, WD$\,$1145$+$017, the transit events are well-defined with prominent out-of-transit phases where the white dwarf appears unobscured. Spectroscopy concurrent with transit photometry reveals the average Ca$\,$K equivalent width remains constant in and out of transit. The broadening observed in several absorption features cannot be reproduced by synthetic photospheric models, suggesting the presence of circumstellar gas. Simultaneous $g+r$- and $g+i$-band light curves from the CHIMERA instrument reveal no color dependence to the transit depths, requiring transiting dust grains to have sizes $s \gtrsim0.2\,μ$m. The transit morphologies appear to be constantly changing at a rate faster than the orbital period. Overall transit activity varies in the system, with transit features completely disappearing during the seven months between our 2023 and 2024 observing seasons and then reappearing in 2025$~$March, still repeating at 4.9704$\,$hr. Our observations of the complete cessation and resumption of transit activity provide a novel laboratory for constraining the evolution of disrupted debris and processes like disk exhaustion and replenishment timescales at white dwarfs.</abstract>
    </arXiv>

            </metadata>
        </record>

    </GetRecord>
</OAI-PMH>