<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<OAI-PMH xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" 
         xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance"
         xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/OAI-PMH.xsd">
    <responseDate>2026-07-13T06:21:38Z</responseDate>
                <request verb="GetRecord" identifier="oai:arXiv.org:2511.08624" metadataPrefix="arXiv">http://oaipmh.arxiv.org/oai</request>


    <GetRecord>
                <record>
                <header>
        <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:2511.08624</identifier>
        <datestamp>2025-11-13</datestamp>
            <setSpec>physics:physics:bio-ph</setSpec>
            <setSpec>physics:astro-ph:EP</setSpec>
    </header>

            <metadata>
                        <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ https://oaipmh.arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
        <id>2511.08624</id>
        <created>2025-11-09</created>
            <updated>2025-11-13</updated>
        <authors>
                <author>
                    <keyname>Ledesma</keyname>
                        <forenames>Andrés</forenames>
                </author>
                <author>
                    <keyname>Michaelian</keyname>
                        <forenames>Karo</forenames>
                </author>
        </authors>
        <title>Abiogenesis on Different Star Types; a Dissipative Photochemical Perspective</title>
            <categories>physics.bio-ph astro-ph.EP</categories>
            <comments>29 pages, 13 figures</comments>
            <msc-class>92B05, 85A20, 92D99, 92C05, 92C15, 92C40, 92C45, 80Axx, 82Cxx, 82B35, 82C26, </msc-class>
            <license>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0/</license>
            <abstract>The thermodynamic dissipation theory for the origin of life asserts a thermodynamic imperative for the origin of life, suggesting that the fundamental molecules of life originated as self-organized molecular photon dissipative structures (chromophores or pigments) that proliferated over the ocean surface to absorb and dissipate into heat the Archean solar soft UV-C (205-285 nm) and UV-B light ($&lt;$320 nm) of our G-type star. Shorter wavelength hard UV-C light ($&lt;$205 nm) may, depending on atmospheric conditions, have reached Earth&#39;s surface and ionized and dissociated or otherwise degraded these carbon-based pigment molecules (as probably occurred on Mars after losing most of its atmosphere). Here we assess the possibility for an abiogenesis of life similar to ours through molecular photon dissipative structuring on planets similar to early Earth but orbiting different star types at distances normalized to the solar constant. Emission spectra of star types are analyzed to determine the ratio of integrated photon fluxes in the soft UV-C wavelength (dissipative structuring) to hard UV-C wavelength (degradation) regions. Our analysis suggests that star types favorable to the dissipative structuring of life, potentially evolving towards complex life forms such as bacteria, are only the F, G and high mass K-types, with intelligent life only possible on G-type stars. Low mass K and M-type stars are highly unlikely to harbor life. Biosignatures related to the thermodynamic imperative of photon dissipation are proposed.</abstract>
    </arXiv>

            </metadata>
        </record>

    </GetRecord>
</OAI-PMH>