<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<OAI-PMH xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" 
         xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance"
         xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/OAI-PMH.xsd">
    <responseDate>2026-07-13T06:26:36Z</responseDate>
                <request verb="GetRecord" identifier="oai:arXiv.org:2603.15734" metadataPrefix="arXiv">http://oaipmh.arxiv.org/oai</request>


    <GetRecord>
                <record>
                <header>
        <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:2603.15734</identifier>
        <datestamp>2026-03-18</datestamp>
            <setSpec>physics:hep-ph</setSpec>
            <setSpec>physics:astro-ph:CO</setSpec>
            <setSpec>physics:astro-ph:HE</setSpec>
            <setSpec>physics:gr-qc</setSpec>
    </header>

            <metadata>
                        <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ https://oaipmh.arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
        <id>2603.15734</id>
        <created>2026-03-16</created>
            <updated>2026-03-18</updated>
        <authors>
                <author>
                    <keyname>Ellis</keyname>
                        <forenames>Sebastian A. R.</forenames>
                </author>
                <author>
                    <keyname>Ning</keyname>
                        <forenames>Orion</forenames>
                </author>
                <author>
                    <keyname>Rodd</keyname>
                        <forenames>Nicholas L.</forenames>
                </author>
                <author>
                    <keyname>Schütte-Engel</keyname>
                        <forenames>Jan</forenames>
                </author>
        </authors>
        <title>Crowdsourcing Gravitational Waves from Superradiant Axions</title>
            <categories>hep-ph astro-ph.CO astro-ph.HE gr-qc</categories>
            <comments>30 pages, 14 figures</comments>
            <report-no>RIKEN-iTHEMS-Report-26</report-no>
            <license>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0/</license>
            <abstract>Black hole superradiance is a powerful probe of ultralight axions. If nature contains a boson with a mass of order $10^{-12}\,$eV, $\textit{mere vacuum fluctuations}$ will lead to its efficient production around spinning stellar mass black holes, forming a gravitational atom that both drains the black hole spin and decays to produce near-monochromatic gravitational waves. Existing superradiance constraints derive primarily from spin measurements of a handful of identified black holes. Here we instead present a detailed study of the population level effect: gravitational waves arising from both the 100 million black holes in the Milky Way and the stochastic signal from axion clouds throughout the universe. We study the impact of a broad range of systematic uncertainties on the black hole properties and compute the projected axion sensitivity for LIGO, as well as the future instruments Einstein Telescope, Cosmic Explorer, and a high-frequency Magnetic Weber Bar. We demonstrate that LIGO can robustly probe axion masses from roughly $10^{-13}\,$eV to $4 \times 10^{-12}\,$eV. If the black hole population extends to masses slightly below $5\,M_{\odot}$ - as hinted for by LIGO inspiral observations - LIGO would approach $10^{-11}\,$eV. Under that same assumption we show that a future high-frequency detector could push considerably higher, potentially beyond $10^{-10}\,$eV in the most optimistic scenarios, reaching towards the lowest masses within the projected sensitivity of axion dark matter searches.</abstract>
    </arXiv>

            </metadata>
        </record>

    </GetRecord>
</OAI-PMH>