<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<OAI-PMH xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" 
         xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance"
         xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/OAI-PMH.xsd">
    <responseDate>2026-07-13T06:25:06Z</responseDate>
                <request verb="GetRecord" identifier="oai:arXiv.org:2606.31678" metadataPrefix="arXiv">http://oaipmh.arxiv.org/oai</request>


    <GetRecord>
                <record>
                <header>
        <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:2606.31678</identifier>
        <datestamp>2026-07-01</datestamp>
            <setSpec>physics:quant-ph</setSpec>
            <setSpec>physics:gr-qc</setSpec>
    </header>

            <metadata>
                        <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ https://oaipmh.arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
        <id>2606.31678</id>
        <created>2026-06-30</created>
            <updated>2026-07-01</updated>
        <authors>
                <author>
                    <keyname>Wakakuwa</keyname>
                        <forenames>Eyuri</forenames>
                </author>
                <author>
                    <keyname>Petruzziello</keyname>
                        <forenames>Luciano</forenames>
                </author>
                <author>
                    <keyname>Lantaño</keyname>
                        <forenames>Trinidad B.</forenames>
                </author>
                <author>
                    <keyname>Huelga</keyname>
                        <forenames>Susana F.</forenames>
                </author>
                <author>
                    <keyname>Plenio</keyname>
                        <forenames>Martin B.</forenames>
                </author>
        </authors>
        <title>Relativistic Gravity-Induced Entanglement via Frame Dragging</title>
            <categories>quant-ph gr-qc</categories>
            <comments>13 pages, 1 figure</comments>
            <license>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0/</license>
            <abstract>Gravity-induced entanglement has been proposed as a method for testing the non-classical nature of gravity via tabletop experiments. While most existing proposals are restricted to the Newtonian limit, the frame dragging effect offers access to genuinely post-Newtonian features of the gravitational interaction and remains comparatively less explored. Here, we study gravity-induced entanglement generated by frame dragging in an interferometric setting and compute the entanglement phase between the rotational degrees of freedom of a source mass and the paths of a particle in two complementary ways: (i) via Schrödinger evolution with a quantized Lense-Thirring Hamiltonian in the large angular momentum limit, and (ii) via the on-shell action of linearized quantum gravity within the stationary phase approximation. Both approaches yield the same entanglement phase, consistent with the proper time difference between the interferometer arms. The path integral derivation further reveals how gravitational retardation modifies the entanglement phase, thereby making the local, relativistically causal linearized-gravity description explicit. Under the standard locality/mediator assumptions used in existing arguments, the resulting entanglement would witness non-classicality of the gravitational interaction.</abstract>
    </arXiv>

            </metadata>
        </record>

    </GetRecord>
</OAI-PMH>