<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<OAI-PMH xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" 
         xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance"
         xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/OAI-PMH.xsd">
    <responseDate>2026-07-13T06:26:39Z</responseDate>
                <request verb="GetRecord" identifier="oai:arXiv.org:2603.23233" metadataPrefix="arXiv">http://oaipmh.arxiv.org/oai</request>


    <GetRecord>
                <record>
                <header>
        <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:2603.23233</identifier>
        <datestamp>2026-03-25</datestamp>
            <setSpec>q-bio:q-bio:NC</setSpec>
            <setSpec>physics:quant-ph</setSpec>
    </header>

            <metadata>
                        <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ https://oaipmh.arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
        <id>2603.23233</id>
        <created>2026-03-24</created>
            <updated>2026-03-25</updated>
        <authors>
                <author>
                    <keyname>Nasu</keyname>
                        <forenames>Ryo</forenames>
                </author>
                <author>
                    <keyname>Maruyama</keyname>
                        <forenames>Yoshihiro</forenames>
                </author>
        </authors>
        <title>Modeling the Disjunction Effect within Classical Probability: A New Decision Process Model and Comparison with Quantum-like Models</title>
            <categories>q-bio.NC quant-ph</categories>
            <comments>30 pages, 2 figures</comments>
            <license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license>
            <abstract>The disjunction effect in human decision making is often taken to show that the classical law of total probability is violated, motivating quantum-like models. We re-examine this claim for the Prisoner&#39;s Dilemma disjunction effect. Under the mental-event reading of the opponent-choice events, the conventional classical decision-process model implicitly builds in a certainty-only premise: its standard partition assumptions leave no room for ambiguity, forcing every participant to be certain that the opponent will defect or will cooperate. We relax this by introducing a new classical model in which each participant carries a continuous expectation parameter representing the anticipated likelihood of opponent defection, and the participant pool is partitioned by expectation level; the resulting ambiguity set is precisely the union of the interior expectation bins. In contrast, under the quantum-like event semantics, ambiguous pure states are generic (dense and of full unitarily invariant measure on the unit sphere), so &#34;certainty states&#34; are mathematically exceptional. We prove that an instance of our classical model can realize any empirically observed triple of defection rates across the three information conditions, including strong disjunction-effect patterns, while strictly obeying the classical law of total probability. We further prove that for any such triple produced by a standard quantum-like model of the same experiment, there exists a classical instance reproducing it exactly. In this sense, classical and quantum-like approaches have the same observable-rate expressiveness; their substantive difference lies in how ambiguity is represented and in their respective event semantics, not in a breakdown of classical probability.</abstract>
    </arXiv>

            </metadata>
        </record>

    </GetRecord>
</OAI-PMH>