<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<OAI-PMH xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" 
         xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance"
         xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/OAI-PMH.xsd">
    <responseDate>2026-07-11T09:33:58Z</responseDate>
                <request verb="GetRecord" identifier="oai:arXiv.org:2606.06692v2" metadataPrefix="arXiv">http://oaipmh.arxiv.org/oai</request>


    <GetRecord>
                <record>
                <header>
        <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:2606.06692</identifier>
        <datestamp>2026-06-17</datestamp>
            <setSpec>physics:astro-ph:IM</setSpec>
            <setSpec>physics:astro-ph:EP</setSpec>
            <setSpec>physics:astro-ph:GA</setSpec>
            <setSpec>physics:astro-ph:SR</setSpec>
    </header>

            <metadata>
                        <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ https://oaipmh.arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
        <id>2606.06692</id>
        <created>2026-06-16</created>
            <updated>2026-06-17</updated>
        <authors>
                <author>
                    <keyname>Torlakcik</keyname>
                        <forenames>Sahin</forenames>
                </author>
        </authors>
        <title>Where Not to Look: A Parametric Avoidance Model for SETI Target Selection</title>
            <categories>astro-ph.IM astro-ph.EP astro-ph.GA astro-ph.SR</categories>
            <comments>18 pages, 11 figures, 5 tables. Published in PASP (PASP 138 064505)</comments>
            <journal-ref>Publ. Astron. Soc. Pac. 138, 064505 (2026)</journal-ref>
            <doi>10.1088/1538-3873/ae75f3</doi>
            <license>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0/</license>
            <abstract>We present a simple, rule-based filter for SETI target selection that flags stars unlikely to host complex life and produces an audit-ready exclusion catalog. Using seven stellar parameters, including age, metallicity, and multiplicity, the model excludes roughly half of a 1.74 million-star Gaia DR3 sample, retaining 777,835 high-priority targets, mainly G and K dwarfs. Age and metallicity dominate the rejections. Importantly, using Gaia&#39;s age upper bounds instead of point estimates saves 355,086 stars from exclusion. A comparison of empirical and synthetic proxies shows that while the overall exclusion rate is robust, individual target assignments change significantly; for instance, the commonly used RUWE indicator flags 2.7x more binaries than Gaia&#39;s own non-single-star flag. Cross-matching with the Breakthrough Listen target list reveals a 56.5% exclusion rate, highlighting the complementary nature of habitability-driven and proximity-driven surveys. The catalog, pipeline, and a generalized community tool are publicly available.</abstract>
    </arXiv>

            </metadata>
        </record>

    </GetRecord>
</OAI-PMH>