<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<OAI-PMH xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" 
         xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance"
         xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/OAI-PMH.xsd">
    <responseDate>2026-07-13T06:24:13Z</responseDate>
                <request verb="GetRecord" identifier="oai:arXiv.org:2603.24522" metadataPrefix="arXiv">http://oaipmh.arxiv.org/oai</request>


    <GetRecord>
                <record>
                <header>
        <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:2603.24522</identifier>
        <datestamp>2026-04-20</datestamp>
            <setSpec>physics:quant-ph</setSpec>
    </header>

            <metadata>
                        <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ https://oaipmh.arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
        <id>2603.24522</id>
        <created>2026-04-17</created>
            <updated>2026-04-20</updated>
        <authors>
                <author>
                    <keyname>Rocha-Soto</keyname>
                        <forenames>Luis Enrique</forenames>
                </author>
                <author>
                    <keyname>Damian-Ascencio</keyname>
                        <forenames>Cesar Eduardo</forenames>
                </author>
                <author>
                    <keyname>Saldaña-Robles</keyname>
                        <forenames>Adriana</forenames>
                </author>
                <author>
                    <keyname>Cano-Andrade</keyname>
                        <forenames>Sergio</forenames>
                </author>
        </authors>
        <title>A Description of the Quantum Mpemba Effect using the Steepest-Entropy-Ascent Quantum Thermodynamics Framework</title>
            <categories>quant-ph</categories>
            <comments>17 pages, 16 figures. References added</comments>
            <license>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0/</license>
            <abstract>The quantum Mpemba effect is a phenomenon characterized by an exponential relaxation from a non-equililbrium state to a steady state. This effect was predicted with an analysis of the Liouvillian superoperator and experimentally demonstrated in a three-level system. In this work, the system dynamics of the Mpemba effect is predicted within the steepest-entropy-ascent quantum thermodynamics framework considering a single constituent three-level isolated system. The system is projected from a four-dimensional Hilbert space onto a three-dimensional one using the Feshbach projection in order to compare the theoretical results with experimental data. Since the quantum Mpemba effect is characterized by a dissipative acceleration, the relaxation parameter, $τ_D$, plays a fundamental rol in the dissipative dynamics predicted by the model and is determined using machine learning methods, resulting in a model that thermodynamically describes this phenomenon at the quantum level.</abstract>
    </arXiv>

            </metadata>
        </record>

    </GetRecord>
</OAI-PMH>