<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<OAI-PMH xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" 
         xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance"
         xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/OAI-PMH.xsd">
    <responseDate>2026-07-13T06:20:59Z</responseDate>
                <request verb="GetRecord" identifier="oai:arXiv.org:2605.02008" metadataPrefix="arXiv">http://oaipmh.arxiv.org/oai</request>


    <GetRecord>
                <record>
                <header>
        <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:2605.02008</identifier>
        <datestamp>2026-05-05</datestamp>
            <setSpec>physics:gr-qc</setSpec>
    </header>

            <metadata>
                        <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ https://oaipmh.arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
        <id>2605.02008</id>
        <created>2026-05-03</created>
            <updated>2026-05-05</updated>
        <authors>
                <author>
                    <keyname>Mavoa</keyname>
                        <forenames>F.</forenames>
                </author>
                <author>
                    <keyname>Sow</keyname>
                        <forenames>M. C.</forenames>
                </author>
                <author>
                    <keyname>Ganiou</keyname>
                        <forenames>M. G.</forenames>
                </author>
                <author>
                    <keyname>Touré</keyname>
                        <forenames>C. S.</forenames>
                </author>
                <author>
                    <keyname>Tefo</keyname>
                        <forenames>C. R.</forenames>
                </author>
        </authors>
        <title>Gravitational baryogenesis in scalar-nonmetricity $f(Q,ϕ)$ gravity</title>
            <categories>gr-qc</categories>
            <license>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0/</license>
            <abstract>In this work, we investigate gravitational baryogenesis in the framework of scalar-nonmetricity theories by considering two classes of modified gravity models, namely $f(Q,ϕ)=Q+ξQ ϕ^2$ and $f(Q,ϕ)=αQ^n + βϕQ$. These models extend standard $f(Q)$ gravity through the inclusion of nonminimal couplings between the scalar field and the nonmetricity scalar, leading to nontrivial modifications of the cosmological dynamics. We analyze the evolution of the baryon-to-entropy ratio in terms of the cosmic expansion parameter $γ$, assuming a power-law behavior of the scale factor. For the first model, we show that the baryon-to-entropy ratio decreases monotonically with increasing $γ$, reflecting the impact of the expansion rate on the efficiency of baryogenesis. The observed baryon asymmetry, of order $10^{-11}$ to $10^{-10}$, is successfully reproduced for $γ\approx 0.2$--$0.3$ without requiring fine-tuning of the model parameters. For the second model, we explore the parameter space of $α$ and $β$, and demonstrate that the correct order of magnitude of the baryon asymmetry can be achieved for physically reasonable values of the parameters. In particular, we find that the baryon-to-entropy ratio lies within observational bounds for $α\sim 10^{-3}$ to $10^{-2}$ and $β\sim 10^{-2}$ to $10^{-1}$, with specific combinations yielding excellent agreement with observations. Overall, our results show that scalar-nonmetricity gravity provides a viable and robust framework for explaining the origin of the baryon asymmetry of the Universe. The interplay between nonlinear geometric terms and scalar field couplings plays a crucial role in controlling the baryogenesis mechanism, opening new perspectives in the study of modified gravity and early Universe cosmology.</abstract>
    </arXiv>

            </metadata>
        </record>

    </GetRecord>
</OAI-PMH>