<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<OAI-PMH xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" 
         xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance"
         xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/OAI-PMH.xsd">
    <responseDate>2026-07-13T06:20:49Z</responseDate>
                <request verb="GetRecord" identifier="oai:arXiv.org:2605.03951" metadataPrefix="arXiv">http://oaipmh.arxiv.org/oai</request>


    <GetRecord>
                <record>
                <header>
        <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:2605.03951</identifier>
        <datestamp>2026-05-06</datestamp>
            <setSpec>physics:quant-ph</setSpec>
            <setSpec>physics:physics:atom-ph</setSpec>
    </header>

            <metadata>
                        <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ https://oaipmh.arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
        <id>2605.03951</id>
        <created>2026-05-05</created>
            <updated>2026-05-06</updated>
        <authors>
                <author>
                    <keyname>Xue</keyname>
                        <forenames>Tian</forenames>
                </author>
                <author>
                    <keyname>Covey</keyname>
                        <forenames>Jacob P.</forenames>
                </author>
        </authors>
        <title>Factoring $2048$ bit RSA integers with a half-million-qubit modular atomic processor</title>
            <categories>quant-ph physics.atom-ph</categories>
            <license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license>
            <abstract>Shor&#39;s algorithm is one of the most promising applications of quantum computers. However, since $\sim 10^6$ physical qubits are believed to be required for established approaches, the algorithm will need to be distributed across many modules. In this paper, we provide a distributed compilation of Shor&#39;s algorithm on a modular atomic processor. We present an end-to-end compilation and optimization strategy that focuses on the interplay between the inter-module communication and the intra-module clock rate. With a half-million-qubit modular atomic processor with a communication rate of $10^5$ Bell pairs per second and a measurement time of 1 ms in a CPU-inspired architecture, we demonstrate that 2048-bit RSA integers can be factored in only 16\% more time than a single-module architecture. Our work presents the first end-to-end analysis and simulation of large-scale integer factorization on modular atomic hardware and it provides a blueprint for the future design of other large-scale modular algorithms.</abstract>
    </arXiv>

            </metadata>
        </record>

    </GetRecord>
</OAI-PMH>