<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<OAI-PMH xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" 
         xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance"
         xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/OAI-PMH.xsd">
    <responseDate>2026-07-11T08:41:49Z</responseDate>
                <request verb="GetRecord" identifier="oai:arXiv.org:2606.05344v1" metadataPrefix="arXiv">http://oaipmh.arxiv.org/oai</request>


    <GetRecord>
                <record>
                <header>
        <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:2606.05344</identifier>
        <datestamp>2026-06-05</datestamp>
            <setSpec>physics:astro-ph:EP</setSpec>
            <setSpec>physics:astro-ph:GA</setSpec>
            <setSpec>physics:astro-ph:IM</setSpec>
    </header>

            <metadata>
                        <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ https://oaipmh.arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
        <id>2606.05344</id>
        <created>2026-06-03</created>
            <updated>2026-06-05</updated>
        <authors>
                <author>
                    <keyname>Walker</keyname>
                        <forenames>Cassidy E.</forenames>
                </author>
                <author>
                    <keyname>Seligman</keyname>
                        <forenames>Darryl Z.</forenames>
                </author>
        </authors>
        <title>Sky-Plane Velocity Distributions of Interstellar Objects and Implications for Their Detection</title>
            <categories>astro-ph.EP astro-ph.GA astro-ph.IM</categories>
            <comments>13 pages, 6 figures, 3 tables, resubmitted to MNRAS following reviewer reports</comments>
            <license>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0/</license>
            <abstract>In the past decade, three macroscopic-scale interstellar objects have been discovered, implying that a larger galactic population exists. In this paper, we investigate the possibility that the rapid sky-plane velocities of interstellar objects may preclude their discovery. We provide an analytic solution for the apparent sky motion of an object on an arbitrary orbit observed at an arbitrary location which (i) is more efficient and (ii) requires less overhead than the numerical approach. This formula is applied to evaluate the typical sky motion of an interstellar object as a function of its orbit and limiting magnitude/distance. We generate three synthetic populations of $\sim10^5$ interstellar objects within heliocentric spheres of radii 1.2, 3.0, and 5.0 AU, and calculate the sky motion for these objects when they reach a range of limiting magnitudes for multiple populations of interstellar asteroids and comets. The sky motions of the three known interstellar objects are broadly characteristic of populations with similar absolute magnitudes. Moreover, the intrinsically brighter objects reach detection magnitude thresholds at lower speeds than the dim objects, and active comets at even lower speeds for the same apparent magnitudes. The tails of these distributions extend to speeds faster than the discovery motion of 1I. Therefore, the difficulties associated with linking rapidly moving interstellar objects, especially those with intrinsically dim properties, could imply that more exist undetected traversing the Solar System.</abstract>
    </arXiv>

            </metadata>
        </record>

    </GetRecord>
</OAI-PMH>