<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<OAI-PMH xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" 
         xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance"
         xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/OAI-PMH.xsd">
    <responseDate>2026-07-13T08:18:40Z</responseDate>
                <request verb="GetRecord" identifier="oai:arXiv.org:2605.20354" metadataPrefix="arXiv">http://oaipmh.arxiv.org/oai</request>


    <GetRecord>
                <record>
                <header>
        <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:2605.20354</identifier>
        <datestamp>2026-05-21</datestamp>
            <setSpec>physics:gr-qc</setSpec>
            <setSpec>physics:hep-th</setSpec>
    </header>

            <metadata>
                        <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ https://oaipmh.arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
        <id>2605.20354</id>
        <created>2026-05-19</created>
            <updated>2026-05-21</updated>
        <authors>
                <author>
                    <keyname>Ahmed</keyname>
                        <forenames>Faizuddin</forenames>
                </author>
                <author>
                    <keyname>Al-Badawi</keyname>
                        <forenames>Ahmad</forenames>
                </author>
                <author>
                    <keyname>Belchior</keyname>
                        <forenames>Fernando M.</forenames>
                </author>
                <author>
                    <keyname>Silva</keyname>
                        <forenames>Edilberto O.</forenames>
                </author>
        </authors>
        <title>Transfer observables of rotating acoustic black holes from ray tracing: shadow centroid, redshift asymmetry and flux imbalance</title>
            <categories>gr-qc hep-th</categories>
            <comments>12 pages, 6 figures, 4 tables. Comments are welcome</comments>
            <license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license>
            <abstract>We construct an impact-parameter-resolved transfer framework for null acoustic rays in the rotating draining-bathtub spacetime. The formalism separates the source-independent ray geometry from the source and detector model by keeping explicit the acoustic redshift, transfer convention, emissivity, emitter velocity field, and source-to-screen mapping. The geometric capture interval provides two clean observables: a shadow centroid that shifts linearly with circulation and a shadow width that grows monotonically with circulation. Observable profiles are obtained from direct ray-source intersections, finite source width or extended-disk integration, detector convolution, and convergence checks, rather than from an approximate semi-analytic ring map. The transfer calculation shows that rotation produces a left-right redshift tilt and a branch-dependent flux imbalance, while the total flux alone remains a degenerate circulation diagnostic. The most useful diagnostics are differential quantities: the shadow centroid, branch-integrated flux asymmetry, peak asymmetry, left-right redshift asymmetry, and global redshift contrast. We also discuss how these observables respond to the transfer convention, intrinsic azimuthal emissivity, the choice of left-right split, finite resolution, and physical limitations such as dispersion, viscosity, and finite-depth corrections.</abstract>
    </arXiv>

            </metadata>
        </record>

    </GetRecord>
</OAI-PMH>