<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<OAI-PMH xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" 
         xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance"
         xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/OAI-PMH.xsd">
    <responseDate>2026-07-13T06:26:50Z</responseDate>
                <request verb="GetRecord" identifier="oai:arXiv.org:2604.19304" metadataPrefix="arXiv">http://oaipmh.arxiv.org/oai</request>


    <GetRecord>
                <record>
                <header>
        <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:2604.19304</identifier>
        <datestamp>2026-04-22</datestamp>
            <setSpec>physics:cond-mat:mes-hall</setSpec>
            <setSpec>physics:cond-mat:mtrl-sci</setSpec>
            <setSpec>physics:quant-ph</setSpec>
    </header>

            <metadata>
                        <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ https://oaipmh.arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
        <id>2604.19304</id>
        <created>2026-04-21</created>
            <updated>2026-04-22</updated>
        <authors>
                <author>
                    <keyname>Zou</keyname>
                        <forenames>Ji</forenames>
                </author>
                <author>
                    <keyname>Klinovaja</keyname>
                        <forenames>Jelena</forenames>
                </author>
                <author>
                    <keyname>Loss</keyname>
                        <forenames>Daniel</forenames>
                </author>
        </authors>
        <title>Perspective: Quantum Computing on Magnetic Racetrack</title>
            <categories>cond-mat.mes-hall cond-mat.mtrl-sci quant-ph</categories>
            <comments>15 pages, 6 figures, invited Perspective</comments>
            <license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license>
            <abstract>Magnetic domain walls have long been pursued as carriers of classical information for storage and processing. With the ability to create, control, and probe domain walls at the nanoscale, they are recently recognized as an ideal platform for studying macroscopic quantum effects and provide a natural blueprint for building scalable quantum computing architectures. In particular, the experimentally demonstrated high mobility of domain walls makes them not only suitable as stationary qubits but also as flying qubits, which may offer advantages over currently explored quantum computing platforms. In this Perspective, we outline our current understanding of the essential ingredients and key requirements for realizing universal quantum computation based on magnetic domain walls. We highlight promising concrete material platforms and identify the experiments that are still needed to advance this concept. We also discuss the potential challenges and point to new opportunities in this emerging research direction at the interface between magnetism and quantum information science.</abstract>
    </arXiv>

            </metadata>
        </record>

    </GetRecord>
</OAI-PMH>