<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<OAI-PMH xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" 
         xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance"
         xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/OAI-PMH.xsd">
    <responseDate>2026-07-13T06:23:46Z</responseDate>
                <request verb="GetRecord" identifier="oai:arXiv.org:2602.07585" metadataPrefix="arXiv">http://oaipmh.arxiv.org/oai</request>


    <GetRecord>
                <record>
                <header>
        <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:2602.07585</identifier>
        <datestamp>2026-04-09</datestamp>
            <setSpec>physics:cond-mat:supr-con</setSpec>
            <setSpec>physics:cond-mat:mes-hall</setSpec>
            <setSpec>physics:cond-mat:mtrl-sci</setSpec>
            <setSpec>physics:physics:app-ph</setSpec>
            <setSpec>physics:quant-ph</setSpec>
    </header>

            <metadata>
                        <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ https://oaipmh.arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
        <id>2602.07585</id>
        <created>2026-04-08</created>
            <updated>2026-04-09</updated>
        <authors>
                <author>
                    <keyname>Ummarino</keyname>
                        <forenames>Giovanni A.</forenames>
                </author>
                <author>
                    <keyname>Zaccone</keyname>
                        <forenames>Alessio</forenames>
                </author>
        </authors>
        <title>Turning non-superconducting elements into superconductors by quantum confinement and proximity</title>
            <categories>cond-mat.supr-con cond-mat.mes-hall cond-mat.mtrl-sci physics.app-ph quant-ph</categories>
            <comments>Topical review</comments>
            <journal-ref>Journal of Physics: Condensed Matter 38 143003 (2026)</journal-ref>
            <doi>10.1088/1361-648X/ae5907</doi>
            <license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license>
            <abstract>Elemental good metals, including noble metals (Cu, Ag, Au) and several $s$-block elements, do not exhibit superconductivity in bulk at ambient pressure, mainly due to weak electron-phonon coupling that cannot overcome Coulomb repulsion. Quantum confinement in ultra-thin films reshapes the electronic spectrum and the density of states near the Fermi level, producing strong, often non-monotonic, thickness dependencies of the critical temperature in established superconductors. Here, we examine whether confinement alone, or combined with proximity effects, can induce superconductivity in metals that are non-superconducting in bulk form. We review recent theoretical progress and introduce a unified framework based on a confinement-generalized, isotropic one-band Eliashberg theory, where the normal density of states becomes energy dependent and key parameters ($E_F$, $λ$, $μ^$) acquire explicit thickness dependence. By numerically solving the Eliashberg equations using ab initio or experimentally determined electron-phonon spectral functions $α^2F(Ω)$ and Coulomb pseudopotentials $μ^$, and without adjustable parameters, we compute the critical temperature $T_c$ as a function of film thickness for representative noble, alkali, and alkaline-earth metals. The results predict that superconductivity emerges only in selected cases and within extremely narrow thickness windows, typically at sub-nanometer scales ($L \sim 0.4-0.6$ nm), indicating strong fine-tuning requirements for confinement-induced superconductivity in good metals. We also consider layered superconductor/normal-metal systems where confinement and proximity effects coexist. In these heterostructures, a substantial enhancement of the critical temperature is predicted, even when the constituent materials are non-superconducting or weak superconductors in bulk form.</abstract>
    </arXiv>

            </metadata>
        </record>

    </GetRecord>
</OAI-PMH>