<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<OAI-PMH xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" 
         xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance"
         xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/OAI-PMH.xsd">
    <responseDate>2026-07-13T06:22:51Z</responseDate>
                <request verb="GetRecord" identifier="oai:arXiv.org:2509.18423" metadataPrefix="arXiv">http://oaipmh.arxiv.org/oai</request>


    <GetRecord>
                <record>
                <header>
        <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:2509.18423</identifier>
        <datestamp>2026-07-02</datestamp>
            <setSpec>physics:quant-ph</setSpec>
    </header>

            <metadata>
                        <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ https://oaipmh.arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
        <id>2509.18423</id>
        <created>2025-11-18</created>
            <updated>2026-07-02</updated>
        <authors>
                <author>
                    <keyname>Liu</keyname>
                        <forenames>Jiarui</forenames>
                </author>
                <author>
                    <keyname>Wu</keyname>
                        <forenames>Qiming</forenames>
                </author>
                <author>
                    <keyname>Moore</keyname>
                        <forenames>Joel E.</forenames>
                </author>
                <author>
                    <keyname>Haeffner</keyname>
                        <forenames>Hartmut</forenames>
                </author>
                <author>
                    <keyname>Wächtler</keyname>
                        <forenames>Christopher W.</forenames>
                </author>
        </authors>
        <title>Observation of synchronization between two quantum van der Pol oscillators in trapped ions</title>
            <categories>quant-ph</categories>
            <journal-ref>Phys. Rev. X 16, 021062 (2026)</journal-ref>
            <doi>10.1103/w1bm-wjl4</doi>
            <license>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0/</license>
            <abstract>Synchronization is a hallmark of collective behavior that emerges when nonlinear systems interact, spanning scales from mechanical oscillators to planetary orbits. As a universal phenomenon it underpins the study of complex systems and has far-reaching technological implications. While classical synchronization has a long and rich history, it has not been observed experimentally between multiple quantum limit-cycle oscillators despite a decade of theoretical investigations. We realize synchronization between two quantum van der Pol oscillators by engineering dissipation in a mixed-isotope trapped-ion quantum simulator. The synchronized state is encoded in a fixed relative phase between the oscillators that is inaccessible to local measurements and only revealed through joint readout of both oscillators, in stark contrast to the classical case where synchronization can be observed via individual phase measurements. We further show that the relative phase can be precisely controlled, and that the chain of two oscillators can synchronize to an external field, suggesting applications in sensing. Our results provide a promising pathway for studying more complex synchronized quantum dynamics beyond two oscillators, where a theoretical treatment becomes increasingly challenging, and it remains to be understood whether genuinely quantum features persist in such cases.</abstract>
    </arXiv>

            </metadata>
        </record>

    </GetRecord>
</OAI-PMH>