<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<OAI-PMH xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" 
         xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance"
         xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/OAI-PMH.xsd">
    <responseDate>2026-07-13T21:14:21Z</responseDate>
                <request verb="GetRecord" identifier="oai:arXiv.org:2606.20540" metadataPrefix="arXiv">http://oaipmh.arxiv.org/oai</request>


    <GetRecord>
                <record>
                <header>
        <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:2606.20540</identifier>
        <datestamp>2026-06-19</datestamp>
            <setSpec>physics:gr-qc</setSpec>
    </header>

            <metadata>
                        <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ https://oaipmh.arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
        <id>2606.20540</id>
        <created>2026-06-18</created>
            <updated>2026-06-19</updated>
        <authors>
                <author>
                    <keyname>Ganguly</keyname>
                        <forenames>Apratim</forenames>
                </author>
                <author>
                    <keyname>Gannouji</keyname>
                        <forenames>Radouane</forenames>
                </author>
                <author>
                    <keyname>Kumar</keyname>
                        <forenames>Akshay</forenames>
                </author>
        </authors>
        <title>Higher Lovelock Curvature Terms Favor Local Nakedness in Dust Collapse</title>
            <categories>gr-qc</categories>
            <comments>18 pages, 2 figures</comments>
            <license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license>
            <abstract>We show that higher-curvature Lovelock terms do not restore local cosmic censorship in spherical dust collapse, but instead promote the local visibility of central shell-focusing singularities. On the collapse branch with positive highest-order Lovelock coefficient \(c_N\), the highest nonvanishing Lovelock order \(N\) controls both the near-singularity collapse and the formation of trapped surfaces. In noncritical dimensions, \(D-1-2N&gt;0\), the apparent-horizon curve approaches the singularity curve with trapping exponent \(β_N=(D-1)/(D-1-2N)\). Comparing this scale with the first nonvanishing correction \(r^\ell\) to the singularity curve gives the local-visibility condition \(\ell&lt;β_N\), provided the singularity curve opens outward. Thus increasing \(N\) enlarges the class of inhomogeneous initial data producing outgoing radial null rays from the central singularity. In the critical odd-dimensional branch, \(D=2N+1\), no apparent horizon forms sufficiently close to the center, so any outward opening of the singularity curve gives local visibility. The locally visible singularities are Królak-strong along the emerging null rays, with Tipler strength reached at threshold. For bound and unbound collapse, the noncritical exponents are unchanged: the energy function modifies the opening of the singularity curve, while in the critical branch it enters the leading terminal collapse velocity.</abstract>
    </arXiv>

            </metadata>
        </record>

    </GetRecord>
</OAI-PMH>