<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<OAI-PMH xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" 
         xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance"
         xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/OAI-PMH.xsd">
    <responseDate>2026-07-13T21:13:57Z</responseDate>
                <request verb="GetRecord" identifier="oai:arXiv.org:2507.21663" metadataPrefix="arXiv">http://oaipmh.arxiv.org/oai</request>


    <GetRecord>
                <record>
                <header>
        <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:2507.21663</identifier>
        <datestamp>2025-07-30</datestamp>
            <setSpec>physics:gr-qc</setSpec>
            <setSpec>physics:hep-th</setSpec>
    </header>

            <metadata>
                        <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ https://oaipmh.arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
        <id>2507.21663</id>
        <created>2025-07-29</created>
            <updated>2025-07-30</updated>
        <authors>
                <author>
                    <keyname>Anand</keyname>
                        <forenames>Ankit</forenames>
                </author>
                <author>
                    <keyname>Gashti</keyname>
                        <forenames>Saeed Noori</forenames>
                </author>
        </authors>
        <title>Van der Waals Black Holes: Universality, Quantum Corrections, and Topological Classifications</title>
            <categories>gr-qc hep-th</categories>
            <comments>35 pages, 5 figures</comments>
            <journal-ref>Physics of the Dark Universe 49 (2025) 102018</journal-ref>
            <doi>10.1016/j.dark.2025.102018</doi>
            <license>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0/</license>
            <abstract>In this paper, we investigate the universal extremality relation and thermodynamic topology of Van der Waals (VdW) black holes-solutions of Einstein&#39;s equations whose thermodynamic behavior closely resembles that of Van der Waals fluids. In the classical case, the black hole entropy obeys the Bekenstein-Hawking area law and satisfies the standard universality relation. We then incorporate quantum corrections using three distinct frameworks: the Generalized Uncertainty Principle (GUP), the Extended Uncertainty Principle (EUP), and Rainbow Gravity. While these corrections modify the entropy law, we find that a generalized form of the universal extremality relation still holds. Next, we explore the thermodynamic topology of VdW black holes, focusing on the distribution of topological charges. Our analysis reveals that variations in the black hole and model parameters lead to significant changes in topological classifications and stability, as quantified by winding numbers. In the GUP-corrected case, topological charge distributions exhibit robustness against parameter variations, suggesting classification stability. For EUP-corrected black holes, we identify two distinct topological classes, with some configurations displaying three non-zero topological charges and others maintaining a total charge of zero, despite changes in individual charge counts. The Rainbow Gravity-corrected scenario shows similar consistency in topological behavior.</abstract>
    </arXiv>

            </metadata>
        </record>

    </GetRecord>
</OAI-PMH>