<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<OAI-PMH xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" 
         xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance"
         xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/OAI-PMH.xsd">
    <responseDate>2026-07-13T06:22:50Z</responseDate>
                <request verb="GetRecord" identifier="oai:arXiv.org:2509.14701" metadataPrefix="arXiv">http://oaipmh.arxiv.org/oai</request>


    <GetRecord>
                <record>
                <header>
        <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:2509.14701</identifier>
        <datestamp>2025-09-30</datestamp>
            <setSpec>physics:hep-ph</setSpec>
            <setSpec>physics:astro-ph:CO</setSpec>
            <setSpec>physics:cond-mat:other</setSpec>
            <setSpec>physics:physics:atom-ph</setSpec>
    </header>

            <metadata>
                        <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ https://oaipmh.arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
        <id>2509.14701</id>
        <created>2025-09-29</created>
            <updated>2025-09-30</updated>
        <authors>
                <author>
                    <keyname>Flambaum</keyname>
                        <forenames>V. V.</forenames>
                </author>
        </authors>
        <title>Enhancement of Weak Interactions in Phase Transitions</title>
            <categories>hep-ph astro-ph.CO cond-mat.other physics.atom-ph</categories>
            <license>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0/</license>
            <abstract>Weak interactions cause small parity-violating energy differences between left- and right-handed chiral systems. Although normally tiny, these effects may be significantly enhanced during collective phenomena such as phase transitions. We propose a theoretical model describing the enhancement of weak interactions in phase transitions. The enhancement factor is proportional to the critical number of atoms, $N_c$, in the nucleus of the new phase. After the nucleus reaches its critical size, it grows until it fills the entire system. Measurement of the ratio of produced left and right chiral structures may provide a way to measure this critical number $N_c$. Experiments where definite spin-chiral structures are formed during a phase transition in crossed electric and magnetic fields, indicate $N_c \sim 10^9 - 10^{10}$. An open question is whether a similar enhancement could operate during cosmological phase transitions - thereby boosting CP-violating effects sufficiently to contribute to the observed matter-antimatter asymmetry (baryogenesis).</abstract>
    </arXiv>

            </metadata>
        </record>

    </GetRecord>
</OAI-PMH>