<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<OAI-PMH xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" 
         xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance"
         xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/OAI-PMH.xsd">
    <responseDate>2026-07-13T06:25:02Z</responseDate>
                <request verb="GetRecord" identifier="oai:arXiv.org:2606.25889" metadataPrefix="arXiv">http://oaipmh.arxiv.org/oai</request>


    <GetRecord>
                <record>
                <header>
        <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:2606.25889</identifier>
        <datestamp>2026-06-25</datestamp>
            <setSpec>physics:quant-ph</setSpec>
            <setSpec>physics:hep-th</setSpec>
    </header>

            <metadata>
                        <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ https://oaipmh.arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
        <id>2606.25889</id>
        <created>2026-06-24</created>
            <updated>2026-06-25</updated>
        <authors>
                <author>
                    <keyname>Humar</keyname>
                        <forenames>Gregor</forenames>
                </author>
                <author>
                    <keyname>Desaules</keyname>
                        <forenames>Jean-Yves</forenames>
                </author>
                <author>
                    <keyname>Pavešić</keyname>
                        <forenames>Luka</forenames>
                </author>
                <author>
                    <keyname>Ljubotina</keyname>
                        <forenames>Marko</forenames>
                </author>
                <author>
                    <keyname>Papić</keyname>
                        <forenames>Zlatko</forenames>
                </author>
                <author>
                    <keyname>Michielsen</keyname>
                        <forenames>Kristel</forenames>
                </author>
                <author>
                    <keyname>Vodeb</keyname>
                        <forenames>Jaka</forenames>
                </author>
        </authors>
        <title>Resonant false vacuum decay in two dimensions on a 4000-qubit quantum annealer</title>
            <categories>quant-ph hep-th</categories>
            <license>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0/</license>
            <abstract>From cosmology to quantum matter, metastable states often decay through the nucleation and growth of competing domains, with false vacuum decay providing the paradigmatic example of this process. Here we demonstrate a distinct regime in which domain growth outpaces nucleation by orders of magnitude and is controlled by local resonance conditions. Using a programmable quantum annealer with more than 4000 qubits, we realize a two-dimensional quantum Ising model whose metastable spin-polarized state encodes a false vacuum. At a specific value of the longitudinal field, single-spin flips at the boundary of a seeded bubble become resonant, enabling kinetically constrained expansion. Combining experiment with tensor-network simulations and stochastic circuit modeling, we observe nearly ballistic growth of true-vacuum domains with sub-ballistic interface broadening, consistent with Kardar--Parisi--Zhang universality. Our results establish a growth-dominated regime of false vacuum decay and show how large-scale quantum simulation can access nonequilibrium metastable dynamics relevant to quantum field theory, cosmology, and strongly correlated matter.</abstract>
    </arXiv>

            </metadata>
        </record>

    </GetRecord>
</OAI-PMH>