<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<OAI-PMH xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" 
         xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance"
         xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/OAI-PMH.xsd">
    <responseDate>2026-07-13T06:25:38Z</responseDate>
                <request verb="GetRecord" identifier="oai:arXiv.org:2511.19946" metadataPrefix="arXiv">http://oaipmh.arxiv.org/oai</request>


    <GetRecord>
                <record>
                <header>
        <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:2511.19946</identifier>
        <datestamp>2026-04-07</datestamp>
            <setSpec>physics:astro-ph:EP</setSpec>
    </header>

            <metadata>
                        <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ https://oaipmh.arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
        <id>2511.19946</id>
        <created>2026-04-06</created>
            <updated>2026-04-07</updated>
        <authors>
                <author>
                    <keyname>Zhao</keyname>
                        <forenames>Wenhao</forenames>
                </author>
                <author>
                    <keyname>Lau</keyname>
                        <forenames>Harriet</forenames>
                </author>
                <author>
                    <keyname>Parman</keyname>
                        <forenames>Stephen</forenames>
                </author>
                <author>
                    <keyname>Head</keyname>
                        <forenames>James W.</forenames>
                        <suffix>III</suffix>
                </author>
        </authors>
        <title>Tidal Heating of the Lunar Magma Ocean: Reconciling an Old Moon with a Young Solidification</title>
            <categories>astro-ph.EP</categories>
            <comments>36 pages, 5 main figures. Supplementary Materials include 6 supplementary figures and 1 supplementary table</comments>
            <license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license>
            <abstract>The timing of the Moon&#39;s formation is fundamental to understanding the early Earth-Moon system. Ages of lunar magma ocean (LMO) crystallization have long been regarded as a key proxy for that event. Yet returned lunar sample ages cluster near the relatively young age of ~4.35 billion years ago (Ga). These ages are commonly interpreted as recording either a young-Moon formation age or later thermal resetting. Here we show that, for an old Moon (&gt;4.5 Ga), the ~4.35 Ga age cluster can instead arise naturally from early LMO thermal evolution under Earth&#39;s tidal forcing. We identify tidal heating within a partially molten LMO as a major internal heat source. It offsets much of the early heat loss and maintains a long-lived high-energy state for &gt;150 million years. As crystallization proceeded, this stable state was ultimately lost through the rapid collapse of tidal heating. The last stages of LMO solidification were compressed into a short interval near ~4.35 Ga. The tidal heat source decouples Moon formation from final LMO solidification. As an outcome of LMO evolution, we predict asymmetric late-stage crystallization between the lunar nearside and farside, potentially linking tidally modulated LMO evolution to the long-term lunar dichotomy.</abstract>
    </arXiv>

            </metadata>
        </record>

    </GetRecord>
</OAI-PMH>