<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<OAI-PMH xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" 
         xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance"
         xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/OAI-PMH.xsd">
    <responseDate>2026-07-09T20:12:30Z</responseDate>
                <request verb="GetRecord" identifier="oai:arXiv.org:2607.02228v1" metadataPrefix="arXiv">http://oaipmh.arxiv.org/oai</request>


    <GetRecord>
                <record>
                <header>
        <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:2607.02228</identifier>
        <datestamp>2026-07-03</datestamp>
            <setSpec>physics:astro-ph:HE</setSpec>
    </header>

            <metadata>
                        <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ https://oaipmh.arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
        <id>2607.02228</id>
        <created>2026-07-02</created>
            <updated>2026-07-03</updated>
        <authors>
                <author>
                    <keyname>Zhu</keyname>
                        <forenames>Haifan</forenames>
                </author>
                <author>
                    <keyname>Méndez</keyname>
                        <forenames>Mariano</forenames>
                </author>
                <author>
                    <keyname>Chen</keyname>
                        <forenames>Xiao</forenames>
                </author>
                <author>
                    <keyname>Wang</keyname>
                        <forenames>Wei</forenames>
                </author>
        </authors>
        <title>Timing and spectral analysis of the 2025 outburst of 4U 1630$-$47 with \textit{NICER}</title>
            <categories>astro-ph.HE</categories>
            <comments>13 pages, 10 figures, accepted for publication in Astronomy &amp; Astrophysics</comments>
            <license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license>
            <abstract>We analyzed \textit{NICER} observations of the 2025 outburst of the black hole X-ray binary 4U~1630$-$47 to investigate the spectral--timing properties of its transient low-frequency quasi-periodic oscillations (QPOs) and millihertz-scale quasi-regular modulation (QRM). During the rising phase of the outburst, the QPO centroid frequency increased from $\sim 0.24$ Hz to $\sim 3.43$ Hz. Wavelet-based state separation shows that the with-QPO intervals are associated with a higher inner disk temperature and a lower \texttt{diskbb} normalization than the without-QPO intervals, while the photon index ($Γ$) shows weaker changes within the uncertainties. Near the outburst peak, the source displayed a weak QRM at $\sim 0.07$ Hz with a fractional rms amplitude of $\sim 4.7\%$, lower than that of the heartbeat state observed in 2023. Phase-resolved Hilbert--Huang analysis shows that the inner disk temperature is positively correlated with the X-ray flux, the \texttt{diskbb} normalization is anticorrelated, and $Γ$ varies only weakly. Overall, the short-timescale spectral--timing variability is expressed most clearly through the disk-related parameters. The transient QPOs are therefore consistent with short-timescale disk-related variability during the rising phase, whereas the millihertz-scale QRM may represent a weaker heartbeat-like variability mode appearing near the outburst peak.</abstract>
    </arXiv>

            </metadata>
        </record>

    </GetRecord>
</OAI-PMH>