<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<OAI-PMH xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" 
         xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance"
         xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/OAI-PMH.xsd">
    <responseDate>2026-07-13T01:20:26Z</responseDate>
                <request verb="GetRecord" identifier="oai:arXiv.org:2605.06321v2" metadataPrefix="arXiv">http://oaipmh.arxiv.org/oai</request>


    <GetRecord>
                <record>
                <header>
        <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:2605.06321</identifier>
        <datestamp>2026-05-19</datestamp>
            <setSpec>physics:astro-ph:HE</setSpec>
            <setSpec>physics:gr-qc</setSpec>
    </header>

            <metadata>
                        <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ https://oaipmh.arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
        <id>2605.06321</id>
        <created>2026-05-16</created>
            <updated>2026-05-19</updated>
        <authors>
                <author>
                    <keyname>Chen</keyname>
                        <forenames>Zhiwei</forenames>
                </author>
                <author>
                    <keyname>Lu</keyname>
                        <forenames>Youjun</forenames>
                </author>
        </authors>
        <title>Gravitational Lensing of Gravitational Waves from Astrophysical Sources: Theory, Detection, and Applications</title>
            <categories>astro-ph.HE gr-qc</categories>
            <comments>47 pages, 8 figures. Invited review for Research in Astronomy and Astrophysics. Several references added</comments>
            <doi>10.1088/1674-4527/ae4bad</doi>
            <license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license>
            <abstract>Gravitational waves (GWs) from distant sources such as inspiralling and merging stellar-mass compact binaries, intermediate-mass and supermassive-binary-black-hole can be gravitationally lensed by intervening objects, ranging from stars and primordial black holes to galaxies and clusters. Depending on the GW wavelength relative to the lens scale, lensing occurs in two regimes: geometric optics, producing multiple images with time delays and magnifications, and wave optics, resulting in frequency-dependent waveform modulations. Lensed signals are identified via parameter overlap between event pairs or characteristic frequency-dependent modulations that distinguish them from unlensed signals. Detection rates depend on the redshift and mass distributions of sources and lenses, with promising prospects for future observatories. Once confirmed, lensed GWs will be powerful probes of fundamental physics and cosmology: they can constrain dark matter, lensing structures, the Hubble constant, and other cosmological parameters. In this review, we provide a concise overview of GW lensing, covering the theoretical framework, predicted detection rates, search strategies, and applications. We conclude with prospects and future directions for observing and exploiting lensed astrophysical GW events.</abstract>
    </arXiv>

            </metadata>
        </record>

    </GetRecord>
</OAI-PMH>