<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<OAI-PMH xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" 
         xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance"
         xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/OAI-PMH.xsd">
    <responseDate>2026-07-13T06:23:54Z</responseDate>
                <request verb="GetRecord" identifier="oai:arXiv.org:2602.21295" metadataPrefix="arXiv">http://oaipmh.arxiv.org/oai</request>


    <GetRecord>
                <record>
                <header>
        <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:2602.21295</identifier>
        <datestamp>2026-05-13</datestamp>
            <setSpec>physics:astro-ph:CO</setSpec>
            <setSpec>physics:astro-ph:HE</setSpec>
    </header>

            <metadata>
                        <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ https://oaipmh.arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
        <id>2602.21295</id>
        <created>2026-05-11</created>
            <updated>2026-05-13</updated>
        <authors>
                <author>
                    <keyname>Magaraggia</keyname>
                        <forenames>Alberto</forenames>
                </author>
                <author>
                    <keyname>Cappelluti</keyname>
                        <forenames>Nico</forenames>
                </author>
        </authors>
        <title>Implications for Primordial Black Hole Dark Matter from a Single Subsolar Mass Gravitational-wave Detection in LVK O1--O4</title>
            <categories>astro-ph.CO astro-ph.HE</categories>
            <comments>9 pages, 2 figures, Published in ApJ. Title updated to match the accepted journal version; minor revisions to the text</comments>
            <journal-ref>2026 ApJ 1000 262</journal-ref>
            <doi>10.3847/1538-4357/ae48f9</doi>
            <license>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0/</license>
            <abstract>The detection of sub-solar mass black holes is a milestone of modern astrophysics as it would open a window either onto new stellar physics or could potentially unveil the nature of Dark Matter as Primordial Black Holes (PBHs). On November 12, 2025, the LIGO-Virgo-KAGRA (LVK) collaboration reported the compact binary merger candidate S251112cm, a system with no obvious electromagnetic counterpart, consistent with binary black hole merger with a chirp mass in the range $0.1-0.87 \, M_\odot$. The probability that at least one component has mass $&lt;$1 $M_{\odot}$ is $&gt;99\%$. Inspired by this trigger, we tested if a population of PBHs formed at Quantum Chromodynamics epoch with a broad mass function could account for a signal of this type. Our results, corresponding to a predicted event rate of $0.8 \,\text{yr}^{-1}$ as seen by LVK O3b, suggest that the observed merger rate of $0.23^{+0.86}_{-0.218}\,\text{yr}^{-1}\;(95\%\;\text{C.L.})$ if the trigger is confirmed as an astrophysical event would be compatible with such a model. Our predicted detection rate is also in agreement with current LVK expectations for stellar-mass binaries, remaining consistent with a scenario in which a non-negligible fraction of the $3-200 \;M_\odot$ mergers observed by LVK originate from Primordial Black Holes. If confirmed, this detection would place a lower limit to the PBH abundance $f_{PBH}&gt;0.04$ for our adopted model.</abstract>
    </arXiv>

            </metadata>
        </record>

    </GetRecord>
</OAI-PMH>