<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<OAI-PMH xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" 
         xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance"
         xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/OAI-PMH.xsd">
    <responseDate>2026-07-12T23:24:47Z</responseDate>
                <request verb="GetRecord" identifier="oai:arXiv.org:2605.16413v2" metadataPrefix="arXiv">http://oaipmh.arxiv.org/oai</request>


    <GetRecord>
                <record>
                <header>
        <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:2605.16413</identifier>
        <datestamp>2026-05-20</datestamp>
            <setSpec>physics:gr-qc</setSpec>
    </header>

            <metadata>
                        <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ https://oaipmh.arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
        <id>2605.16413</id>
        <created>2026-05-19</created>
            <updated>2026-05-20</updated>
        <authors>
                <author>
                    <keyname>Ishkaeva</keyname>
                        <forenames>Valeria A.</forenames>
                </author>
                <author>
                    <keyname>Sushkov</keyname>
                        <forenames>Sergey V.</forenames>
                </author>
        </authors>
        <title>Image of a wormhole with an arbitrary throat profile</title>
            <categories>gr-qc</categories>
            <comments>15 pages, 20 figures</comments>
            <license>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0/</license>
            <abstract>We investigate the observable signatures -- the shadow, the throat silhouette, and the image of a thin accretion disk -- for a family of static, spherically symmetric wormholes with an arbitrary throat profile. First, we derive expressions for the shadow radius, the throat silhouette radius, and the photon energy shift for a general static, spherically symmetric metric. Then we apply these results to a specific wormhole metric containing three free parameters: the throat radius~$a$, the throat length~$λ$, and the parameter~$u_0$ that controls the depth of the gravitational well. We numerically obtain the shadow and silhouette radii as functions of $λ$, $u_0$, and $a$, construct accretion disk images for three representative parameter sets, and compare the results with those for a Schwarzschild black hole. We find that there exist sets of parameters $a$, $λ$, $u_0$ such that the wormhole shadow and throat silhouette radii coincide with the shadow and event horizon silhouette of a Schwarzschild black hole of the same mass. Nevertheless, the accretion disk images of these objects differ substantially. In wormhole images, the Doppler effect plays a major role, not the gravitational redshift. As a result, the accreting wormhole images appear brighter.</abstract>
    </arXiv>

            </metadata>
        </record>

    </GetRecord>
</OAI-PMH>