<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<OAI-PMH xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" 
         xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance"
         xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/OAI-PMH.xsd">
    <responseDate>2026-07-13T06:24:16Z</responseDate>
                <request verb="GetRecord" identifier="oai:arXiv.org:2604.07435" metadataPrefix="arXiv">http://oaipmh.arxiv.org/oai</request>


    <GetRecord>
                <record>
                <header>
        <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:2604.07435</identifier>
        <datestamp>2026-04-10</datestamp>
            <setSpec>physics:hep-lat</setSpec>
            <setSpec>physics:cond-mat:quant-gas</setSpec>
            <setSpec>physics:cond-mat:str-el</setSpec>
            <setSpec>physics:hep-th</setSpec>
            <setSpec>physics:quant-ph</setSpec>
    </header>

            <metadata>
                        <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ https://oaipmh.arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
        <id>2604.07435</id>
        <created>2026-04-08</created>
            <updated>2026-04-10</updated>
        <authors>
                <author>
                    <keyname>Xu</keyname>
                        <forenames>Kaidi</forenames>
                </author>
                <author>
                    <keyname>Borla</keyname>
                        <forenames>Umberto</forenames>
                </author>
                <author>
                    <keyname>Hemery</keyname>
                        <forenames>Kevin</forenames>
                </author>
                <author>
                    <keyname>Joshi</keyname>
                        <forenames>Rohan</forenames>
                </author>
                <author>
                    <keyname>Dreyer</keyname>
                        <forenames>Henrik</forenames>
                </author>
                <author>
                    <keyname>Rinaldi</keyname>
                        <forenames>Enrico</forenames>
                </author>
                <author>
                    <keyname>Halimeh</keyname>
                        <forenames>Jad C.</forenames>
                </author>
        </authors>
        <title>Observation of glueball excitations and string breaking in a $2+1$D $\mathbb{Z}_2$ lattice gauge theory on a trapped-ion quantum computer</title>
            <categories>hep-lat cond-mat.quant-gas cond-mat.str-el hep-th quant-ph</categories>
            <comments>$12+7$ pages, $4+6$ figures, $0+1$ table. See parallel submission by R. Joshi et al., &#34;Observation of genuine $2+1$D string dynamics in a U$(1)$ lattice gauge theory with a tunable plaquette term on a trapped-ion quantum computer&#39;&#39;</comments>
            <license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license>
            <abstract>A major goal of the quantum simulation of high-energy physics (HEP) is to probe real-time nonperturbative far-from-equilibrium quantum processes underlying phenomena such as hadronization in quantum chromodynamics (QCD). The quantum simulation of the dynamics of confining strings and glueballs, both essential aspects of quark confinement, in a controllable first-principles way is an important step towards this goal. Here, we realize a $\mathbb{Z}_2$ lattice gauge theory in $2+1$D with a tunable plaquette term on a \texttt{Quantinuum System Model H2} trapped-ion quantum computer. We implement a shallow depth-6 Trotter circuit on a $6 \times 5$ matter-site square lattice utilizing all $56$ available qubits to execute over $1000$ entangling gates. We prepare far-from-equilibrium initial string configurations that we quench across a range of parameters to observe rich dynamical phenomena, such as the formation of gauge-invariant closed-loop excitations reminiscent of glueballs in QCD and multi-order string breaking accompanied by spontaneous matter creation. We further demonstrate experimentally that the system displays genuine $2+1$D dynamics, as evidenced by string snapshots over time that cannot be trivially mapped to $1+1$D physics. Our results demonstrate digital quantum simulations of nonequilibrium dynamics in a higher-dimensional lattice gauge theory and provide an experimentally accessible setting for phenomena related to confinement physics.</abstract>
    </arXiv>

            </metadata>
        </record>

    </GetRecord>
</OAI-PMH>