<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<OAI-PMH xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" 
         xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance"
         xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/OAI-PMH.xsd">
    <responseDate>2026-07-13T21:13:44Z</responseDate>
                <request verb="GetRecord" identifier="oai:arXiv.org:2512.05078" metadataPrefix="arXiv">http://oaipmh.arxiv.org/oai</request>


    <GetRecord>
                <record>
                <header>
        <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:2512.05078</identifier>
        <datestamp>2025-12-05</datestamp>
            <setSpec>physics:astro-ph:IM</setSpec>
            <setSpec>physics:astro-ph:GA</setSpec>
    </header>

            <metadata>
                        <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ https://oaipmh.arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
        <id>2512.05078</id>
        <created>2025-12-04</created>
            <updated>2025-12-05</updated>
        <authors>
                <author>
                    <keyname>Yunus</keyname>
                        <forenames>Mikaeel</forenames>
                </author>
                <author>
                    <keyname>Wu</keyname>
                        <forenames>John F.</forenames>
                </author>
                <author>
                    <keyname>Holwerda</keyname>
                        <forenames>Benne W.</forenames>
                </author>
        </authors>
        <title>Improving Posterior Inference of Galaxy Properties with Image-Based Conditional Flow Matching</title>
            <categories>astro-ph.IM astro-ph.GA</categories>
            <comments>Accepted at NeurIPS 2025 ML4PS workshop</comments>
            <license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license>
            <abstract>Estimating physical properties of galaxies from wide-field surveys remains a central challenge in astrophysics. While spectroscopy provides precise measurements, it is observationally expensive, and photometry discards morphological information that correlates with mass, star formation history, metallicity, and dust. We present a conditional flow matching (CFM) framework that leverages pixel-level imaging alongside photometry to improve posterior inference of galaxy properties. Using $\sim10^5$ SDSS galaxies, we compare models trained on photometry alone versus photometry plus images. The image+photometry model outperforms the photometry-only model in posterior inference and more reliably recovers known scaling relations. Morphological information also helps mitigate the dust--age degeneracy. Our results highlight the potential of integrating morphology into photometric SED fitting pipelines, opening a pathway towards more accurate and physically informed constraints on galaxy properties.</abstract>
    </arXiv>

            </metadata>
        </record>

    </GetRecord>
</OAI-PMH>