<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<OAI-PMH xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" 
         xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance"
         xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/OAI-PMH.xsd">
    <responseDate>2026-07-13T21:13:53Z</responseDate>
                <request verb="GetRecord" identifier="oai:arXiv.org:2606.02986" metadataPrefix="arXiv">http://oaipmh.arxiv.org/oai</request>


    <GetRecord>
                <record>
                <header>
        <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:2606.02986</identifier>
        <datestamp>2026-06-03</datestamp>
            <setSpec>physics:quant-ph</setSpec>
    </header>

            <metadata>
                        <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ https://oaipmh.arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
        <id>2606.02986</id>
        <created>2026-06-02</created>
            <updated>2026-06-03</updated>
        <authors>
                <author>
                    <keyname>Maleki</keyname>
                        <forenames>Yusef</forenames>
                </author>
                <author>
                    <keyname>Palma</keyname>
                        <forenames>Luis D. Zambrano</forenames>
                </author>
        </authors>
        <title>Machine-Learning Prediction of Quantum Fisher Information from Collective Spin and Spectral Features</title>
            <categories>quant-ph</categories>
            <comments>13 pages, 7 figures</comments>
            <license>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0/</license>
            <abstract>Quantum Fisher information (QFI) is a fundamental quantifier in quantum metrology, determining the ultimate precision achievable in parameter-estimation protocols through the quantum Cramér-Rao bound. However, direct evaluation of the QFI generally requires detailed knowledge of the density matrix, making it increasingly demanding as the Hilbert-space dimension grows. In this work, we investigate the extent to which the QFI of multipartite quantum systems can be predicted from a limited set of experimentally accessible quantities using support vector regression (SVR). By comparing different physically motivated features, we identify a dominant feature set governing QFI and show that the predictive power of collective spin moments alone decreases as system size and consequently Hilbert-space dimension grows. We demonstrate that QFI is governed primarily by the interplay between collective covariance and low-order spectral moments of the density matrix. Our results identify the physically relevant information sectors governing the QFI and demonstrate that accurate estimation of metrological sensitivity can be achieved from a restricted set of experimentally accessible quantities without requiring full quantum-state tomography.</abstract>
    </arXiv>

            </metadata>
        </record>

    </GetRecord>
</OAI-PMH>