<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<OAI-PMH xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" 
         xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance"
         xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/OAI-PMH.xsd">
    <responseDate>2026-07-12T15:15:26Z</responseDate>
                <request verb="GetRecord" identifier="oai:arXiv.org:2505.02057v4" metadataPrefix="arXiv">http://oaipmh.arxiv.org/oai</request>


    <GetRecord>
                <record>
                <header>
        <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:2505.02057</identifier>
        <datestamp>2026-01-14</datestamp>
            <setSpec>physics:quant-ph</setSpec>
    </header>

            <metadata>
                        <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ https://oaipmh.arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
        <id>2505.02057</id>
        <created>2026-01-13</created>
            <updated>2026-01-14</updated>
        <authors>
                <author>
                    <keyname>Caleffi</keyname>
                        <forenames>Marcello</forenames>
                </author>
                <author>
                    <keyname>d&#39;Avossa</keyname>
                        <forenames>Laura</forenames>
                </author>
                <author>
                    <keyname>Han</keyname>
                        <forenames>Xu</forenames>
                </author>
                <author>
                    <keyname>Cacciapuoti</keyname>
                        <forenames>Angela Sara</forenames>
                </author>
        </authors>
        <title>Quantum Transduction: Enabling Quantum Networking</title>
            <categories>quant-ph</categories>
            <comments>Accepted manuscript for publication in IEEE Communications Surveys &amp; Tutorials 2025. This work has been funded by the European Union under Horizon Europe ERG-CoG grant QNattyNet (&#34;Quantum-Native Communication Networks: from Quantum Message to Quantum Functioning&#34;), n.101169850. Details at http://qnattynet.quantuminternet.it</comments>
            <journal-ref>IEEE Communications Surveys &amp; Tutorials 2025</journal-ref>
            <doi>10.1109/COMST.2025.3631150</doi>
            <license>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0/</license>
            <abstract>The complementary features of different qubit platforms for computing and communicating impose an intrinsic hardware heterogeneity in any quantum network, where nodes, while processing and storing quantum information, must also communicate through quantum links. Indeed, one of the most promising hardware platforms at quantum node scale for scalable and fast quantum computing is the superconducting technology, which operates at microwave frequencies. Whereas, for communicating at distances of practical interest beyond few meters, quantum links should operate at optical frequencies. Therefore, to allow the interaction between superconducting and photonic technologies, a quantum interface, known as quantum transducer, able to convert one type of qubit to another is required. This paper aims to provide a tutorial treatise on the fundamental research challenges of quantum transduction. The tutorial is structured around a communications engineering framework, thereby shedding light on its fundamental role in quantum network design and deployment -- a perspective often overlooked in existing literature. This framework allows us to categorize different transduction modalities and to reveal an unorthodox one where the transducer itself can act as an entanglement source. From this standpoint, it is possible to conceive different source-destination link archetypes, where transduction plays a crucial role in the communication performances. The analysis also translates the quantum transduction process into a proper functional block within a new communication system model for a quantum network.</abstract>
    </arXiv>

            </metadata>
        </record>

    </GetRecord>
</OAI-PMH>