<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<OAI-PMH xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" 
         xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance"
         xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/OAI-PMH.xsd">
    <responseDate>2026-07-11T08:09:22Z</responseDate>
                <request verb="GetRecord" identifier="oai:arXiv.org:2606.14738v1" metadataPrefix="arXiv">http://oaipmh.arxiv.org/oai</request>


    <GetRecord>
                <record>
                <header>
        <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:2606.14738</identifier>
        <datestamp>2026-06-16</datestamp>
            <setSpec>physics:physics:geo-ph</setSpec>
            <setSpec>physics:astro-ph:EP</setSpec>
            <setSpec>physics:astro-ph:IM</setSpec>
            <setSpec>physics:physics:ao-ph</setSpec>
            <setSpec>physics:physics:ins-det</setSpec>
            <setSpec>physics:physics:space-ph</setSpec>
    </header>

            <metadata>
                        <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ https://oaipmh.arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
        <id>2606.14738</id>
        <created>2026-06-02</created>
            <updated>2026-06-16</updated>
        <authors>
                <author>
                    <keyname>Fuchs</keyname>
                        <forenames>Tim M.</forenames>
                </author>
                <author>
                    <keyname>Simcox</keyname>
                        <forenames>Elliot</forenames>
                </author>
                <author>
                    <keyname>Hawker</keyname>
                        <forenames>Michael</forenames>
                </author>
                <author>
                    <keyname>Headley</keyname>
                        <forenames>Francis J.</forenames>
                </author>
                <author>
                    <keyname>Ulbricht</keyname>
                        <forenames>Hendrik</forenames>
                </author>
        </authors>
        <title>Detection of the Earth Tides by Diamagnetic Levitation</title>
            <categories>physics.geo-ph astro-ph.EP astro-ph.IM physics.ao-ph physics.ins-det physics.space-ph</categories>
            <comments>22 pages, 12 figures, Comments welcomed</comments>
            <license>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0/</license>
            <abstract>The detection of mass distributions and mass transport via gravity mapping is a key geophysical tool for understanding the structure and dynamics of the earth. Changes in mass distribution, driven by natural processes and human activity (e.g., extraction of oil, gas, and minerals), contribute to observable phenomena such as sea-level rise (3 mm per year), increased flooding, landslides, and ice mass loss (hundreds of giga-tons per year). These processes generate gravity variations detectable by gravimeters and gradiometers on ground and in space. Current instruments achieve sensitivities of 10-100 micro-GAL per square root of Hz and enable applications including hydrocarbon exploration, volcanic monitoring, and subsurface detection. They also measure Earth tides (100-300 micro-GAL amplitude), requiring long-term stability over days. However, existing systems are limited by size (more than 8 kg) and cost (more than 100,000 USD), restricting widespread deployment. Here we demonstrate a levitated mechanical sensor (LOMS) with a demonstrated sensitivity of 18 micro-GAL, a large dynamical range, and an integration time of 6 s, with an expected sensitivity of smaller than 200 nano-GAL per square root of Hz in a volume of only a few cubic cm. We resolve earth tide signals, demonstrating stability comparable to state-of-the-art instruments. Unlike conventional accelerometers (micro-g sensitivity, low stability), our device operates as a true gravimeter. Its compact size and low projected cost enable scalable deployment, including drone-based surveys (10-100 m altitude), distributed sensor networks, and multipixel gravity imaging arrays. This platform enables high-resolution, cost-effective gravity mapping with potential for large-scale geophysical monitoring.</abstract>
    </arXiv>

            </metadata>
        </record>

    </GetRecord>
</OAI-PMH>