<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<OAI-PMH xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" 
         xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance"
         xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/OAI-PMH.xsd">
    <responseDate>2026-07-11T09:17:09Z</responseDate>
                <request verb="GetRecord" identifier="oai:arXiv.org:2606.04462v1" metadataPrefix="arXiv">http://oaipmh.arxiv.org/oai</request>


    <GetRecord>
                <record>
                <header>
        <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:2606.04462</identifier>
        <datestamp>2026-06-04</datestamp>
            <setSpec>physics:astro-ph:GA</setSpec>
    </header>

            <metadata>
                        <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ https://oaipmh.arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
        <id>2606.04462</id>
        <created>2026-06-03</created>
            <updated>2026-06-04</updated>
        <authors>
                <author>
                    <keyname>Wang</keyname>
                        <forenames>Hai-Feng</forenames>
                </author>
                <author>
                    <keyname>Wang</keyname>
                        <forenames>Guan-Yu</forenames>
                </author>
                <author>
                    <keyname>Carraro</keyname>
                        <forenames>Giovanni</forenames>
                </author>
                <author>
                    <keyname>Tautvaišienė</keyname>
                        <forenames>Gražina</forenames>
                </author>
                <author>
                    <keyname>Bland-Hawthorn</keyname>
                        <forenames>Joss</forenames>
                </author>
                <author>
                    <keyname>Tepper-García</keyname>
                        <forenames>Thor</forenames>
                </author>
        </authors>
        <title>A More Complex Than Expected Formation History of the Milky Way&#39;s Last Major Merger</title>
            <categories>astro-ph.GA</categories>
            <comments>25 pages, 12 figures</comments>
            <license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license>
            <abstract>The Gaia$-$Sausage$-$Enceladus (GSE) structure, widely recognized as the most recent major accretion event experienced by our Galaxy, is traditionally interpreted as the remnant of a single ancient merger that played a significant role in building the Milky Way&#39;s inner halo. Most previous studies have characterized the GSE as a kinematically coherent population that originated from either a single progenitor or a recent infall event. Here, we present evidence for a more complex origin, based on data from the DESI and a novel unsupervised clustering algorithm, GS$^3$ Hunter. Applying this method to local halo stars near the solar neighborhood, we identify 17 structures, including known systems such as Sequoia and GSE, as well as several previously unrecognized structures/stellar streams. A more detailed analysis incorporating chronological, dynamical, and chemical dimensions reveals four distinct substructures within the GSE region, herein designated GSE$-$GSH1 (12 Gyr), GSE$-$GSH2 (10 Gyr), GSE$-$GSH3 (8 Gyr), and GSE$-$GSH4 (7 Gyr). Although all four are broadly consistent with the overall phase$-$space distribution and abundance patterns of the GSE, they display markedly distinct orbital actions and chemical abundances relative to previously reported results. This finding reveals an unprecedented level of internal complexity in the GSE&#39;s formation history and supports a scenario in which the GSE is not the remnant of a single accretion event, but rather a composite structure assembled through multiple, sequential merger episodes during the early Milky Way.</abstract>
    </arXiv>

            </metadata>
        </record>

    </GetRecord>
</OAI-PMH>