<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<OAI-PMH xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" 
         xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance"
         xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/OAI-PMH.xsd">
    <responseDate>2026-07-13T06:21:24Z</responseDate>
                <request verb="GetRecord" identifier="oai:arXiv.org:2510.19976" metadataPrefix="arXiv">http://oaipmh.arxiv.org/oai</request>


    <GetRecord>
                <record>
                <header>
        <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:2510.19976</identifier>
        <datestamp>2025-10-24</datestamp>
            <setSpec>physics:quant-ph</setSpec>
            <setSpec>physics:physics:bio-ph</setSpec>
    </header>

            <metadata>
                        <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ https://oaipmh.arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
        <id>2510.19976</id>
        <created>2025-10-22</created>
            <updated>2025-10-24</updated>
        <authors>
                <author>
                    <keyname>Bajpai</keyname>
                        <forenames>Suyash</forenames>
                </author>
                <author>
                    <keyname>Lucas-DeMott</keyname>
                        <forenames>Aviva</forenames>
                </author>
                <author>
                    <keyname>Murugan</keyname>
                        <forenames>Nirosha J</forenames>
                </author>
                <author>
                    <keyname>Levin</keyname>
                        <forenames>Michael</forenames>
                </author>
                <author>
                    <keyname>Kurian</keyname>
                        <forenames>Philip</forenames>
                </author>
        </authors>
        <title>Morphological computational capacity of Physarum polycephalum</title>
            <categories>quant-ph physics.bio-ph</categories>
            <license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license>
            <abstract>While computational capacity limits of the universe and carbon-based life have been estimated, a stricter bound for aneural organisms has not been established. Physarum polycephalum, a unicellular, multinucleated amoeba, is capable of complex problem-solving despite lacking neurons. By analyzing growth dynamics in two distinct Physarum strains under diverse biological conditions, we map morphological evolution to information processing. As the Margolus-Levitin theorem constrains maximum computation rates by accessible energies, we analyze high-throughput time-series data of Physarum&#39;s morphology--quantified through area, perimeter, circularity, and fractal dimension-to determine upper bounds on the number of logical operations achievable through its hydromechanical, chemical, kinetic, and quantum-optical degrees of freedom. Based on spatial distribution of ATP and explored areas, Physarum can perform up to ~$10^{36}$ logical operations in 24 hours, scaling linearly in the non-equilibrium steady state. This framework enables comparison of the computational capacities of life, exploiting either classical or quantum degrees of freedom.</abstract>
    </arXiv>

            </metadata>
        </record>

    </GetRecord>
</OAI-PMH>