<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<OAI-PMH xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" 
         xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance"
         xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/OAI-PMH.xsd">
    <responseDate>2026-07-13T09:49:21Z</responseDate>
                <request verb="GetRecord" identifier="oai:arXiv.org:2605.26490" metadataPrefix="arXiv">http://oaipmh.arxiv.org/oai</request>


    <GetRecord>
                <record>
                <header>
        <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:2605.26490</identifier>
        <datestamp>2026-05-27</datestamp>
            <setSpec>physics:gr-qc</setSpec>
            <setSpec>physics:hep-th</setSpec>
            <setSpec>physics:quant-ph</setSpec>
    </header>

            <metadata>
                        <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ https://oaipmh.arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
        <id>2605.26490</id>
        <created>2026-05-26</created>
            <updated>2026-05-27</updated>
        <authors>
                <author>
                    <keyname>Poopathysankar</keyname>
                        <forenames>P.</forenames>
                </author>
                <author>
                    <keyname>Hackl</keyname>
                        <forenames>Lucas</forenames>
                </author>
                <author>
                    <keyname>Chakraborty</keyname>
                        <forenames>Anwesha</forenames>
                </author>
        </authors>
        <title>Probing Spacetime Topology and Superposition with Accelerated Detectors</title>
            <categories>gr-qc hep-th quant-ph</categories>
            <comments>14 pages, 4 figures</comments>
            <license>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0/</license>
            <abstract>We study entanglement harvested by Unruh DeWitt detectors following Rindler trajectories in compactified and superposed Minkowski spacetime. We consider different directions of acceleration (both parallel and antiparallel), separation between detectors and direction of spatial compactification mutually perpendicular to each other. Using the standard entanglement harvesting protocol, we analyze how these features influence the extracted correlations. When detector separation is perpendicular to the direction of acceleration, the harvested entanglement is uniformly suppressed due to increased spacelike separation. Compactification enhances field correlations leading to an increased concurrence and an extended harvesting range at higher accelerations. Additionally, we show that spacetime superposition introduces interference effects that further enlarge the entanglement harvesting region in parameter space, particularly in the high acceleration regime. We also find that the effect of antiparallel acceleration yielding significantly higher entanglement than parallel acceleration prevails in compactified and superposed spacetime.</abstract>
    </arXiv>

            </metadata>
        </record>

    </GetRecord>
</OAI-PMH>