<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<OAI-PMH xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" 
         xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance"
         xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/OAI-PMH.xsd">
    <responseDate>2026-07-13T06:28:20Z</responseDate>
                <request verb="GetRecord" identifier="oai:arXiv.org:2604.21402" metadataPrefix="arXiv">http://oaipmh.arxiv.org/oai</request>


    <GetRecord>
                <record>
                <header>
        <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:2604.21402</identifier>
        <datestamp>2026-04-24</datestamp>
            <setSpec>physics:astro-ph:SR</setSpec>
    </header>

            <metadata>
                        <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ https://oaipmh.arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
        <id>2604.21402</id>
        <created>2026-04-23</created>
            <updated>2026-04-24</updated>
        <authors>
                <author>
                    <keyname>Bao</keyname>
                        <forenames>Yuchen</forenames>
                </author>
                <author>
                    <keyname>Li</keyname>
                        <forenames>Zhenwei</forenames>
                </author>
                <author>
                    <keyname>Ge</keyname>
                        <forenames>Hongwei</forenames>
                </author>
                <author>
                    <keyname>Chen</keyname>
                        <forenames>Hailiang</forenames>
                </author>
                <author>
                    <keyname>Jiang</keyname>
                        <forenames>Dengkai</forenames>
                </author>
                <author>
                    <keyname>Chen</keyname>
                        <forenames>Xuefei</forenames>
                </author>
                <author>
                    <keyname>Han</keyname>
                        <forenames>Zhanwen</forenames>
                </author>
        </authors>
        <title>A New Pathway to Single Be Stars: Ejected Companions from Type Ia Supernovae</title>
            <categories>astro-ph.SR</categories>
            <comments>accepted for publication in RAA</comments>
            <license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license>
            <abstract>Be stars are rapid rotators generally produced by binary interactions. The single Be stars in the observations pose challenges to the Be star formation theory. In this paper, we propose a new pathway for the formation of single Be stars, in which the Be star is taken as the ejected companion star from a Type Ia supernova (SN Ia) explosion. Recent numerical simulations suggest that explosive oxygen burning, initiated via the convective Urca process in certain helium (He) stars near the Chandrasekhar mass limit, can set off a SN Ia. Based on this proposition, we further demonstrate that about $0.4\%$ of He star + main-sequence (MS) star binaries may evolve into single Be stars, where the MS star is spun up due to the mass accretion from the He star, and then the He star explodes as a SN Ia. We employ detailed binary evolutionary simulations and find the parameter space that would produce single Be stars via the SN Ia channel. Around $22\%$ of Be stars from the SN Ia progenitor channel exhibit peculiar tangential velocities exceeding $24\ \rm km/s$, classifying them as runaway stars. This suggests that the SN Ia channel plays a meaningful role in forming single Be stars, particularly within the runaway star population.</abstract>
    </arXiv>

            </metadata>
        </record>

    </GetRecord>
</OAI-PMH>