<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<OAI-PMH xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" 
         xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance"
         xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/OAI-PMH.xsd">
    <responseDate>2026-07-08T08:07:45Z</responseDate>
                <request verb="GetRecord" identifier="oai:arXiv.org:2607.01330v1" metadataPrefix="arXiv">http://oaipmh.arxiv.org/oai</request>


    <GetRecord>
                <record>
                <header>
        <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:2607.01330</identifier>
        <datestamp>2026-07-03</datestamp>
            <setSpec>physics:astro-ph:GA</setSpec>
    </header>

            <metadata>
                        <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ https://oaipmh.arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
        <id>2607.01330</id>
        <created>2026-07-01</created>
            <updated>2026-07-03</updated>
        <authors>
                <author>
                    <keyname>Ma</keyname>
                        <forenames>Guozhen</forenames>
                </author>
                <author>
                    <keyname>Geier</keyname>
                        <forenames>Stefan J.</forenames>
                </author>
                <author>
                    <keyname>Fynbo</keyname>
                        <forenames>Johan P. U.</forenames>
                </author>
                <author>
                    <keyname>Christensen</keyname>
                        <forenames>Lise</forenames>
                </author>
                <author>
                    <keyname>Berdyugin</keyname>
                        <forenames>Andrei</forenames>
                </author>
                <author>
                    <keyname>Frederiksen</keyname>
                        <forenames>Rasmus</forenames>
                </author>
                <author>
                    <keyname>Heintz</keyname>
                        <forenames>Kasper E.</forenames>
                </author>
                <author>
                    <keyname>Henriksen</keyname>
                        <forenames>Phillip D.</forenames>
                </author>
                <author>
                    <keyname>Krogager</keyname>
                        <forenames>Jens-Kristian</forenames>
                </author>
                <author>
                    <keyname>Ledoux</keyname>
                        <forenames>Cédric</forenames>
                </author>
                <author>
                    <keyname>Piirola</keyname>
                        <forenames>Vilppu</forenames>
                </author>
                <author>
                    <keyname>Møller</keyname>
                        <forenames>Palle</forenames>
                </author>
                <author>
                    <keyname>Vejlgaard</keyname>
                        <forenames>Simone</forenames>
                </author>
                <author>
                    <keyname>Choi</keyname>
                        <forenames>Hyunseop</forenames>
                </author>
        </authors>
        <title>Extreme outflow velocities and weak UV emission lines indicate quasars shedding their dust cocoons</title>
            <categories>astro-ph.GA</categories>
            <comments>30 pages, 27 figures, accepted for publication in A&amp;A</comments>
            <license>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0/</license>
            <abstract>The recently discovered low-ionisation broad absorption line (LoBAL) quasar GQ 1309$+$2904 is unusual due to its very broad, highly blueshifted absorption troughs and an absence of broad emission lines except for ${\mathrm{H} α}$. In this paper, we present observations of six quasars that appear very similar to GQ 1309$+$2904 in the rest-frame ultraviolet (UV). We measure the systemic redshifts of these quasars to be $z\approx$ 2.07--3.28 from detected ${\mathrm{H} α}$ emission lines. We confirm that all targets are quasars with highly blueshifted BALs possessing high-speed outflows with velocities up to $\sim 0.16\,c$, and five of them are confidently identified as LoBAL quasars. Based on ${\mathrm{H} α}$ emission, black hole masses and Eddington ratios of these quasars are $M_{\mathrm{BH}} \approx 10^{8.7}$--$10^{9.4}\,M_{\odot}$ and $L_{\mathrm{bol}} / L_{\mathrm{Edd}} \approx$ 0.14--0.34, indicating that their central black holes are very massive and active. Every quasar in our sample exhibits a very flat or reddened continuum. The spectral shapes of three objects are well-fitted by a normal quasar composite reddened by a Small-Magellanic-Cloud-like (SMC-like) extinction curve, while the other three require a steeper extinction law. Broad-band ($BVR$) polarimetry for two of the latter group (plus GQ 1309$+$2904) reveals their low polarisations, consistent with low inclination (more face-on) angles. We propose that these objects are weak emission-line quasars (WLQs) observed through the disc wind, caught emerging from their dust cocoons. As quasars shed their cocoons, dust grains in the disc wind are shattered into smaller particles, producing the UV-steeper extinction curve observed along the outflow. We present a schematic illustration of this shedding process that can account for the peculiar spectral features observed in our sample.</abstract>
    </arXiv>

            </metadata>
        </record>

    </GetRecord>
</OAI-PMH>