<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<OAI-PMH xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" 
         xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance"
         xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/OAI-PMH.xsd">
    <responseDate>2026-07-13T06:21:02Z</responseDate>
                <request verb="GetRecord" identifier="oai:arXiv.org:2508.17300" metadataPrefix="arXiv">http://oaipmh.arxiv.org/oai</request>


    <GetRecord>
                <record>
                <header>
        <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:2508.17300</identifier>
        <datestamp>2025-09-09</datestamp>
            <setSpec>physics:gr-qc</setSpec>
            <setSpec>physics:astro-ph:HE</setSpec>
    </header>

            <metadata>
                        <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ https://oaipmh.arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
        <id>2508.17300</id>
        <created>2025-09-06</created>
            <updated>2025-09-09</updated>
        <authors>
                <author>
                    <keyname>Feleppa</keyname>
                        <forenames>Fabiano</forenames>
                </author>
                <author>
                    <keyname>Tamburini</keyname>
                        <forenames>Fabrizio</forenames>
                </author>
                <author>
                    <keyname>Lambiase</keyname>
                        <forenames>Gaetano</forenames>
                </author>
        </authors>
        <title>Charge constraint on M87* with twisted light</title>
            <categories>gr-qc astro-ph.HE</categories>
            <comments>7 pages, 1 figure; v2: typos corrected, published version</comments>
            <journal-ref>Journal of High Energy Astrophysics 49, 100455 (2026)</journal-ref>
            <doi>10.1016/j.jheap.2025.100455</doi>
            <license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license>
            <abstract>We propose a novel method to constrain the electric charge of the supermassive black hole M87* by analyzing the orbital angular momentum content of the light it emits. By leveraging the established analogy between rotating spacetimes and inhomogeneous optical media, we derive a simple analytical formula that relates the average orbital angular momentum in the observed radiation to the black hole&#39;s charge-to-mass ratio. Applying this relation to existing observational data, we place an upper bound of $\mathcal{Q}/M \lesssim 0.39$ on the charge of M87*. While the analysis focuses on electric charge, which is used here purely as a theoretical example since astrophysical black holes are expected to be approximately neutral, the method is general and can be extended to constrain other types of charges $\unicode{x2013}$ degrees of freedom that define distinct black hole solutions. These results demonstrate the potential of orbital angular momentum as a new fundamental degree of freedom to be exploited in astrophysics, providing a complementary and independent alternative to shadow-based techniques for probing the properties of rotating compact objects and testing gravity in the strong-field regime.</abstract>
    </arXiv>

            </metadata>
        </record>

    </GetRecord>
</OAI-PMH>