<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<OAI-PMH xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" 
         xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance"
         xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/OAI-PMH.xsd">
    <responseDate>2026-07-13T06:24:04Z</responseDate>
                <request verb="GetRecord" identifier="oai:arXiv.org:2603.19631" metadataPrefix="arXiv">http://oaipmh.arxiv.org/oai</request>


    <GetRecord>
                <record>
                <header>
        <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:2603.19631</identifier>
        <datestamp>2026-03-23</datestamp>
            <setSpec>physics:quant-ph</setSpec>
    </header>

            <metadata>
                        <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ https://oaipmh.arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
        <id>2603.19631</id>
        <created>2026-03-20</created>
            <updated>2026-03-23</updated>
        <authors>
                <author>
                    <keyname>Pi</keyname>
                        <forenames>Jiahao</forenames>
                </author>
                <author>
                    <keyname>Liu</keyname>
                        <forenames>Xiangjia</forenames>
                </author>
                <author>
                    <keyname>Cao</keyname>
                        <forenames>Junle</forenames>
                </author>
                <author>
                    <keyname>Wang</keyname>
                        <forenames>Pengfei</forenames>
                </author>
                <author>
                    <keyname>Ou</keyname>
                        <forenames>Lingfeng</forenames>
                </author>
                <author>
                    <keyname>Gao</keyname>
                        <forenames>Erfu</forenames>
                </author>
                <author>
                    <keyname>Tu</keyname>
                        <forenames>Hengchao</forenames>
                </author>
                <author>
                    <keyname>Zou</keyname>
                        <forenames>Menglin</forenames>
                </author>
                <author>
                    <keyname>Zhang</keyname>
                        <forenames>Xiang</forenames>
                </author>
                <author>
                    <keyname>Zhang</keyname>
                        <forenames>Junhua</forenames>
                </author>
                <author>
                    <keyname>Kim</keyname>
                        <forenames>Kihwan</forenames>
                </author>
        </authors>
        <title>Beyond-Ten-Hour Coherence in a Decoherence-Free Trapped-Ion Clock Qubit</title>
            <categories>quant-ph</categories>
            <license>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0/</license>
            <abstract>Quantum systems promise to revolutionize information processing science and technology [1-3]. The preservation of quantum coherence, the defining property of qubits, fundamentally constrains the performance of quantum information processing with quantum memories [4]. While trapped atomic ions theoretically support million-year coherence based on spontaneous emission [5-7], experimental demonstrations have reached far less, only about an hour [8-13]. Here we combine clock-state qubits with decoherence-free subspace (DFS) encoding to achieve coherence exceeding ten hours. Using correlation-based phase tracking in 171Yb+ ion pairs sympathetically cooled by 138Ba+ ion, we demonstrate this without magnetic shielding or enhanced microwave phase stabilization that previously limited coherence times. DFS encoding references the qubit phase to the inter-ion energy difference to reject microwave phase noise and common-mode magnetic fluctuations, while clock states provide environmental insensitivity. Throughout measurements extended to 1600 seconds, we observe minimal coherence decay, with exponential fits yielding a coherence time of (3.77 +/- 1.09) x 10^4 seconds. Our results establish DFS encoding as a form of passive error correction that eliminates technical noise constraints, unlocking the million-year coherence potential of atomic ions for scalable quantum information processing.</abstract>
    </arXiv>

            </metadata>
        </record>

    </GetRecord>
</OAI-PMH>