<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<OAI-PMH xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" 
         xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance"
         xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/OAI-PMH.xsd">
    <responseDate>2026-07-12T20:55:57Z</responseDate>
                <request verb="GetRecord" identifier="oai:arXiv.org:2605.02446v2" metadataPrefix="arXiv">http://oaipmh.arxiv.org/oai</request>


    <GetRecord>
                <record>
                <header>
        <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:2605.02446</identifier>
        <datestamp>2026-06-02</datestamp>
            <setSpec>physics:hep-th</setSpec>
            <setSpec>physics:gr-qc</setSpec>
            <setSpec>physics:quant-ph</setSpec>
    </header>

            <metadata>
                        <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ https://oaipmh.arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
        <id>2605.02446</id>
        <created>2026-05-30</created>
            <updated>2026-06-02</updated>
        <authors>
                <author>
                    <keyname>Liu</keyname>
                        <forenames>Yan</forenames>
                </author>
                <author>
                    <keyname>Sun</keyname>
                        <forenames>Ya-Wen</forenames>
                </author>
                <author>
                    <keyname>Wang</keyname>
                        <forenames>Yuan-Tai</forenames>
                </author>
        </authors>
        <title>Quantum scars from holographic boson stars</title>
            <categories>hep-th gr-qc quant-ph</categories>
            <comments>13 pages, 8 figures, added numerical computation and updated bibliography</comments>
            <license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license>
            <abstract>Quantum many-body scars are atypical nonthermal states embedded in the chaotic spectrum that evade conventional ergodicity. We propose the asymptotically AdS mini-boson star as a holographic candidate for scar-like states. Their spectrum exhibits random-matrix signatures of chaos while supporting embedded integrable spectral branches. The whole holographic system, including black holes, is generically chaotic with most eigenstates satisfying the eigenstate thermalization hypothesis; in contrast, the boson star macrostate probes a near-integrable subsector within this chaotic spectrum, signaling scarred spectral structures. Boson stars further display anomalously low entanglement relative to black holes at the same energy density, and also robust revivals in Krylov complexity, revealing nonergodic dynamics. These spectral, entanglement, and dynamical diagnostics provide unified evidence for holographic quantum scars in a self-gravitating system. Our work suggests a new connection between many-body scar physics, quantum chaos, and horizonless gravitational dynamics.</abstract>
    </arXiv>

            </metadata>
        </record>

    </GetRecord>
</OAI-PMH>