<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<OAI-PMH xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" 
         xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance"
         xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/OAI-PMH.xsd">
    <responseDate>2026-07-11T10:47:28Z</responseDate>
                <request verb="GetRecord" identifier="oai:arXiv.org:2606.06884v1" metadataPrefix="arXiv">http://oaipmh.arxiv.org/oai</request>


    <GetRecord>
                <record>
                <header>
        <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:2606.06884</identifier>
        <datestamp>2026-06-08</datestamp>
            <setSpec>physics:astro-ph:HE</setSpec>
            <setSpec>physics:astro-ph:EP</setSpec>
            <setSpec>physics:astro-ph:SR</setSpec>
            <setSpec>physics:gr-qc</setSpec>
    </header>

            <metadata>
                        <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ https://oaipmh.arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
        <id>2606.06884</id>
        <created>2026-06-05</created>
            <updated>2026-06-08</updated>
        <authors>
                <author>
                    <keyname>Pandey</keyname>
                        <forenames>Shreesham</forenames>
                </author>
                <author>
                    <keyname>Singh</keyname>
                        <forenames>Sunita</forenames>
                </author>
        </authors>
        <title>Tidal Disruption of Blanets in Kerr Spacetime</title>
            <categories>astro-ph.HE astro-ph.EP astro-ph.SR gr-qc</categories>
            <comments>9 pages; 10 figures</comments>
            <license>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-sa/4.0/</license>
            <abstract>Blanets are planetary-mass bodies ($20$--$3000\,\Me$) that may orbit supermassive black holes (SMBHs) in the circumnuclear disks of active galactic nuclei (AGN). We examine tidal disruption events produced by blanet--SMBH encounters, from the test-particle limit to massive planetary bodies in Kerr spacetime. Using the geodesic deviation equation and the Kerr tidal tensor, we derive disruption criteria, tidal radii, and Hills masses for planetary-mass objects, and show that blanet TDEs can remain observable for SMBHs up to $\sim10^{10}\,\Msun$, well above the stellar Hills mass of $\sim10^8\,\Msun$. The fallback rate retains the usual $t^{-5/3}$ form, but the peak timescales are shorter -- from hours to months -- with lower peak accretion rates and multi-wavelength signatures that differ from those of stellar TDEs. We also examine orbital stability, including Keplerian precession, Lense--Thirring nodal precession, migration in the circumnuclear disk, and the Kozai--Lidov resonance, and identify the region where blanets can survive before disruption. We derive relativistic corrections to the tidal radius, spin-dependent disruption thresholds, and the effect of Kerr spin on the disruption geometry. We also discuss gravitational-wave emission from blanet debris EMRIs and the prospects for LISA detection, which may help in interpreting unusual TDE-like transients in AGN environments.</abstract>
    </arXiv>

            </metadata>
        </record>

    </GetRecord>
</OAI-PMH>