<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<OAI-PMH xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" 
         xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance"
         xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/OAI-PMH.xsd">
    <responseDate>2026-07-13T06:28:20Z</responseDate>
                <request verb="GetRecord" identifier="oai:arXiv.org:2604.21005" metadataPrefix="arXiv">http://oaipmh.arxiv.org/oai</request>


    <GetRecord>
                <record>
                <header>
        <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:2604.21005</identifier>
        <datestamp>2026-07-07</datestamp>
            <setSpec>physics:physics:chem-ph</setSpec>
            <setSpec>physics:astro-ph:GA</setSpec>
            <setSpec>physics:physics:comp-ph</setSpec>
            <setSpec>physics:quant-ph</setSpec>
    </header>

            <metadata>
                        <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ https://oaipmh.arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
        <id>2604.21005</id>
        <created>2026-04-22</created>
            <updated>2026-07-07</updated>
        <authors>
                <author>
                    <keyname>Dastider</keyname>
                        <forenames>Saptarshi G.</forenames>
                </author>
                <author>
                    <keyname>Prashant</keyname>
                        <forenames>K.</forenames>
                </author>
                <author>
                    <keyname>Shruti</keyname>
                        <forenames>P.</forenames>
                </author>
                <author>
                    <keyname>Sudheesh</keyname>
                        <forenames>C.</forenames>
                </author>
                <author>
                    <keyname>Cyriac</keyname>
                        <forenames>Jobin</forenames>
                </author>
        </authors>
        <title>Chaos Gated Tunneling Drives Molecular Reactivity in Astrophysical Environments</title>
            <categories>physics.chem-ph astro-ph.GA physics.comp-ph quant-ph</categories>
            <journal-ref>Discov Sp 130, 15 (2026)</journal-ref>
            <doi>10.1007/s11038-026-09595-1</doi>
            <license>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0/</license>
            <abstract>Accurate modeling of ion-molecule reaction networks is essential for understanding the chemical evolution of planetary ionospheres, particularly for giant planets where proton-transfer chains drive atmospheric composition. However, predicting reaction rates in these ultracold environments remains a challenge due to the non-trivial interplay between vibrational dynamics and quantum tunneling. In this work we present a chaos-diagnostic framework that integrates multireference electronic structure theory, Adiabatic Gauge Potentials (AGP), and Random Matrix Theory (RMT) to characterize the microscopic dynamics of proton transport. Using the formation of H+3 and the proton-bound cluster H+5 as representative model systems relevant to Jovian atmospheres, we demonstrate that the transition state acts as a dynamical bottleneck where quantum chaos is notably suppressed, effectively enhancing tunneling probabilities. We introduce a fragility index based on the AGP slope to quantify how specific vibrational modes reintroduce chaos and suppress reactivity. This diagnostic approach offers a generalizable, data-driven metric for identifying vibrationally gated pathways in complex astrochemical networks, providing a theoretical basis for refining kinetic models of planetary and interstellar plasmas</abstract>
    </arXiv>

            </metadata>
        </record>

    </GetRecord>
</OAI-PMH>