<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<OAI-PMH xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" 
         xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance"
         xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/OAI-PMH.xsd">
    <responseDate>2026-07-13T06:28:25Z</responseDate>
                <request verb="GetRecord" identifier="oai:arXiv.org:2605.10476" metadataPrefix="arXiv">http://oaipmh.arxiv.org/oai</request>


    <GetRecord>
                <record>
                <header>
        <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:2605.10476</identifier>
        <datestamp>2026-07-07</datestamp>
            <setSpec>physics:astro-ph:CO</setSpec>
            <setSpec>physics:hep-th</setSpec>
    </header>

            <metadata>
                        <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ https://oaipmh.arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
        <id>2605.10476</id>
        <created>2026-07-06</created>
            <updated>2026-07-07</updated>
        <authors>
                <author>
                    <keyname>Anchordoqui</keyname>
                        <forenames>Luis A.</forenames>
                </author>
                <author>
                    <keyname>Lust</keyname>
                        <forenames>Dieter</forenames>
                </author>
        </authors>
        <title>Breaking Free from the Swampland of Impossible Universes through the DESI Portal</title>
            <categories>astro-ph.CO hep-th</categories>
            <comments>References added; submitted for publication in &#34;String Theory and Particle Physics: A Themed Issue of Universe in Honor of Professor Ignatios Antoniadis on the Occasion of His 70th Birthday&#34; https://www.mdpi.com/journal/universe/special_issues/826L06607W</comments>
            <report-no>MPP-2026-84</report-no>
            <license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license>
            <abstract>The persistent challenge of creating stable de Sitter vacua within string theory undermines the observational validity of the $Λ$ cold dark matter (CDM) model. This difficulty suggests that the concordance model of cosmology, characterized by a constant dark energy $Λ$, may reside in the swampland of inconsistent quantum gravity theories rather than the string landscape of consistent ones. Recent observational data, particularly from the Dark Energy Spectroscopic Instrument (DESI), have significantly challenged $Λ$CDM cosmology. Specifically, the combination of DESI baryon acoustic oscillation measurements with cosmological surveys seem to indicate a preference for a dynamic, time-evolving dark energy rather than a constant, with roughly 10\% reduction in density over the last several billion years. This review summarizes significant advancements made over the past two years in linking DESI findings to string-inspired scenarios.</abstract>
    </arXiv>

            </metadata>
        </record>

    </GetRecord>
</OAI-PMH>