<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<OAI-PMH xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" 
         xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance"
         xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/OAI-PMH.xsd">
    <responseDate>2026-07-11T21:03:53Z</responseDate>
                <request verb="GetRecord" identifier="oai:arXiv.org:2601.04344v3" metadataPrefix="arXiv">http://oaipmh.arxiv.org/oai</request>


    <GetRecord>
                <record>
                <header>
        <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:2601.04344</identifier>
        <datestamp>2026-06-17</datestamp>
            <setSpec>physics:astro-ph:GA</setSpec>
    </header>

            <metadata>
                        <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ https://oaipmh.arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
        <id>2601.04344</id>
        <created>2026-04-14</created>
            <updated>2026-06-17</updated>
        <authors>
                <author>
                    <keyname>Ebihara</keyname>
                        <forenames>Sho</forenames>
                </author>
                <author>
                    <keyname>Fujii</keyname>
                        <forenames>Michiko S.</forenames>
                </author>
                <author>
                    <keyname>Saitoh</keyname>
                        <forenames>Takayuki R.</forenames>
                </author>
                <author>
                    <keyname>Hirai</keyname>
                        <forenames>Yutaka</forenames>
                </author>
                <author>
                    <keyname>Umeda</keyname>
                        <forenames>Hideyuki</forenames>
                </author>
                <author>
                    <keyname>Isobe</keyname>
                        <forenames>Yuki</forenames>
                </author>
                <author>
                    <keyname>Nagele</keyname>
                        <forenames>Chris</forenames>
                </author>
        </authors>
        <title>Nitrogen enhancement of GN-z11 by metal pollution from supermassive stars</title>
            <categories>astro-ph.GA</categories>
            <comments>14 pages, 11 figures, accepted for publication in A&amp;A</comments>
            <journal-ref>A&amp;A 710, A239 (2026)</journal-ref>
            <doi>10.1051/0004-6361/202558704</doi>
            <license>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0/</license>
            <abstract>Spectroscopic observations by the James Webb Space Telescope (JWST) have revealed young, compact, high-redshift ($z$) galaxies with high nitrogen-to-oxygen (N/O) ratios. GN-z11 at z=10.6 is one of these galaxies. One possible scenario for such a high N/O ratio is pollution from supermassive stars (SMSs), from which stellar winds are expected to be nitrogen-rich. The abundance pattern is determined by both galaxy evolution and SMS pollution, but so far, simple one-zone models have been used. Using a galaxy formation simulation, we tested the SMS scenario. We used a cosmological zoom-in simulation that includes chemical evolution driven by rotating massive stars (Wolf-Rayet stars), supernovae, and asymptotic giant branch stars. As a post-process, we assumed the formation of an SMS with a mass between $10^3$ and $10^5$ $M_\odot$ and investigated the contribution of its ejecta to the abundance pattern. The N/O ratio was enhanced by the SMS ejecta, and the abundance pattern of GN-z11, including carbon-to-oxygen and oxygen-to-hydrogen ratios, was reproduced by our SMS pollution model if the pollution mass fraction ranges within 10-30 per cent. Such a pollution fraction can be realized when the gas ionized by the SMS is polluted, and the gas density is $10^4$-$10^5$ cm$^{-3}$ assuming a Strömgren sphere. We also compared the abundance pattern with those of other N/O-enhanced high-$z$ galaxies. Some of these galaxies can also be explained by SMS pollution.</abstract>
    </arXiv>

            </metadata>
        </record>

    </GetRecord>
</OAI-PMH>