<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<OAI-PMH xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" 
         xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance"
         xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/OAI-PMH.xsd">
    <responseDate>2026-07-12T23:24:47Z</responseDate>
                <request verb="GetRecord" identifier="oai:arXiv.org:2605.14027v1" metadataPrefix="arXiv">http://oaipmh.arxiv.org/oai</request>


    <GetRecord>
                <record>
                <header>
        <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:2605.14027</identifier>
        <datestamp>2026-05-15</datestamp>
            <setSpec>physics:gr-qc</setSpec>
    </header>

            <metadata>
                        <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ https://oaipmh.arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
        <id>2605.14027</id>
        <created>2026-05-13</created>
            <updated>2026-05-15</updated>
        <authors>
                <author>
                    <keyname>Maier</keyname>
                        <forenames>Rodrigo</forenames>
                </author>
        </authors>
        <title>A No-Go Theorem for Topological Bridges with Matter-Vacuum Coupling</title>
            <categories>gr-qc</categories>
            <comments>Honourable Mention in the Gravity Research Foundation 2026 Awards for Essays on Gravitation</comments>
            <license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license>
            <abstract>Traversable topological bridges traditionally require exotic matter, violating the Null Energy Condition (NEC). This essay investigates whether matter-vacuum coupling can circumvent this necessity. Focusing on zero-tidal-force solutions, we establish a rigorous no-go theorem for static configurations, proving that such coupling cannot bypass the requirement for NEC violation. We demonstrate that the geometric flare-out condition is incompatible with NEC-compliant sources, regardless of the coupling $Q$ or equation of state. Crucially, the vacuum fails to shield the throat; instead, interaction gradients mathematically obstruct the required geometry. This result suggests that causality protection is inherent in the field equations, rendering the vacuum&#39;s evolution a regulator rather than a facilitator of topological shortcuts, thereby reinforcing the robustness of classical energy conditions.</abstract>
    </arXiv>

            </metadata>
        </record>

    </GetRecord>
</OAI-PMH>