<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<OAI-PMH xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" 
         xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance"
         xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/OAI-PMH.xsd">
    <responseDate>2026-07-13T06:27:31Z</responseDate>
                <request verb="GetRecord" identifier="oai:arXiv.org:2606.23307" metadataPrefix="arXiv">http://oaipmh.arxiv.org/oai</request>


    <GetRecord>
                <record>
                <header>
        <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:2606.23307</identifier>
        <datestamp>2026-06-23</datestamp>
            <setSpec>physics:gr-qc</setSpec>
            <setSpec>physics:astro-ph:CO</setSpec>
    </header>

            <metadata>
                        <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ https://oaipmh.arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
        <id>2606.23307</id>
        <created>2026-06-22</created>
            <updated>2026-06-23</updated>
        <authors>
                <author>
                    <keyname>Han</keyname>
                        <forenames>Chang</forenames>
                </author>
                <author>
                    <keyname>Chen</keyname>
                        <forenames>Zu-Cheng</forenames>
                </author>
                <author>
                    <keyname>Yu</keyname>
                        <forenames>Hongwei</forenames>
                </author>
                <author>
                    <keyname>Wu</keyname>
                        <forenames>Puxun</forenames>
                </author>
        </authors>
        <title>Primordial Black Holes from Vector-Induced Curvature Perturbations Sourced by Primordial Magnetic Fields</title>
            <categories>gr-qc astro-ph.CO</categories>
            <comments>13 pages, 2 figures</comments>
            <license>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0/</license>
            <abstract>Generating an appreciable abundance of primordial black holes (PBHs) requires a substantial enhancement of primordial curvature perturbations on small scales. In this work, we propose a new post-inflationary mechanism in which such an enhancement arises during a stiff, or kination, epoch. The mechanism is driven by metric vector perturbations sourced by the vector component of the electromagnetic stress-energy tensor associated with primordial magnetic fields (PMFs). Since these first-order vector modes remain approximately constant during kination, they act as persistent nonlinear sources for second-order scalar perturbations. We show that the resulting vector-induced curvature perturbations are amplified toward the infrared cutoff of the kination band and exhibit the characteristic scaling $\mathcal P_{\mathcal R}(k)\propto k^{-5}$. As a concrete realization, we consider PMFs generated in a Ratra-type magnetogenesis scenario and find that the induced curvature perturbations can produce PBHs with an abundance large enough to constitute a substantial fraction of the dark matter.</abstract>
    </arXiv>

            </metadata>
        </record>

    </GetRecord>
</OAI-PMH>