<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<OAI-PMH xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" 
         xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance"
         xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/OAI-PMH.xsd">
    <responseDate>2026-07-13T06:27:50Z</responseDate>
                <request verb="GetRecord" identifier="oai:arXiv.org:2510.13577" metadataPrefix="arXiv">http://oaipmh.arxiv.org/oai</request>


    <GetRecord>
                <record>
                <header>
        <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:2510.13577</identifier>
        <datestamp>2026-04-01</datestamp>
            <setSpec>physics:quant-ph</setSpec>
            <setSpec>physics:cond-mat:stat-mech</setSpec>
            <setSpec>physics:cond-mat:str-el</setSpec>
    </header>

            <metadata>
                        <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ https://oaipmh.arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
        <id>2510.13577</id>
        <created>2026-03-31</created>
            <updated>2026-04-01</updated>
        <authors>
                <author>
                    <keyname>Shinjo</keyname>
                        <forenames>Kazuya</forenames>
                </author>
                <author>
                    <keyname>Seki</keyname>
                        <forenames>Kazuhiro</forenames>
                </author>
                <author>
                    <keyname>Yunoki</keyname>
                        <forenames>Seiji</forenames>
                </author>
        </authors>
        <title>Noise-stabilized discrete time crystals on digital quantum processors</title>
            <categories>quant-ph cond-mat.stat-mech cond-mat.str-el</categories>
            <comments>12 pages, 9 figures + Supplemental Material (26 pages, 17 figures)</comments>
            <license>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0/</license>
            <abstract>Floquet many-body phases such as discrete time crystals (DTCs) are typically fragile to imperfections, and stabilizing them on noisy quantum hardware remains a central challenge in nonequilibrium quantum physics. Here, we use IBM Eagle and Heron superconducting processors to implement Floquet dynamics of a kicked Ising model on two-dimensional Kagome lattices, engineered via ancilla-assisted embeddings into the heavy-hex connectivity of the devices. By combining error-mitigated measurements on quantum hardware with matrix-product-state simulations incorporating an ancilla-noise model constructed from experimental device data, we observe long-lived subharmonic magnetization oscillations that are stabilized -- rather than destroyed -- by structured quantum noise. Across different two-dimensional lattice geometries, increasing cases beyond Kagome lattices, and with or without boundary symmetry-charge pumping, ancilla errors effectively act as spatiotemporal disorder that induces stochastic sign flips of the Ising couplings, providing a unified mechanism for robust period-doubling responses. When symmetry-charge pumping is present, intrinsic boundary-localized $π$ modes cooperate with this disorder to yield a boundary-assisted DTC characterized by suppressed scrambling and sharply localized dynamics. In contrast, in implementations without pumping, the noiseless dynamics rapidly thermalize and exhibit no subharmonic order, whereas the same noise process alone generates a DTC-like long-lived subharmonic response over experimentally accessible time windows. These results identify engineered ancilla noise as a practical control knob for inducing, stabilizing, and geometrically tailoring nonequilibrium dynamical order on scalable superconducting quantum processors.</abstract>
    </arXiv>

            </metadata>
        </record>

    </GetRecord>
</OAI-PMH>