<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<OAI-PMH xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" 
         xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance"
         xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/OAI-PMH.xsd">
    <responseDate>2026-07-11T20:34:04Z</responseDate>
                <request verb="GetRecord" identifier="oai:arXiv.org:2601.02171v4" metadataPrefix="arXiv">http://oaipmh.arxiv.org/oai</request>


    <GetRecord>
                <record>
                <header>
        <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:2601.02171</identifier>
        <datestamp>2026-02-03</datestamp>
            <setSpec>physics:astro-ph:EP</setSpec>
    </header>

            <metadata>
                        <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ https://oaipmh.arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
        <id>2601.02171</id>
        <created>2026-02-01</created>
            <updated>2026-02-03</updated>
        <authors>
                <author>
                    <keyname>Escolà-Rodrigo</keyname>
                        <forenames>Biel</forenames>
                </author>
        </authors>
        <title>Vetting and False Positive Analysis of TOI 864.01: Evidence for a Likely Hierarchical Eclipsing Binary Masked by Dilution</title>
            <categories>astro-ph.EP</categories>
            <comments>4 pages, 3 figures. Data and code available at DOI: https://doi.org/10.5281/zenodo.17881756</comments>
            <license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license>
            <abstract>We present a detailed vetting analysis of the TESS candidate TOI 864.01, initially identified as a potential ultra-short-period (P ~ 0.52 d) Earth-sized planet orbiting an M-dwarf. Using 12 sectors of TESS photometry spanning a multi-year baseline, we recover a robust periodic transit-like signal. While the recovered transit depth is attenuated by detrending (~ 158 ppm), the SPOC pipeline reports an undiluted depth of ~ 640 ppm. Stellar characterization based on Gaia DR3 astrometry yields a nominally single-star solution (RUWE = 1.18), highlighting the limitations of astrometric vetting for tight companions. We performed a statistical validation analysis using TRICERATOPS, aggregating data from all 12 available sectors. The analysis yields a False Positive Probability (FPP) of 0.25 and a Nearby False Positive Probability (NFPP) of &lt; 10^-4. While these metrics ostensibly classify the target as a viable planetary candidate based on Gaia-resolved sources, they fail to account for sub-pixel companions. Crucially, archival high-resolution imaging from the TESS Follow-up Observing Program (TFOP SG1) reveals a stellar companion at a separation of 0.04&#34;, unresolved by both Gaia and TESS. When this companion is considered, the signal is best interpreted as a Hierarchical Eclipsing Binary (HEB) on the companion. Bayesian model comparison yields an inconclusive result (Delta ln Z ~ 0.25), consistent with the degeneracy introduced by unresolved blending. Ground-based follow-up photometry further supports significant dilution, with a measured transit depth (~ 0.37 ppt) shallower than predicted (~ 0.64 ppt) and a timing offset of 6.3 minutes. Taken together, we classify TOI 864.01 as a probable False Positive and recommend its retirement from planetary candidate lists.</abstract>
    </arXiv>

            </metadata>
        </record>

    </GetRecord>
</OAI-PMH>