<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<OAI-PMH xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" 
         xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance"
         xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/OAI-PMH.xsd">
    <responseDate>2026-07-13T06:25:29Z</responseDate>
                <request verb="GetRecord" identifier="oai:arXiv.org:2510.11879" metadataPrefix="arXiv">http://oaipmh.arxiv.org/oai</request>


    <GetRecord>
                <record>
                <header>
        <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:2510.11879</identifier>
        <datestamp>2025-10-15</datestamp>
            <setSpec>physics:hep-ph</setSpec>
            <setSpec>physics:astro-ph:HE</setSpec>
            <setSpec>physics:gr-qc</setSpec>
            <setSpec>physics:hep-th</setSpec>
    </header>

            <metadata>
                        <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ https://oaipmh.arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
        <id>2510.11879</id>
        <created>2025-10-13</created>
            <updated>2025-10-15</updated>
        <authors>
                <author>
                    <keyname>Ettengruber</keyname>
                        <forenames>Manuel</forenames>
                </author>
                <author>
                    <keyname>Herrera</keyname>
                        <forenames>Gonzalo</forenames>
                </author>
        </authors>
        <title>New Tests of Low-Scale Quantum Gravity with Cosmic-Ray Collisions</title>
            <categories>hep-ph astro-ph.HE gr-qc hep-th</categories>
            <license>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0/</license>
            <abstract>Cosmic ray collisions at high center of mass energy could enable graviton and black hole production as expected in theories of low-scale quantum gravity, such as extra-dimensions, many species, or some versions of string theory. Here we propose three novel phenomenological tests of these theories. We first consider the collision of cosmic rays with ambient protons, electrons and photons in Active Galactic Nuclei (AGN), finding that high-energy neutrino data from the blazar TXS 0506+056 places a constraint on the fundamental scale of gravity of $M_f \gtrsim 0.3$ TeV, and future high-energy neutrino data could raise this bound to $M_f \gtrsim 200$ TeV. We then point out that collisions of pairs of cosmic rays could occur at a sizable rate in AGN where the accelerated cosmic rays are not collimated, or on supermassive black hole binaries. This consideration could potentially let us test unprecedented large fundamental scales of $M_f \gtrsim 2$ PeV. We further compute the corresponding thermal neutrino emission arising from the Hawking evaporation of black holes produced in cosmic ray collisions, finding a spectrum that clearly differs from that expected in meson decays. Finally, we speculate with an scenario which would produce high-energy neutrino and gamma-ray emission from regions in the sky where no multi-wavelength counterparts would be expected, via graviton propagation from a different brane, which then decays in our Universe.</abstract>
    </arXiv>

            </metadata>
        </record>

    </GetRecord>
</OAI-PMH>