<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<OAI-PMH xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" 
         xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance"
         xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/OAI-PMH.xsd">
    <responseDate>2026-07-11T21:49:55Z</responseDate>
                <request verb="GetRecord" identifier="oai:arXiv.org:2601.05734v1" metadataPrefix="arXiv">http://oaipmh.arxiv.org/oai</request>


    <GetRecord>
                <record>
                <header>
        <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:2601.05734</identifier>
        <datestamp>2026-01-12</datestamp>
            <setSpec>physics:gr-qc</setSpec>
            <setSpec>physics:astro-ph:HE</setSpec>
    </header>

            <metadata>
                        <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ https://oaipmh.arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
        <id>2601.05734</id>
        <created>2026-01-09</created>
            <updated>2026-01-12</updated>
        <authors>
                <author>
                    <keyname>Wang</keyname>
                        <forenames>Yi-Fan</forenames>
                </author>
                <author>
                    <keyname>Ma</keyname>
                        <forenames>Sizheng</forenames>
                </author>
                <author>
                    <keyname>Khera</keyname>
                        <forenames>Neev</forenames>
                </author>
                <author>
                    <keyname>Yang</keyname>
                        <forenames>Huan</forenames>
                </author>
        </authors>
        <title>A nonlinear voice from GW250114 ringdown</title>
            <categories>gr-qc astro-ph.HE</categories>
            <comments>9 pages, 6 figures. Data release at https://github.com/yi-fan-wang/nonlinear-ringdown-GW250114. Comments welcome!</comments>
            <report-no>LIGO-P2500804</report-no>
            <license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license>
            <abstract>The detection of quadratic quasi-normal modes would provide a direct probe into black hole nonlinear perturbations. We report the first observational evidence of a set of quadratic quasi-normal modes in the gravitational-wave ringdown of a binary black hole merger. Analyzing the signal from GW250114, we detect six nonlinear modes from the quadratic coupling of the fundamental $(2,2,0)$ mode and its first two overtones. At 5 final mass ($M_\mathrm{f}$) after the merger, the evidence for these nonlinear modes reaches a Bayes factor of 74. To single out these contributions, we employ recent theoretical progress to compute the waveforms and subtract the corresponding nonlinear modes from a numerical relativity surrogate waveform. Our data analysis uses a novel method that incorporates inspiral-merger inference results as a highly constraining prior for the ringdown inference. We further perform a test allowing for phenomenological deviations for the theoretically predicted amplitudes of the quadratic modes. The results show that an amplitude of zero is excluded at $3.0~σ$ significance level, while the theoretical expectation is consistent with the inference. This detection marks a first step towards observationally characterizing nonlinear perturbations in the ringdown of a black hole.</abstract>
    </arXiv>

            </metadata>
        </record>

    </GetRecord>
</OAI-PMH>