<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<OAI-PMH xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" 
         xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance"
         xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/OAI-PMH.xsd">
    <responseDate>2026-07-11T20:41:47Z</responseDate>
                <request verb="GetRecord" identifier="oai:arXiv.org:2601.01697v1" metadataPrefix="arXiv">http://oaipmh.arxiv.org/oai</request>


    <GetRecord>
                <record>
                <header>
        <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:2601.01697</identifier>
        <datestamp>2026-01-06</datestamp>
            <setSpec>physics:astro-ph:GA</setSpec>
    </header>

            <metadata>
                        <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ https://oaipmh.arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
        <id>2601.01697</id>
        <created>2026-01-05</created>
            <updated>2026-01-06</updated>
        <authors>
                <author>
                    <keyname>Dalmasso</keyname>
                        <forenames>Nicolò</forenames>
                </author>
                <author>
                    <keyname>Ferrami</keyname>
                        <forenames>Giovanni</forenames>
                </author>
                <author>
                    <keyname>Leethochawalit</keyname>
                        <forenames>Nicha</forenames>
                </author>
                <author>
                    <keyname>Ventura</keyname>
                        <forenames>Emanuele M.</forenames>
                </author>
                <author>
                    <keyname>Trenti</keyname>
                        <forenames>Michele</forenames>
                </author>
        </authors>
        <title>Accelerated evolution of galaxy host halo masses during Cosmic Dawn from deep JWST clustering</title>
            <categories>astro-ph.GA</categories>
            <comments>Published on MNRAS-Monthly Notices of the Royal Astronomical Society; 8 pages, 3 figures, 2 tables</comments>
            <doi>10.1093/mnras/stag001</doi>
            <license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license>
            <abstract>We present the deepest clustering analysis of early galaxies to date, analyzing $N_{\rm{g}} \simeq 6500$ photometrically-selected Lyman Break Galaxies from JWST&#39;s Advanced Deep Extragalactic Survey (JADES) to reveal how galaxies and dark matter evolved during cosmic dawn ($5 \leq z &lt; 11$). Using halo occupation distribution (HOD) modeling of the two-point angular correlation function, we trace the galaxy-halo relationships across the first billion years of cosmic history. Our analysis reveals that galaxies at $z = 10.6$ reside in dark matter halos over an order of magnitude less massive ($M_{\rm{h}} \sim 10^{10.12} M_{\odot}$) than their counterparts at $z = 5.5$ ($M_{\rm{h}} \sim 10^{11.45} M_{\odot}$), while exhibiting correspondingly higher effective bias values ($b_{\rm{g}}^{\rm{eff}} = 8.13^{+0.04}_{-0.02}$ compared to $5.64^{+0.10}_{-0.13}$). Correspondingly, the satellite galaxy fraction hints at a declining trend with decreasing redshift, reaching $&lt;1\%$ by $z \sim 5-6$. However, the significant systematic and random uncertainties in the data-model comparison prevent us from drawing robust conclusions on the evolution - if any - of the satellite fraction during the epoch of reionization. These results provide the first view of the coevolution between galaxies and dark matter evolved at redshift $\gtrsim 10$, offering additional and independent constraints on early galaxy formation models tuned to reproducing luminosity function evolution.</abstract>
    </arXiv>

            </metadata>
        </record>

    </GetRecord>
</OAI-PMH>