<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<OAI-PMH xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" 
         xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance"
         xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/OAI-PMH.xsd">
    <responseDate>2026-07-13T06:21:11Z</responseDate>
                <request verb="GetRecord" identifier="oai:arXiv.org:2509.04165" metadataPrefix="arXiv">http://oaipmh.arxiv.org/oai</request>


    <GetRecord>
                <record>
                <header>
        <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:2509.04165</identifier>
        <datestamp>2025-09-05</datestamp>
            <setSpec>physics:astro-ph:HE</setSpec>
            <setSpec>physics:astro-ph:EP</setSpec>
            <setSpec>physics:astro-ph:GA</setSpec>
    </header>

            <metadata>
                        <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ https://oaipmh.arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
        <id>2509.04165</id>
        <created>2025-09-04</created>
            <updated>2025-09-05</updated>
        <authors>
                <author>
                    <keyname>Ozsvárt</keyname>
                        <forenames>Péter</forenames>
                </author>
                <author>
                    <keyname>Kun</keyname>
                        <forenames>Emma</forenames>
                </author>
                <author>
                    <keyname>Bartos</keyname>
                        <forenames>Imre</forenames>
                </author>
                <author>
                    <keyname>Márka</keyname>
                        <forenames>Zsolt Gy.</forenames>
                </author>
                <author>
                    <keyname>Márka</keyname>
                        <forenames>Szabolcs</forenames>
                </author>
        </authors>
        <title>Galactic forcing increases origination of marine microplankton</title>
            <categories>astro-ph.HE astro-ph.EP astro-ph.GA</categories>
            <comments>26 pages, 6 figures. Accepted for publication in Paleoceanography and Paleoclimatology</comments>
            <license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license>
            <abstract>The continuous flux of Galactic cosmic rays that bombard Earth&#39;s atmosphere creates ionizing radiation that can damage the DNA of living organisms. While this radiation on Earth is relatively constant in the short term, large and long-scale fluctuations are expected with a period of $\sim 63.5$ million years. As the Solar System moves above or below the Galactic plane during its oscillatory motion about the Galactic center, the Galactic magnetic shielding weakens, allowing more cosmic rays to reach Earth and trigger mutations in organisms. We identify a significant correlation (weighted global p-value: $1.25\times 10^{-4}$, or $3.72σ$) between the Solar System&#39;s Galactic oscillations and the origination of marine zoo- and phyto-microplankton genera over the Phanerozoic. When we restrict the analysis to time intervals during which all four groups coexisted, a post-trial significance of $4.52σ$ emerges. Our findings suggest that changes in biodiversity have been significantly influenced by long-term Galactic forcing.</abstract>
    </arXiv>

            </metadata>
        </record>

    </GetRecord>
</OAI-PMH>