<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<OAI-PMH xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" 
         xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance"
         xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/OAI-PMH.xsd">
    <responseDate>2026-07-13T06:23:00Z</responseDate>
                <request verb="GetRecord" identifier="oai:arXiv.org:2510.23996" metadataPrefix="arXiv">http://oaipmh.arxiv.org/oai</request>


    <GetRecord>
                <record>
                <header>
        <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:2510.23996</identifier>
        <datestamp>2026-04-03</datestamp>
            <setSpec>physics:quant-ph</setSpec>
    </header>

            <metadata>
                        <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ https://oaipmh.arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
        <id>2510.23996</id>
        <created>2025-10-28</created>
            <updated>2026-04-03</updated>
        <authors>
                <author>
                    <keyname>Zhu</keyname>
                        <forenames>Y. T.</forenames>
                </author>
                <author>
                    <keyname>Xue</keyname>
                        <forenames>Shibei</forenames>
                </author>
                <author>
                    <keyname>Ju</keyname>
                        <forenames>Fangfang</forenames>
                </author>
                <author>
                    <keyname>Yuan</keyname>
                        <forenames>Haidong</forenames>
                </author>
        </authors>
        <title>Nonreciprocity enhanced Quantum Gyroscopes based on Surface Acoustic Waves</title>
            <categories>quant-ph</categories>
            <comments>Submitted to Physical Review Applied</comments>
            <journal-ref>Physical Review Applied, 25, 034091 (2026)</journal-ref>
            <doi>10.1103/n52d-dr86</doi>
            <license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license>
            <abstract>Surface acoustic waves (SAWs), as Rayleigh waves generated by elastic media, have been used in gyroscopes for over 40 years due to their unique propagation characteristics. However, their working principle, based on Coriolis effects, has become increasingly ineffective for addressing modern sensing challenges in complex scenarios. Fortunately, recent advancements in quantized SAWs offer a promising solution: SAWs operating at extremely low pump powers (approximately at the single-phonon level) can exhibit substantial quantum coherence, enabling investigations into the fundamental limits of SAW gyroscopes as constrained by the Heisenberg uncertainty relation. In particular, when multiple SAWs couple to a common waveguide at distinct locations, the nonlocality arising from the spatial separation among coupling points induces directional coupling between the SAWs. To elucidate this directionality, we propose a quantum gyroscope characterized by multiplepoint couplings. Unlike traditional single-point coupling designs, our gyroscope exhibits distinctive time-delayed dynamics that depend on the system&#39;s topologies. We emphasize that these dynamics invalidate the Markovian approximation, even when the time delay is relatively small. Through a comprehensive analysis of all possible topologies, we observe that the directional coupling implies an inherent nonreciprocal transfer. This nonreciprocity confers signiffcant advantages to our gyroscope compared to traditional designs, notably enhancing both the signal-to-noise ratio and sensitivity. Speciffcally, it enables the extraction of output signals that would otherwise be obscured by noise. Consequently, our ffndings suggest that systems with multiple-point couplings and the associated nonreciprocity can serve as valuable resources for advancing quantum sensing technologies.</abstract>
    </arXiv>

            </metadata>
        </record>

    </GetRecord>
</OAI-PMH>