<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<OAI-PMH xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" 
         xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance"
         xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/OAI-PMH.xsd">
    <responseDate>2026-07-13T06:25:08Z</responseDate>
                <request verb="GetRecord" identifier="oai:arXiv.org:2607.02631" metadataPrefix="arXiv">http://oaipmh.arxiv.org/oai</request>


    <GetRecord>
                <record>
                <header>
        <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:2607.02631</identifier>
        <datestamp>2026-07-07</datestamp>
            <setSpec>physics:gr-qc</setSpec>
    </header>

            <metadata>
                        <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ https://oaipmh.arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
        <id>2607.02631</id>
        <created>2026-07-02</created>
            <updated>2026-07-07</updated>
        <authors>
                <author>
                    <keyname>Errehymy</keyname>
                        <forenames>A.</forenames>
                </author>
                <author>
                    <keyname>Khedif</keyname>
                        <forenames>Y.</forenames>
                </author>
                <author>
                    <keyname>Daoud</keyname>
                        <forenames>M.</forenames>
                </author>
                <author>
                    <keyname>Turimov</keyname>
                        <forenames>B.</forenames>
                </author>
                <author>
                    <keyname>Usanov</keyname>
                        <forenames>S.</forenames>
                </author>
                <author>
                    <keyname>Yasakov</keyname>
                        <forenames>Z.</forenames>
                </author>
                <author>
                    <keyname>Avezmuratova</keyname>
                        <forenames>Z.</forenames>
                </author>
        </authors>
        <title>Observational Constraints on Kazakov-Solodukhin Quantum-Deformed Black Holes from M87$^*$ and Sgr A$^*$ Shadows</title>
            <categories>gr-qc</categories>
            <comments>14 pages, 9 figures, accepted for publication in Nuclear Physics B</comments>
            <license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license>
            <abstract>We explore the Kazakov-Solodukhin quantum-deformed black hole spacetime, characterized by a single deformation parameter \( η\) that encodes quantum corrections to the classical Schwarzschild solution. The model preserves the correct general-relativistic limit as \( η\to 0 \), while introducing significant and physically meaningful deviations in the strong-field regime. A central and remarkable feature of the geometry is the regularization of the classical singularity: curvature invariants remain finite near the minimal radius \( r = η\), effectively replacing the divergent core with a smooth and well-behaved region. This behavior naturally introduces a minimal length scale into the spacetime structure, offering a geometrically motivated resolution of the singularity problem. The deformation modifies the horizon structure, shifts the event horizon location, and alters the mass-radius relation. It also reduces the surface gravity, leading to a lower Hawking temperature and a slower evaporation process, thereby enhancing the thermodynamic stability of the black hole. Photon dynamics are correspondingly affected, resulting in a displaced photon sphere and modified strong-lensing characteristics. While the shadow remains perfectly circular due to spherical symmetry, its size depends sensitively on \( η\). Observational constraints can be expressed through \( \left| R_{sh}(η) - R_{obs} \right| \leq ΔR_{obs}, \) which places an upper bound on the deformation parameter. In the weak-field limit, the deflection angle acquires a quadratic correction proportional to \( η^2 \), ensuring consistency with precision tests while allowing potentially detectable deviations in strong-gravity observations. These features make the model both theoretically appealing and observationally testable.</abstract>
    </arXiv>

            </metadata>
        </record>

    </GetRecord>
</OAI-PMH>