<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<OAI-PMH xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" 
         xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance"
         xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/OAI-PMH.xsd">
    <responseDate>2026-07-13T06:26:16Z</responseDate>
                <request verb="GetRecord" identifier="oai:arXiv.org:2602.05070" metadataPrefix="arXiv">http://oaipmh.arxiv.org/oai</request>


    <GetRecord>
                <record>
                <header>
        <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:2602.05070</identifier>
        <datestamp>2026-02-06</datestamp>
            <setSpec>physics:astro-ph:CO</setSpec>
    </header>

            <metadata>
                        <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ https://oaipmh.arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
        <id>2602.05070</id>
        <created>2026-02-04</created>
            <updated>2026-02-06</updated>
        <authors>
                <author>
                    <keyname>Oayda</keyname>
                        <forenames>Oliver T.</forenames>
                </author>
                <author>
                    <keyname>Lewis</keyname>
                        <forenames>Geraint F.</forenames>
                </author>
        </authors>
        <title>Wising up to CatWISE: using simulation-based inference to interpret the ecliptic bias and confirm the cosmic dipole excess</title>
            <categories>astro-ph.CO</categories>
            <comments>Accepted for publication in MNRAS; 15 pages, 10 figures</comments>
            <license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license>
            <abstract>We apply Simulation-Based Inference (&#39;SBI&#39;) to the cosmic dipole problem for the first time, measuring the distribution of quasar counts over the sky in the CatWISE2020 (&#39;CatWISE&#39;) sample. We show that the quadrupole anisotropy in CatWISE can be attributed to the correlation between WISE&#39;s scanning law and photometric uncertainty in the $W1$ and $W2$ magnitudes, inducing an Eddington bias which varies with sky position. After explicitly modelling this with SBI, we use a neural likelihood estimator to find the posterior distribution for CatWISE&#39;s dipole, confirming the presence of a dipole twice as large as the CMB expectation but more seriously misaligned with the CMB direction ($\approx 3 σ$). We also use our learned likelihood to infer the Bayesian evidence, learning that models which increase the scale of CatWISE&#39;s photometric errors are most favoured. This is strong evidence that the sample&#39;s errors are underestimated or that there is an additional, unresolved systematic producing the same effect as Eddington bias. While our results indicate that the cosmic dipole excess is a persistent issue for $Λ$CDM, we showcase that SBI can untangle the subtle and complex systematic issues affecting any sample derived from real astronomical data.</abstract>
    </arXiv>

            </metadata>
        </record>

    </GetRecord>
</OAI-PMH>