<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<OAI-PMH xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" 
         xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance"
         xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/OAI-PMH.xsd">
    <responseDate>2026-07-11T21:58:02Z</responseDate>
                <request verb="GetRecord" identifier="oai:arXiv.org:2601.06409v1" metadataPrefix="arXiv">http://oaipmh.arxiv.org/oai</request>


    <GetRecord>
                <record>
                <header>
        <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:2601.06409</identifier>
        <datestamp>2026-01-13</datestamp>
            <setSpec>physics:astro-ph:HE</setSpec>
    </header>

            <metadata>
                        <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ https://oaipmh.arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
        <id>2601.06409</id>
        <created>2026-01-10</created>
            <updated>2026-01-13</updated>
        <authors>
                <author>
                    <keyname>Chiche</keyname>
                        <forenames>Simon</forenames>
                </author>
                <author>
                    <keyname>de Vries</keyname>
                        <forenames>Krijn D.</forenames>
                </author>
                <author>
                    <keyname>Toscano</keyname>
                        <forenames>Simona</forenames>
                </author>
        </authors>
        <title>Radio Signatures of Cosmic-Ray Particle Showers in Deep In-Ice Antennas</title>
            <categories>astro-ph.HE</categories>
            <comments>9 pages, 5 figures, 39th International Cosmic Ray Conference (ICRC2025)</comments>
            <journal-ref>PoS(ICRC2025)221</journal-ref>
            <license>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0/</license>
            <abstract>To detect ultra-high-energy neutrinos, experiments such as ARA and RNO-G target the radio emission induced by these particles as they cascade in the ice, using deep in-ice antennas at the South Pole or in Greenland. In this context, it is essential to first characterize the in-ice radio signature from cosmic-ray-induced particle showers, which constitute a primary background for neutrino detection, and represent the fist in-situ detection of in-ice particle cascades with radio antennas. This characterization will help validate the detection principle and assist in calibration. To achieve this goal, we used FAERIE, the &#34;Framework for the simulation of Air shower Emission of Radio for in-Ice Experiments&#34;, that combines CoREAS and GEANT4 to simulate the radio emission of cosmic ray showers deep in the ice. Using this tool, we analyze in-ice radio signatures of cosmic-ray showers, including polarization, timing, and radiation energy, as well as their dependence on shower parameters. These insights will facilitate the first cosmic-ray detections and improve cosmic-ray/neutrino discrimination.</abstract>
    </arXiv>

            </metadata>
        </record>

    </GetRecord>
</OAI-PMH>