<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<OAI-PMH xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" 
         xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance"
         xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/OAI-PMH.xsd">
    <responseDate>2026-07-13T05:22:05Z</responseDate>
                <request verb="GetRecord" identifier="oai:arXiv.org:2605.11046" metadataPrefix="arXiv">http://oaipmh.arxiv.org/oai</request>


    <GetRecord>
                <record>
                <header>
        <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:2605.11046</identifier>
        <datestamp>2026-07-07</datestamp>
            <setSpec>physics:hep-th</setSpec>
            <setSpec>physics:cond-mat:other</setSpec>
            <setSpec>physics:gr-qc</setSpec>
    </header>

            <metadata>
                        <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ https://oaipmh.arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
        <id>2605.11046</id>
        <created>2026-07-06</created>
            <updated>2026-07-07</updated>
        <authors>
                <author>
                    <keyname>Castorina</keyname>
                        <forenames>Paolo</forenames>
                </author>
                <author>
                    <keyname>Iorio</keyname>
                        <forenames>Alfredo</forenames>
                </author>
                <author>
                    <keyname>Kriš</keyname>
                        <forenames>Jakub</forenames>
                </author>
                <author>
                    <keyname>Nejati</keyname>
                        <forenames>Mohaddese Shams</forenames>
                </author>
        </authors>
        <title>On the dilaton gravity of analogue black holes</title>
            <categories>hep-th cond-mat.other gr-qc</categories>
            <comments>30 pages, 2 figures. Some typos removed. Improved discussion on state dependence in dilaton gravity</comments>
            <license>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0/</license>
            <abstract>We investigate which dilaton gravity models can reproduce the typical two dimensional analogue black holes realized in platforms such as superconducting quantum circuits. We identify the most reasonable assumptions these models must satisfy, and determine the dilaton models for which the state-dependence of the Hawking temperature, T, can be switched on and off, a feature that is absent in four dimensional black holes. When the analogue black hole exhibits state-independent temperature, as in the cases considered here, the kinematics governing T decouples from the dynamics underlying S. Our numerical analysis reveals that the given analogue black holes do not correspond to known dilaton gravity models, limiting their usefulness for extracting theoretical insights. We then show that the logic can be easily reversed: starting from established well known dilaton models, one can derive the conditions that laboratory implementations must satisfy. This shifts the challenge from the theoretical perspective to the experimental realization.</abstract>
    </arXiv>

            </metadata>
        </record>

    </GetRecord>
</OAI-PMH>