<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<OAI-PMH xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" 
         xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance"
         xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/OAI-PMH.xsd">
    <responseDate>2026-07-13T06:23:41Z</responseDate>
                <request verb="GetRecord" identifier="oai:arXiv.org:2601.22697" metadataPrefix="arXiv">http://oaipmh.arxiv.org/oai</request>


    <GetRecord>
                <record>
                <header>
        <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:2601.22697</identifier>
        <datestamp>2026-04-13</datestamp>
            <setSpec>physics:quant-ph</setSpec>
            <setSpec>physics:hep-th</setSpec>
    </header>

            <metadata>
                        <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ https://oaipmh.arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
        <id>2601.22697</id>
        <created>2026-04-10</created>
            <updated>2026-04-13</updated>
        <authors>
                <author>
                    <keyname>Zhang</keyname>
                        <forenames>Yong</forenames>
                </author>
        </authors>
        <title>A complex-linear reformulation of Hamilton-Jacobi theory and emergent quantum structure</title>
            <categories>quant-ph hep-th</categories>
            <comments>10+6 pages, 4 figures, 1 table. Revised version with improved presentation, clarified Born-rule discussion, a new schematic figure, and a streamlined discussion of the complex-$κ$ branch</comments>
            <license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license>
            <abstract>Classical mechanics admits multiple equivalent formulations, from Newton&#39;s equations to the variational Lagrange-Hamilton framework and the scalar Hamilton-Jacobi (HJ) theory. In the HJ formulation, classical ensembles evolve through the continuity equation for a real density $ρ= R^{2}$ coupled to Hamilton&#39;s principal function $S$. Here we develop a complementary formulation, the Hamilton-Jacobi-Schrödinger (HJS) theory, by embedding the pair $(R,S)$ into a single complex field. Starting from a completely general complex ansatz $ψ= f(R,S)\, e^{i g(R,S)},$ and imposing two minimal structural requirements, we obtain a unique map $ψ= R\, e^{iS/κ}\, $ together with a linear HJS equation whose $|κ| \to 0$ limit reproduces the HJ formulation exactly. Remarkably, when $\mathrm{Re}(κ)\neq 0$, essential features of quantum mechanics, superposition, operator algebra, commutators, the Heisenberg uncertainty principle, Born&#39;s rule and unitary evolution, follow naturally as structural consistency conditions. HJS thus provides a unified mathematical viewpoint in which classical and quantum dynamics appear as different limits of a single underlying structure.</abstract>
    </arXiv>

            </metadata>
        </record>

    </GetRecord>
</OAI-PMH>