<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<OAI-PMH xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" 
         xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance"
         xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/OAI-PMH.xsd">
    <responseDate>2026-07-13T06:25:55Z</responseDate>
                <request verb="GetRecord" identifier="oai:arXiv.org:2512.17959" metadataPrefix="arXiv">http://oaipmh.arxiv.org/oai</request>


    <GetRecord>
                <record>
                <header>
        <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:2512.17959</identifier>
        <datestamp>2026-07-01</datestamp>
            <setSpec>physics:gr-qc</setSpec>
    </header>

            <metadata>
                        <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ https://oaipmh.arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
        <id>2512.17959</id>
        <created>2026-06-30</created>
            <updated>2026-07-01</updated>
        <authors>
                <author>
                    <keyname>Toussaint</keyname>
                        <forenames>Vladimir</forenames>
                </author>
        </authors>
        <title>Detecting the Unruh Effect via an Engineered Low-Mass Field in a Superconducting Qubit</title>
            <categories>gr-qc</categories>
            <comments>21 pages, Abstract shortened due to arXiv limits, this is the published version</comments>
            <journal-ref>2026 Class. Quantum Grav. 43 075012</journal-ref>
            <doi>10.1088/1361-6382/ae5b1c</doi>
            <license>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0/</license>
            <abstract>Detecting the Unruh effect is a major challenge in fundamental physics. It is known that exciting massive fields with the Unruh thermal bath is heavily suppressed when the field&#39;s rest energy is much larger than the acceleration energy scale, $Mc^2 \gg\hbar a/c$. However, the standard literature lacks an explicit quantitative derivation of this suppression. In this work, we first fill this gap by deriving the exponential suppression, $\sim \exp(-\text{constant}\times Mc^2/(\hbar a/c))$, in two different frameworks: a (3+1)-dimensional Unruh-DeWitt detector and a (1+1)-dimensional cavity QED setup. This shows the suppression is universal and sets an insurmountable barrier for any detection method that relies on exciting massive fields. For an electron-mass field at achievable accelerations ($a \sim 10^{20}$ m/s$^2$), the suppression exceeds $10^9$ orders of magnitude. To avoid this suppression, the field&#39;s rest energy must be less than or of the order of the acceleration energy scale, $M c^2 \lesssim \hbar a / c$. Achieving this condition, however, requires astronomically high accelerations. For example, detecting the effect for an electron-mass field would require accelerations of $a \gtrsim 4.6\times 10^{29}$ m/s$^2$, which is far beyond experimental reach. While using a massless field avoids this suppression, we show the best strategy is not to avoid mass, but to engineer a small effective mass that satisfies the optimal condition $\hbar a / c \gg M_{\text{eff}} c^2$. We propose a concrete implementation using a superconducting circuit with a Josephson persistent-current qubit (the analog of a UDW detector) coupled to a microwave resonator (the analog of the scalar field). For this system, the optimal condition is $2I_pΔΦ\gg Δ$, where $I_p$ is the persistent current, $ΔΦ$ is the magnetic flux swing, and $Δ$ is the qubit&#39;s tunneling energy gap....</abstract>
    </arXiv>

            </metadata>
        </record>

    </GetRecord>
</OAI-PMH>