<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<OAI-PMH xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" 
         xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance"
         xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/OAI-PMH.xsd">
    <responseDate>2026-07-13T06:23:52Z</responseDate>
                <request verb="GetRecord" identifier="oai:arXiv.org:2602.17702" metadataPrefix="arXiv">http://oaipmh.arxiv.org/oai</request>


    <GetRecord>
                <record>
                <header>
        <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:2602.17702</identifier>
        <datestamp>2026-02-23</datestamp>
            <setSpec>physics:physics:gen-ph</setSpec>
            <setSpec>physics:gr-qc</setSpec>
    </header>

            <metadata>
                        <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ https://oaipmh.arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
        <id>2602.17702</id>
        <created>2026-02-08</created>
            <updated>2026-02-23</updated>
        <authors>
                <author>
                    <keyname>Gaztanaga</keyname>
                        <forenames>Enrique</forenames>
                </author>
        </authors>
        <title>Cosmological Bounce Relics: Black Holes, Gravitational Waves, and Dark Matter</title>
            <categories>physics.gen-ph gr-qc</categories>
            <comments>accept for publication in Phys. Rev. D</comments>
            <doi>10.1103/pr4p-6m49</doi>
            <license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license>
            <abstract>We propose a new mechanism for generating cosmological relics -- black holes, gravitational waves (GWs), and possibly dark matter (DM) -- in a bouncing Universe. Relics arise through two channels: (i) compact objects and GWs produced during pre-bounce collapse that remain super-horizon and re-enter after the bounce, and (ii) dark-matter halos formed during collapse that exit the horizon and collapse into black holes upon re-entry. Unlike inflationary primordial black holes, these relic black holes originate from nonlinear structure formation during collapse. We derive the particle horizon and horizon-crossing conditions in bouncing cosmology and show that perturbations or compact objects larger than 90 m survive the bounce. The resulting population of relic black holes and GWs spans a wide mass range, offering a unified origin for dark matter, gravitational-wave backgrounds, and the early growth of supermassive black holes and galaxies.</abstract>
    </arXiv>

            </metadata>
        </record>

    </GetRecord>
</OAI-PMH>