<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<OAI-PMH xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" 
         xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance"
         xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/OAI-PMH.xsd">
    <responseDate>2026-07-13T21:13:39Z</responseDate>
                <request verb="GetRecord" identifier="oai:arXiv.org:2502.10043" metadataPrefix="arXiv">http://oaipmh.arxiv.org/oai</request>


    <GetRecord>
                <record>
                <header>
        <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:2502.10043</identifier>
        <datestamp>2025-02-17</datestamp>
            <setSpec>physics:gr-qc</setSpec>
            <setSpec>physics:hep-th</setSpec>
            <setSpec>physics:quant-ph</setSpec>
    </header>

            <metadata>
                        <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ https://oaipmh.arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
        <id>2502.10043</id>
        <created>2025-02-14</created>
            <updated>2025-02-17</updated>
        <authors>
                <author>
                    <keyname>Luciano</keyname>
                        <forenames>Giuseppe Gaetano</forenames>
                </author>
                <author>
                    <keyname>Sekhmani</keyname>
                        <forenames>Yassine</forenames>
                </author>
        </authors>
        <title>Generalized Uncertainty Principle mimicking dynamical Dark Energy: matter perturbations and gravitational wave data analysis</title>
            <categories>gr-qc hep-th quant-ph</categories>
            <comments>10 pages, 5 figures. Comments are welcome</comments>
            <journal-ref>Phys.Lett.B 862 (2025) 139315</journal-ref>
            <doi>10.1016/j.physletb.2025.139315</doi>
            <license>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0/</license>
            <abstract>The Generalized Uncertainty Principle (GUP) stands out as a nearly ubiquitous feature in quantum gravity modeling, predicting the emergence of a minimum length at the Planck scale. Recently, it has been shown to modify the area-law scaling of the Bekenstein-Hawking entropy, giving rise to deformed Friedmann equations within Jacobson&#39;s approach. The ensuing model incorporates the GUP correction as a quintessence-like dark energy that supplements the cosmological constant, influencing the dynamics of the early Universe while aligning with the $Λ$CDM paradigm in the current epoch. In this extended scenario, we examine the growth of matter perturbations and structure formation employing the Top-Hat Spherical Collapse approach. Our analysis reveals that the profile of the density contrast is sensitive to the GUP parameter $β$, resulting in a slower gravitational evolution of primordial fluctuations in the matter density. We also discuss implications for the relic density of Primordial Gravitational Waves (PGWs), identifying the parameter space that enhances the PGW spectrum. Using the sensitivity of the next-generation GW observatories in the frequency range below $10^3\,\mathrm{Hz}$, we constrain $β\lesssim10^{39}$, which is more stringent than most other cosmological/astrophysical limits. This finding highlights the potential role of GWs in the pursuit of understanding quantum gravity phenomenology.</abstract>
    </arXiv>

            </metadata>
        </record>

    </GetRecord>
</OAI-PMH>