<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<OAI-PMH xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" 
         xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance"
         xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/OAI-PMH.xsd">
    <responseDate>2026-07-13T06:27:53Z</responseDate>
                <request verb="GetRecord" identifier="oai:arXiv.org:2511.19802" metadataPrefix="arXiv">http://oaipmh.arxiv.org/oai</request>


    <GetRecord>
                <record>
                <header>
        <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:2511.19802</identifier>
        <datestamp>2025-11-26</datestamp>
            <setSpec>physics:astro-ph:CO</setSpec>
            <setSpec>physics:hep-ph</setSpec>
    </header>

            <metadata>
                        <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ https://oaipmh.arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
        <id>2511.19802</id>
        <created>2025-11-25</created>
            <updated>2025-11-26</updated>
        <authors>
                <author>
                    <keyname>Liang</keyname>
                        <forenames>Guanming</forenames>
                </author>
        </authors>
        <title>Cold Dark Matter and Dark Energy Based on an Analogy with Superconductivity</title>
            <categories>astro-ph.CO hep-ph</categories>
            <comments>This senior thesis provides more details and explanations to PhysRevLett.134.191004. Comments welcome!</comments>
            <journal-ref>PhysRevLett.134.191004, 2025</journal-ref>
            <license>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0/</license>
            <abstract>We present a novel candidate for cold dark matter consisting of condensed Cooper pairs in a theory of interacting fermions with broken chiral symmetry. Establishing the thermal history from the early radiation era to the present, the fermions are shown to behave like standard radiation at high temperatures, but then experience a critical era decaying faster than radiation, akin to freeze-out that sets the relic abundance. Through a second-order phase transition, fermion - antifermion pairs condense and the system asymptotes towards zero temperature and pressure. By the present era, the non-relativistic, massive condensate decays slightly faster than in the standard scenario -- a unique prediction that may be tested by combined measurements of the cosmic microwave background and large scale structure. We also show that in the case of massive fermions, the phase transition is frustrated, and freeze-out instead leaves a residual, long-lived</abstract>
    </arXiv>

            </metadata>
        </record>

    </GetRecord>
</OAI-PMH>