<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<OAI-PMH xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" 
         xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance"
         xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/OAI-PMH.xsd">
    <responseDate>2026-07-11T21:28:11Z</responseDate>
                <request verb="GetRecord" identifier="oai:arXiv.org:2601.05313v1" metadataPrefix="arXiv">http://oaipmh.arxiv.org/oai</request>


    <GetRecord>
                <record>
                <header>
        <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:2601.05313</identifier>
        <datestamp>2026-01-12</datestamp>
            <setSpec>physics:astro-ph:SR</setSpec>
            <setSpec>physics:astro-ph:EP</setSpec>
    </header>

            <metadata>
                        <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ https://oaipmh.arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
        <id>2601.05313</id>
        <created>2026-01-08</created>
            <updated>2026-01-12</updated>
        <authors>
                <author>
                    <keyname>Glidden</keyname>
                        <forenames>Ana</forenames>
                </author>
                <author>
                    <keyname>Witzke</keyname>
                        <forenames>Veronika</forenames>
                </author>
                <author>
                    <keyname>Shapiro</keyname>
                        <forenames>Alexander I.</forenames>
                </author>
                <author>
                    <keyname>Seager</keyname>
                        <forenames>Sara</forenames>
                </author>
        </authors>
        <title>Overestimated Pressure Broadening Misleads Model Spectra in Cool M Dwarf Stars</title>
            <categories>astro-ph.SR astro-ph.EP</categories>
            <comments>9 pages, 5 figures, accepted for publication in ApJL</comments>
            <license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license>
            <abstract>Available one-dimensional stellar models fail to reproduce the observed spectrum of the ultracool M dwarf TRAPPIST-1. In particular, current models predict strong iron hydride (FeH) absorption due to the Wing-Ford bands at 0.99$μ$m, yet this spectral feature is only weakly present in TRAPPIST-1 and other mid-to-late M dwarf stars. Additionally, the shape of the continuum between the water bands in the near-infrared does not match between models and observations. Here, we show that assumptions about pressure broadening, specifically van der Waals broadening, have a dramatic effect on modeled broadband spectral features. We use Merged Parallelized Simplified-ATLAS to generate synthetic spectra over a range of van der Waals broadening strengths, adopting 1D PHOENIX temperature-pressure structures. We find that minimal broadening best matches the observed FeH profile at 0.99$μ$m and in the pseudocontinuum between the large water bands. These results suggest that broadening prescriptions derived for Sun-like stars are not valid for lower-mass stars and that pressure broadening for molecular lines in cool stellar atmospheres must be reevaluated. Refining pressure broadening treatments will improve the accuracy of M dwarf spectral models, enabling more reliable determinations of stellar properties and atmospheric compositions of planets orbiting M dwarfs.</abstract>
    </arXiv>

            </metadata>
        </record>

    </GetRecord>
</OAI-PMH>