<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<OAI-PMH xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" 
         xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance"
         xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/OAI-PMH.xsd">
    <responseDate>2026-07-11T21:14:00Z</responseDate>
                <request verb="GetRecord" identifier="oai:arXiv.org:2601.03950v2" metadataPrefix="arXiv">http://oaipmh.arxiv.org/oai</request>


    <GetRecord>
                <record>
                <header>
        <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:2601.03950</identifier>
        <datestamp>2026-06-24</datestamp>
            <setSpec>physics:astro-ph:HE</setSpec>
    </header>

            <metadata>
                        <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ https://oaipmh.arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
        <id>2601.03950</id>
        <created>2026-06-23</created>
            <updated>2026-06-24</updated>
        <authors>
                <author>
                    <keyname>Xiao</keyname>
                        <forenames>Shuo</forenames>
                </author>
                <author>
                    <keyname>Jiang</keyname>
                        <forenames>Zheng-Huo</forenames>
                </author>
                <author>
                    <keyname>Li</keyname>
                        <forenames>Di</forenames>
                </author>
        </authors>
        <title>Evidence for a Damped Millisecond Quasi-Periodic Structure in a Fast Radio Burst</title>
            <categories>astro-ph.HE</categories>
            <comments>Under review</comments>
            <license>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0/</license>
            <abstract>Fast radio bursts (FRBs) are millisecond-duration transients of unknown origin, likely associated with compact astrophysical objects. We report evidence for a damped millisecond quasi-periodic structure in a non-repeat FRB~20190122C. The burst consists of eight closely spaced radio pulses separated by $\sim$1 ms, with pulse amplitudes exhibiting an exponential decay starting from the brightest component. Combined Gaussian fitting and time-series analysis reveal a quasi-periodic oscillation (QPO) at $\sim$1 kHz. The observed QPO is consistent with damped magnetospheric oscillations. Assuming an Alfvén wave origin, we estimate a surface magnetic field of $\sim 10^{12}$ G and a characteristic spin period of $\sim$1 s, favoring a low-field magnetar or young neutron star scenario. The absence of frequency drift and the presence of exponential damping disfavor a merger-driven origin. These results suggest the first detection of an exponentially decaying QPO in any FRB, marking a rare detection of coherent oscillatory behavior in FRBs.</abstract>
    </arXiv>

            </metadata>
        </record>

    </GetRecord>
</OAI-PMH>