<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<OAI-PMH xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" 
         xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance"
         xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/OAI-PMH.xsd">
    <responseDate>2026-07-13T06:26:21Z</responseDate>
                <request verb="GetRecord" identifier="oai:arXiv.org:2602.14838" metadataPrefix="arXiv">http://oaipmh.arxiv.org/oai</request>


    <GetRecord>
                <record>
                <header>
        <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:2602.14838</identifier>
        <datestamp>2026-02-17</datestamp>
            <setSpec>physics:astro-ph:HE</setSpec>
    </header>

            <metadata>
                        <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ https://oaipmh.arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
        <id>2602.14838</id>
        <created>2026-02-16</created>
            <updated>2026-02-17</updated>
        <authors>
                <author>
                    <keyname>Goodwin</keyname>
                        <forenames>Adelle J.</forenames>
                </author>
                <author>
                    <keyname>Mummery</keyname>
                        <forenames>Andrew</forenames>
                </author>
        </authors>
        <title>A universal critical accretion rate for black hole jet formation</title>
            <categories>astro-ph.HE</categories>
            <comments>8 pages + 48 pages of appendices. 3 Figures + 19 Figures in appendices. Under review, comments welcome. Both authors contributed equally</comments>
            <license>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0/</license>
            <abstract>It has long been suspected that black hole accretion-outflow coupling is invariant from the stellar to supermassive scales. Stellar mass black hole accretion flows are known to launch jets and outflows as they transition through critical accretion rate thresholds, with values well constrained observationally owing to their short evolutionary timescales. In contrast, accretion flows in typical supermassive black hole (SMBH) systems (those in active galactic nuclei) evolve over thousands of years, making the critical transitions at which jets are launched impossible to constrain in individual systems. Tidal disruption events (TDEs) provide the unique opportunity to witness the birth and evolution of an accretion flow onto a SMBH which evolves on timescales of years. Here we show that TDEs launch outflows during a super-Eddington accretion phase and a second, physically distinct outflow, at a critical accretion rate of $L_{\rm crit} \approx0.02$ $L_{\rm Edd}$, the same as the critical accretion rate for state transitions observed in accreting stellar mass black holes. This work naturally explains the mechanism, observed properties, and detection rate for prompt and delayed outflows observed in TDEs, which until now have been open problems. More broadly, we demonstrate that SMBHs exhibit the same accretion-outflow coupling as stellar mass black holes and that the critical low accretion rate threshold for jet formation in black holes is scale invariant.</abstract>
    </arXiv>

            </metadata>
        </record>

    </GetRecord>
</OAI-PMH>