<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<OAI-PMH xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" 
         xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance"
         xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/OAI-PMH.xsd">
    <responseDate>2026-07-13T06:24:13Z</responseDate>
                <request verb="GetRecord" identifier="oai:arXiv.org:2603.24067" metadataPrefix="arXiv">http://oaipmh.arxiv.org/oai</request>


    <GetRecord>
                <record>
                <header>
        <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:2603.24067</identifier>
        <datestamp>2026-04-02</datestamp>
            <setSpec>physics:quant-ph</setSpec>
            <setSpec>physics:physics:optics</setSpec>
    </header>

            <metadata>
                        <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ https://oaipmh.arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
        <id>2603.24067</id>
        <created>2026-04-01</created>
            <updated>2026-04-02</updated>
        <authors>
                <author>
                    <keyname>Singh</keyname>
                        <forenames>Ranjit</forenames>
                </author>
                <author>
                    <keyname>Barinov</keyname>
                        <forenames>Leonid A.</forenames>
                </author>
                <author>
                    <keyname>Amosov</keyname>
                        <forenames>Grigori G.</forenames>
                </author>
                <author>
                    <keyname>Masalov</keyname>
                        <forenames>Anatoly V.</forenames>
                </author>
        </authors>
        <title>Towards Schrödinger Cat States in the Second Harmonic Generation</title>
            <categories>quant-ph physics.optics</categories>
            <license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license>
            <abstract>We investigate the quantum evolution of the pump field in second-harmonic generation under strong pump depletion. Starting from a coherent state, the pump develops a nonclassical phase-space structure resembling a Schrödinger cat state. This behavior originates from phase instability induced by vacuum fluctuations of the harmonic mode. A rigorous quantum analysis has been performed for mean photon numbers up to $\langle \hat n \rangle = 100$ in pump mode. For larger photon numbers, up to $\langle \hat n \rangle = 10^{7}$, the dynamics have been analyzed using a classical trajectory method with sampled initial conditions that reproduces the main features of the quantum evolution. The results indicate that nonlinear frequency conversion can generate macroscopic superposition-like states of the pump field. Although the resulting state is not pure due to correlations with the second-harmonic wave, it remains non-classical with negative zones of Wigner function. These results indicate that strongly nonlinear frequency conversion can provide a scalable route toward macroscopic nonclassical states of light.</abstract>
    </arXiv>

            </metadata>
        </record>

    </GetRecord>
</OAI-PMH>