<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<OAI-PMH xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" 
         xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance"
         xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/OAI-PMH.xsd">
    <responseDate>2026-07-13T06:25:36Z</responseDate>
                <request verb="GetRecord" identifier="oai:arXiv.org:2511.13173" metadataPrefix="arXiv">http://oaipmh.arxiv.org/oai</request>


    <GetRecord>
                <record>
                <header>
        <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:2511.13173</identifier>
        <datestamp>2026-06-01</datestamp>
            <setSpec>physics:quant-ph</setSpec>
    </header>

            <metadata>
                        <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ https://oaipmh.arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
        <id>2511.13173</id>
        <created>2026-05-29</created>
            <updated>2026-06-01</updated>
        <authors>
                <author>
                    <keyname>Zhang</keyname>
                        <forenames>Ze-Zhou</forenames>
                </author>
                <author>
                    <keyname>Luo</keyname>
                        <forenames>Hong-Gang</forenames>
                </author>
                <author>
                    <keyname>Wu</keyname>
                        <forenames>Wei</forenames>
                </author>
        </authors>
        <title>Quantum Mpemba Effect Induced by Non-Markovian Exceptional Points</title>
            <categories>quant-ph</categories>
            <journal-ref>Physical Review Letters 136, 210402 (2026)</journal-ref>
            <doi>10.1103/zjdz-rqqd</doi>
            <license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license>
            <abstract>Quantum Mpemba effect describes an anomalous phenomenon of accelerated relaxation which is of fundamental interest in the field of nonequilibrium thermodynamics. Conventional theories on this phenomenon strongly rely on the Born-Markovian approximation resulting in a Lindblad-type master equation whose evolution is governed by a Liouvillian superoperator. It has been demonstrated that exceptional points of the Liouvillian superoperator can induce the Mpemba effect in Markovian regimes. Moving beyond this Markovian limit, we here propose a mechanism for realizing the quantum Mpemba effect in a general non-Markovian relaxation process by means of non-Markovian exceptional points. We verify the feasibility of this mechanism within a dissipative quantum harmonic oscillator model, which is exactly solvable and experimentally practical. Providing new insight into the interesting non-equilibrium dynamics, our work paves a way to accelerate the transfer of energy and information in quantum systems.</abstract>
    </arXiv>

            </metadata>
        </record>

    </GetRecord>
</OAI-PMH>