<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<OAI-PMH xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" 
         xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance"
         xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/OAI-PMH.xsd">
    <responseDate>2026-07-13T06:27:23Z</responseDate>
                <request verb="GetRecord" identifier="oai:arXiv.org:2606.11296" metadataPrefix="arXiv">http://oaipmh.arxiv.org/oai</request>


    <GetRecord>
                <record>
                <header>
        <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:2606.11296</identifier>
        <datestamp>2026-06-25</datestamp>
            <setSpec>physics:hep-ph</setSpec>
            <setSpec>physics:hep-ex</setSpec>
            <setSpec>physics:quant-ph</setSpec>
    </header>

            <metadata>
                        <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ https://oaipmh.arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
        <id>2606.11296</id>
        <created>2026-06-24</created>
            <updated>2026-06-25</updated>
        <authors>
                <author>
                    <keyname>Gonçalves</keyname>
                        <forenames>Dorival</forenames>
                </author>
                <author>
                    <keyname>Navarro</keyname>
                        <forenames>Alberto</forenames>
                </author>
                <author>
                    <keyname>Sakurai</keyname>
                        <forenames>Kazuki</forenames>
                </author>
        </authors>
        <title>Tripartite Entanglement in $e^+ e^- \to t \bar{t} Z$</title>
            <categories>hep-ph hep-ex quant-ph</categories>
            <comments>Figures 4-7 and the associated discussion have been updated</comments>
            <license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license>
            <abstract>Multipartite entanglement is a uniquely quantum form of correlation that captures collective properties of a composite quantum state beyond those encoded in its bipartite subsystems. We investigate this phenomenon in the process $e^+e^-\to t\bar tZ$ at a future lepton collider, where the final state spins span the tripartite Hilbert space $\mathscr{H} = \mathbb{C}^2 \otimes \mathbb{C}^2 \otimes \mathbb{C}^3$. Starting from the Standard Model helicity amplitudes, we reconstruct the full $12\times 12$ spin density matrix and characterise its entanglement structure through one-to-one negativities, one-to-other negativities, and the genuine multipartite negativity, evaluated at three increasingly inclusive levels of phase space integration. Pairwise entanglement is generally suppressed relative to the collective (one-to-other) and the genuine multipartite entanglement, and all measures decrease as more kinematic information is integrated out. Assuming quantum tomography in the fully leptonic decay channel at $\sqrt{s}=1$ TeV, we find that collective entanglement should be accessible at a realistic high-luminosity polarised lepton collider. By contrast, certifying genuine multipartite entanglement is more challenging, with only limited sensitivity projected for a specific polarisation benchmark within the expected ILC luminosity. The study establishes $e^+e^-\to t \bar{t}Z$ as an attractive laboratory for probing multipartite entanglement in high-energy collisions and provides a general mixed state framework that applies to any tripartite spin system.</abstract>
    </arXiv>

            </metadata>
        </record>

    </GetRecord>
</OAI-PMH>