<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<OAI-PMH xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" 
         xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance"
         xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/OAI-PMH.xsd">
    <responseDate>2026-07-11T09:59:27Z</responseDate>
                <request verb="GetRecord" identifier="oai:arXiv.org:2606.06409v1" metadataPrefix="arXiv">http://oaipmh.arxiv.org/oai</request>


    <GetRecord>
                <record>
                <header>
        <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:2606.06409</identifier>
        <datestamp>2026-06-05</datestamp>
            <setSpec>physics:astro-ph:HE</setSpec>
    </header>

            <metadata>
                        <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ https://oaipmh.arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
        <id>2606.06409</id>
        <created>2026-06-04</created>
            <updated>2026-06-05</updated>
        <authors>
                <author>
                    <keyname>Lu</keyname>
                        <forenames>Ming-Xuan</forenames>
                </author>
                <author>
                    <keyname>Liang</keyname>
                        <forenames>Yun-Feng</forenames>
                </author>
                <author>
                    <keyname>Ouyang</keyname>
                        <forenames>Xue-Rui</forenames>
                </author>
                <author>
                    <keyname>Lin</keyname>
                        <forenames>Da-Bin</forenames>
                </author>
                <author>
                    <keyname>Wang</keyname>
                        <forenames>Xiang-Gao</forenames>
                </author>
                <author>
                    <keyname>Fan</keyname>
                        <forenames>Yi-Zhong</forenames>
                </author>
        </authors>
        <title>A high-energy neutrino flare associated with nearby bright interacting supernova SN 2021foa</title>
            <categories>astro-ph.HE</categories>
            <comments>21 pages, 5 figures</comments>
            <license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license>
            <abstract>While core-collapse supernovae have been widely discussed as potential neutrino sources, definitive observational evidence has remained elusive. In this work, we report evidence of high-energy neutrino emission in the direction of supernova SN 2021foa, which is one of the closest and brightest interacting supernovae observed to date. Using the second data release of muon track data from the IceCube Neutrino Observatory, we conducted a time-dependent analysis and identified a neutrino clustering that temporally coincides with the optical peak of SN 2021foa, occurring approximately 16 to 22 days after the discovery date, with a maximum test statistic of $\sim 28.2$. Monte Carlo simulations indicate that the probability of observing such a neutrino excess by chance is $\sim6.7 \times 10^{-5}$, corresponding to a significance of $\sim4.0\,σ$. The spatial and temporal correlation strongly suggests that the neutrinos originate from the supernova. SN 2021foa is a unique &#34;flip-flop&#34; supernova; its spectra repeatedly transitioned between hydrogen-rich (Type IIn) and helium-rich (Type Ibn) phases within 50 days post-peak, reflecting a violent and complex mass-loss history of its progenitor. The inferred neutrino energy exceeds the optical radiative energy and ejecta kinetic energy of the supernova by orders of magnitude, suggesting that the neutrino emission is likely powered by a delayed central engine driving a jet that is choked within the dense circumstellar medium.</abstract>
    </arXiv>

            </metadata>
        </record>

    </GetRecord>
</OAI-PMH>