<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<OAI-PMH xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" 
         xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance"
         xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/OAI-PMH.xsd">
    <responseDate>2026-07-11T21:03:56Z</responseDate>
                <request verb="GetRecord" identifier="oai:arXiv.org:2601.04312v2" metadataPrefix="arXiv">http://oaipmh.arxiv.org/oai</request>


    <GetRecord>
                <record>
                <header>
        <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:2601.04312</identifier>
        <datestamp>2026-06-16</datestamp>
            <setSpec>physics:astro-ph:CO</setSpec>
            <setSpec>physics:hep-ph</setSpec>
            <setSpec>physics:hep-th</setSpec>
    </header>

            <metadata>
                        <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ https://oaipmh.arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
        <id>2601.04312</id>
        <created>2026-06-14</created>
            <updated>2026-06-16</updated>
        <authors>
                <author>
                    <keyname>Abellán</keyname>
                        <forenames>Guillermo Franco</forenames>
                </author>
        </authors>
        <title>Neutrino decays as a natural explanation of the neutrino mass tension</title>
            <categories>astro-ph.CO hep-ph hep-th</categories>
            <comments>5+4 pages, 7 figures, 1 table. Expanded discussion on goodness-of-fit and particle physics implications. v2 matches the published PRD version. Comments welcome!</comments>
            <journal-ref>Phys.Rev.D 113 (2026) 12, 123527</journal-ref>
            <doi>10.1103/lwdv-qrcc</doi>
            <license>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0/</license>
            <abstract>A new tension is emerging between the tight cosmological upper bounds on the total neutrino mass ($\sum m_ν\lesssim 0.06 \, \rm{eV}$) and the lower limits from oscillation experiments, with potentially far-reaching implications for cosmology and particle physics. Neutrinos decaying into massless BSM particles with lifetimes $τ_ν\sim 0.01-1\, \rm{Gyr}$ represent a theoretically well-motivated mechanism to reconcile such measurements. Using DESI DR2 and CMB datasets, we show that such decays relax the bound on the total neutrino mass up to $\sum m_ν&lt; 0.23 \, \rm{eV}$ (95%), restoring full agreement with oscillation data. We also present the first late-time cosmological analysis of neutrino decays into lighter neutrinos in a manner consistent with the measured mass splittings. In contrast to the decays into massless BSM particles, we find that this scenario only marginally alleviates - or even tightens - the cosmological neutrino mass bounds, depending on the mass ordering.</abstract>
    </arXiv>

            </metadata>
        </record>

    </GetRecord>
</OAI-PMH>