<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<OAI-PMH xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" 
         xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance"
         xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/OAI-PMH.xsd">
    <responseDate>2026-07-13T06:22:35Z</responseDate>
                <request verb="GetRecord" identifier="oai:arXiv.org:2508.03569" metadataPrefix="arXiv">http://oaipmh.arxiv.org/oai</request>


    <GetRecord>
                <record>
                <header>
        <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:2508.03569</identifier>
        <datestamp>2026-03-19</datestamp>
            <setSpec>physics:astro-ph:GA</setSpec>
            <setSpec>physics:astro-ph:CO</setSpec>
    </header>

            <metadata>
                        <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ https://oaipmh.arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
        <id>2508.03569</id>
        <created>2026-03-18</created>
            <updated>2026-03-19</updated>
        <authors>
                <author>
                    <keyname>Ko</keyname>
                        <forenames>Enoch</forenames>
                </author>
                <author>
                    <keyname>Yasin</keyname>
                        <forenames>Tariq</forenames>
                </author>
                <author>
                    <keyname>Desmond</keyname>
                        <forenames>Harry</forenames>
                </author>
                <author>
                    <keyname>Stiskalek</keyname>
                        <forenames>Richard</forenames>
                </author>
                <author>
                    <keyname>Jarvis</keyname>
                        <forenames>Matt J.</forenames>
                </author>
        </authors>
        <title>Renzo&#39;s rule revisited: A statistical study of galaxies&#39; baryon - dark matter coupling</title>
            <categories>astro-ph.GA astro-ph.CO</categories>
            <comments>20 pages, 15 figures, 2 tables; minor revision to match MNRAS published version</comments>
            <journal-ref>Mon Not R Astron Soc (2025) 4288-4305</journal-ref>
            <doi>10.1093/mnras/staf2004</doi>
            <license>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0/</license>
            <abstract>We present a systematic statistical analysis of an informal astrophysical phenomenon known as Renzo&#39;s rule (or Sancisi&#39;s law), which states that &#34;for any feature in a galaxy&#39;s luminosity profile, there is a corresponding feature in the rotation curve, and vice versa.&#34; This is often posed as a challenge for the standard LCDM model while supporting alternative theories such as MOND. Indeed, we identify clear features in the dwarf spiral NGC 1560 -- a prime example for Renzo&#39;s rule -- and find correlation statistics which support Renzo&#39;s rule with a slight preference for MOND over LCDM halo fits. However, a broader analysis on galaxies in the SPARC database reveals an excess of features in rotation curves that lack clear baryonic counterparts, with correlation statistics deviating up to $3σ$ on average from that predicted by both MOND and LCDM haloes, challenging the validity of Renzo&#39;s rule. Thus we do not find clear evidence for Renzo&#39;s rule in present galaxy data overall. We additionally perform mock tests, which show that a definitive test of Renzo&#39;s rule is primarily limited by the lack of clearly resolved baryonic features in current galaxy data.</abstract>
    </arXiv>

            </metadata>
        </record>

    </GetRecord>
</OAI-PMH>