<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<OAI-PMH xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" 
         xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance"
         xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/OAI-PMH.xsd">
    <responseDate>2026-07-13T06:21:29Z</responseDate>
                <request verb="GetRecord" identifier="oai:arXiv.org:2511.00146" metadataPrefix="arXiv">http://oaipmh.arxiv.org/oai</request>


    <GetRecord>
                <record>
                <header>
        <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:2511.00146</identifier>
        <datestamp>2025-11-04</datestamp>
            <setSpec>physics:cond-mat:supr-con</setSpec>
            <setSpec>physics:cond-mat:mtrl-sci</setSpec>
            <setSpec>physics:hep-lat</setSpec>
            <setSpec>physics:hep-th</setSpec>
            <setSpec>physics:quant-ph</setSpec>
    </header>

            <metadata>
                        <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ https://oaipmh.arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
        <id>2511.00146</id>
        <created>2025-10-31</created>
            <updated>2025-11-04</updated>
        <authors>
                <author>
                    <keyname>Landry</keyname>
                        <forenames>Michael J</forenames>
                </author>
                <author>
                    <keyname>Li</keyname>
                        <forenames>Mingda</forenames>
                </author>
        </authors>
        <title>Chimeric states of matter: Meissner effect without superconductivity</title>
            <categories>cond-mat.supr-con cond-mat.mtrl-sci hep-lat hep-th quant-ph</categories>
            <comments>7 pages, 3 figures</comments>
            <license>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0/</license>
            <abstract>Symmetry is central to how we classify phases of matter: solids break spatial translations, superfluids break particle-number conservation, and superconductors &#34;break&#34; gauge symmetry. Mixed anomalies involving higher-form symmetries, however, present a generalization of spontaneous symmetry breaking that admits a wider and more versatile set of possibilities. We introduce chimeric states of matter, in which aspects of broken and unbroken phases coexist. We find that the Meissner effect -- usually regarded as the defining hallmark of superconductivity -- can occur in media that are resistive or even insulating when probed by electric fields. We demonstrate this by constructing an effective field theory of &#34;symmetry chimerization&#34; and propose that Josephson junction networks could provide a laboratory realization. These results broaden the landscape of possible phases of matter, showing that physical media can mix features of symmetry-restored and symmetry-broken states in a single substrate.</abstract>
    </arXiv>

            </metadata>
        </record>

    </GetRecord>
</OAI-PMH>