<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<OAI-PMH xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" 
         xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance"
         xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/OAI-PMH.xsd">
    <responseDate>2026-07-13T21:13:24Z</responseDate>
                <request verb="GetRecord" identifier="oai:arXiv.org:2510.05963" metadataPrefix="arXiv">http://oaipmh.arxiv.org/oai</request>


    <GetRecord>
                <record>
                <header>
        <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:2510.05963</identifier>
        <datestamp>2025-10-09</datestamp>
            <setSpec>physics:physics:ao-ph</setSpec>
            <setSpec>physics:physics:geo-ph</setSpec>
    </header>

            <metadata>
                        <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ https://oaipmh.arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
        <id>2510.05963</id>
        <created>2025-10-08</created>
            <updated>2025-10-09</updated>
        <authors>
                <author>
                    <keyname>Hafner</keyname>
                        <forenames>Katharina</forenames>
                </author>
                <author>
                    <keyname>Shamekh</keyname>
                        <forenames>Sara</forenames>
                </author>
                <author>
                    <keyname>Bertoli</keyname>
                        <forenames>Guillaume</forenames>
                </author>
                <author>
                    <keyname>Lauer</keyname>
                        <forenames>Axel</forenames>
                </author>
                <author>
                    <keyname>Pincus</keyname>
                        <forenames>Robert</forenames>
                </author>
                <author>
                    <keyname>Savre</keyname>
                        <forenames>Julien</forenames>
                </author>
                <author>
                    <keyname>Eyring</keyname>
                        <forenames>Veronika</forenames>
                </author>
        </authors>
        <title>Representing Subgrid-Scale Cloud Effects in a Radiation Parameterization using Machine Learning: MLe-radiation v1.0</title>
            <categories>physics.ao-ph physics.geo-ph</categories>
            <comments>submitted to Geoscientific Model Development, 22 pages, 8 figures</comments>
            <license>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0/</license>
            <abstract>Improvements of Machine Learning (ML)-based radiation emulators remain constrained by the underlying assumptions to represent horizontal and vertical subgrid-scale cloud distributions, which continue to introduce substantial uncertainties. In this study, we introduce a method to represent the impact of subgrid-scale clouds by applying ML to learn processes from high-resolution model output with a horizontal grid spacing of 5km. In global storm resolving models, clouds begin to be explicitly resolved. Coarse-graining these high-resolution simulations to the resolution of coarser Earth System Models yields radiative heating rates that implicitly include subgrid-scale cloud effects, without assumptions about their horizontal or vertical distributions. We define the cloud radiative impact as the difference between all-sky and clear-sky radiative fluxes, and train the ML component solely on this cloud-induced contribution to heating rates. The clear-sky tendencies remain being computed with a conventional physics-based radiation scheme. This hybrid design enhances generalization, since the machine-learned part addresses only subgrid-scale cloud effects, while the clear-sky component remains responsive to changes in greenhouse gas or aerosol concentrations. Applied to coarse-grained data offline, the ML-enhanced radiation scheme reduces errors by a factor of 4-10 compared with a conventional coarse-scale radiation scheme. This shows the potential of representing subgrid-scale cloud effects in radiation schemes with ML for the next generation of Earth System Models.</abstract>
    </arXiv>

            </metadata>
        </record>

    </GetRecord>
</OAI-PMH>