<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<OAI-PMH xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" 
         xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance"
         xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/OAI-PMH.xsd">
    <responseDate>2026-07-13T06:23:34Z</responseDate>
                <request verb="GetRecord" identifier="oai:arXiv.org:2601.14368" metadataPrefix="arXiv">http://oaipmh.arxiv.org/oai</request>


    <GetRecord>
                <record>
                <header>
        <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:2601.14368</identifier>
        <datestamp>2026-01-22</datestamp>
            <setSpec>physics:astro-ph:GA</setSpec>
            <setSpec>physics:astro-ph:CO</setSpec>
            <setSpec>physics:astro-ph:HE</setSpec>
    </header>

            <metadata>
                        <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ https://oaipmh.arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
        <id>2601.14368</id>
        <created>2026-01-20</created>
            <updated>2026-01-22</updated>
        <authors>
                <author>
                    <keyname>Pacucci</keyname>
                        <forenames>Fabio</forenames>
                </author>
                <author>
                    <keyname>Ferrara</keyname>
                        <forenames>Andrea</forenames>
                </author>
                <author>
                    <keyname>Kocevski</keyname>
                        <forenames>Dale D.</forenames>
                </author>
        </authors>
        <title>The Little Red Dots Are Direct Collapse Black Holes</title>
            <categories>astro-ph.GA astro-ph.CO astro-ph.HE</categories>
            <comments>Submitted. 17 pages, 4 figures</comments>
            <license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license>
            <abstract>The discovery by JWST of a substantial population of compact &#34;Little Red Dots&#34; (LRDs) presents a major puzzle: their observed spectra defy standard astrophysical interpretations. Here, we show that LRD spectra are naturally reproduced by emission from an accreting Direct Collapse Black Hole (DCBH). Using radiation-hydrodynamic simulations, we follow the growth of the DCBH seed via a dense, compressionally heated, collisionally ionized accretion flow. The model self-consistently reproduces the screen responsible for the observed Balmer absorption, while allowing UV/optical emission to partially escape, along with reprocessed infrared radiation. Crucially, this structure is not a blackbody and requires no stellar contribution: the UV continuum originates entirely from reprocessed DCBH radiation, attenuated only by a small amount of dust with an extinction curve consistent with high-redshift galaxies. This single framework simultaneously explains the key observational puzzles of LRDs: (a) weak X-ray emission, (b) metal and high-ionization lines alongside absent star-formation features, (c) overmassive black holes, (d) compact morphology, (e) abundance and redshift evolution -- linking them directly to pristine atomic-cooling halos, (f) long-lived ($&gt;100$ Myr), slowly variable phases driven by radiation pressure. Our findings indicate that JWST is witnessing the widespread formation of heavy black hole seeds in the early Universe.</abstract>
    </arXiv>

            </metadata>
        </record>

    </GetRecord>
</OAI-PMH>