<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<OAI-PMH xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" 
         xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance"
         xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/OAI-PMH.xsd">
    <responseDate>2026-07-04T19:20:20Z</responseDate>
                <request verb="GetRecord" identifier="oai:arXiv.org:2606.02828v1" metadataPrefix="arXiv">http://oaipmh.arxiv.org/oai</request>


    <GetRecord>
                <record>
                <header>
        <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:2606.02828</identifier>
        <datestamp>2026-06-03</datestamp>
            <setSpec>physics:astro-ph:HE</setSpec>
    </header>

            <metadata>
                        <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ https://oaipmh.arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
        <id>2606.02828</id>
        <created>2026-06-01</created>
            <updated>2026-06-03</updated>
        <authors>
                <author>
                    <keyname>de Avellar</keyname>
                        <forenames>Marcio G B</forenames>
                </author>
                <author>
                    <keyname>Horvath</keyname>
                        <forenames>Jorge E</forenames>
                </author>
                <author>
                    <keyname>Pires</keyname>
                        <forenames>Nathalia D</forenames>
                </author>
                <author>
                    <keyname>Rocha</keyname>
                        <forenames>Lívia S</forenames>
                </author>
                <author>
                    <keyname>de Sá</keyname>
                        <forenames>Lucas M</forenames>
                </author>
                <author>
                    <keyname>Martins</keyname>
                        <forenames>Bianca B</forenames>
                </author>
                <author>
                    <keyname>Barão</keyname>
                        <forenames>Lucas G</forenames>
                </author>
                <author>
                    <keyname>Rodrigues</keyname>
                        <forenames>Davi V</forenames>
                </author>
                <author>
                    <keyname>Sampaio</keyname>
                        <forenames>Guilherme R C</forenames>
                </author>
                <author>
                    <keyname>Takahashi</keyname>
                        <forenames>Rachel M</forenames>
                </author>
        </authors>
        <title>The mass of the neutron star in 4U 1820-30 revisited</title>
            <categories>astro-ph.HE</categories>
            <comments>8 pages, 1 figure</comments>
            <doi>10.1016/j.jheap.2026.100651</doi>
            <license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license>
            <abstract>We revisit the mass of the neutron star in the ultracompact binary 4U 1820--30 in light of a recently reported transient absorption feature at about 3.8 keV, interpreted as a gravitationally redshifted, highly ionized iron line and implying \(1+z\simeq1.72\), a very high stellar compactness. We examine whether the mass-radius locus implied by this interpretation can be made compatible with external EoS-informed benchmarks and timing-based estimates. We map the compactness implied by the redshift onto the mass-radius plane, including rotational effects, and compare the resulting region with an EoS-informed 95\% reference contour derived from NICER data of several neutron-star systems. While we do not perform a statistically self-consistent joint mass-radius inference for 4U 1820--30, we present a quantitative conditional consistency test in a common \(M-R\) framework, comparing published inputs under explicitly stated assumptions. We find that, if the maximum neutron-star mass is restricted to low values \((\leq 2.3\,M_{\odot})\), the redshift-implied locus shows at most marginal overlap with the EoS-informed contour, indicating substantial tension. Allowing a higher maximum mass enlarges the parameter space and can restore compatibility with that benchmark. However, such high masses remain in tension with previous touchdown-flux estimates, although they are not necessarily excluded by interpretations based on the highest detected quasi-periodic oscillation frequency. We conclude that the redshift interpretation of the 3.8 keV feature, the touchdown-flux estimates, and the QPO/ISCO interpretation do not naturally select the same mass-radius sector for this source under these assumptions. Reconciling them requires auxiliary assumptions with high leverage on the inferred compactness.</abstract>
    </arXiv>

            </metadata>
        </record>

    </GetRecord>
</OAI-PMH>