<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<OAI-PMH xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" 
         xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance"
         xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/OAI-PMH.xsd">
    <responseDate>2026-07-11T21:35:05Z</responseDate>
                <request verb="GetRecord" identifier="oai:arXiv.org:2601.04774v1" metadataPrefix="arXiv">http://oaipmh.arxiv.org/oai</request>


    <GetRecord>
                <record>
                <header>
        <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:2601.04774</identifier>
        <datestamp>2026-05-13</datestamp>
            <setSpec>physics:astro-ph:CO</setSpec>
    </header>

            <metadata>
                        <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ https://oaipmh.arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
        <id>2601.04774</id>
        <created>2026-01-08</created>
            <updated>2026-05-13</updated>
        <authors>
                <author>
                    <keyname>Andrade-Oliveira</keyname>
                        <forenames>Felipe</forenames>
                </author>
                <author>
                    <keyname>Sanchez-Cid</keyname>
                        <forenames>David</forenames>
                </author>
                <author>
                    <keyname>Laghi</keyname>
                        <forenames>Danny</forenames>
                </author>
                <author>
                    <keyname>Soares-Santos</keyname>
                        <forenames>Marcelle</forenames>
                </author>
        </authors>
        <title>First measurement of the Hubble constant from a combined weak lensing and gravitational-wave standard siren analysis</title>
            <categories>astro-ph.CO</categories>
            <comments>5 pages, 2 figures</comments>
            <journal-ref>A&amp;A 709, L14 (2026)</journal-ref>
            <doi>10.1051/0004-6361/202659044</doi>
            <license>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0/</license>
            <abstract>We present a new measurement of the Hubble constant ($H_0$) resulting from the first joint analysis of standard sirens with weak gravitational lensing and galaxy clustering observables comprising three two-point correlation functions (3$\times$2pt). For the 3$\times$2pt component of the analysis, we use data from the Dark Energy Survey (DES) Year 3 release. For the standard sirens component, we use data from the Gravitational-Wave Transient Catalog 4.0 released by the LIGO-Virgo-KAGRA (LVK) Collaboration. For GW170817, the only standard siren for which extensive electromagnetic follow-up observations exist, we also use measurements of the host galaxy redshift and inclination angle estimates derived from observations of a superluminal jet from its remnant. Our joint analysis yields $H_0 = 67.9^{+4.4}_{-4.3}$~km~s$^{-1}$~Mpc$^{-1}$, a $6.4\%$ measurement, while improving the DES constraint on the total abundance of matter $Ω_m$ by $22\%$. Removing the jet information degrades the $H_0$ precision to $9.9\%$. The measurement of $H_0$ remains a central problem in cosmology with a multitude of approaches being vigorously pursued in the community aiming to reconcile significantly discrepant measurements at the percent-level. In light of the impending new data releases from DES and LVK, and anticipating much more constraining power from 3$\times$2pt observables using newly commissioned survey instruments, we demonstrate that incorporating standard sirens into the cosmology framework of large cosmic surveys is a viable route towards that goal.</abstract>
    </arXiv>

            </metadata>
        </record>

    </GetRecord>
</OAI-PMH>