<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<OAI-PMH xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" 
         xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance"
         xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/OAI-PMH.xsd">
    <responseDate>2026-07-11T20:14:19Z</responseDate>
                <request verb="GetRecord" identifier="oai:arXiv.org:2601.01039v1" metadataPrefix="arXiv">http://oaipmh.arxiv.org/oai</request>


    <GetRecord>
                <record>
                <header>
        <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:2601.01039</identifier>
        <datestamp>2026-01-06</datestamp>
            <setSpec>physics:cond-mat:quant-gas</setSpec>
            <setSpec>physics:astro-ph:CO</setSpec>
            <setSpec>physics:astro-ph:GA</setSpec>
            <setSpec>physics:gr-qc</setSpec>
            <setSpec>physics:quant-ph</setSpec>
    </header>

            <metadata>
                        <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ https://oaipmh.arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
        <id>2601.01039</id>
        <created>2026-01-03</created>
            <updated>2026-01-06</updated>
        <authors>
                <author>
                    <keyname>Liu</keyname>
                        <forenames>Ning</forenames>
                </author>
        </authors>
        <title>Ground State and Collective Modes of Bose-Einstein Condensates in Newtonian and MOND-inspired gravitational potentials</title>
            <categories>cond-mat.quant-gas astro-ph.CO astro-ph.GA gr-qc quant-ph</categories>
            <comments>9 pages, 3 figures</comments>
            <license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license>
            <abstract>We analytically and numerically study the ground state and collective dynamics of Bose-Einstein condensates in two traps: a Newtonian potential and a logarithmic potential inspired by Modified Newtonian Dynamics (MOND). In the ground state, the MOND potential supports bound states only in the deep-MOND regime, where the condensate becomes significantly larger than its Newtonian counterpart. The size increases with repulsive coupling parameter $β$ in both potentials. A clear scaling law of the size with $β^{1/3}$ emerges in the MOND case and is confirmed numerically over a wide parameter range, while for the Newtonian potential no simple scaling law exists as the Thomas-Fermi approximation ceases to be valid. For the dynamics, we derive and solve equations for the monopole collective mode. The larger MOND-bound condensate oscillates at a lower frequency, which scales as $β^{-1/3}$ in the strong-interaction limit. These scaling laws provide insights for quantum-simulation experiments aiming to probe modified-gravity scenarios with cold atoms.</abstract>
    </arXiv>

            </metadata>
        </record>

    </GetRecord>
</OAI-PMH>