<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<OAI-PMH xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" 
         xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance"
         xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/OAI-PMH.xsd">
    <responseDate>2026-07-12T23:44:19Z</responseDate>
                <request verb="GetRecord" identifier="oai:arXiv.org:2605.15374v1" metadataPrefix="arXiv">http://oaipmh.arxiv.org/oai</request>


    <GetRecord>
                <record>
                <header>
        <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:2605.15374</identifier>
        <datestamp>2026-05-18</datestamp>
            <setSpec>physics:gr-qc</setSpec>
    </header>

            <metadata>
                        <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ https://oaipmh.arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
        <id>2605.15374</id>
        <created>2026-05-14</created>
            <updated>2026-05-18</updated>
        <authors>
                <author>
                    <keyname>Jay</keyname>
                        <forenames>Kanabar</forenames>
                </author>
                <author>
                    <keyname>Khlopov</keyname>
                        <forenames>Maxim</forenames>
                </author>
                <author>
                    <keyname>Novák</keyname>
                        <forenames>Jan</forenames>
                </author>
        </authors>
        <title>The cosmological inflation inside the cyclic model of the universe</title>
            <categories>gr-qc</categories>
            <comments>All comments are welcome. Essay written for the Gravity Research Foundation 2026 Awards for Essays on Gravitation</comments>
            <license>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0/</license>
            <abstract>Inflationary cosmology explains the homogeneity and large-scale structure of the universe through a brief epoch of accelerated expansion following the Big Bang. Cyclic cosmologies, in contrast, describe a universe undergoing successive phases of expansion and contraction and can generate primordial perturbations through alternative mechanisms while extending cosmic history beyond a singular beginning. Because these paradigms address different aspects of cosmic evolution, they are often treated separately. Here we explore the possibility that they may instead arise together. In a cosmological scenario involving two scalar fields, one field governs the cyclic evolution of the universe while the other drives an inflationary phase after each cosmological bounce, suggesting that inflation may be a recurring feature of a cyclic universe.</abstract>
    </arXiv>

            </metadata>
        </record>

    </GetRecord>
</OAI-PMH>