<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<OAI-PMH xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" 
         xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance"
         xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/OAI-PMH.xsd">
    <responseDate>2026-07-13T06:21:14Z</responseDate>
                <request verb="GetRecord" identifier="oai:arXiv.org:2509.07386" metadataPrefix="arXiv">http://oaipmh.arxiv.org/oai</request>


    <GetRecord>
                <record>
                <header>
        <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:2509.07386</identifier>
        <datestamp>2025-09-10</datestamp>
            <setSpec>physics:hep-ex</setSpec>
            <setSpec>physics:gr-qc</setSpec>
    </header>

            <metadata>
                        <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ https://oaipmh.arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
        <id>2509.07386</id>
        <created>2025-09-09</created>
            <updated>2025-09-10</updated>
        <authors>
                <author>
                    <keyname>Hessami</keyname>
                        <forenames>Rafi</forenames>
                </author>
                <author>
                    <keyname>Al-Naseri</keyname>
                        <forenames>Haidar</forenames>
                </author>
                <author>
                    <keyname>Yadav</keyname>
                        <forenames>Monika</forenames>
                </author>
                <author>
                    <keyname>Oruganti</keyname>
                        <forenames>Maanas Hemanth</forenames>
                </author>
                <author>
                    <keyname>Naranjo</keyname>
                        <forenames>Brian</forenames>
                </author>
                <author>
                    <keyname>Rosenzweig</keyname>
                        <forenames>James</forenames>
                </author>
        </authors>
        <title>Simulating Unruh Radiation in High-Intensity Laser-Electron Interactions for Near-Term Experimental Tests</title>
            <categories>hep-ex gr-qc</categories>
            <comments>9 pages, 7 figures</comments>
            <license>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0/</license>
            <abstract>The Unruh effect predicts that a uniformly accelerating observer perceives the vacuum as a thermal bath, yet direct observation remains elusive [1]. We simulate Unruh radiation in realistic high-intensity laser-electron collisions relevant to FACET-II and LUXE using fully three-dimensional Monte Carlo methods. In our model, Unruh emission is treated as scattering from a rest-frame thermal spectrum with Klein-Nishina cross sections, while nonlinear Compton radiation is computed across many harmonic orders with photon recoil. We map the laboratory-frame spectral-angular distributions and identify phase-space regions where the Unruh-to-Compton ratio is maximized. For current FACET-II-like parameters (a0 = 5), favorable windows for observing Unruh radiation occur at 200-400 microrad and 2-3 GeV, although the absolute signal is small. For future LUXE Phase-1 (a0 = 23.6), the ratio increases by more than two orders of magnitude, with optimal angles around 800 microrad and photon energies 2-6 GeV. Our results suggest that targeted off-axis, mid-energy selections can enhance sensitivity to Unruh-like signatures, motivating dedicated measurements and further theoretical scrutiny of the emission model at high field strengths.</abstract>
    </arXiv>

            </metadata>
        </record>

    </GetRecord>
</OAI-PMH>