<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<OAI-PMH xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" 
         xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance"
         xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/OAI-PMH.xsd">
    <responseDate>2026-07-11T08:50:36Z</responseDate>
                <request verb="GetRecord" identifier="oai:arXiv.org:2606.05320v1" metadataPrefix="arXiv">http://oaipmh.arxiv.org/oai</request>


    <GetRecord>
                <record>
                <header>
        <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:2606.05320</identifier>
        <datestamp>2026-06-05</datestamp>
            <setSpec>physics:hep-ph</setSpec>
            <setSpec>physics:astro-ph:CO</setSpec>
            <setSpec>physics:astro-ph:HE</setSpec>
            <setSpec>physics:hep-ex</setSpec>
    </header>

            <metadata>
                        <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ https://oaipmh.arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
        <id>2606.05320</id>
        <created>2026-06-03</created>
            <updated>2026-06-05</updated>
        <authors>
                <author>
                    <keyname>Babu</keyname>
                        <forenames>K. S.</forenames>
                </author>
                <author>
                    <keyname>Chandrasekar</keyname>
                        <forenames>Sai Charan</forenames>
                </author>
                <author>
                    <keyname>Jana</keyname>
                        <forenames>Sudip</forenames>
                </author>
                <author>
                    <keyname>Manna</keyname>
                        <forenames>Sudip</forenames>
                </author>
        </authors>
        <title>Gravitational Wave Imprints of a High-Quality Axion and the Origin of Flavor Hierarchies</title>
            <categories>hep-ph astro-ph.CO astro-ph.HE hep-ex</categories>
            <comments>10 pages, 3 figures</comments>
            <report-no>HRI-RECAPP-2026-05</report-no>
            <license>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0/</license>
            <abstract>Axions, arising from an anomalous global Peccei-Quinn symmetry $U(1)_{\text{PQ}}$, offer a compelling solution to the strong CP problem but are vulnerable to Planck-suppressed operators. Gauged abelian flavor symmetries $U(1)_F$, invoked to explain the flavor hierarchies via the Froggatt-Nielsen mechanism, can naturally shield the axion from such effects, yielding an accidental high-quality flavored axion with unit domain wall number. Such constructions predict two complementary signatures: (i) flavor-changing neutral currents from $K\toπa$ decays, typically associated with high flavor scales $Λ_{\text{FN}}\gtrsim f_a$, and (ii) stochastic Gravitational Waves (GWs) sourced by the evolution and decay of gauged flavonic and axionic cosmic-string networks. In addition, global axionic strings can efficiently radiate axions, potentially accounting for the observed dark matter relic abundance. We show that the resulting characteristic plateau--valley structure in the GW spectrum provides a distinctive and powerful probe of high-quality flavored axion dark matter models, complementary to low-energy flavor experiments.</abstract>
    </arXiv>

            </metadata>
        </record>

    </GetRecord>
</OAI-PMH>