<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<OAI-PMH xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" 
         xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance"
         xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/OAI-PMH.xsd">
    <responseDate>2026-07-13T06:22:08Z</responseDate>
                <request verb="GetRecord" identifier="oai:arXiv.org:2604.09524" metadataPrefix="arXiv">http://oaipmh.arxiv.org/oai</request>


    <GetRecord>
                <record>
                <header>
        <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:2604.09524</identifier>
        <datestamp>2026-04-13</datestamp>
            <setSpec>physics:astro-ph:EP</setSpec>
            <setSpec>physics:astro-ph:HE</setSpec>
            <setSpec>physics:astro-ph:IM</setSpec>
    </header>

            <metadata>
                        <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ https://oaipmh.arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
        <id>2604.09524</id>
        <created>2026-04-10</created>
            <updated>2026-04-13</updated>
        <authors>
                <author>
                    <keyname>Costello</keyname>
                        <forenames>Emily S.</forenames>
                </author>
                <author>
                    <keyname>Ellis</keyname>
                        <forenames>John</forenames>
                </author>
                <author>
                    <keyname>Fields</keyname>
                        <forenames>Brian D.</forenames>
                </author>
                <author>
                    <keyname>Surman</keyname>
                        <forenames>Rebecca</forenames>
                </author>
                <author>
                    <keyname>Wang</keyname>
                        <forenames>Xilu</forenames>
                </author>
        </authors>
        <title>Gardening on the Moon: An Advection-Diffusion Model to Guide the Search for Supernova Debris in the Lunar Regolith</title>
            <categories>astro-ph.EP astro-ph.HE astro-ph.IM</categories>
            <comments>5 pages + Supplementary Material, 6 figures</comments>
            <report-no>KCL-PH-TH/2026-10, CERN-TH-2026-073</report-no>
            <license>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0/</license>
            <abstract>The vertical redistribution of materials in the lunar regolith - ranging from continuously produced space-weathering products to sporadic pulses of supernova- or kilonova-derived isotopes - remains a fundamental problem in planetary science. We present a unified stochastic model of regolith gardening induced by the impact flux. Treating gardening as a competition between impact-driven advection and diffusion predicts the maturity profiles of Apollo cores over more than two orders of magnitude in time ($1.4 \times 10^7$ to $4.5 \times 10^8$ years). This model describes well the depth profiles of live Fe60 in Apollo regolith samples, suggesting that supernova dust capture is independent of native iron abundance, and is consistent with a uniform influx at the latitudes of the Apollo landing sites. We extend our model to predict lunar signals for live r-process species that might originate from supernovae or kilonovae: Pu244 tied to terrestrial detections, and I129, Hf182, and Cm247 based on r-process calculations. The Pu244/Fe60 depth profile can probe the origin of Pu244, motivating searches in Artemis regolith samples down to depths O(100) cm.</abstract>
    </arXiv>

            </metadata>
        </record>

    </GetRecord>
</OAI-PMH>