<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<OAI-PMH xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" 
         xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance"
         xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/OAI-PMH.xsd">
    <responseDate>2026-07-13T06:22:49Z</responseDate>
                <request verb="GetRecord" identifier="oai:arXiv.org:2509.08868" metadataPrefix="arXiv">http://oaipmh.arxiv.org/oai</request>


    <GetRecord>
                <record>
                <header>
        <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:2509.08868</identifier>
        <datestamp>2025-10-08</datestamp>
            <setSpec>physics:hep-lat</setSpec>
            <setSpec>physics:cond-mat:quant-gas</setSpec>
            <setSpec>physics:cond-mat:stat-mech</setSpec>
            <setSpec>physics:hep-ph</setSpec>
            <setSpec>physics:quant-ph</setSpec>
    </header>

            <metadata>
                        <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ https://oaipmh.arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
        <id>2509.08868</id>
        <created>2025-10-07</created>
            <updated>2025-10-08</updated>
        <authors>
                <author>
                    <keyname>Cataldi</keyname>
                        <forenames>Giovanni</forenames>
                </author>
                <author>
                    <keyname>Orlando</keyname>
                        <forenames>Simone</forenames>
                </author>
                <author>
                    <keyname>Halimeh</keyname>
                        <forenames>Jad C.</forenames>
                </author>
        </authors>
        <title>Real-Time String Dynamics in a $2+1$D Non-Abelian Lattice Gauge Theory: String Breaking, Glueball Formation, Baryon Blockade, and Tension Reduction</title>
            <categories>hep-lat cond-mat.quant-gas cond-mat.stat-mech hep-ph quant-ph</categories>
            <comments>$10+5$ pages, $5+3$ figures</comments>
            <license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license>
            <abstract>Understanding flux string dynamics can provide insight into quark confinement and hadronization. First-principles quantum and numerical simulations have mostly focused on toy-model Abelian lattice gauge theories (LGTs). With the advent of state-of-the-art quantum simulation experiments, it is important to bridge this gap and study string dynamics in non-Abelian LGTs beyond one spatial dimension. Using tensor network methods, we simulate the real-time string dynamics of a $2\!+\!1$D SU$(2)$ Yang--Mills LGT with dynamical matter. In the strong-coupling regime and at resonance, string breaking occurs through sharp Casimir reduction along with meson and baryon-antibaryon formation, a distinctively non-Abelian feature. At finite baryon density, we discover a \textit{baryon blockade} mechanism that delays string breaking. Away from resonance, the magnetic term drives purely non-Abelian fluctuations: glueball loops and self-crossed strings that resolve two SU$(2)$ intertwiners with distinct dynamics. For higher-energy strings, we uncover representation-dependent tension-reduction resonances. Our findings serve as a guide for upcoming quantum simulators of non-Abelian LGTs.</abstract>
    </arXiv>

            </metadata>
        </record>

    </GetRecord>
</OAI-PMH>