<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<OAI-PMH xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" 
         xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance"
         xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/OAI-PMH.xsd">
    <responseDate>2026-07-12T15:51:09Z</responseDate>
                <request verb="GetRecord" identifier="oai:arXiv.org:2506.01401v2" metadataPrefix="arXiv">http://oaipmh.arxiv.org/oai</request>


    <GetRecord>
                <record>
                <header>
        <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:2506.01401</identifier>
        <datestamp>2025-10-09</datestamp>
            <setSpec>physics:cond-mat:mes-hall</setSpec>
            <setSpec>physics:quant-ph</setSpec>
    </header>

            <metadata>
                        <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ https://oaipmh.arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
        <id>2506.01401</id>
        <created>2025-08-31</created>
            <updated>2025-10-09</updated>
        <authors>
                <author>
                    <keyname>Zhou</keyname>
                        <forenames>Longwen</forenames>
                </author>
                <author>
                    <keyname>Zhang</keyname>
                        <forenames>Fan</forenames>
                </author>
                <author>
                    <keyname>Pan</keyname>
                        <forenames>Jiaxin</forenames>
                </author>
        </authors>
        <title>Floquet Möbius topological insulators</title>
            <categories>cond-mat.mes-hall quant-ph</categories>
            <comments>19 pages, 10 figures</comments>
            <journal-ref>Phys. Rev. B 112, 134302 (2025)</journal-ref>
            <doi>10.1103/7y54-n6js</doi>
            <license>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0/</license>
            <abstract>Möbius topological insulators have dispersive edge bands with Möbius twists in momentum space, which are protected by the combination of chiral and $Z_2$-projective translational symmetries. In this work, we reveal a unique type of Möbius topological insulator, whose edge bands could twist around the quasienergy $π$ of a periodically driven system and are thus of Floquet origin. By applying time-periodic quenches to an experimentally realized Möbius insulator model, we obtain interconnected Möbius edge bands around zero and $π$ quasienergies, which can coexist with a gapped or gapless bulk. These Möbius bands are topologically characterized by a pair of generalized winding numbers, which are integer-quantized due to an emergent chiral symmetry at a high-symmetry point in momentum space. Numerical investigations of the quasienergy and entanglement spectra provide consistent evidence for the presence of such Möbius topological phases. A protocol based on the adiabatic switching of edge-band populations is further introduced to dynamically characterize the topology of Floquet Möbius edge bands. Our findings thus extend the scope of Möbius topological phases to nonequilibrium settings and unveil a unique class of Möbius-twisted topological edge states without static counterparts.</abstract>
    </arXiv>

            </metadata>
        </record>

    </GetRecord>
</OAI-PMH>