<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<OAI-PMH xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" 
         xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance"
         xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/OAI-PMH.xsd">
    <responseDate>2026-07-11T08:20:25Z</responseDate>
                <request verb="GetRecord" identifier="oai:arXiv.org:2606.03414v1" metadataPrefix="arXiv">http://oaipmh.arxiv.org/oai</request>


    <GetRecord>
                <record>
                <header>
        <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:2606.03414</identifier>
        <datestamp>2026-06-04</datestamp>
            <setSpec>physics:astro-ph:CO</setSpec>
            <setSpec>physics:gr-qc</setSpec>
            <setSpec>physics:hep-th</setSpec>
    </header>

            <metadata>
                        <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ https://oaipmh.arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
        <id>2606.03414</id>
        <created>2026-06-02</created>
            <updated>2026-06-04</updated>
        <authors>
                <author>
                    <keyname>Lin</keyname>
                        <forenames>Chunshan</forenames>
                </author>
        </authors>
        <title>Hidden-sector accretion and warped black-string seeds for high-redshift supermassive black holes</title>
            <categories>astro-ph.CO gr-qc hep-th</categories>
            <comments>16 pages, 1 figure</comments>
            <license>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0/</license>
            <abstract>The earliest massive black holes are often discussed in terms of heavy baryonic seeds, primordial black holes, or super-Eddington accretion. We develop a different possibility: a compact object on a hidden donor brane forms a common five-dimensional horizon whose intersection with our brane is observed as a black-hole seed. Donor-side matter accretes onto the common five-dimensional horizon, increases the horizon radius, and consequently enlarges its intersection with our brane. As a result, the gravitational mass inferred by an observer living on our brane grows. We slice the five-dimensional geometry onto each brane and show that the induced exterior on our brane has the usual Schwarzschild/Vaidya monopole form at leading order, with subleading Weyl/Kaluza-Klein corrections in the localized-feeding branch. We construct a perturbative gradient-expansion solution satisfying the regular bulk equations and brane junction conditions. The matter sector satisfies the null energy condition for positive mass growth. The linear perturbation stability is investigated, and for supermassive seeds with horizon radius far larger than the interbrane scale, the dangerous long-wavelength mode is absent. The primary observational consequences are overmassive high-redshift black holes in underdeveloped hosts, hidden mass growth relative to the luminous accretion budget, LISA-band heavy-seed mergers, and the absence of primordial fossils required by primordial-black-hole explanations.</abstract>
    </arXiv>

            </metadata>
        </record>

    </GetRecord>
</OAI-PMH>