<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<OAI-PMH xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" 
         xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance"
         xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/OAI-PMH.xsd">
    <responseDate>2026-07-13T06:25:43Z</responseDate>
                <request verb="GetRecord" identifier="oai:arXiv.org:2512.03118" metadataPrefix="arXiv">http://oaipmh.arxiv.org/oai</request>


    <GetRecord>
                <record>
                <header>
        <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:2512.03118</identifier>
        <datestamp>2025-12-04</datestamp>
            <setSpec>physics:gr-qc</setSpec>
            <setSpec>physics:astro-ph:EP</setSpec>
            <setSpec>physics:astro-ph:IM</setSpec>
    </header>

            <metadata>
                        <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ https://oaipmh.arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
        <id>2512.03118</id>
        <created>2025-12-02</created>
            <updated>2025-12-04</updated>
        <authors>
                <author>
                    <keyname>Halpern</keyname>
                        <forenames>Paul</forenames>
                </author>
                <author>
                    <keyname>Cauley</keyname>
                        <forenames>Erik</forenames>
                </author>
                <author>
                    <keyname>Stoltzmann</keyname>
                        <forenames>Max</forenames>
                </author>
                <author>
                    <keyname>Wilshusen</keyname>
                        <forenames>Mauritz</forenames>
                </author>
        </authors>
        <title>Probing for primordial black hole candidates in exoplanet search data</title>
            <categories>gr-qc astro-ph.EP astro-ph.IM</categories>
            <comments>9 pages; 2 figures</comments>
            <license>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0/</license>
            <abstract>We have sifted through astrophysical data collected by various radial velocity and gravitational microlensing searches for exoplanets with the goal of identifying potential signs of the presence of primordial black holes (PBH). Our motivation is that those hypothesized remnants of inhomogeneous energetic fluctuations in the early universe, though too small for direct detection, are thought to have a mass range similar to that of planets. Thereby, if captured by stars, they could conceivably make their presence known through stellar wobbles picked up by means of Doppler spectroscopy in the radial velocity method, or alternatively through microlensing. In our analysis of such data, we have identified potential PBH contenders by ruling out any exoplanet candidates that have been detected through direct imaging or transit methods, as they would have sizes consistent with planets rather than PBHs. In particular we focus on the objects Kepler-21 Ac, HD 219134 f, Gliese 686 b, HR 5183 b, HD 20794 e, and Wolf 1061 d, each of which has been found using the radial velocity method but never imaged (either directly or through transit). We also examine the microlensing events MOA 2009-BLG-387L and OGLE-2016-BLG-1540, which offer promise as candidate PBHs. We present these as a representative, but not exclusive list, of potential PBH contenders. Furthermore, future imaging, especially focused on signals of planetary dimensions versus evaporation signatures, might clarify which of these are indeed exoplanets.</abstract>
    </arXiv>

            </metadata>
        </record>

    </GetRecord>
</OAI-PMH>