<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<OAI-PMH xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" 
         xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance"
         xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/OAI-PMH.xsd">
    <responseDate>2026-07-13T06:21:04Z</responseDate>
                <request verb="GetRecord" identifier="oai:arXiv.org:2508.18131" metadataPrefix="arXiv">http://oaipmh.arxiv.org/oai</request>


    <GetRecord>
                <record>
                <header>
        <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:2508.18131</identifier>
        <datestamp>2026-03-24</datestamp>
            <setSpec>physics:quant-ph</setSpec>
            <setSpec>physics:cond-mat:mes-hall</setSpec>
    </header>

            <metadata>
                        <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ https://oaipmh.arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
        <id>2508.18131</id>
        <created>2026-02-25</created>
            <updated>2026-03-24</updated>
        <authors>
                <author>
                    <keyname>Hou</keyname>
                        <forenames>Vince</forenames>
                </author>
                <author>
                    <keyname>Kleinherbers</keyname>
                        <forenames>Eric</forenames>
                </author>
                <author>
                    <keyname>Kelly</keyname>
                        <forenames>Shane P.</forenames>
                </author>
                <author>
                    <keyname>Tserkovnyak</keyname>
                        <forenames>Yaroslav</forenames>
                </author>
        </authors>
        <title>Breaking conservation law enables steady-state entanglement out of equilibrium</title>
            <categories>quant-ph cond-mat.mes-hall</categories>
            <comments>5 pages + supplemental material, 4 figures</comments>
            <doi>10.1103/vbq1-xv4w</doi>
            <license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license>
            <abstract>We show how entangled steady states can be prepared by purely dissipative dynamics in a system coupled to a thermal environment. While entanglement is hindered by thermalization when the system and environment exchange a conserved quantity, we demonstrate that breaking this conservation law through the system-environment interaction drives the system to a nonequilibrium steady state. Such an interaction will generate multiple competing equilibration channels, effectively mimicking baths at distinct chemical potentials. When the environment also supports long-range correlations, these channels mediate nonlocal dissipation capable of generating entanglement. We illustrate the scheme in a model of two nitrogen-vacancy (NV) centers weakly coupled to a spin-pumped magnet, where tuneable magnon excitations enable steady-state entanglement over finite distances. Our results identifies a general mechanism for dissipative entanglement generation, rooted in the conservation structure and environmental correlations rather than fine-tuned coherent control or active driving.</abstract>
    </arXiv>

            </metadata>
        </record>

    </GetRecord>
</OAI-PMH>