<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<OAI-PMH xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" 
         xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance"
         xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/OAI-PMH.xsd">
    <responseDate>2026-07-13T06:28:32Z</responseDate>
                <request verb="GetRecord" identifier="oai:arXiv.org:2606.03993" metadataPrefix="arXiv">http://oaipmh.arxiv.org/oai</request>


    <GetRecord>
                <record>
                <header>
        <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:2606.03993</identifier>
        <datestamp>2026-06-03</datestamp>
            <setSpec>physics:nucl-th</setSpec>
            <setSpec>physics:hep-ph</setSpec>
            <setSpec>physics:nucl-ex</setSpec>
    </header>

            <metadata>
                        <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ https://oaipmh.arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
        <id>2606.03993</id>
        <created>2026-06-02</created>
            <updated>2026-06-03</updated>
        <authors>
                <author>
                    <keyname>Giacalone</keyname>
                        <forenames>Giuliano</forenames>
                </author>
                <author>
                    <keyname>Nijs</keyname>
                        <forenames>Govert</forenames>
                </author>
                <author>
                    <keyname>van der Schee</keyname>
                        <forenames>Wilke</forenames>
                </author>
        </authors>
        <title>Yoctosecond imaging of the ground state of $^{129}$Xe at the Large Hadron Collider</title>
            <categories>nucl-th hep-ph nucl-ex</categories>
            <comments>6 pages, 4 figures plus supplemental. Comments welcome</comments>
            <report-no>CERN-TH-2026-124</report-no>
            <license>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0/</license>
            <abstract>Imaging a quantum many-body system requires probes that resolve the coordinates of its constituents in sufficiently large event samples, allowing measurements of correlation functions [1-4]. High-energy nuclear collisions provide this opportunity on the nuclear scale [5], enabling features of colliding ions, such as their deformation, to be probed through particle correlation observables [6, 7]. However, a quantitative extraction of the correlation properties of nuclei from these measurements is still lacking. Here we show that this is possible for the nucleus $^{129}$Xe using Bayesian inference methods. We combine a deformed-rotor description of the colliding nuclei, which encodes the many-body dynamics of constituent neutrons and protons, with hydrodynamic simulations of the ensuing collision evolution. From a combined global analysis of Large Hadron Collider data on Xe-Xe and Pb-Pb collisions, we then infer that the shape of $^{129}$Xe is nearly maximally triaxial, which aligns with mean-field results for xenon isotopes away from shell closure [8, 9]. From this we evaluate two- and three-particle correlations in the nuclear ground state to provide new constraints for \textit{ab initio} methods in nuclear theory. We establish thus collider experiments as a means of quantifying correlations of protons and neutrons arising from residual forces of quantum chromodynamics.</abstract>
    </arXiv>

            </metadata>
        </record>

    </GetRecord>
</OAI-PMH>