<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<OAI-PMH xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" 
         xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance"
         xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/OAI-PMH.xsd">
    <responseDate>2026-07-13T06:29:04Z</responseDate>
                <request verb="GetRecord" identifier="oai:arXiv.org:2509.19944" metadataPrefix="arXiv">http://oaipmh.arxiv.org/oai</request>


    <GetRecord>
                <record>
                <header>
        <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:2509.19944</identifier>
        <datestamp>2026-06-30</datestamp>
            <setSpec>physics:quant-ph</setSpec>
    </header>

            <metadata>
                        <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ https://oaipmh.arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
        <id>2509.19944</id>
        <created>2026-06-29</created>
            <updated>2026-06-30</updated>
        <authors>
                <author>
                    <keyname>Perciavalle</keyname>
                        <forenames>Francesco</forenames>
                </author>
                <author>
                    <keyname>Rizzo</keyname>
                        <forenames>Gian Marco</forenames>
                </author>
                <author>
                    <keyname>Plastina</keyname>
                        <forenames>Francesco</forenames>
                </author>
                <author>
                    <keyname>Gullo</keyname>
                        <forenames>Nicola Lo</forenames>
                </author>
        </authors>
        <title>Local reminiscence in the PXP model</title>
            <categories>quant-ph</categories>
            <comments>Main: 12 pages, 6 figures. Appendix: 3 pages, 2 figures</comments>
            <license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license>
            <abstract>We study the emergence of local reminiscence in the PXP model, a constrained spin system realized in Rydberg atom arrays. The spectrum of this model is characterized by a majority of eigenstates that satisfy the eigenstate thermalization hypothesis, alongside a set of nonthermal eigenstates, known as quantum many-body scars, that violate it. While generic initial states lead to thermalization consistent with eigenstate thermalization hypothesis, special configurations generate non-ergodic dynamics and preserve memory of the initial state. In this work, we explore local memory retention using local fidelity and the dynamics of local observables. We find that two specific states, $θ$-symmetric and blockaded states, exhibit robust local reminiscence, with fidelities near unity and suppressed fluctuations as the system size increases. Our results show that non-ergodic regimes can sustain stable local memory while still allowing for complex global dynamics, providing new insights into quantum many-body scars and constrained dynamics.</abstract>
    </arXiv>

            </metadata>
        </record>

    </GetRecord>
</OAI-PMH>