<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<OAI-PMH xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" 
         xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance"
         xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/OAI-PMH.xsd">
    <responseDate>2026-07-09T20:36:22Z</responseDate>
                <request verb="GetRecord" identifier="oai:arXiv.org:2607.03913v1" metadataPrefix="arXiv">http://oaipmh.arxiv.org/oai</request>


    <GetRecord>
                <record>
                <header>
        <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:2607.03913</identifier>
        <datestamp>2026-07-07</datestamp>
            <setSpec>physics:astro-ph:GA</setSpec>
    </header>

            <metadata>
                        <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ https://oaipmh.arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
        <id>2607.03913</id>
        <created>2026-07-04</created>
            <updated>2026-07-07</updated>
        <authors>
                <author>
                    <keyname>Mentzer</keyname>
                        <forenames>C. E.</forenames>
                </author>
                <author>
                    <keyname>Li</keyname>
                        <forenames>Aigen</forenames>
                </author>
                <author>
                    <keyname>Yang</keyname>
                        <forenames>X. J.</forenames>
                </author>
        </authors>
        <title>Widespread Detection of Aromatic and Aliphatic Emission in the Dual Quasar J0749+2255 at Cosmic Noon</title>
            <categories>astro-ph.GA</categories>
            <comments>19 pages, 6 figures; accepted for publication in The Astrophysical Journal Letters</comments>
            <license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license>
            <abstract>Based on JWST/MIRI integral field observations, we report a widespread detection of aromatic and aliphatic hydrocarbon emission at rest-frame 3.3 and 3.4 micron in SDSSJ074922.96+225511.7 (hereafter J0749+2255), a dual quasar at redshift z~2.17, corresponding to a cosmic age of ~3 billion years after the Big Bang, a time period known as the &#34;cosmic noon&#34; when star formation and black hole growth peak. With the 3.3 micron emission ascribed to aromatic C--H stretches of small PAH molecules and the 3.4 micron emission assigned to aliphatic C--H stretches of aliphatic sidegroups attached to PAHs, we utilize the observed intensities of the 3.3 and 3.4 micron emission bands to estimate the aliphatic fractions of PAHs and their variations across J0749+2255, which is, to our knowledge, the most distant object to date in which both aromatics and aliphatics have ever been detected. We find that both the 3.3 and 3.4 micron emission bands are pronounced and the aliphatic fractions are surprisingly high in the most luminous regions centered on the two quasar nuclei, suggesting that not only small PAHs (of ~20--30 carbon atoms) but also their attached aliphatic sidegroups survive in intense ultraviolet radiation arising from extreme starburst.</abstract>
    </arXiv>

            </metadata>
        </record>

    </GetRecord>
</OAI-PMH>