<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<OAI-PMH xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" 
         xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance"
         xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/OAI-PMH.xsd">
    <responseDate>2026-07-11T21:11:51Z</responseDate>
                <request verb="GetRecord" identifier="oai:arXiv.org:2601.04290v1" metadataPrefix="arXiv">http://oaipmh.arxiv.org/oai</request>


    <GetRecord>
                <record>
                <header>
        <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:2601.04290</identifier>
        <datestamp>2026-01-09</datestamp>
            <setSpec>physics:gr-qc</setSpec>
            <setSpec>physics:astro-ph:CO</setSpec>
            <setSpec>physics:astro-ph:GA</setSpec>
    </header>

            <metadata>
                        <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ https://oaipmh.arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
        <id>2601.04290</id>
        <created>2026-01-07</created>
            <updated>2026-01-09</updated>
        <authors>
                <author>
                    <keyname>Singh</keyname>
                        <forenames>Tejinder P.</forenames>
                </author>
        </authors>
        <title>A Relativistic MOND</title>
            <categories>gr-qc astro-ph.CO astro-ph.GA</categories>
            <comments>4 pages; prepared for the proceedings of the 22nd Lomonosov conference, Moscow, August 21-27, 2025</comments>
            <license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license>
            <abstract>We present a minimal relativistic completion of MOND in which (i) General Relativity is recovered exactly in the high-acceleration regime, while (ii) the Bekenstein--Milgrom (AQUAL) equation emerges in the low-acceleration regime, without introducing additional propagating fields beyond those already present in a right-handed gauge sector. The construction is motivated by an $E_6\times E_6$ framework in which $SU(3)_R\rightarrow SU(2)_R\times U(1)_{Y&#39;}\rightarrow U(1)_{\rm dem}$, leaving a healthy repulsive $U(1)_{\rm dem}$ interaction whose charge is the square-root mass label. Gravity itself arises from the $SU(2)_R$ connection via a Plebanski/MacDowell--Mansouri mechanism, yielding an emergent tetrad and the Einstein--Hilbert action. MOND is implemented by an infrared (IR) metric deformation $ΔS_{\rm IR}[g]$ that is UV-vanishing (so GR is recovered) while its deep-MOND/static limit is fixed by a symmetry principle: in three spatial dimensions, the deep-MOND action is conformally invariant with a 10-parameter group isomorphic to $SO(4,1)$ (the de Sitter group). The single MOND acceleration scale is set by a de Sitter radius selected dynamically in the IR, $a_0=c^2/(ξ\,\ell_{\rm dS})$ with $ξ={ O}(1)$ fixed by matching to the static limit. MOND resides in perturbations and quasistatic systems; the homogeneous FRW background is controlled by the IR vacuum kinematics rather than an ad hoc cosmological constant.</abstract>
    </arXiv>

            </metadata>
        </record>

    </GetRecord>
</OAI-PMH>