<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<OAI-PMH xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" 
         xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance"
         xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/OAI-PMH.xsd">
    <responseDate>2026-07-13T06:23:31Z</responseDate>
                <request verb="GetRecord" identifier="oai:arXiv.org:2601.06608" metadataPrefix="arXiv">http://oaipmh.arxiv.org/oai</request>


    <GetRecord>
                <record>
                <header>
        <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:2601.06608</identifier>
        <datestamp>2026-01-13</datestamp>
            <setSpec>physics:quant-ph</setSpec>
    </header>

            <metadata>
                        <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ https://oaipmh.arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
        <id>2601.06608</id>
        <created>2026-01-10</created>
            <updated>2026-01-13</updated>
        <authors>
                <author>
                    <keyname>Xiang</keyname>
                        <forenames>Qian</forenames>
                </author>
                <author>
                    <keyname>Elahi</keyname>
                        <forenames>Shafaq Gulzar</forenames>
                </author>
                <author>
                    <keyname>Geraci</keyname>
                        <forenames>Andrew</forenames>
                </author>
                <author>
                    <keyname>Bose</keyname>
                        <forenames>Sougato</forenames>
                </author>
                <author>
                    <keyname>Mazumdar</keyname>
                        <forenames>Anupam</forenames>
                </author>
        </authors>
        <title>Magnetic levitation and spatial superposition of a nanodiamond with a current-carrying chip</title>
            <categories>quant-ph</categories>
            <comments>16 pages, 7 figures</comments>
            <license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license>
            <abstract>We propose a current-carrying-chip scheme for generating spatial quantum superpositions using a levitating nanodiamond with a built-in nitrogen-vacancy (NV) centre defect. Our setup is quite versatile and we aim to create the superposition for a mass range of $10^{-19}~{\rm kg}&lt; m&lt; 10^{-15}~{\rm kg}$ and a superposition size ${\cal O}(10) {\rm μm} &lt; Δx &lt; {\cal O}(1){\rm nm}$, respectively, in $t\leq 0.1$s, depending on the position we launch from the center of the diamagnetic trap. We provide an in-depth analysis of two parallel chips that can create levitation and spatial superposition along the $x$-axis, while producing a very tight trap in the $y$ direction, and the direction of gravity, i.e., the $z$ direction. Numerical simulations demonstrate that our setup can create a one-dimensional spatial superposition state along the x-axis. Throughout this process, the particle is stably levitated in the z-direction, and its motion is effectively confined in the y-direction for a Gaussian initial condition. This setup presents a viable platform for a diamagnetically levitated nanoparticle for a table-top experiment exploring the possibility of creating a macroscopic Schrödinger Cat state to test the quantum gravity induced entanglement of masses (QGEM) protocol.</abstract>
    </arXiv>

            </metadata>
        </record>

    </GetRecord>
</OAI-PMH>