<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<OAI-PMH xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" 
         xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance"
         xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/OAI-PMH.xsd">
    <responseDate>2026-07-11T20:33:24Z</responseDate>
                <request verb="GetRecord" identifier="oai:arXiv.org:2601.02331v2" metadataPrefix="arXiv">http://oaipmh.arxiv.org/oai</request>


    <GetRecord>
                <record>
                <header>
        <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:2601.02331</identifier>
        <datestamp>2026-04-29</datestamp>
            <setSpec>physics:hep-th</setSpec>
            <setSpec>physics:astro-ph:CO</setSpec>
            <setSpec>physics:hep-lat</setSpec>
            <setSpec>physics:hep-ph</setSpec>
    </header>

            <metadata>
                        <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ https://oaipmh.arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
        <id>2601.02331</id>
        <created>2026-04-27</created>
            <updated>2026-04-29</updated>
        <authors>
                <author>
                    <keyname>Budd</keyname>
                        <forenames>Evan</forenames>
                </author>
                <author>
                    <keyname>Florio</keyname>
                        <forenames>Adrien</forenames>
                </author>
                <author>
                    <keyname>Frenklakh</keyname>
                        <forenames>David</forenames>
                </author>
                <author>
                    <keyname>Mukherjee</keyname>
                        <forenames>Swagato</forenames>
                </author>
        </authors>
        <title>Quantum dynamics of cosmological particle production: interacting quantum field theories with matrix product states</title>
            <categories>hep-th astro-ph.CO hep-lat hep-ph</categories>
            <comments>45 pages, 13 figures</comments>
            <journal-ref>J. High Energ. Phys. 2026, 183 (2026)</journal-ref>
            <doi>10.1007/JHEP04(2026)183</doi>
            <license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license>
            <abstract>Understanding real-time dynamics of interacting quantum fields in curved spacetime remains a major theoretical challenge. We employ tensor network methods to study such dynamics using interacting scalar and gauge theories in 1+1 spacetime dimensions, subject to a quench modeling a homogeneously expanding gravitational background. The models considered are the scalar $λϕ^4$ theory and the Schwinger model, i.e. a Dirac fermion coupled to a $U(1)$ gauge field which is equivalent via bosonization to a scalar field with a cosine self-interaction. In the free scalar limit, both theories reproduce known analytical results, providing a nontrivial numerical validation of bosonization in curved spacetime for the Schwinger model. Our central finding is that self-interactions lead to a suppression of gravitational particle production compared to the free-field case, as evidenced by two-point functions and the spectra of produced particles. We further examine the behavior of entanglement generation and find that interactions suppress entanglement growth in the $λϕ^4$ theory, while in the Schwinger model, the interplay between suppressed particle production and enhanced inter-particle correlations leads to more complex entanglement behavior. Our results pave the way for further explorations of nonperturbative quantum real-time dynamics of interacting scalar and gauge theories in arbitrary gravitational backgrounds.</abstract>
    </arXiv>

            </metadata>
        </record>

    </GetRecord>
</OAI-PMH>