<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<OAI-PMH xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" 
         xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance"
         xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/OAI-PMH.xsd">
    <responseDate>2026-07-13T21:14:01Z</responseDate>
                <request verb="GetRecord" identifier="oai:arXiv.org:2411.16633" metadataPrefix="arXiv">http://oaipmh.arxiv.org/oai</request>


    <GetRecord>
                <record>
                <header>
        <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:2411.16633</identifier>
        <datestamp>2025-06-23</datestamp>
            <setSpec>physics:quant-ph</setSpec>
    </header>

            <metadata>
                        <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ https://oaipmh.arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
        <id>2411.16633</id>
        <created>2025-04-22</created>
            <updated>2025-06-23</updated>
        <authors>
                <author>
                    <keyname>Malavazi</keyname>
                        <forenames>André H. A.</forenames>
                </author>
                <author>
                    <keyname>Sagar</keyname>
                        <forenames>Rishav</forenames>
                </author>
                <author>
                    <keyname>Ahmadi</keyname>
                        <forenames>Borhan</forenames>
                </author>
                <author>
                    <keyname>Dieguez</keyname>
                        <forenames>Pedro R.</forenames>
                </author>
        </authors>
        <title>Two-time weak measurement protocol for ergotropy protection in open quantum batteries</title>
            <categories>quant-ph</categories>
            <comments>Updated version with extended analysis, 27 pages, and 23 figures</comments>
            <doi>10.1103/bv4w-jr6q</doi>
            <license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license>
            <abstract>Quantum batteries are emerging as highly efficient energy storage devices that can exceed classical performance limits. Although there have been significant advancements in controlling these systems, challenges remain in stabilizing stored energy and minimizing losses due to inevitable environmental interaction. In this paper, we propose a protocol that employs selective weak measurements to protect quantum states from such influence and mitigate battery discharging, that is feasible in state-of-the-art technologies. We establish thermodynamic constraints that allow this method to be implemented without disrupting the overall energy and ergotropy balance of the system, i.e., with no extra net recharging. Our findings demonstrate that appropriately chosen measurement intensity can reduce unwanted discharging effects, thereby preserving ergotropy and improving the stability of quantum batteries. We illustrate the protocol with single and two-qubit systems and establish the generalization for $N$-cell batteries. Additionally, we explore how weak measurements influence the coherent and incoherent components of ergotropy, providing new insights into the practical application of quantum coherence in energy storage technologies.</abstract>
    </arXiv>

            </metadata>
        </record>

    </GetRecord>
</OAI-PMH>