<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<OAI-PMH xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" 
         xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance"
         xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/OAI-PMH.xsd">
    <responseDate>2026-07-13T08:41:20Z</responseDate>
                <request verb="GetRecord" identifier="oai:arXiv.org:2605.21910" metadataPrefix="arXiv">http://oaipmh.arxiv.org/oai</request>


    <GetRecord>
                <record>
                <header>
        <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:2605.21910</identifier>
        <datestamp>2026-05-22</datestamp>
            <setSpec>physics:gr-qc</setSpec>
    </header>

            <metadata>
                        <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ https://oaipmh.arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
        <id>2605.21910</id>
        <created>2026-05-21</created>
            <updated>2026-05-22</updated>
        <authors>
                <author>
                    <keyname>Yang</keyname>
                        <forenames>Ruixin</forenames>
                </author>
                <author>
                    <keyname>Chen</keyname>
                        <forenames>Songbai</forenames>
                </author>
                <author>
                    <keyname>Jing</keyname>
                        <forenames>Jiliang</forenames>
                </author>
        </authors>
        <title>Vacuum breakdown in a misaligned magnetized Kerr spacetime</title>
            <categories>gr-qc</categories>
            <comments>15 pages,8 figures</comments>
            <license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license>
            <abstract>Electron-positron ($e^{+}e^{-}$) pair creation by vacuum breakdown around compact objects is believed to power high-energy astrophysical transients like gamma-ray bursts (GRBs). In this work, we focus on vacuum breakdown around a Kerr black hole (BH) immersed in an asymptotically uniform magnetic field that is inclined with respect to the BH spin axis. The dyadoregion, the region where the induced electric field exceeds the critical value $E_{\text{c}}=m_{e}^{2}c^{3}/(e\hbar)$, is identified via the electromagnetic invariants. It is found that the dyadoregion consists of several lobes whose number, size, and orientation vary with the inclination. We also estimate the electromagnetic energy available for pair creation and derive a beaming factor that allows a conversion between the intrinsic dyadoregion energy and the observed isotropic energy. The thermodynamic properties of the resulting electron-positron-photon ($e^{+}e^{-}γ$) plasma are included, revealing an initial magnetic dominance. The evaluation of the minimum magnetic field required shows that misaligned magnetic fields generally favor pair creation more than aligned ones.</abstract>
    </arXiv>

            </metadata>
        </record>

    </GetRecord>
</OAI-PMH>