<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<OAI-PMH xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" 
         xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance"
         xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/OAI-PMH.xsd">
    <responseDate>2026-07-13T06:27:54Z</responseDate>
                <request verb="GetRecord" identifier="oai:arXiv.org:2512.02521" metadataPrefix="arXiv">http://oaipmh.arxiv.org/oai</request>


    <GetRecord>
                <record>
                <header>
        <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:2512.02521</identifier>
        <datestamp>2026-04-10</datestamp>
            <setSpec>physics:quant-ph</setSpec>
            <setSpec>physics:physics:atom-ph</setSpec>
    </header>

            <metadata>
                        <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ https://oaipmh.arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
        <id>2512.02521</id>
        <created>2026-03-03</created>
            <updated>2026-04-10</updated>
        <authors>
                <author>
                    <keyname>Zarraoa</keyname>
                        <forenames>Laura</forenames>
                </author>
                <author>
                    <keyname>Lamich</keyname>
                        <forenames>Tomas</forenames>
                </author>
                <author>
                    <keyname>Elsehimy</keyname>
                        <forenames>Sondos</forenames>
                </author>
                <author>
                    <keyname>Mitchell</keyname>
                        <forenames>Morgan W.</forenames>
                </author>
                <author>
                    <keyname>Veyron</keyname>
                        <forenames>Romain</forenames>
                </author>
        </authors>
        <title>Detection of photon-level signals embedded in sunlight with an atomic photodetector</title>
            <categories>quant-ph physics.atom-ph</categories>
            <comments>7 pages, 4 figures</comments>
            <report-no>AVS Quantum Sci. 8, 025001 (2026)</report-no>
            <doi>10.1116/5.0314886</doi>
            <license>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0/</license>
            <abstract>The detection of few-photon signals in a broadband background is an extreme challenge for photon counting, requiring filtering that accepts a narrow range of optical frequencies while strongly rejecting all others. Recent work [Zarraoa et. al, Phys. Rev. Res. 6, 033338 (2024)] demonstrated that trapped single atoms can act as low dark-count narrow-band photodetectors. Here we show that this ``quantum jump photodetector&#39;&#39; (QJPD) approach can also detect photon-level signals embedded in strong sunlight. Using a single rubidium atom as a QJPD, we count arrivals of individual narrow-band laser photons embedded in sunlight powers of order $10^{10}$ photons/s. We derive a rate-equation model for the atom&#39;s internal-state dynamics in sunlight, and find quantitative agreement with experiment. Using this model, we calculate the channel capacity over a noisy communication channel when sending weak coherent states and detecting them in the presence of sunlight, achieving a representative rate of 0.5 bits per symbol when sending 150 probe photons per 10 ms time-bin, embedded in 1 nW of sunlight (of order $10^{10}$ photons/s in the visible and near-infrared bands). The demonstration may benefit background-limited applications such as daytime light detection and ranging (LIDAR), remote magnetometry, and free-space classical and quantum optical communications.</abstract>
    </arXiv>

            </metadata>
        </record>

    </GetRecord>
</OAI-PMH>