<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<OAI-PMH xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" 
         xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance"
         xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/OAI-PMH.xsd">
    <responseDate>2026-07-13T06:20:38Z</responseDate>
                <request verb="GetRecord" identifier="oai:arXiv.org:2510.26295" metadataPrefix="arXiv">http://oaipmh.arxiv.org/oai</request>


    <GetRecord>
                <record>
                <header>
        <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:2510.26295</identifier>
        <datestamp>2025-10-31</datestamp>
            <setSpec>physics:quant-ph</setSpec>
    </header>

            <metadata>
                        <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ https://oaipmh.arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
        <id>2510.26295</id>
        <created>2025-10-30</created>
            <updated>2025-10-31</updated>
        <authors>
                <author>
                    <keyname>Xiang</keyname>
                        <forenames>Ya-Xin</forenames>
                </author>
                <author>
                    <keyname>Bai</keyname>
                        <forenames>Zhengyang</forenames>
                </author>
                <author>
                    <keyname>Ma</keyname>
                        <forenames>Yu-Qiang</forenames>
                </author>
        </authors>
        <title>Quantum predator-prey cycles in dissipative Rydberg lattices</title>
            <categories>quant-ph</categories>
            <license>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0/</license>
            <abstract>The Lotka-Volterra model is a paradigm for self-organized predator-prey oscillations in far-from-equilibrium systems, yet testing it in real-world ecosystems is hindered by uncontrollable microscopic parameters. Here, we propose a quantum analogue of predator-prey dynamics using a tunable two-dimensional Rydberg atom array. Through mean-field analysis and numerical simulations based on the open-system discrete truncated Wigner approximation, we demonstrate that Rydberg excitations exhibit predator-prey cycles on microsecond timescales. We show that quantum coherence drives spontaneous symmetry breaking, while long-range interactions stabilize global oscillations against quantum-noise-induced desynchronization. We further reveal that quantum jump induce quasicycles whose amplitude scales inversely with the square root of the system size. Our work extends the study of predator-prey models to the quantum realm and advances quantum simulation stratagies that leverage engineered many-body nonequilibrium effects.</abstract>
    </arXiv>

            </metadata>
        </record>

    </GetRecord>
</OAI-PMH>