<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<OAI-PMH xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" 
         xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance"
         xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/OAI-PMH.xsd">
    <responseDate>2026-07-11T10:36:42Z</responseDate>
                <request verb="GetRecord" identifier="oai:arXiv.org:2606.07505v2" metadataPrefix="arXiv">http://oaipmh.arxiv.org/oai</request>


    <GetRecord>
                <record>
                <header>
        <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:2606.07505</identifier>
        <datestamp>2026-06-16</datestamp>
            <setSpec>physics:astro-ph:HE</setSpec>
            <setSpec>physics:astro-ph:CO</setSpec>
    </header>

            <metadata>
                        <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ https://oaipmh.arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
        <id>2606.07505</id>
        <created>2026-06-15</created>
            <updated>2026-06-16</updated>
        <authors>
                <author>
                    <keyname>Leung</keyname>
                        <forenames>Shing-Chi</forenames>
                </author>
                <author>
                    <keyname>Walther</keyname>
                        <forenames>Seth</forenames>
                </author>
                <author>
                    <keyname>Kusenko</keyname>
                        <forenames>Alexander</forenames>
                </author>
                <author>
                    <keyname>Nomoto</keyname>
                        <forenames>Ken&#39;ichi</forenames>
                </author>
                <author>
                    <keyname>Suzuki</keyname>
                        <forenames>Tomoharu</forenames>
                </author>
        </authors>
        <title>Primordial Black Hole Triggered Type Ia Supernovae II: Comparison with Supernova Remnants and Galactic Chemical Evolution</title>
            <categories>astro-ph.HE astro-ph.CO</categories>
            <comments>24 pages, 28 figures. Submitted to The Astrophysical Journal on Feb 5 2026, revised on May 1 2026, accepted on May 12 2026, published Jun 15 2026</comments>
            <journal-ref>The Astrophysical Journal 1004, 202 (2026)</journal-ref>
            <doi>10.3847/1538-4357/ae6db7</doi>
            <license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license>
            <abstract>The asteroid-mass class of Primordial Black Holes (PBHs) is one of the candidates for the dark matter in the universe. With a mass between $4 \times 10^{-17} &lt; M_{\rm PBH} &lt; 4 \times 10^{-12}~M_{\odot}$, they could be the major component of dark matter in the cosmic mass budget. The infall of these PBH into a white dwarf could be one triggering mechanism of Type Ia supernovae (SNe Ia). In [Leung et al, ApJ 991, 11 (2025)] (Paper I), we studied the ignition, explosion dynamics, radiative transfer, and post-explosion nucleosynthesis of the PBH-triggered SNe Ia. The diversity of the explosion models can reconcile with the empirical Phillips relation. In this work, we developed the PBH-triggered SN Ia models in various metallicity. We show that models from this channel can explain some recently observed SN Ia light curves and supernova remnants. We further investigate how these supernovae could affect the chemical evolution on the galactic scale by adding the new SN Ia models as a new chemical source. We examine how the observed chemical trends of stars can lead to constraints on the fraction of this explosion channel relative to the canonical binary star channel. Our models suggest that the PBH can be one major SN Ia channel in the early universe. We also include a comparative study to extract the effects of PBH-triggered SN Ia parameters on the actual chemical trends in the galactic chemical evolution model.</abstract>
    </arXiv>

            </metadata>
        </record>

    </GetRecord>
</OAI-PMH>