<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<OAI-PMH xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" 
         xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance"
         xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/OAI-PMH.xsd">
    <responseDate>2026-07-13T06:27:23Z</responseDate>
                <request verb="GetRecord" identifier="oai:arXiv.org:2606.11062" metadataPrefix="arXiv">http://oaipmh.arxiv.org/oai</request>


    <GetRecord>
                <record>
                <header>
        <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:2606.11062</identifier>
        <datestamp>2026-06-10</datestamp>
            <setSpec>physics:gr-qc</setSpec>
            <setSpec>physics:astro-ph:CO</setSpec>
            <setSpec>physics:hep-ph</setSpec>
            <setSpec>physics:hep-th</setSpec>
    </header>

            <metadata>
                        <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ https://oaipmh.arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
        <id>2606.11062</id>
        <created>2026-06-09</created>
            <updated>2026-06-10</updated>
        <authors>
                <author>
                    <keyname>Akarsu</keyname>
                        <forenames>Özgür</forenames>
                </author>
                <author>
                    <keyname>Perivolaropoulos</keyname>
                        <forenames>Leandros</forenames>
                </author>
                <author>
                    <keyname>Yükselci</keyname>
                        <forenames>A. Emrah</forenames>
                </author>
                <author>
                    <keyname>Zhuk</keyname>
                        <forenames>Alexander</forenames>
                </author>
        </authors>
        <title>A Friendly Phantom: Late-time AdS-to-dS transition and cosmological tensions</title>
            <categories>gr-qc astro-ph.CO hep-ph hep-th</categories>
            <comments>16 pages, 3 figures. Honorable Mention, 2026 Gravity Research Foundation Awards for Essays on Gravitation. Invited for submission to Int. J. Mod. Phys. D. GRF essay developing the friendly-phantom interpretation of Ph-Lambda_sCDM; related full technical article: arXiv:2502.14667</comments>
            <license>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0/</license>
            <abstract>We present Ph-$Λ_{\rm s}$CDM, a phantom-scalar realization within General Relativity of the sign-switching cosmological-constant idea, $Λ_{\rm s}$CDM, in which a phantom scalar evolving on a bounded hyperbolic-tangent potential induces a smooth mirror AdS-to-dS transition in the late-time dark-energy density. The wrong-sign kinetic term, usually viewed as pathological, becomes the mechanism lifting the field from a negative- to a positive-energy vacuum-like regime. The construction also shows that the field can become repulsive while its energy density is still negative. The cosmology nevertheless remains controlled: total energy stays positive, the late-time attractor is de Sitter rather than a Big Rip, and the dynamics remain safely infrared. Ph-$Λ_{\rm s}$CDM thus offers a concrete late-time mechanism with the potential to address multiple cosmological tensions.</abstract>
    </arXiv>

            </metadata>
        </record>

    </GetRecord>
</OAI-PMH>