<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<OAI-PMH xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" 
         xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance"
         xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/OAI-PMH.xsd">
    <responseDate>2026-07-13T06:25:49Z</responseDate>
                <request verb="GetRecord" identifier="oai:arXiv.org:2512.14066" metadataPrefix="arXiv">http://oaipmh.arxiv.org/oai</request>


    <GetRecord>
                <record>
                <header>
        <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:2512.14066</identifier>
        <datestamp>2026-03-16</datestamp>
            <setSpec>physics:astro-ph:GA</setSpec>
            <setSpec>physics:astro-ph:CO</setSpec>
    </header>

            <metadata>
                        <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ https://oaipmh.arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
        <id>2512.14066</id>
        <created>2026-03-12</created>
            <updated>2026-03-16</updated>
        <authors>
                <author>
                    <keyname>Zhang</keyname>
                        <forenames>Saiyang</forenames>
                </author>
                <author>
                    <keyname>Liu</keyname>
                        <forenames>Boyuan</forenames>
                </author>
                <author>
                    <keyname>Bromm</keyname>
                        <forenames>Volker</forenames>
                </author>
                <author>
                    <keyname>Kühnel</keyname>
                        <forenames>Florian</forenames>
                </author>
        </authors>
        <title>Primordial Black Holes as Seeds for Extremely Overmassive AGN Observed by JWST</title>
            <categories>astro-ph.GA astro-ph.CO</categories>
            <comments>12 pages, 3 figures, Accepted by ApJL</comments>
            <doi>10.3847/2041-8213/ae4bd0</doi>
            <license>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0/</license>
            <abstract>The James Webb Space Telescope (JWST) has recently identified Abell 2744-QSO1 as a compact, metal-poor, black hole (BH) dominated galaxy at $z\simeq 7$. This system exhibits an extreme black-hole-to-stellar mass ratio and unusually low metallicity, posing significant challenges to BH seeding models. Motivated by these discoveries, we perform high-resolution cosmological simulations with a massive primordial black hole (PBH; $M_{\rm BH}=5\times10^7\,M_\odot$) seed, incorporating for the first time a fully coupled treatment of PBH accretion, BH feedback, and Population~III/II star formation and stellar feedback. Although PBHs accelerate structure formation through the seed effect, the associated strong thermal feedback from the accretion delays the onset of star formation to $z\lesssim 10$, producing short, bursty episodes throughout the subsequent evolution. PBH-driven outflows expel enriched gas from the nucleus, while sustained inflows from the intergalactic medium continuously replenish pristine material. This feedback-regulated cycle naturally yields low accretion rates ($\dot{m}_{\rm BH}/\dot{m}_{\rm edd} \sim 1-10\%$), subsolar metallicities ($Z/Z_\odot\lesssim10^{-2}$) and extreme $M_{\rm BH}/M_\star$ ratios during both the initial star-forming phase and the subsequent quenching phases, in excellent agreement with JWST observations. Our results demonstrate that massive PBHs offer a viable pathway for forming the most extreme high-redshift systems, providing a physically motivated explanation for the extraordinary properties of Abell 2744-QSO1, as a sub-class of the broader population of JWST-discovered &#34;little red dots&#34;.</abstract>
    </arXiv>

            </metadata>
        </record>

    </GetRecord>
</OAI-PMH>