<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<OAI-PMH xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" 
         xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance"
         xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/OAI-PMH.xsd">
    <responseDate>2026-07-13T06:25:36Z</responseDate>
                <request verb="GetRecord" identifier="oai:arXiv.org:2511.07785" metadataPrefix="arXiv">http://oaipmh.arxiv.org/oai</request>


    <GetRecord>
                <record>
                <header>
        <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:2511.07785</identifier>
        <datestamp>2025-11-12</datestamp>
            <setSpec>physics:quant-ph</setSpec>
            <setSpec>physics:cond-mat:mes-hall</setSpec>
    </header>

            <metadata>
                        <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ https://oaipmh.arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
        <id>2511.07785</id>
        <created>2025-11-11</created>
            <updated>2025-11-12</updated>
        <authors>
                <author>
                    <keyname>Selco</keyname>
                        <forenames>Cooper M.</forenames>
                </author>
                <author>
                    <keyname>Bengs</keyname>
                        <forenames>Christian</forenames>
                </author>
                <author>
                    <keyname>Shah</keyname>
                        <forenames>Chaitali</forenames>
                </author>
                <author>
                    <keyname>Zhang</keyname>
                        <forenames>Zhuorui</forenames>
                </author>
                <author>
                    <keyname>Ajoy</keyname>
                        <forenames>Ashok</forenames>
                </author>
        </authors>
        <title>Emergent Decoherence Dynamics in Doubly Disordered Spin Networks</title>
            <categories>quant-ph cond-mat.mes-hall</categories>
            <comments>7 pages, 4 figures</comments>
            <license>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0/</license>
            <abstract>Elucidating the emergence of irreversible macroscopic laws from reversible quantum many-body dynamics is a question of broad importance across all quantum science. Many-body decoherence plays a key role in this transition, yet connecting microscopic dynamics to emergent macroscopic behavior remains challenging. Here, in a doubly disordered electron-nuclear spin network, we uncover an emergent decoherence law for nuclear polarization, $e^{-\sqrt{R_{p}t}}e^{-R_{d}t}$, that is robust across broad parameter regimes. We trace its microscopic origins to two interdependent decoherence channels: long-range interactions mediated by the electron network and spin transport within the nuclear network exhibiting anomalous, sub-diffusive dynamics. We demonstrate the capacity to control--and even eliminate--either channel individually through a combination of Floquet engineering and (optical) environment modulation. We find that disorder, typically viewed as detrimental, here proves protective, generating isolated electron-free clusters that localize polarization and prolong coherence lifetimes. These findings establish a microscopic framework for manipulating decoherence pathways and suggests engineered disorder as a new design principle for realizing long-lived quantum memories and sensors.</abstract>
    </arXiv>

            </metadata>
        </record>

    </GetRecord>
</OAI-PMH>