<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<OAI-PMH xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" 
         xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance"
         xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/OAI-PMH.xsd">
    <responseDate>2026-07-11T21:10:24Z</responseDate>
                <request verb="GetRecord" identifier="oai:arXiv.org:2601.04294v1" metadataPrefix="arXiv">http://oaipmh.arxiv.org/oai</request>


    <GetRecord>
                <record>
                <header>
        <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:2601.04294</identifier>
        <datestamp>2026-01-09</datestamp>
            <setSpec>physics:astro-ph:HE</setSpec>
            <setSpec>physics:astro-ph:SR</setSpec>
            <setSpec>physics:nucl-th</setSpec>
    </header>

            <metadata>
                        <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ https://oaipmh.arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
        <id>2601.04294</id>
        <created>2026-01-07</created>
            <updated>2026-01-09</updated>
        <authors>
                <author>
                    <keyname>Sun</keyname>
                        <forenames>Boyang</forenames>
                </author>
                <author>
                    <keyname>Zhao</keyname>
                        <forenames>Tianqi</forenames>
                </author>
                <author>
                    <keyname>Lattimer</keyname>
                        <forenames>James M.</forenames>
                </author>
        </authors>
        <title>A New Bayesian Framework with Natural Priors to Constrain the Neutron Star Equation of State</title>
            <categories>astro-ph.HE astro-ph.SR nucl-th</categories>
            <comments>8 pages, 2 figures</comments>
            <license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license>
            <abstract>We propose a new Bayesian framework to infer the neutron star equation of state (EOS) from mass and radius observations and neutron matter theory by defining priors that directly parameterize mass-radius space instead of pressure-energy density space. We use direct and accurate inversion approximations to map mass-radius relations to the underlying EOS. We systematically compare its EOS inferences with those inferred from traditional EOS parameterizations, taking care to quantify the systematic prior uncertainties of both. Our results show that prior uncertainties should be included in all Bayesian approaches. The more natural alternative framework provides broader coverage of the physically allowed mass-radius space, especially small radius configurations, and yields enhanced computational efficiency and substantially reduced dependence on prior choices. Our results demonstrate that direct parameterization in observed space offers a robust and efficient alternative to traditional methods.</abstract>
    </arXiv>

            </metadata>
        </record>

    </GetRecord>
</OAI-PMH>