<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<OAI-PMH xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" 
         xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance"
         xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/OAI-PMH.xsd">
    <responseDate>2026-07-08T04:43:48Z</responseDate>
                <request verb="GetRecord" identifier="oai:arXiv.org:2607.00565v1" metadataPrefix="arXiv">http://oaipmh.arxiv.org/oai</request>


    <GetRecord>
                <record>
                <header>
        <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:2607.00565</identifier>
        <datestamp>2026-07-02</datestamp>
            <setSpec>physics:astro-ph:HE</setSpec>
    </header>

            <metadata>
                        <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ https://oaipmh.arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
        <id>2607.00565</id>
        <created>2026-07-01</created>
            <updated>2026-07-02</updated>
        <authors>
                <author>
                    <keyname>Flanagan</keyname>
                        <forenames>Elizabeth</forenames>
                </author>
                <author>
                    <keyname>Stegmann</keyname>
                        <forenames>Jakob</forenames>
                </author>
                <author>
                    <keyname>Romero-Shaw</keyname>
                        <forenames>Isobel</forenames>
                </author>
                <author>
                    <keyname>Callister</keyname>
                        <forenames>Thomas</forenames>
                </author>
                <author>
                    <keyname>Olejak</keyname>
                        <forenames>Aleksandra</forenames>
                </author>
                <author>
                    <keyname>Antonini</keyname>
                        <forenames>Fabio</forenames>
                </author>
        </authors>
        <title>Distinct spin properties and astrophysical origin of low mass binary black holes in gravitational wave data</title>
            <categories>astro-ph.HE</categories>
            <license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license>
            <abstract>We analyze the effective-spin distribution of binary black hole mergers in GWTC-5.0 as a function of primary black hole mass using hierarchical Bayesian inference. We model the population as a mixture of two spin components separated by a transition mass scale inferred directly from the data. We find strong evidence for a transition at $\tilde{m} = 15.2^{+4.3}_{-3.6}\, M_\odot$. Mock-catalog analyses show that such a transition is unlikely to arise from finite-sample fluctuations of a mass-independent $χ_{\rm eff}$ population and the posterior predictive distributions of $χ_{\rm eff}$ inferred below and above the transition are clearly distinct. Below the transition mass, the effective-spin distribution is narrow, peaks at a small positive value $χ_{\rm eff}&gt;0$, but also shows significant support for negative $χ_{\rm eff}$. Above the transition, the distribution is broader and its peak shifts to values consistent with $χ_{\rm eff}\simeq0$, making its support at both positive and negative $χ_{\rm eff}$ roughly similar. These findings suggest that the dominant merger population concentrated around $10\,M_{\odot}$ is statistically distinct from the rest and that it arises from a different formation channel. We show that this low-mass population is broadly consistent with formation from massive stellar multiples in the field: it may either arise from isolated binary star evolution but only if black hole natal kicks below $\tilde{m}$ are generally very large ($\gtrsim100\,\rm km/s$) or be caused by the dynamical evolution of hierarchical triples. In contrast, isolated binary evolution with standard fallback kick models cannot reproduce the support for negative $χ_{\rm eff}$.</abstract>
    </arXiv>

            </metadata>
        </record>

    </GetRecord>
</OAI-PMH>