<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<OAI-PMH xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" 
         xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance"
         xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/OAI-PMH.xsd">
    <responseDate>2026-07-12T21:54:23Z</responseDate>
                <request verb="GetRecord" identifier="oai:arXiv.org:2605.05635v3" metadataPrefix="arXiv">http://oaipmh.arxiv.org/oai</request>


    <GetRecord>
                <record>
                <header>
        <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:2605.05635</identifier>
        <datestamp>2026-06-17</datestamp>
            <setSpec>physics:gr-qc</setSpec>
            <setSpec>physics:astro-ph:CO</setSpec>
            <setSpec>physics:astro-ph:HE</setSpec>
    </header>

            <metadata>
                        <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ https://oaipmh.arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
        <id>2605.05635</id>
        <created>2026-06-16</created>
            <updated>2026-06-17</updated>
        <authors>
                <author>
                    <keyname>Fathi</keyname>
                        <forenames>Mohsen</forenames>
                </author>
        </authors>
        <title>Adaptive ray tracing, image diagnostics, and photon ring signatures of rotating dark-matter-dressed black holes</title>
            <categories>gr-qc astro-ph.CO astro-ph.HE</categories>
            <comments>18 pages, 12 figures, 2 tables</comments>
            <license>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0/</license>
            <abstract>We study the optical appearance of rotating black holes embedded in dark matter environments using a phenomenological ray tracing framework. Rather than focusing on a single geometry, we compare two effective rotating backgrounds obtained from static dark matter sourced seed metrics: a regular Einasto-type black hole and a cored-NFW black hole. Kerr is used as the reference spacetime. We construct observer-screen images by numerical backward ray tracing and analyse the horizon structure, shadow boundary, lensing bands, transfer maps, and synthetic intensity distributions produced by a common semi-analytic accretion prescription. We also introduce simple image-level diagnostics, an angular-size confrontation with M87* and Sgr A*, and simplified visibility-amplitude diagnostics. These additions are not intended as an EHT fit, but as a controlled way to identify which observables are most affected by the dark matter dressing. For the representative parameters considered here, the Einasto-supported geometry remains very close to Kerr, while the cored-NFW case produces a stronger redistribution of the image, with larger centroid displacement, stronger brightness asymmetry, an outward shift of the characteristic bright-ring scale, and a visible change in the normalized visibility amplitude. The results indicate that rotating dark-matter-dressed backgrounds can produce systematic image-domain and Fourier-domain deviations that are partially degenerate with spin, inclination, and emission modelling. The framework is lightweight and extensible, and provides a first step toward future GRRT and GRMHD studies of rotating black holes in dark matter environments.</abstract>
    </arXiv>

            </metadata>
        </record>

    </GetRecord>
</OAI-PMH>