<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<OAI-PMH xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" 
         xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance"
         xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/OAI-PMH.xsd">
    <responseDate>2026-07-13T07:44:00Z</responseDate>
                <request verb="GetRecord" identifier="oai:arXiv.org:2605.17589" metadataPrefix="arXiv">http://oaipmh.arxiv.org/oai</request>


    <GetRecord>
                <record>
                <header>
        <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:2605.17589</identifier>
        <datestamp>2026-06-05</datestamp>
            <setSpec>physics:gr-qc</setSpec>
            <setSpec>physics:astro-ph:HE</setSpec>
            <setSpec>physics:hep-ph</setSpec>
    </header>

            <metadata>
                        <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ https://oaipmh.arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
        <id>2605.17589</id>
        <created>2026-06-04</created>
            <updated>2026-06-05</updated>
        <authors>
                <author>
                    <keyname>Gómez</keyname>
                        <forenames>Samuel Gómez</forenames>
                </author>
                <author>
                    <keyname>Forteza</keyname>
                        <forenames>Xisco Jimenez</forenames>
                </author>
                <author>
                    <keyname>Luque</keyname>
                        <forenames>Carlos Palenzuela</forenames>
                </author>
        </authors>
        <title>Impact of the axion-like self-interactions in gravitational atoms for LISA</title>
            <categories>gr-qc astro-ph.HE hep-ph</categories>
            <comments>19 pages, 12 figures</comments>
            <license>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0/</license>
            <abstract>Ultralight bosons with self-interactions, such as axion-like particles, can form astrophysical Bose--Einstein condensates around stars or compact objects, often referred to as gravitational atoms. In this work, we adopt a recently proposed dynamical formation mechanism for these halos and estimate their impact on extreme- and intermediate-mass-ratio inspirals when present around the primary black hole. We show that, for signal-to-noise ratios $\lesssim 100$, LISA can distinguish gravitational waveforms from binaries embedded in such halo overdensities. Our analysis indicates that LISA can probe boson masses $m_\mathrm{dm}\sim10^{-17}$--$10^{-15}\,\mathrm{eV}$ and decay constants $f_a\sim3 \times 10^{10}$--$6 \times 10^{12}\,\mathrm{GeV}$ using binaries with total masses $M\sim10^4$--$10^5\,M_\odot$, assuming conservative DM densities consistent with the central values of Navarro--Frenk--White profiles. Allowing for higher background densities and different extreme-mass-ratio configurations further extends the accessible parameter space. Moreover, we find that for a binary configuration with $M\sim10^4M_{\odot}$, $ρ_{\rm dm} = 10^4\,\mathrm{GeV/cm^3}$, and signal to noise ratio $\text{SNR} \sim 20$, a particle mass of $m_{dm} = 3.2 \cdot 10^{-15}$ eV and decay constant of $f_a = 1.6 \cdot 10^{11}$ GeV maximize the dephasing due to dynamical friction, enabling the recovery of the particle parameters at the percent level. These results demonstrate that LISA can place constraints on axion-like particle masses and self-interactions without requiring additional couplings to Standard Model fields.</abstract>
    </arXiv>

            </metadata>
        </record>

    </GetRecord>
</OAI-PMH>