<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<OAI-PMH xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" 
         xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance"
         xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/OAI-PMH.xsd">
    <responseDate>2026-07-13T06:23:04Z</responseDate>
                <request verb="GetRecord" identifier="oai:arXiv.org:2510.27511" metadataPrefix="arXiv">http://oaipmh.arxiv.org/oai</request>


    <GetRecord>
                <record>
                <header>
        <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:2510.27511</identifier>
        <datestamp>2025-11-04</datestamp>
            <setSpec>physics:quant-ph</setSpec>
    </header>

            <metadata>
                        <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ https://oaipmh.arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
        <id>2510.27511</id>
        <created>2025-11-03</created>
            <updated>2025-11-04</updated>
        <authors>
                <author>
                    <keyname>Chen</keyname>
                        <forenames>Chunyin</forenames>
                </author>
                <author>
                    <keyname>Yan</keyname>
                        <forenames>Sizhe</forenames>
                </author>
                <author>
                    <keyname>Wu</keyname>
                        <forenames>Biao</forenames>
                </author>
        </authors>
        <title>Area-Law Entanglement in Quantum Chaotic System</title>
            <categories>quant-ph</categories>
            <license>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0/</license>
            <abstract>Entanglement entropy is a fundamental diagnostic for quantum chaos, typically exhibiting volume-law scaling in highly excited eigenstates of chaotic many-body systems. In this work, we present a striking counterexample: a Floquet-driven quantum many-body system with Rydberg-like blockade that, despite being fully chaotic as indicated by its Wigner-Dyson level statistics and local thermalization, exhibits a strict area-law entanglement entropy. Specifically, the entanglement entropy of every Floquet eigenstate is bounded by $\ln2$, independent of system size. We trace this anomaly to the specific Hilbert space structure imposed by the blockades, which restricts the Schmidt rank across a bipartition. Furthermore, we generalize this discovery by establishing a duality between constrained many-body Hamiltonians and single-particle quantum walks on median graphs, and we outline a general procedure for constructing systems with an entanglement entropy bounded by a predetermined constant. Our results demonstrate that entanglement entropy alone is an insufficient diagnostic of many-body quantum chaos and highlight the profound impact of Hilbert space geometry on quantum dynamics and thermalization.</abstract>
    </arXiv>

            </metadata>
        </record>

    </GetRecord>
</OAI-PMH>