<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<OAI-PMH xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" 
         xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance"
         xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/OAI-PMH.xsd">
    <responseDate>2026-07-13T08:41:20Z</responseDate>
                <request verb="GetRecord" identifier="oai:arXiv.org:2605.22434" metadataPrefix="arXiv">http://oaipmh.arxiv.org/oai</request>


    <GetRecord>
                <record>
                <header>
        <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:2605.22434</identifier>
        <datestamp>2026-05-22</datestamp>
            <setSpec>physics:gr-qc</setSpec>
            <setSpec>physics:hep-th</setSpec>
    </header>

            <metadata>
                        <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ https://oaipmh.arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
        <id>2605.22434</id>
        <created>2026-05-21</created>
            <updated>2026-05-22</updated>
        <authors>
                <author>
                    <keyname>Bhattacharya</keyname>
                        <forenames>Krishnakanta</forenames>
                </author>
                <author>
                    <keyname>Ram</keyname>
                        <forenames>Bhera</forenames>
                </author>
                <author>
                    <keyname>Majhi</keyname>
                        <forenames>Bibhas Ranjan</forenames>
                </author>
        </authors>
        <title>Entropic route to Brown-York tensor: A unified framework for null and timelike hypersurfaces</title>
            <categories>gr-qc hep-th</categories>
            <comments>LaTeX, 23 pages, no figure</comments>
            <license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license>
            <abstract>Building on Padmanabhan&#39;s entropy functional, originally introduced to derive Einstein&#39;s equations and highlight the emergent nature of gravity, we demonstrate its robustness in a broader context. Using the same entropy density, we show that the Brown-York (BY) tensor arises naturally as the projection of the canonical momentum conjugate to the normal vectors on the relevant hypersurface, thereby providing a common construction applicable to both timelike and null hypersurfaces. This perspective also offers insight into the structural differences of the null BY tensor, including its non-symmetric character. We further extend the analysis to scalar-tensor theories, showing that the entropy-based formulation reproduces the expected equations of motion along with the corresponding BY tensor, and, clarifies its non-conservation in the presence of additional scalar field which is non-minimally coupled. Our results provide a coherent variational interpretation of quasi-local gravitational quantities and reveal a common underlying structure linking bulk dynamics and boundary momentum.</abstract>
    </arXiv>

            </metadata>
        </record>

    </GetRecord>
</OAI-PMH>