<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<OAI-PMH xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" 
         xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance"
         xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/OAI-PMH.xsd">
    <responseDate>2026-07-13T06:20:50Z</responseDate>
                <request verb="GetRecord" identifier="oai:arXiv.org:2606.17105" metadataPrefix="arXiv">http://oaipmh.arxiv.org/oai</request>


    <GetRecord>
                <record>
                <header>
        <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:2606.17105</identifier>
        <datestamp>2026-06-19</datestamp>
            <setSpec>physics:physics:pop-ph</setSpec>
            <setSpec>physics:astro-ph:IM</setSpec>
            <setSpec>physics:gr-qc</setSpec>
    </header>

            <metadata>
                        <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ https://oaipmh.arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
        <id>2606.17105</id>
        <created>2026-06-14</created>
            <updated>2026-06-19</updated>
        <authors>
                <author>
                    <keyname>Fargion</keyname>
                        <forenames>Daniele</forenames>
                </author>
        </authors>
        <title>Mass Extinctions by Gravitational Tides</title>
            <categories>physics.pop-ph astro-ph.IM gr-qc</categories>
            <comments>22 pages, 16 figures, Multi-frequency Behaviour of High Energy Cosmic Sources - XV (MULTIF 2025) 9-14 June, 2025, Mondello, Palermo, Italy</comments>
            <journal-ref>PoS(MULTIF2025)009</journal-ref>
            <license>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0/</license>
            <abstract>Past and recent observations suggest that many planetary mass or dwarf planet objects may exist in the outer Solar System. Gravitational perturbations may occasionally bring some of them into the inner Solar System. The early, rare collision between the early Earth and a Mars sized body is generally invoked to explain the formation of the Moon. More probable than a direct impact, are grazing or near Earth flybys of similar objects. Such passages may have left strong tidal signatures: giant waves, large volcanic episodes, sea regressions, coherent meteor showers, and major climatic perturbations. These mechanisms could have contributed to several major biological mass extinctions over the past $600$ million years, as suggested by peculiar correlations in the geological record. Similar events may have occurred several times during the earlier history of Earth. Accretion of mini planets by largest planets and in particular by the Sun may also have occurred many more times over the last four billion years. Possibly producing additional temperature variations on planets and Earth.</abstract>
    </arXiv>

            </metadata>
        </record>

    </GetRecord>
</OAI-PMH>