<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<OAI-PMH xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" 
         xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance"
         xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/OAI-PMH.xsd">
    <responseDate>2026-07-13T06:21:16Z</responseDate>
                <request verb="GetRecord" identifier="oai:arXiv.org:2509.13451" metadataPrefix="arXiv">http://oaipmh.arxiv.org/oai</request>


    <GetRecord>
                <record>
                <header>
        <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:2509.13451</identifier>
        <datestamp>2025-09-18</datestamp>
            <setSpec>physics:quant-ph</setSpec>
    </header>

            <metadata>
                        <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ https://oaipmh.arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
        <id>2509.13451</id>
        <created>2025-09-16</created>
            <updated>2025-09-18</updated>
        <authors>
                <author>
                    <keyname>Chatterjee</keyname>
                        <forenames>Arijit</forenames>
                </author>
                <author>
                    <keyname>Khan</keyname>
                        <forenames>Sakil</forenames>
                </author>
                <author>
                    <keyname>Jain</keyname>
                        <forenames>Sachin</forenames>
                </author>
                <author>
                    <keyname>Mahesh</keyname>
                        <forenames>T S</forenames>
                </author>
        </authors>
        <title>Direct Experimental Observation of Quantum Mpemba Effect without Bath Engineering</title>
            <categories>quant-ph</categories>
            <license>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0/</license>
            <abstract>The quantum Mpemba effect refers to the phenomenon of a quantum system in an initial state, far away from equilibrium, relaxing much faster than a state comparatively nearer to equilibrium. We experimentally demonstrate that this highly counterintuitive effect can occur naturally during the thermalization of quantum systems. Considering dipolar relaxation as the dominant decoherence process, we theoretically derive the conditions that can lead to the Mpemba effect in nuclear spins. After experimentally preparing nuclear spin states dictated by those conditions, we observe the occurrence of the Mpemba effect when they are left to thermalize without any external control. We also experimentally observe the genuine quantum Mpemba effect during thermalization of nuclear spins. Our results establish that both these effects are natural in thermalization of quantum systems, and may show up without the need for any bath engineering.</abstract>
    </arXiv>

            </metadata>
        </record>

    </GetRecord>
</OAI-PMH>