<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<OAI-PMH xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" 
         xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance"
         xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/OAI-PMH.xsd">
    <responseDate>2026-07-13T08:27:55Z</responseDate>
                <request verb="GetRecord" identifier="oai:arXiv.org:2605.21419" metadataPrefix="arXiv">http://oaipmh.arxiv.org/oai</request>


    <GetRecord>
                <record>
                <header>
        <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:2605.21419</identifier>
        <datestamp>2026-07-09</datestamp>
            <setSpec>physics:hep-ph</setSpec>
            <setSpec>physics:astro-ph:CO</setSpec>
            <setSpec>physics:gr-qc</setSpec>
            <setSpec>physics:hep-th</setSpec>
    </header>

            <metadata>
                        <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ https://oaipmh.arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
        <id>2605.21419</id>
        <created>2026-07-07</created>
            <updated>2026-07-09</updated>
        <authors>
                <author>
                    <keyname>You</keyname>
                        <forenames>Jingtao</forenames>
                </author>
                <author>
                    <keyname>Song</keyname>
                        <forenames>Linghao</forenames>
                </author>
                <author>
                    <keyname>Han</keyname>
                        <forenames>Chengcheng</forenames>
                </author>
                <author>
                    <keyname>He</keyname>
                        <forenames>Hong-Jian</forenames>
                </author>
                <author>
                    <keyname>Chen</keyname>
                        <forenames>Xingang</forenames>
                </author>
                <author>
                    <keyname>Xianyu</keyname>
                        <forenames>Zhong-Zhi</forenames>
                </author>
        </authors>
        <title>Cosmological Collider Signatures from Right-Handed Neutrino Loop</title>
            <categories>hep-ph astro-ph.CO gr-qc hep-th</categories>
            <comments>80 pages, improved version, references added</comments>
            <license>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0/</license>
            <abstract>We study cosmological collider (CC) signatures generated by right-handed neutrino loops in the setup of inflation combined with the neutrino seesaw mechanism. We formulate the inflaton interaction with the right-handed neutrinos through a unique dimension-5 operator respecting shift symmetry, which induces an effective chemical potential in the slow-roll background, leading to helicity-dependent production of right-handed neutrinos and enhancing the CC signatures. The right-handed neutrino is described by a two-component Weyl spinor with a Majorana mass term. Using the Schwinger-Keldysh formalism, we derive a set of seed integrals for fermion propagators of the right-handed Majorana neutrino. With these, we compute the factorized nonlocal contributions to the three-point inflaton correlator generated by the triangle loop of right-handed neutrinos. We show that the chemical potential can substantially soften the heavy-mass Boltzmann suppression and amplify the oscillatory non-Gaussianity signatures associated with the dominant helicity mode. We systematically analyze the spinor structure, the factorization of fermion triangle loop, the loop-momentum integrals and the time seed integrals, which give a controlled computation of the nonlocal contributions to the CC signals of the right-handed neutrinos.</abstract>
    </arXiv>

            </metadata>
        </record>

    </GetRecord>
</OAI-PMH>