<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<OAI-PMH xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" 
         xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance"
         xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/OAI-PMH.xsd">
    <responseDate>2026-07-11T08:41:49Z</responseDate>
                <request verb="GetRecord" identifier="oai:arXiv.org:2606.05352v2" metadataPrefix="arXiv">http://oaipmh.arxiv.org/oai</request>


    <GetRecord>
                <record>
                <header>
        <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:2606.05352</identifier>
        <datestamp>2026-07-10</datestamp>
            <setSpec>physics:gr-qc</setSpec>
            <setSpec>physics:astro-ph:CO</setSpec>
            <setSpec>physics:hep-ph</setSpec>
            <setSpec>physics:hep-th</setSpec>
    </header>

            <metadata>
                        <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ https://oaipmh.arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
        <id>2606.05352</id>
        <created>2026-06-14</created>
            <updated>2026-07-10</updated>
        <authors>
                <author>
                    <keyname>Peracaula</keyname>
                        <forenames>Joan Solà</forenames>
                </author>
        </authors>
        <title>Running Vacuum in the expanding Universe: a unified QFT paradigm for Inflation and Dark Energy</title>
            <categories>gr-qc astro-ph.CO hep-ph hep-th</categories>
            <comments>LaTeX, 111 pages, 5 figures, typos corrected, references updated</comments>
            <journal-ref>Int.J.Mod.Phys.A , Vol. 41, No. 19 (2026) 2630009</journal-ref>
            <doi>10.1142/S0217751X26300097</doi>
            <license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license>
            <abstract>The concordance $Λ$CDM model, based on a rigid $Λ$-term for the entire cosmic history, has been in crisis for a long time. In our expanding Universe, an evolving $Λ$ with the expansion is intuitively much more reasonable. In the running vacuum model (RVM) framework, based on quantum field theory (QFT) in curved spacetime, quantum effects induce a vacuum energy density (VED) $ρ_{\rm vac}=Λ/(8πG)$ which is a function of the Hubble rate $H$ and its time derivatives, $ρ_{\rm vac}=ρ_{\rm vac}(H, \dot{H},\ddot{H},\dots)$. Currently, $ρ_{\rm vac}$ evolves very slowly with the expansion, $δρ_{\rm vac}\sim {\cal O}(m_{Pl} ^2 H^2)$, and this fact provides a possible fundamental origin of dark energy (DE), conceived as dynamical vacuum energy. In the RVM, Newton&#39;s $G$ is also evolving, but much more slowly (logarithmically with $H$): $G=G(\ln H)$. In the very early universe, the vacuum fluctuations induce higher (even) powers, e.g. $\sim H^4$, capable of triggering fast inflation in a very short period, in which $H$ is very large and approximately constant. This is the mechanism of `RVM-inflation&#39;. It does not require an `inflaton&#39; field since inflation is brought about by pure QFT effects on the dynamical background. It differs from Starobinsky&#39;s inflation, where $H$ is never constant. Furthermore, the dynamics of $ρ_{\rm vac}(H)$ and $G(H)$ can also have implications on the frequently discussed possibility that the fundamental `constants&#39; of Nature can be mildly evolving with the cosmic expansion. Putting things together, a unified QFT framework of dark energy and inflation ensues as a realistic theory for the description of the universe as a whole on fundamental grounds. In it, dynamical VED is predicted and is much welcomed, since it fits in with current DESI measurements, preferring dynamical DE over a rigid $Λ$ term.</abstract>
    </arXiv>

            </metadata>
        </record>

    </GetRecord>
</OAI-PMH>