<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<OAI-PMH xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" 
         xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance"
         xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/OAI-PMH.xsd">
    <responseDate>2026-07-11T09:08:09Z</responseDate>
                <request verb="GetRecord" identifier="oai:arXiv.org:2606.04966v1" metadataPrefix="arXiv">http://oaipmh.arxiv.org/oai</request>


    <GetRecord>
                <record>
                <header>
        <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:2606.04966</identifier>
        <datestamp>2026-06-04</datestamp>
            <setSpec>physics:astro-ph:HE</setSpec>
    </header>

            <metadata>
                        <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ https://oaipmh.arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
        <id>2606.04966</id>
        <created>2026-06-03</created>
            <updated>2026-06-04</updated>
        <authors>
                <author>
                    <keyname>Chen</keyname>
                        <forenames>Tian-Shun</forenames>
                </author>
                <author>
                    <keyname>Lai</keyname>
                        <forenames>Dong</forenames>
                </author>
        </authors>
        <title>Bridging Roche Lobe Overflow and micro-TDEs: The Runaway Evolution of Eccentric Mass Transfer in Star-Black Hole Binaries</title>
            <categories>astro-ph.HE</categories>
            <comments>14 pages, 19 figures</comments>
            <license>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0/</license>
            <abstract>Binary systems may undergo mass transfer while maintaining significant orbital eccentricities. Stellar-mass black holes (sBHs) can strip stars on eccentric orbits and produce micro-tidal disruption events (micro-TDEs). While previous hydrodynamical studies have focused on compact systems on the verge of disruption, the transition between self-regulated eccentric mass transfer and runaway disruption remains poorly understood. We present SPH simulations of a Sun-like star interacting with a $10\,M_\odot$ sBH across a range of initial eccentricities ($e_0=0.30$--$0.70$) and pericenter distances ($b_0=3.33$--$3.57$ in units of the tidal radius), tracking the systems for tens to over 100 orbital periods. Our results reveal that these binaries can evolve along two distinct pathways, dictated by the competition between mass-transfer-driven stellar expansion and orbital widening: (i) Runaway disruption ($b_0\lesssim 3.45$), in which mass loss at pericenter drives adiabatic expansion of the stellar envelope, leading to unstable Roche-lobe overflow and runaway disruption of the star. The stripped debris forms a thick accretion flow with hyper-Eddington accretion rates onto the sBH, potentially powering fast X-ray/UV or blue/optical transients. (ii) Stable mass transfer ($b_0\gtrsim 3.57$), in which the binary settles into a long-lived, stable mass-transfer phase lasting up to 150 orbits (the limit of our simulation), regulated by orbital expansion from pericenter mass loss. These eccentric mass-transfer events could manifest observationally as repeating, quasi-periodic flares.</abstract>
    </arXiv>

            </metadata>
        </record>

    </GetRecord>
</OAI-PMH>