<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<OAI-PMH xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" 
         xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance"
         xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/OAI-PMH.xsd">
    <responseDate>2026-07-13T06:27:31Z</responseDate>
                <request verb="GetRecord" identifier="oai:arXiv.org:2606.24681" metadataPrefix="arXiv">http://oaipmh.arxiv.org/oai</request>


    <GetRecord>
                <record>
                <header>
        <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:2606.24681</identifier>
        <datestamp>2026-06-29</datestamp>
            <setSpec>physics:quant-ph</setSpec>
    </header>

            <metadata>
                        <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ https://oaipmh.arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
        <id>2606.24681</id>
        <created>2026-06-26</created>
            <updated>2026-06-29</updated>
        <authors>
                <author>
                    <keyname>Compagnini</keyname>
                        <forenames>Domenico</forenames>
                </author>
                <author>
                    <keyname>Tagliavacche</keyname>
                        <forenames>Noemi</forenames>
                </author>
                <author>
                    <keyname>Congia</keyname>
                        <forenames>Sara</forenames>
                </author>
                <author>
                    <keyname>Bernardi</keyname>
                        <forenames>Andrea</forenames>
                </author>
                <author>
                    <keyname>Liscidini</keyname>
                        <forenames>Marco</forenames>
                </author>
                <author>
                    <keyname>Galli</keyname>
                        <forenames>Matteo</forenames>
                </author>
                <author>
                    <keyname>Bajoni</keyname>
                        <forenames>Daniele</forenames>
                </author>
        </authors>
        <title>A Universal All-Fiber Quantum Buffer for the Telecom Band</title>
            <categories>quant-ph</categories>
            <license>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0/</license>
            <abstract>The realization of a scalable quantum internet relies on the ability to temporally align asynchronous photonic signals through on-demand buffering. While matter-based quantum memories achieve long storage times, their extremely narrow bandwidths and cryogenic requirements pose significant barriers to integration with existing telecommunications infrastructure. Conversely, current all-optical memories operate at room temperature but are hampered by high input/output losses and a lack of universality across different photonic degrees of freedom. Here, we demonstrate a universal, fully fiber-integrated quantum buffer operating over the full telecom C-band that overcomes these fundamental trade-offs. By implementing an actively switched dual-Sagnac cavity driven by cross-phase modulation, we achieve an ultra-low input/output loss of 0.46 dB and a storage time exceeding 18 $μ$s. The device exhibits an operational bandwidth exceeding 12.5 THz ($\sim$100 nm), covering the full telecom C-band. We show the simultaneous buffering of over 200 temporal modes with the ability to address them either collectively or one by one. We demonstrate high-fidelity storage for all three degrees of freedom compatible with optical fiber propagation, namely time-bin, frequency-bin, and polarization qubits, along with faithful preservation of entanglement, confirming the platform&#39;s true universality. These results provide a robust, room-temperature solution for the high-rate synchronization of multidimensional quantum states, clearing a major hurdle for the deployment of global photonic quantum networks.</abstract>
    </arXiv>

            </metadata>
        </record>

    </GetRecord>
</OAI-PMH>