<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<OAI-PMH xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" 
         xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance"
         xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/OAI-PMH.xsd">
    <responseDate>2026-07-13T06:23:13Z</responseDate>
                <request verb="GetRecord" identifier="oai:arXiv.org:2511.14363" metadataPrefix="arXiv">http://oaipmh.arxiv.org/oai</request>


    <GetRecord>
                <record>
                <header>
        <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:2511.14363</identifier>
        <datestamp>2025-11-19</datestamp>
            <setSpec>physics:quant-ph</setSpec>
            <setSpec>physics:cond-mat:mtrl-sci</setSpec>
            <setSpec>physics:physics:bio-ph</setSpec>
    </header>

            <metadata>
                        <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ https://oaipmh.arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
        <id>2511.14363</id>
        <created>2025-11-18</created>
            <updated>2025-11-19</updated>
        <authors>
                <author>
                    <keyname>Chen</keyname>
                        <forenames>Rong-Hang</forenames>
                </author>
                <author>
                    <keyname>Dong</keyname>
                        <forenames>Jing</forenames>
                </author>
                <author>
                    <keyname>Yang</keyname>
                        <forenames>Wen</forenames>
                </author>
                <author>
                    <keyname>Ai</keyname>
                        <forenames>Qing</forenames>
                </author>
                <author>
                    <keyname>Long</keyname>
                        <forenames>Gui-Lu</forenames>
                </author>
        </authors>
        <title>Quantum Biology, Quantum Simulation and Quantum Coherent Devices</title>
            <categories>quant-ph cond-mat.mtrl-sci physics.bio-ph</categories>
            <license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license>
            <abstract>Many living organisms can exploit quantum mechanical effects to gain distinct biological advantages. In plants, photosynthesis uses quantum coherence to achieve near 100% efficiency in energy transfer. With advances in experimental techniques, two-dimensional electronic spectroscopy can reveal dynamic processes such as coherence and coupling within a system, and it plays an important role in studying energy transfer in photosynthesis. On the theory side, methods such as the generalized Bloch-Redfield theory and the hierarchical equations of motion are used to model photosynthetic systems. Quantum simulation, as a high-efficiency and low-complexity approach, has also made progress across various platforms in the study of photosynthesis. In recent years, a series of studies has introduced quantum coherence into artificial systems to enhance energy transfer efficiency, laying the groundwork for the design of coherent devices with efficient energy transport. Birds can use the weak geomagnetic field and spin-dependent chemical reactions to detect direction. Theoretical frameworks for animal navigation include magnetite-based mechanisms, magnetoreceptor genes, and the radical-pair mechanism. Quantum simulations of navigation have also advanced on multiple platforms. Inspired by animal navigation, diverse quantum effects have been applied to improve sensing and to support navigation tasks. This paper presents a comprehensive review of progress on quantum coherence in photosynthesis and avian navigation, along with related theoretical methods, quantum simulation approaches, and research on quantum coherent devices.</abstract>
    </arXiv>

            </metadata>
        </record>

    </GetRecord>
</OAI-PMH>