<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<OAI-PMH xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" 
         xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance"
         xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/OAI-PMH.xsd">
    <responseDate>2026-07-13T06:21:34Z</responseDate>
                <request verb="GetRecord" identifier="oai:arXiv.org:2511.04895" metadataPrefix="arXiv">http://oaipmh.arxiv.org/oai</request>


    <GetRecord>
                <record>
                <header>
        <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:2511.04895</identifier>
        <datestamp>2026-03-17</datestamp>
            <setSpec>physics:gr-qc</setSpec>
            <setSpec>physics:astro-ph:CO</setSpec>
            <setSpec>physics:astro-ph:SR</setSpec>
            <setSpec>physics:hep-th</setSpec>
    </header>

            <metadata>
                        <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ https://oaipmh.arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
        <id>2511.04895</id>
        <created>2025-11-07</created>
            <updated>2026-03-17</updated>
        <authors>
                <author>
                    <keyname>Trivedi</keyname>
                        <forenames>Oem</forenames>
                </author>
                <author>
                    <keyname>Loeb</keyname>
                        <forenames>Abraham</forenames>
                </author>
        </authors>
        <title>Novel Solar System Probes for Primordial Black Holes</title>
            <categories>gr-qc astro-ph.CO astro-ph.SR hep-th</categories>
            <comments>10 pages with no figures, comments are very welcome !</comments>
            <journal-ref>Physics of the Dark Universe, Volume 51, February 2026, 102195</journal-ref>
            <doi>10.1016/j.dark.2025.102195</doi>
            <license>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0/</license>
            <abstract>Primordial Black Holes (PBHs) represent one of the more interesting ways to address dark matter, at the interface of both cosmology and quantum gravity. It is no surprise then that testing PBHs is a venue of active interest, with several cosmological and astrophysical probes constraining different mass ranges. In this work, we propose novel Solar System scale searches for PBHs, motivated by the unique precision and coverage of local observables. We show that asteroid to dwarf planet mass PBHs can induce measurable dipolar timing signatures in pulsar timing arrays, while planetary mass PBHs can generate detectable ADAF accretion flares through interactions with Kuiper Belt bodies. Together, these complementary approaches open a new observational frontier for probing PBHs across mass ranges that remain unconstrained by conventional cosmological methods.</abstract>
    </arXiv>

            </metadata>
        </record>

    </GetRecord>
</OAI-PMH>