<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<OAI-PMH xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" 
         xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance"
         xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/OAI-PMH.xsd">
    <responseDate>2026-07-13T06:26:08Z</responseDate>
                <request verb="GetRecord" identifier="oai:arXiv.org:2601.14185" metadataPrefix="arXiv">http://oaipmh.arxiv.org/oai</request>


    <GetRecord>
                <record>
                <header>
        <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:2601.14185</identifier>
        <datestamp>2026-02-11</datestamp>
            <setSpec>physics:quant-ph</setSpec>
            <setSpec>physics:cond-mat:stat-mech</setSpec>
    </header>

            <metadata>
                        <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ https://oaipmh.arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
        <id>2601.14185</id>
        <created>2026-02-10</created>
            <updated>2026-02-11</updated>
        <authors>
                <author>
                    <keyname>Manna</keyname>
                        <forenames>Sourav</forenames>
                </author>
                <author>
                    <keyname>Lakshminarayan</keyname>
                        <forenames>Arul</forenames>
                </author>
                <author>
                    <keyname>Madhok</keyname>
                        <forenames>Vaibhav</forenames>
                </author>
        </authors>
        <title>Localizable Entanglement as an Order Parameter for Measurement-Induced Phase Transitions</title>
            <categories>quant-ph cond-mat.stat-mech</categories>
            <comments>8 pages, 6 figures. Identifies localizable entanglement as an operational order parameter for measurement-induced phase transitions in monitored quantum circuits. Reveals an emergent entanglement correlation length whose divergence allows extraction of the critical exponent from single-system-size data.A two-ancilla protocol provides an experimentally accessible probe of the transition</comments>
            <license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license>
            <abstract>We identify localizable entanglement (LE) as an order parameter for measurement-induced phase transitions (MIPT). LE exhibits universal finite-size scaling with critical exponents that match previous MIPT results and gives a nice operational interpretation connecting MIPTs to classical percolation. Remarkably, we find that LE decays exponentially with distance in the area-law phase as opposed to being essentially constant for the volume-law phase thereby, discover an intrinsic length scale $ξ_E$ that diverges at the critical measurement probability $p_c$. While classical percolation transition captures successful transport across a network, MIPT as characterized by LE can be interpreted as quantifying the amount of quantum teleportation between two given nodes in a quantum circuit. Building on this insight, we propose a two-ancilla protocol that provides an experimentally accessible readout of entanglement redistribution across the transition.</abstract>
    </arXiv>

            </metadata>
        </record>

    </GetRecord>
</OAI-PMH>