<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<OAI-PMH xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" 
         xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance"
         xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/OAI-PMH.xsd">
    <responseDate>2026-07-13T06:23:56Z</responseDate>
                <request verb="GetRecord" identifier="oai:arXiv.org:2602.22587" metadataPrefix="arXiv">http://oaipmh.arxiv.org/oai</request>


    <GetRecord>
                <record>
                <header>
        <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:2602.22587</identifier>
        <datestamp>2026-06-19</datestamp>
            <setSpec>physics:astro-ph:CO</setSpec>
            <setSpec>physics:gr-qc</setSpec>
    </header>

            <metadata>
                        <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ https://oaipmh.arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
        <id>2602.22587</id>
        <created>2026-05-05</created>
            <updated>2026-06-19</updated>
        <authors>
                <author>
                    <keyname>Lacki</keyname>
                        <forenames>Brian C.</forenames>
                </author>
        </authors>
        <title>Shadows of Giants: Constraints on Stupendously Large Black Holes from Negative Sources against the Cosmic Microwave Background</title>
            <categories>astro-ph.CO gr-qc</categories>
            <comments>20 pages, 5 figures, 1 table, accepted by JCAP</comments>
            <journal-ref>JCAP 06 (2026) 049</journal-ref>
            <doi>10.1088/1475-7516/2026/06/049</doi>
            <license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license>
            <abstract>Stupendously large astrophysical black holes (SLABs) are hypothetical black holes with masses of more than a trillion Suns. Because observable consequences of their existence have only recently been seriously considered, there have been relatively few constraints on their abundance. This work motivates a simple yet powerful constraint on SLABs: their huge shadows are visible against the cosmic microwave background. SLABs could thus appear as negative sources in microwave data. In fact, the shadow of a SLAB with a fixed mass becomes easier to detect with increasing redshifts past $1.6$ where the angular diameter distance starts falling. The limits are powerful enough to rule out SLABs of mass $\gtrsim 10^{17}\ M_{\odot}$ within the last scattering surface, and imply $Ω_{BH} \lesssim 10^{-5}$ for masses $10^{15}$--$10^{18}\ M_{\odot}$. I also discuss the effects of accretion and their implications for the limits: SLAB growth, positive accretion luminosity, and obscuring material.</abstract>
    </arXiv>

            </metadata>
        </record>

    </GetRecord>
</OAI-PMH>