<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<OAI-PMH xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" 
         xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance"
         xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/OAI-PMH.xsd">
    <responseDate>2026-07-12T16:14:17Z</responseDate>
                <request verb="GetRecord" identifier="oai:arXiv.org:2506.02920v3" metadataPrefix="arXiv">http://oaipmh.arxiv.org/oai</request>


    <GetRecord>
                <record>
                <header>
        <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:2506.02920</identifier>
        <datestamp>2026-01-09</datestamp>
            <setSpec>physics:quant-ph</setSpec>
            <setSpec>cs:cs:NI</setSpec>
    </header>

            <metadata>
                        <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ https://oaipmh.arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
        <id>2506.02920</id>
        <created>2026-01-08</created>
            <updated>2026-01-09</updated>
        <authors>
                <author>
                    <keyname>Cacciapuoti</keyname>
                        <forenames>Angela Sara</forenames>
                </author>
                <author>
                    <keyname>Pellitteri</keyname>
                        <forenames>Claudio</forenames>
                </author>
                <author>
                    <keyname>Illiano</keyname>
                        <forenames>Jessica</forenames>
                </author>
                <author>
                    <keyname>d&#39;Avossa</keyname>
                        <forenames>Laura</forenames>
                </author>
                <author>
                    <keyname>Mazza</keyname>
                        <forenames>Francesco</forenames>
                </author>
                <author>
                    <keyname>Chen</keyname>
                        <forenames>Siyi</forenames>
                </author>
                <author>
                    <keyname>Caleffi</keyname>
                        <forenames>Marcello</forenames>
                </author>
        </authors>
        <title>Quantum Data Centres: Why Entanglement Changes Everything</title>
            <categories>quant-ph cs.NI</categories>
            <comments>This work has been funded by the European Union under the ERC grant QNattyNet, n.101169850 (https://qnattynet.quantuminternet.it/)</comments>
            <doi>10.1098/rsta.2024.0518</doi>
            <license>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0/</license>
            <abstract>The Quantum Internet is key for distributed quantum computing, by interconnecting multiple quantum processors into a virtual quantum computation system. This allows to scale the number of qubits, by overcoming the inherent limitations of noisy-intermediate-scale quantum (NISQ) devices. Thus, the Quantum Internet is the foundation for large-scale, fault-tolerant quantum computation. Among the distributed architectures, Quantum Data Centres emerge as the most viable in the medium-term, since they integrate multiple quantum processors within a localized network infrastructure, by allowing modular design of quantum networking. We analyze the physical and topological constraints of Quantum Data Centres, by emphasizing the role of entanglement orchestrators in dynamically reconfiguring network topologies through local operations. We examine the major hardware challenge of quantum transduction, essential for interfacing heterogeneous quantum systems. Furthermore, we explore how interconnecting multiple Quantum Data Centres could enable large-scale quantum networks. We discuss the topological constraints of such a scaling and identify open challenges, including entanglement routing and synchronization. The carried analysis positions Quantum Data Centres as both a practical implementation platform and strategic framework for the future Quantum Internet.</abstract>
    </arXiv>

            </metadata>
        </record>

    </GetRecord>
</OAI-PMH>