<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<OAI-PMH xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" 
         xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance"
         xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/OAI-PMH.xsd">
    <responseDate>2026-07-13T06:27:36Z</responseDate>
                <request verb="GetRecord" identifier="oai:arXiv.org:2508.00353" metadataPrefix="arXiv">http://oaipmh.arxiv.org/oai</request>


    <GetRecord>
                <record>
                <header>
        <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:2508.00353</identifier>
        <datestamp>2026-01-28</datestamp>
            <setSpec>physics:quant-ph</setSpec>
    </header>

            <metadata>
                        <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ https://oaipmh.arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
        <id>2508.00353</id>
        <created>2025-11-30</created>
            <updated>2026-01-28</updated>
        <authors>
                <author>
                    <keyname>Solki</keyname>
                        <forenames>H.</forenames>
                </author>
                <author>
                    <keyname>Motazedifard</keyname>
                        <forenames>Ali</forenames>
                </author>
                <author>
                    <keyname>Naderi</keyname>
                        <forenames>M. H.</forenames>
                </author>
                <author>
                    <keyname>Youssefi</keyname>
                        <forenames>A.</forenames>
                </author>
                <author>
                    <keyname>Roknizadeh</keyname>
                        <forenames>R.</forenames>
                </author>
        </authors>
        <title>Nonclassical microwave radiation from the parametric dynamical Casimir effect in the reversed-dissipation regime of circuit optomechanics</title>
            <categories>quant-ph</categories>
            <journal-ref>Phys. Rev. A 113, 013737 (2026)</journal-ref>
            <doi>10.1103/tmwf-s4k8</doi>
            <license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license>
            <abstract>We propose an experimentally feasible optomechanical system (OMS) that is dispersively driven and operates in the reversed dissipation regime (RDR), where the mechanical damping rate far exceeds the cavity decay rate. We demonstrate that coherent, fast-time modulation of the driving laser frequency on time scales longer than the mechanical decoherence time allows for adiabatic elimination of the mechanical mode, resulting in strong parametric amplification of quantum vacuum fluctuations of the intracavity field. This mechanism, known as the parametric dynamical Casimir effect (parametric-DCE), leads to the generation of Casimir photons. In the dispersive RDR, we find that the total system Hamiltonian-including the DCE term-is intrinsically modified by a generalized optomechanical Kerr-type nonlinearity. This nonlinearity not only saturates the mean number of radiated Casimir photons on short time scales, even without dissipation, but also induces oscillatory behavior in their dynamics and quantum characteristics. Remarkably, the presence of the Kerr nonlinearity causes the generated DCE photons to exhibit nonclassical features, including simultaneous sub-Poissonian statistics and negative Wigner function, as well as quadrature squeezing, which can be controlled by adjusting the system parameters. Surprisingly, the controllable simultaneous nonclassical dynamics in the same physical parameter regime, which is induced by the optomechanical Kerr nonlinearity to the parametric DCE cannot occur in the standard DCE or Kerr-type systems. The proposed nonclassical microwave radiation source possesses the potential to be applied in quantum information processing, quantum computing as well as microwave quantum sensing.</abstract>
    </arXiv>

            </metadata>
        </record>

    </GetRecord>
</OAI-PMH>