<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<OAI-PMH xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" 
         xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance"
         xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/OAI-PMH.xsd">
    <responseDate>2026-07-13T06:20:43Z</responseDate>
                <request verb="GetRecord" identifier="oai:arXiv.org:2512.18008" metadataPrefix="arXiv">http://oaipmh.arxiv.org/oai</request>


    <GetRecord>
                <record>
                <header>
        <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:2512.18008</identifier>
        <datestamp>2025-12-23</datestamp>
            <setSpec>physics:gr-qc</setSpec>
    </header>

            <metadata>
                        <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ https://oaipmh.arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
        <id>2512.18008</id>
        <created>2025-12-19</created>
            <updated>2025-12-23</updated>
        <authors>
                <author>
                    <keyname>Rodal</keyname>
                        <forenames>José</forenames>
                </author>
        </authors>
        <title>A warp drive with predominantly positive invariant energy density and global Hawking-Ellis Type I</title>
            <categories>gr-qc</categories>
            <comments>56 pages, 10 figures, 12 tables</comments>
            <journal-ref>General Relativity and Gravitation (Springer), Volume 58, Article Number 1 (2026), published December 17, 2025</journal-ref>
            <doi>10.1007/s10714-025-03495-x</doi>
            <license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license>
            <abstract>We present the first fully explicit, continuous, analytically derived warp-drive spacetime within General Relativity whose shift-vector flow is kinematically irrotational. Building on Santiago \emph{et al.} that scalar-potential, zero-vorticity warp fields are Hawking-Ellis Type I for unit lapse and flat spatial slices, we supply a closed-form scalar potential and smooth shift components with proper boundary behavior, together with a Cartan-tetrad analytic pipeline and high-precision eigenanalysis. Compared with the Alcubierre and Natário models (evaluated at identical parameters $ρ, σ, v/c$), our irrotational solution exhibits \emph{significantly reduced} local NEC/WEC stress: its peak proper-energy deficit is reduced by a factor of $\approx 38$ relative to Alcubierre and $\approx 2.6 \times 10^{3}$ relative to Natário, and its peak NEC violation is more than $60 \times$ smaller than Natário. Crucially, the stress-energy is \emph{globally} Hawking-Ellis Type I, with a well-defined timelike eigenvalue (proper energy density) everywhere. A fixed-smoothing vortical ablation confirms that this improvement is causally due to irrotational, curl-free kinematics rather than profile shaping: adding modest vorticity collapses the $E_{+} / E_{-}$ balance and drives large increases in the negative-energy magnitude $E_{-}$. We quantify the negative-energy requirement via a \emph{slice-integrated} (on $Σ_{t}$) negative-energy volume and tabulate global measures. A far-field extrapolation to $R \to \infty$ yields tail-corrected totals $|E_{+} - E_{-}| / (E_{+} + E_{-}) = 0.04\%$. Thus the net \emph{proper} energy is consistent with zero to four decimal places (in fractional units). We also establish regularity at $r=0$ for the irrotational construction.</abstract>
    </arXiv>

            </metadata>
        </record>

    </GetRecord>
</OAI-PMH>