<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<OAI-PMH xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" 
         xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance"
         xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/OAI-PMH.xsd">
    <responseDate>2026-07-13T06:22:03Z</responseDate>
                <request verb="GetRecord" identifier="oai:arXiv.org:2603.22863" metadataPrefix="arXiv">http://oaipmh.arxiv.org/oai</request>


    <GetRecord>
                <record>
                <header>
        <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:2603.22863</identifier>
        <datestamp>2026-03-25</datestamp>
            <setSpec>physics:astro-ph:GA</setSpec>
    </header>

            <metadata>
                        <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ https://oaipmh.arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
        <id>2603.22863</id>
        <created>2026-03-24</created>
            <updated>2026-03-25</updated>
        <authors>
                <author>
                    <keyname>Wu</keyname>
                        <forenames>Hao</forenames>
                </author>
                <author>
                    <keyname>Huang</keyname>
                        <forenames>Yang</forenames>
                </author>
                <author>
                    <keyname>Zhang</keyname>
                        <forenames>Huawei</forenames>
                </author>
                <author>
                    <keyname>Sun</keyname>
                        <forenames>Guangze</forenames>
                </author>
                <author>
                    <keyname>Shao</keyname>
                        <forenames>Shi</forenames>
                </author>
        </authors>
        <title>The Fate of the Milky Way--Andromeda System: To Merge or Not?</title>
            <categories>astro-ph.GA</categories>
            <comments>15 pages, 11 figures (6 in main text, 5 in Appendix); Accepted by The Astrophysical Journal Letters</comments>
            <license>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0/</license>
            <abstract>It has long been predicted that the Milky Way (MW) will eventually merge with Andromeda (M31), a view reinforced by \textit{HST} measurements indicating a small M31 transverse velocity. However, using updated \textit{Gaia}-based proper motions (PMs) and including the dynamical influence of the Large Magellanic Cloud (LMC) and M33, Sawala et al. reported an MW--M31 merger probability of $\sim$50\% within 10 Gyr, leaving the fate of the Local Group (LG) uncertain. Adopting their semi-analytic framework, we revisit this problem with the latest and most precise \textit{Gaia}-based PMs for M31 and M33, corrected for systematic offsets in \textit{Gaia} astrometry. In our fiducial model, the MW--M31 merger probability rises to 90\%, with a median merger time of $6.5_{-1.5}^{+1.3}$ Gyr, broadly restoring the classical picture. A sensitivity analysis shows that the merger probability depends strongly on the adopted M31 PM through two channels: a direct effect via the radial-tangential balance of the MW-M31 orbit, and a satellite-mediated effect, where the M31 PM fixes the orbital plane and determines how satellite-induced barycentric reflex motions project onto it, either promoting or suppressing a merger. Given this sensitivity, current measurements, while favoring a high merger probability, remain inconclusive, spanning from 64.7\% to 100\% across the 2$σ$ PM region. Future PM measurements with uncertainty of $\lesssim2\,\upmu\mathrm{as\,yr^{-1}}$ will be required to reach a firm conclusion, i.e., to constrain the probability range within 10\% at the 2$σ$ level.</abstract>
    </arXiv>

            </metadata>
        </record>

    </GetRecord>
</OAI-PMH>