<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<OAI-PMH xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" 
         xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance"
         xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/OAI-PMH.xsd">
    <responseDate>2026-07-13T06:23:35Z</responseDate>
                <request verb="GetRecord" identifier="oai:arXiv.org:2601.15565" metadataPrefix="arXiv">http://oaipmh.arxiv.org/oai</request>


    <GetRecord>
                <record>
                <header>
        <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:2601.15565</identifier>
        <datestamp>2026-01-23</datestamp>
            <setSpec>physics:quant-ph</setSpec>
            <setSpec>physics:physics:optics</setSpec>
    </header>

            <metadata>
                        <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ https://oaipmh.arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
        <id>2601.15565</id>
        <created>2026-01-22</created>
            <updated>2026-01-23</updated>
        <authors>
                <author>
                    <keyname>Terrasson</keyname>
                        <forenames>Alex</forenames>
                </author>
                <author>
                    <keyname>Madsen</keyname>
                        <forenames>Lars</forenames>
                </author>
                <author>
                    <keyname>Grim</keyname>
                        <forenames>Joel</forenames>
                </author>
                <author>
                    <keyname>Bowen</keyname>
                        <forenames>Warwick</forenames>
                </author>
        </authors>
        <title>Bright Pulsed Squeezed Light for Quantum-Enhanced Precision Microscopy</title>
            <categories>quant-ph physics.optics</categories>
            <comments>5 pages, 3 figures</comments>
            <license>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0/</license>
            <abstract>Squeezed states of light enable enhanced measurement precision by reducing noise below the standard quantum limit. A key application of squeezed light is nonlinear microscopy, where state-of-the-art performance is limited by photodamage and quantum-limited noise. Such microscopes require bright, pulsed light for optimal operation, yet generating and detecting bright pulsed squeezing at high levels remains challenging. In this work, we present an efficient technique to generate high levels of bright picosecond pulsed squeezed light using a $χ^2$ optical parametric amplification process in a waveguide. We measure $-3.2~\mathrm{dB}$ of bright squeezing with optical power compatible with nonlinear microscopy, as well as $-3.6~\mathrm{dB}$ of vacuum squeezing. Corrected for losses, these squeezing levels correspond to $-15.4^{+2.7}_{-8.7}~\mathrm{dB}$ of squeezing generated in the waveguide. The measured level of bright amplitude pulsed squeezing is to our knowledge the highest reported to date, and will contribute to the broader adoption of quantum-enhanced nonlinear microscopy in biological studies.</abstract>
    </arXiv>

            </metadata>
        </record>

    </GetRecord>
</OAI-PMH>