<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<OAI-PMH xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" 
         xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance"
         xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/OAI-PMH.xsd">
    <responseDate>2026-07-13T06:27:49Z</responseDate>
                <request verb="GetRecord" identifier="oai:arXiv.org:2510.09520" metadataPrefix="arXiv">http://oaipmh.arxiv.org/oai</request>


    <GetRecord>
                <record>
                <header>
        <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:2510.09520</identifier>
        <datestamp>2025-10-13</datestamp>
            <setSpec>physics:quant-ph</setSpec>
    </header>

            <metadata>
                        <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ https://oaipmh.arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
        <id>2510.09520</id>
        <created>2025-10-10</created>
            <updated>2025-10-13</updated>
        <authors>
                <author>
                    <keyname>Javadi-Abhari</keyname>
                        <forenames>Ali</forenames>
                </author>
                <author>
                    <keyname>Martiel</keyname>
                        <forenames>Simon</forenames>
                </author>
                <author>
                    <keyname>Seif</keyname>
                        <forenames>Alireza</forenames>
                </author>
                <author>
                    <keyname>Takita</keyname>
                        <forenames>Maika</forenames>
                </author>
                <author>
                    <keyname>Wei</keyname>
                        <forenames>Ken X.</forenames>
                </author>
        </authors>
        <title>Big cats: entanglement in 120 qubits and beyond</title>
            <categories>quant-ph</categories>
            <license>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0/</license>
            <abstract>Entanglement is the quintessential quantum phenomenon and a key enabler of quantum algorithms. The ability to faithfully entangle many distinct particles is often used as a benchmark for the quality of hardware and control in a quantum computer. Greenberger-Horne-Zeilinger (GHZ) states, also known as Schrödinger cat states, are useful for this task. They are easy to verify, but difficult to prepare due to their high sensitivity to noise. In this Letter we report on the largest GHZ state prepared to date consisting of 120 superconducting qubits. We do this via a combination of optimized compilation, low-overhead error detection and temporary uncomputation. We use an automated compiler to maximize error-detection in state preparation circuits subject to arbitrary qubit connectivity constraints and variations in error rates. We measure a GHZ fidelity of 0.56(3) with a post-selection rate of 28%. We certify the fidelity of our GHZ states using multiple methods and show that they are all equivalent, albeit with different practical considerations.</abstract>
    </arXiv>

            </metadata>
        </record>

    </GetRecord>
</OAI-PMH>