<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<OAI-PMH xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" 
         xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance"
         xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/OAI-PMH.xsd">
    <responseDate>2026-07-13T10:16:52Z</responseDate>
                <request verb="GetRecord" identifier="oai:arXiv.org:2605.30145" metadataPrefix="arXiv">http://oaipmh.arxiv.org/oai</request>


    <GetRecord>
                <record>
                <header>
        <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:2605.30145</identifier>
        <datestamp>2026-05-29</datestamp>
            <setSpec>physics:gr-qc</setSpec>
            <setSpec>physics:astro-ph:CO</setSpec>
            <setSpec>physics:astro-ph:GA</setSpec>
    </header>

            <metadata>
                        <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ https://oaipmh.arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
        <id>2605.30145</id>
        <created>2026-05-28</created>
            <updated>2026-05-29</updated>
        <authors>
                <author>
                    <keyname>Galoppo</keyname>
                        <forenames>Marco</forenames>
                </author>
                <author>
                    <keyname>Bruni</keyname>
                        <forenames>Marco</forenames>
                </author>
                <author>
                    <keyname>Harada</keyname>
                        <forenames>Tomohiro</forenames>
                </author>
        </authors>
        <title>Supermassive black hole seeds from direct collapse of CDM-curvature peaks</title>
            <categories>gr-qc astro-ph.CO astro-ph.GA</categories>
            <comments>34 pages, 10 figures</comments>
            <report-no>RUP-26-10</report-no>
            <license>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0/</license>
            <abstract>We study black hole (BH) formation from the nonlinear growth and collapse of primordial perturbations during the matter-dominated era. Modelling cold dark matter (CDM) as pressureless dust, we describe the collapse in a fully nonlinear relativistic framework using the Lemaître-Tolman-Bondi (LTB) and quasi-spherical Szekeres solutions as exact perturbations of a spatially-flat Friedmann-Lemaître-Robertson-Walker (FLRW) $Λ$CDM background. At first order in relativistic scalar perturbation theory, the growing mode of any relevant quantity can be expressed in terms of the conserved gauge-invariant curvature perturbation $\mathcal{R}_c$, which acts as a potential for the 3-curvature of hypersurfaces orthogonal to the matter 4-velocity. We use this result to express the active gravitational mass and curvature functions of the LTB and Szekeres models in terms of the initial values of $\mathcal{R}_c$ and its spatial derivatives. From these initial curvature data we derive: (i) the turn-around, collapse, and apparent-horizon formation times, and (ii) the regularity conditions required for BH formation. We show that sinusoidal and Gaussian profiles do not provide viable BH-forming channels, whereas broad compensated curvature peaks, naturally predicted by peak theory, do. We then estimate the formation times of $10^{3}-10^{6}~\mathrm{M}_\odot$ massive BH seeds produced by the direct collapse of primordial CDM curvature peaks, finding full BH formation at redshifts $z&gt;5$, with core collapse beginning at $10 \lesssim z \lesssim 16$. Finally, we characterize the local dynamics and singularity type of the collapse (point-like, cigar-like, or pancake-like) directly from the initial comoving curvature data, clarifying the role of the initial shear in selecting the collapse end-state.</abstract>
    </arXiv>

            </metadata>
        </record>

    </GetRecord>
</OAI-PMH>