<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<OAI-PMH xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" 
         xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance"
         xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/OAI-PMH.xsd">
    <responseDate>2026-07-13T06:27:57Z</responseDate>
                <request verb="GetRecord" identifier="oai:arXiv.org:2512.03681" metadataPrefix="arXiv">http://oaipmh.arxiv.org/oai</request>


    <GetRecord>
                <record>
                <header>
        <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:2512.03681</identifier>
        <datestamp>2025-12-04</datestamp>
            <setSpec>physics:quant-ph</setSpec>
    </header>

            <metadata>
                        <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ https://oaipmh.arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
        <id>2512.03681</id>
        <created>2025-12-03</created>
            <updated>2025-12-04</updated>
        <authors>
                <author>
                    <keyname>Zschetzsche</keyname>
                        <forenames>Lilith</forenames>
                </author>
                <author>
                    <keyname>Mansuroglu</keyname>
                        <forenames>Refik</forenames>
                </author>
                <author>
                    <keyname>Molnár</keyname>
                        <forenames>András</forenames>
                </author>
                <author>
                    <keyname>Schuch</keyname>
                        <forenames>Norbert</forenames>
                </author>
        </authors>
        <title>Direct Equivalence between Dynamics of Quantum Walks and Coupled Classical Oscillators</title>
            <categories>quant-ph</categories>
            <comments>17 pages, 3 figures</comments>
            <license>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0/</license>
            <abstract>Continuous time quantum walks on exponentially large, sparse graphs form a powerful paradigm for quantum computing: On the one hand, they can be efficiently simulated on a quantum computer. On the other hand, they are themselves BQP-complete, providing an alternative framework for thinking about quantum computing -- a perspective which has indeed led to a number of novel algorithms and oracle problems. Recently, simulating the dynamics of a system of harmonic oscillators (that is, masses and springs) was set forth as another BQP-complete problem defined on exponentially large, sparse graphs. In this work, we establish a direct and transparent mapping between these two classes of problems. As compared to linking the two classes of problems via their BQP-completeness, our mapping has several desirable features: It is transparent, in that it respects the structure of the problem, including the geometry of the underlying graph, initialization, read-out, and efficient oracle access, resulting in low overhead in terms of both space and time; it allows to map also between restricted subsets of instances of both problems which are not BQP-complete; it provides a recipe to directly translate any quantum algorithm designed in the quantum walk paradigm to harmonic oscillators (and vice versa); and finally, it provides an alternative, transparent way to prove BQP-completeness of the harmonic oscillator problem by mapping it to BQP-completeness construction for the quantum walk problem (or vice versa).</abstract>
    </arXiv>

            </metadata>
        </record>

    </GetRecord>
</OAI-PMH>