<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<OAI-PMH xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" 
         xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance"
         xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/OAI-PMH.xsd">
    <responseDate>2026-07-13T06:28:54Z</responseDate>
                <request verb="GetRecord" identifier="oai:arXiv.org:2512.24538" metadataPrefix="arXiv">http://oaipmh.arxiv.org/oai</request>


    <GetRecord>
                <record>
                <header>
        <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:2512.24538</identifier>
        <datestamp>2026-01-01</datestamp>
            <setSpec>physics:astro-ph:EP</setSpec>
    </header>

            <metadata>
                        <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ https://oaipmh.arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
        <id>2512.24538</id>
        <created>2025-12-31</created>
            <updated>2026-01-01</updated>
        <authors>
                <author>
                    <keyname>Zhu</keyname>
                        <forenames>Livia</forenames>
                </author>
                <author>
                    <keyname>Graham</keyname>
                        <forenames>R. J.</forenames>
                </author>
                <author>
                    <keyname>Abbot</keyname>
                        <forenames>Dorian S.</forenames>
                </author>
        </authors>
        <title>Seafloor Weathering and Stochastic Outgassing Unlikely to Significantly Shorten the Future Lifespan of Earth&#39;s Terrestrial Biosphere</title>
            <categories>astro-ph.EP</categories>
            <journal-ref>The Astrophysical Journal Letters, 996(1), L14 (2025)</journal-ref>
            <doi>10.3847/2041-8213/ae2b58</doi>
            <license>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0/</license>
            <abstract>Current understanding suggests that as the Sun brightens in the far future, Earth&#39;s carbonate-silicate cycle will offset increasing temperatures by drawing CO$_2$ out of the atmosphere, ultimately leading to the extinction of all terrestrial plant life via either overheating or CO$_2$ starvation. Most previous estimates put the future lifespan of Earth&#39;s terrestrial biosphere at $\sim$1 billion yr, but recent work used a new coupled climate-continental weathering model with up-to-date parameter constraints to revise this estimate upward to 1.6-1.86 billion yr. In this study, we extend the model to examine the impacts of seafloor weathering and stochastic variations in CO$_2$ outgassing rates on the remaining lifespan of Earth&#39;s terrestrial biosphere. We find that if seafloor weathering has a stronger feedback than continental weathering and accounts for a large portion of global silicate weathering, then the remaining lifespan of the terrestrial biosphere can be shortened, but a lifespan of more than 1 billion yr (Gyr) remains likely. Similarly, stochastic fluctuations in outgassing rates can have a significant impact if the size of the fluctuations exceed those observed over the last 1 billion yr. The impact of weak seafloor weathering and lower variability stochasticity are minor. Our work provisionally supports a lengthened lifespan of Earth&#39;s terrestrial biosphere, suggests robustness of this lengthened lifespan to planetary parameters that may vary among exoplanets, and identifies seafloor weathering as a key process that requires further study and constraint.</abstract>
    </arXiv>

            </metadata>
        </record>

    </GetRecord>
</OAI-PMH>