<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<OAI-PMH xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" 
         xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance"
         xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/OAI-PMH.xsd">
    <responseDate>2026-07-11T08:10:29Z</responseDate>
                <request verb="GetRecord" identifier="oai:arXiv.org:2606.03707v2" metadataPrefix="arXiv">http://oaipmh.arxiv.org/oai</request>


    <GetRecord>
                <record>
                <header>
        <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:2606.03707</identifier>
        <datestamp>2026-06-16</datestamp>
            <setSpec>physics:astro-ph:HE</setSpec>
            <setSpec>physics:hep-ph</setSpec>
    </header>

            <metadata>
                        <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ https://oaipmh.arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
        <id>2606.03707</id>
        <created>2026-06-15</created>
            <updated>2026-06-16</updated>
        <authors>
                <author>
                    <keyname>Tang</keyname>
                        <forenames>Shao-Peng</forenames>
                </author>
                <author>
                    <keyname>Huang</keyname>
                        <forenames>Yong-Jia</forenames>
                </author>
                <author>
                    <keyname>Fan</keyname>
                        <forenames>Yi-Zhong</forenames>
                </author>
        </authors>
        <title>Neutron Star Observations Challenge a Large Colour-Superconducting Gap in Dense Quark Matter</title>
            <categories>astro-ph.HE hep-ph</categories>
            <comments>22 pages, 8 figures; model and results updated</comments>
            <license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license>
            <abstract>At asymptotically high density, quantum chromodynamics (QCD) predicts that quark matter becomes a colour superconductor in the colour-flavour-locked (CFL) phase, yet, away from the asymptotic regime, the magnitude of the pairing gap is uncertain. Here we combine multi-messenger neutron star observations with perturbative QCD and chiral effective field theory inputs in a Bayesian inference built on a flexible Gaussian-process--neural-network representation of the equation of state (EOS). By matching the EOS at a baryon chemical potential of 2.6 GeV to the perturbative QCD prediction supplemented by the next-to-leading-order CFL contribution, we infer a gap of $ĂŽÂ”^{*}_{\rm CFL}=34^{+32}_{-28}$ MeV and a 95% credible upper limit of about 66 MeV, which is a factor of two tighter than previous bounds and at the lower edge of most microscopic model predictions. We further place the first data-driven constraint on the unknown high-order constant of the perturbative QCD pressure, i.e., $c_0=-21^{+9}_{-8}$. Our results indicate that colour-superconducting pairing makes only a subdominant contribution to dense matter pressure, tightening the connection between neutron star data and the QCD phase diagram.</abstract>
    </arXiv>

            </metadata>
        </record>

    </GetRecord>
</OAI-PMH>