<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<OAI-PMH xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" 
         xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance"
         xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/OAI-PMH.xsd">
    <responseDate>2026-07-11T20:31:59Z</responseDate>
                <request verb="GetRecord" identifier="oai:arXiv.org:2601.02469v2" metadataPrefix="arXiv">http://oaipmh.arxiv.org/oai</request>


    <GetRecord>
                <record>
                <header>
        <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:2601.02469</identifier>
        <datestamp>2026-03-12</datestamp>
            <setSpec>physics:astro-ph:GA</setSpec>
            <setSpec>physics:astro-ph:HE</setSpec>
    </header>

            <metadata>
                        <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ https://oaipmh.arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
        <id>2601.02469</id>
        <created>2026-03-10</created>
            <updated>2026-03-12</updated>
        <authors>
                <author>
                    <keyname>Jeon</keyname>
                        <forenames>Junehyoung</forenames>
                </author>
                <author>
                    <keyname>Bromm</keyname>
                        <forenames>Volker</forenames>
                </author>
                <author>
                    <keyname>Venditti</keyname>
                        <forenames>Alessandra</forenames>
                </author>
                <author>
                    <keyname>Finkelstein</keyname>
                        <forenames>Steven L.</forenames>
                </author>
                <author>
                    <keyname>Hsiao</keyname>
                        <forenames>Tiger Yu-Yang</forenames>
                </author>
        </authors>
        <title>Hunting for the First Explosions at the High-Redshift Frontier</title>
            <categories>astro-ph.GA astro-ph.HE</categories>
            <comments>10 pages, 4 figures. Accepted for publication in ApJ</comments>
            <license>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0/</license>
            <abstract>The James Webb Space Telescope (JWST) has spectroscopically confirmed galaxies up to $z\sim14$, 300 Myr after the Big Bang, and several candidates have been discovered at $z\sim15-25$, with one candidate as high as $z\sim30$, only 100 Myr after the Big Bang. Such objects are unexpected, since theoretical studies have not predicted the existence of detectable galaxies at $z\sim30$. While any $z\sim30$ candidates may be contaminants at lower redshifts, we explore whether such extreme redshift sources could be consistent with hyper-energetic transient events linked to the formation of the first, metal-free, stars. Specifically, we consider pair-instability supernovae (PISNe), a predicted class of extreme thermonuclear explosions that leave no remnant behind. Using cosmological simulations, we investigate an overdense cosmic region, where star formation and subsequent PISNe occur at $z\sim30-40$, even within standard cosmology. Assessing the likelihood of such a region, the corresponding number of PISNe at $z\gtrsim20$, and their observed flux, we find that JWST has a non-negligible chance to detect a PISN event at extremely high redshifts. If a transient event were confirmed at $z\sim30$, this would provide a direct glimpse into the epoch of first star formation, dramatically extending the empirical reach of astronomy.</abstract>
    </arXiv>

            </metadata>
        </record>

    </GetRecord>
</OAI-PMH>