<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<OAI-PMH xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" 
         xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance"
         xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/OAI-PMH.xsd">
    <responseDate>2026-07-13T06:23:56Z</responseDate>
                <request verb="GetRecord" identifier="oai:arXiv.org:2602.24019" metadataPrefix="arXiv">http://oaipmh.arxiv.org/oai</request>


    <GetRecord>
                <record>
                <header>
        <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:2602.24019</identifier>
        <datestamp>2026-06-12</datestamp>
            <setSpec>physics:gr-qc</setSpec>
    </header>

            <metadata>
                        <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ https://oaipmh.arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
        <id>2602.24019</id>
        <created>2026-03-15</created>
            <updated>2026-06-12</updated>
        <authors>
                <author>
                    <keyname>Niehof</keyname>
                        <forenames>Lorens F.</forenames>
                </author>
                <author>
                    <keyname>Venkatasubramanian</keyname>
                        <forenames>Ananya</forenames>
                </author>
                <author>
                    <keyname>Toschi</keyname>
                        <forenames>Federico</forenames>
                </author>
                <author>
                    <keyname>Liberati</keyname>
                        <forenames>Stefano</forenames>
                </author>
        </authors>
        <title>Freezing lakes as analogue models of $Λ$CDM cosmology and beyond</title>
            <categories>gr-qc</categories>
            <doi>10.1103/cw4j-q9ch</doi>
            <license>http://creativecommons.org/publicdomain/zero/1.0/</license>
            <abstract>We extend previous conduction-based analogies between ice growth in a lake and cosmological expansion by incorporating buoyancy-driven heat transport. Reformulating the Stefan problem with both conductive and convective fluxes yields an evolution equation for the ice thickness $s(t)$ that is structurally analogous to the Friedmann equations for the cosmological scale factor $a(t)$. Beyond reproducing radiation-, matter-, and curvature-like behaviors, we introduce a reduced description of convection in which the vertically integrated heat flux reaching the moving ice-water interface is modeled as a power-law function of the instantaneous liquid-layer thickness, generating two additional effective contributions. The first is a constant term, directly analogous to a cosmological constant, arising from the persistence of buoyancy-driven transport under geometric confinement. The second is a $s^{-1}$ contribution originating from the coupling between the moving ice boundary and the convective boundary layer. This term reflects the specific reduced flux-height Ansatz adopted, rather than a universal physical prediction. When expressed in Friedmann-like cosmological form, this term entails a fluid with negative energy density and equation-of-state parameter $w=-2/3$. In cosmology this term may be an effective one associated to a network of domain walls made of exotic energy/matter, but it might also arise from an energy exchange between cosmological components. Overall, the results should be interpreted as a structural analogy between evolution equations, showing how nonlinear transport mechanisms in a classical moving-boundary problem can reproduce the hierarchy of scaling terms familiar from cosmology within a reduced and analytically tractable framework.</abstract>
    </arXiv>

            </metadata>
        </record>

    </GetRecord>
</OAI-PMH>