<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<OAI-PMH xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" 
         xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance"
         xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/OAI-PMH.xsd">
    <responseDate>2026-07-13T06:23:04Z</responseDate>
                <request verb="GetRecord" identifier="oai:arXiv.org:2511.00570" metadataPrefix="arXiv">http://oaipmh.arxiv.org/oai</request>


    <GetRecord>
                <record>
                <header>
        <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:2511.00570</identifier>
        <datestamp>2025-12-11</datestamp>
            <setSpec>physics:physics:optics</setSpec>
            <setSpec>physics:quant-ph</setSpec>
    </header>

            <metadata>
                        <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ https://oaipmh.arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
        <id>2511.00570</id>
        <created>2025-12-09</created>
            <updated>2025-12-11</updated>
        <authors>
                <author>
                    <keyname>Hu</keyname>
                        <forenames>Jierui</forenames>
                </author>
                <author>
                    <keyname>Yuan</keyname>
                        <forenames>Hao</forenames>
                </author>
                <author>
                    <keyname>Akin</keyname>
                        <forenames>Joshua</forenames>
                </author>
                <author>
                    <keyname>Fan</keyname>
                        <forenames>Shanhui</forenames>
                </author>
                <author>
                    <keyname>Fang</keyname>
                        <forenames>Kejie</forenames>
                </author>
        </authors>
        <title>Quantum-coherent optical isolation and circulation using frequency conversion on a chip</title>
            <categories>physics.optics quant-ph</categories>
            <license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license>
            <abstract>Breaking optical reciprocity enables new regimes of light--matter interaction with broad implications for fundamental physics and emerging quantum technologies. Although various approaches have been explored to achieve optical nonreciprocity, realizing it at the single-photon level has remained a major challenge. Here, we demonstrate nonmagnetic optical nonreciprocity -- including both isolation and circulation -- in the quantum regime, enabled by efficient and noiseless all-optical frequency conversion on an integrated III-V photonic chip. Our device preserves the quantum coherence and entanglement of the input photons while delivering exceptional performance parameters, including a high extinction ratio of 34 dB, low insertion loss of 0.8 dB, broad bandwidth of 44 GHz, high operational fidelity of 97%, and widely tunable operation wavelength. This realization of quantum optical nonreciprocity in a scalable photonic platform opens a pathway toward directional quantum communication and noise-resilient quantum networks.</abstract>
    </arXiv>

            </metadata>
        </record>

    </GetRecord>
</OAI-PMH>