<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<OAI-PMH xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" 
         xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance"
         xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/OAI-PMH.xsd">
    <responseDate>2026-07-13T06:23:11Z</responseDate>
                <request verb="GetRecord" identifier="oai:arXiv.org:2511.06844" metadataPrefix="arXiv">http://oaipmh.arxiv.org/oai</request>


    <GetRecord>
                <record>
                <header>
        <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:2511.06844</identifier>
        <datestamp>2025-11-11</datestamp>
            <setSpec>physics:quant-ph</setSpec>
    </header>

            <metadata>
                        <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ https://oaipmh.arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
        <id>2511.06844</id>
        <created>2025-11-10</created>
            <updated>2025-11-11</updated>
        <authors>
                <author>
                    <keyname>Yang</keyname>
                        <forenames>Mu</forenames>
                </author>
                <author>
                    <keyname>Li</keyname>
                        <forenames>Yue</forenames>
                </author>
                <author>
                    <keyname>Xu</keyname>
                        <forenames>Mingtao</forenames>
                </author>
                <author>
                    <keyname>Yi</keyname>
                        <forenames>Wei</forenames>
                </author>
                <author>
                    <keyname>Xu</keyname>
                        <forenames>Jin-Shi</forenames>
                </author>
                <author>
                    <keyname>Li</keyname>
                        <forenames>Chuan-Feng</forenames>
                </author>
                <author>
                    <keyname>Guo</keyname>
                        <forenames>Guang-Can</forenames>
                </author>
        </authors>
        <title>Observation of Non-Hermitian Spectral Deformation in Complex Momentum Space</title>
            <categories>quant-ph</categories>
            <license>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0/</license>
            <abstract>Open systems feature a variety of phenomena that arise from non-Hermitian physics. Recent theoretical studies have offered much insights into these phenomena through the non-Bloch band theory, though many of the theory&#39;s key features are experimentally elusive. For instance, the correspondence between complex momenta and non-Hermitian bands, while central to non-Bloch band theory, has so far defied direct experimental observation. Here we experimentally study the non-Hermitian spectral deformation in complex-momentum space, by implementing a non-Hermitian lattice with long-range couplings in the synthetic orbital-angular-momentum (OAM) dimension of photons inside a degenerate cavity. Encoding the complex momenta in the phase and amplitude modulations of the OAM modes, and devising a complex-momentum-resolved projective detection, we reconstruct the spectral deformation in momentum space, where the eigenspectrum on the complex plane morphs through distinct geometries. This enables us to experimentally extract key information of the system under the non-Bloch band theory, including exceptional points in the complex-momentum space, the open-boundary spectra, and the generalized Brillouin zone. Our work demonstrates a versatile platform for exploring non-Hermitian physics and non-Bloch band theory, and opens the avenue for direct experimental investigation of non-Bloch features in the complex-momentum space.</abstract>
    </arXiv>

            </metadata>
        </record>

    </GetRecord>
</OAI-PMH>